<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Assessing communica on success in triads based on group decisionmaking outcomes</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ingvi</forename><surname>Örnolfsson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Health Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Tobias May Hearing Systems Sec on</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University of Denmark</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kgs. Lyngby</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Axel</forename><surname>Ahrens</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Health Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Tobias May Hearing Systems Sec on</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University of Denmark</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kgs. Lyngby</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Torsten</forename><surname>Dau</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Health Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Tobias May Hearing Systems Sec on</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University of Denmark</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kgs. Lyngby</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Assessing communica on success in triads based on group decisionmaking outcomes</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:31+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Ecological validity</term>
					<term>face-to-face communica on</term>
					<term>triadic conversa ons</term>
					<term>task-oriented dialogue</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Group decision-making is a fundamental aspect of many communica ve interac ons. When inves ga ng human communica on, analyses of group decision-making offer the poten al to quan ta vely evaluate various criteria that are indica ve of successful communica on. This study inves gated how background noise influenced group decision-making in triadic interac ons. Ten triads of normal-hearing par cipants were recruited. Ini ally, each par cipant responded to a series of binary general knowledge ques ons and provided a confidence ra ng along with their response. Subsequently, the ques ons were discussed in groups of three in two dis nct condi ons; a highintensity background noise condi on (78 dB, referred to as the &apos;noisy&apos; condi on&apos;) or a low-intensity condi on (48dB, referred to as the &apos;quiet&apos; condi on). Finally, par cipants individually answered the same ques ons again. Three outcome measures-stay/switch behavior, decision convergence, and vo ng strategy-were employed to assess how par cipants modified their posterior decisions rela ve to their ini al decisions. These measures collec vely revealed an interac on between confidence and noise level. Confident members generally had a stronger influence on post-conversa on decisions in the noisy condi on compared to the quiet condi on. This finding suggests that low-confidence members might be more inclined to withhold their opinions in noisy environments compared to their high-confidence peers. From a broader perspec ve, the results demonstrate the sensi vity of the group decision-making task and proposed outcome measures to adverse changes in the acous c environment. This task paradigm could poten ally serve as a means for obtaining an objec ve evalua on of hearing interven ons based on high-level decision-making in interac ve, face-to-face communica on scenarios.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>of communica ve interac on is less precisely defined than the clear goals of one-way, non-interac ve listening. The la er can be easily evaluated based on whether the signal -a tone, a word, or a complete sentence -was received and recognized, yielding outcomes with well-behaved psychometric proper es. In contrast, the defini on of successful communica on and how to measure it as robustly as successful listening remains uncertain.</p><p>In recent years, there has been a growing interest in studying conversa onal behavior within the context of hearing-related research <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Buchholz, Davis, Beadle, &amp; Kim, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Hadley, Brimijoin, &amp; Whitmer, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Hadley, Whitmer, Brimijoin, &amp; Naylor, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Miles et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Petersen, MacDonald, &amp; Sørensen, 2022)</ref>. These studies o en u lize task-oriented dialogue materials, offering a means to measure successful informa on exchange through task performance. Examples include the tangram maze task, where par cipants navigate through a maze whose layout is divided between them <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Beechey, Buchholz, &amp; Keidser, 2018</ref>, and the diapix task <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Baker &amp; Hazan, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Petersen et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Sørensen &amp; Fereczkowski, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Watson, Sørensen, &amp; MacDonald, 2019)</ref>, a spot-the-difference task where each par cipant views only one version of the image. In these tasks, successful communica on is conceptualized as the ability of interlocutors to exchange informa on. While informa on exchange can poten ally serve as a meaningful concept related to communica on success, at least three concerns limit the relevance of the diapix and tangram maze tasks for measuring successful informa on exchange in naturalis c conversa ons.</p><p>The first concern is that exis ng studies have either reported that par cipants consistently solved the task perfectly regardless of their hearing status or noise level, or inten onally omi ed repor ng par cipants' performance, acknowledging that other cogni ve skills play a more significant role in determining their performance than their communica on ability. Regardless of the accuracy of the la er, if tasks generally result in ceiling performance, one is le with task comple on me as a poten al performance measure. However, a low task comple on me does not necessarily indicate a desirable trait for informa on exchange. While one could argue that a challenging communica on environment may require more conversa onal repairs (e.g., requests for clarifica on), thereby increasing the me to solve the task, the reality is that these repairs represent the applica on of the ability to adapt one's behavior to overcome a communica ve obstacle. Any successfully completed diapix puzzle -regardless of the me taken or the number of mes par cipants needed to repeat themselves -represents the same degree of successful informa on exchange, i.e. an equivalent amount of task-relevant informa on transmi ed and compared between individuals.</p><p>The second concern with these tasks is that they may enforce a very specific and unbalanced form of conversa on. For example, in the diapix task, one person can describe all the contents of their picture while the other person only interrupts to inform them when their own picture differs. This strategy may be effec ve for the task at hand, but it represents an asymmetric communica on situa on that may not mirror naturalis c conversa ons. It a broader sense, the core problem here may be that, in both tasks, each par cipant has complete certainty in the informa on they wish to transmit, as well as the informa on they receive, since they know that their interlocutors also have complete certainty in their informa on. This makes it rela vely easy to solve the task through what could be called 'serial monologues', i.e. a series of completely independent speech u erances, without any need to interact or nego ate the meaning or relevance of these u erances. An extreme manifesta on of this would be the case where, in the diapix task, one par cipant describes the complete contents of their picture while the other takes notes of the differences.</p><p>The third concern with the tangram maze and diapix tasks is that they are designed for only two par cipants, making them imprac cal for studies involving larger groups. In dyadic interac ons, the roles of interlocutors are more or less fixed, with a clear dis nc on between the speaker and the listener. Furthermore, there is never any doubt about who is being addressed, and there is no compe on with other listeners for the opportunity to speak next. These common challenges only begin to surface when three or more individuals par cipate in the conversa on. In reality, most everyday interac ons involve more than two par cipants <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Peperkoorn et al., 2020)</ref>, and it is well-established that these situa ons are par cularly challenging for hearing-impaired individuals <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Kiessling et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Nicoras, Gotowiec, Hadley, Smeds, &amp; Naylor, 2022)</ref>. Expanding hearing research to go beyond dyadic interac ons is thus crucial for comprehending the most challenging everyday communica on scenarios for hearing-impaired individuals.</p><p>In this study, we introduce the group confidence judgment task, a novel approach for assessing communica on success designed to address the limita ons of exis ng communica on tasks. To elicit communica on, this task employs general-knowledge ques ons, about which par cipants are not necessarily en rely certain. This increases task difficulty and mi gates the ceiling performance issues observed in exis ng tasks. The general knowledge ques ons also foster less constrained conversa onal dynamics, as discussions revolve around themes with personal and/or emo onal a achment. While theore cally applicable to any group size and interven on, we employ the task in a triadic se ng to explore communica on success in mul -talker background noise presented either at a high intensity ('noisy' condi on) or at a low intensity ('quiet' condi on). Alongside the task, we introduce three outcome measures for quan fying informa on exchange: one drawn from the literature on group decision-making processes, and two newly devised measures for this study. By comparing individuals' decisions before and a er the conversa on, these measures quan fy the extent and nature of informa on exchange among par cipants, which we consider to be indica ve of -or at least related to -successful communica on. This approach is commonly employed in studies on group decisionmaking <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bahrami et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bang et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Koriat, 2012)</ref> and may enable the quan fica on of the detrimental effects of communica on-inhibi ng factors, such as background noise or hearing loss.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Par cipants</head><p>The study comprised 30 par cipants organized into groups of ten triads. All par cipants, aged between 20 and 35 years, were na ve Danish speakers with self-reported normal-hearing status. Except for two pairs, par cipants were unfamiliar with each other prior to the experiment. The experiment was conducted in Danish and took approximately 2.5 hours. Par cipants received compensa on for their me a er providing informed consent. Ethical approval was obtained from the Science-Ethics Commi ee for the Capital Region of Denmark (reference H-16036391).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Environment and Experimental setup</head><p>The par cipants were seated in an equilateral triangle configura on, facing the other two group members, as illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 1b</ref>. The distance between par cipants was approximately 1.5 m. They wore eye-tracking glasses capturing point-of-view footage, eye-gaze data, and pupil dila on.</p><p>Addi onally, three microphones were u lized, including a pair of in-ear binaural microphones and a cheek-mounted microphone; however, data from these devices were not analyzed in this study.</p><p>The group was surrounded by eight loudspeakers (Dynaudio BM6P), arranged in a ring of radius 2.4 m.</p><p>Each loudspeaker played a separate Danish monologue <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ahrens &amp; Lund, 2022)</ref>, resul ng in a spa ally distributed mul -talker masker. The monologues lasted approximately 90 seconds each and were looped for the dura on of the conversa on. The loudspeakers were driven by a sonible d:24 amplifier.</p><p>The masker was presented at sound pressure levels (SPLs) of either 48 dB or 78 dB, corresponding to the quiet and the noisy condi on, respec vely. The simultaneous presenta on of mul ple masking speech sources rendered them individually unintelligible in both condi ons. To eliminate visual distrac ons, a circular black curtain en rely enclosed the par cipant area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task</head><p>The ini al task for the par cipants involved responding individually to a series of binary generalknowledge ques ons categorized into three topics: Hollywood movies (iden fying the oldest of two movies), Copenhagen landmarks (determining which of two loca ons is closest to the city center), and European countries (determining which of two countries has the most inhabitants). Each topic comprised two lists of 28 ques ons, one for each acous c noise condi on. Consequently, each list contained 28 trials, formulated by employing all unique binary ques ons from the eight items associated with that topic (e.g., eight Hollywood movies). Before the primary experiment, the group underwent a brief trial round on a different topic not used in the study. This allowed par cipants to familiarize themselves with the task, the technical interface, and with each other, thus overcoming any ini al awkwardness in their conversa ons.</p><p>Ques ons were presented on a touch-screen tablet, showing a visual illustra on of the two op ons along with accompanying labels. The par cipants were instructed to select an op on and provide a confidence level, expressed as a percentage between 50% and 100%, with 50% indica ng no preference for either op on, while 100% meant absolute certainty in the decision <ref type="figure">(Figure 1a</ref>). They were asked to interpret the scale as indica ng their es mated probability of having answered the ques on correctly, i.e. a metacogni ve judgment.</p><p>A er the ini al set of 28 ques ons, a conversa on round followed, during which the par cipants discussed their answers with the other group members. Collabora ve problem-solving was encouraged, emphasizing the importance of improving the performance of all group members, not just oneself. Each par cipant was given a sheet displaying the eight items from the preceding ques on round during the conversa on (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1b)</ref>. Once a 10-minute me limit was reached or the conversa on concluded naturally, par cipants individually answered the same 28 ques ons again (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1c</ref>). This process was repeated six mes, once for each of the three topics and in each of the <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Overview of the experimental procedure. a) Par cipants ini ally made individual decisions on a series of binary general knowledge ques ons, submi ng decisions along with a confidence ra ng using a con nuous scale. b) Subsequently, par cipants engaged in group conversa ons with two other members, with the aim of improving each other's answers. The conversa on took place in either loud background noise (78 dB spa alized 8-talker babble) or in quiet (48 dB spa alized 8talker babble). c) Following the conversa on, par cipants independently and privately repeated the same ques ons.</p><p>two noise condi ons. The order of topics and condi ons was randomized between groups, ensuring that the same topic did not appear consecu vely. A brief break was incorporated a er the third ques on round.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Outcome measures</head><p>To evaluate the impact of group communica on, we analyzed the pre-and post-conversa on responses of group members using three different outcome measures: 1) individual stay/switch behavior, 2) group and pair convergence within the group, and 3) the group's vo ng strategy. The first two measures were designed specifically for this study, while the third represents an established metric from the literature on group decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Koriat, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Meyen, Sigg, Luxburg, &amp; Franz, 2021</ref>).</p><p>The terms staying and switching refer to the post conversa on decisions of individuals when another group member disagrees with their ini al decision. In such a scenario, the individual faces two op ons; staying with their ini al decision or switching to the alterna ve proposed by the other member. Each Convergence was defined in two dis nct ways: at the pairwise level and at the group level. Pairwise convergence was defined as trials where a pair transi ons from disagreeing before the conversa on to agreeing a erwards, e.g. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data preprocessing and sta s cal analyses</head><p>The par cipants' confidence ra ngs were transformed into a linear scale ranging from 0 to 50. Here, 0 corresponded to 50% (indica ng no preference or confidence), and 50 corresponded to 100%</p><p>(reflec ng maximal confidence in either decision). In cases where direc onality was relevant, the sign was used to indicate the decision's direc on (i.e., which of the two op ons was chosen), effec vely extending the linear scale to [−50; 50].</p><p>The main effects of the background noise on outcome measures were evaluated using Fisher's exact test (two-tailed), and results are presented in con ngency tables along with the 95% confidence intervals of the odds ra o of the two condi ons.</p><p>Interac on effects between noise and confidence levels on the outcome measures were es mated using logis c regression models. Confidence was used as the predictor variable, and separate models were fi ed for the two noise condi ons. Sta s cal significance of the difference between condi ons was evaluated based on two-sided permuta on test of the difference in the intercept ( ) and slope ( ) parameters of these models. The permuta on test was performed by randomizing the noise and quiet labels of each trial = 10.000 mes, thus simula ng draws from the proposed null distribu on where the condi on has no effect on the outcome. Confidence intervals for the difference in parameter es mates between condi ons are also reported; these were determined using the percen le bootstrap method using = 10.000 bootstrap samples for each condi on. The bootstrapped samples from each condi on were subtracted from each other, and the 5 th and 95 th percen les of the bootstraps are reported as the confidence intervals of the difference between condi ons.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Impact of noise and confidence on stay/switch behavior Par cipant decisions were analyzed in rela on to the noise and quiet condi ons and whether the decision maker was the most or least confident member. Trials were excluded if either member had a confidence level of 0 (i.e., no preference). Addi onally, when assessing the difference in confidence between the most and least confident member, trials were omi ed if both par cipants had equal confidence. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> illustrates the stay/switch behavior of the par cipants. Par cipants were more inclined to stay with their ini al decision (65.6%) in trials where they were more confident than another member. Conversely, when they were the least confident member, they stayed with their ini al response in only 42.8% of trials. There was no significant main effect of background noise on the To explore the interac on between confidence level and background noise, each instance of pairwise disagreement was categorized based on stay/switch outcomes and noise/quiet condi ons. The le panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> illustrates these four trial categories with semitransparent markers, where each marker corresponds to a single pairwise prior disagreement. On the x-axis, the difference in confidence between the two members in each trial is shown. Posi ve values indicate that the first-person member (the decision-maker) is more confident, while nega ve values suggest the opposite. The solid lines represent logis c regressions conducted separately in each condi on, with deno ng the slope and the intercept at − = 0. These regressions predict the probability of a trial being a stay trial as a func on of confidence difference. In both condi ons, the slope was consistently posi ve. This is consistent with the analysis from the most/least confident split in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> indica ng that more confident members are more likely to stay, whereas less confident members are more inclined to switch. The overall bias towards staying is evident in the y-axis intercept, which exceeds the 50% mark in both condi ons.</p><p>The noise condi on exhibited a significantly steeper slope in the regression model. This finding suggests an interac on between condi on and confidence level, indica ng that in the noise condi on, the prior answer of the most confident member was even more likely to be chosen a er the conversa on. Note that the slope parameters reported in the legend of The pairwise stay/switch model does not consider the contribu on of the third group member, who also influences the decision on any given trial. To address this, a model using the total summed confidence was employed, as depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2 (</ref> While the pairwise and group-level stay/switch models illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> demonstrate an interac on between rela ve confidence and stay/switch decisions, they do not provide evidence about the influence of absolute confidence levels. For example, a pairwise disagreement between individuals with confidence levels of 60% and 70%, respec vely, is mapped to the same point on the x-axis (i.e., 10) as a disagreement where confidence levels are 80% and 90%. To assess the effect of absolute confidence level, separate models using first-and second-person confidence levels were fi ed as depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>. In these models, the x-value of individual data points now exclusively represents the confidence of either individual in the disagreeing pair in that specific trial. The results indicate that increasing first-person confidence and decreasing second-person confidence both increase the likelihood of staying. In both scenarios, there is an interac on with noise level, with the noise condi on yielding significantly steeper slopes. The slope parameters of the first-and second-person confidence models were remarkably similar, except for the nega ve sign in the second-person model. This implies that increasing first-person confidence has the same effect as decreasing second-person confidence, providing valida on for the use of the difference-based models shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. The intercepts of . This indicates that the impact of both first-and second-person confidence on the decision to stay or switch is more pronounced in noisy environments compared to quiet ones. For both models, the intercept is also significantly different between the two condi ons the first-and second-person models are significantly different between condi ons, as well as being no ceably different from the approximately 55% intercept of the pairwise and group-level models.</p><p>This can be explained by the base confidence rate across the dataset; the median confidence level across all trials is 17. Thus, when condi oning on trials where the first-person member has a confidence level of 0, we would expect the other member's confidence to be 17, which explains why the stay rate is lower. This also explains why condi oning on the second-person member's confidence causes the stay rate at = 0 to be higher. For both the first-and second-person models, we see that when condi oning on a confidence level of 17, there is no difference between the noise and quiet condi ons, and the stay rates are back to the same level as for the difference-based models when the difference is zero. This further emphasizes that reducing first-person confidence and increasing second-person confidence (and vice versa) impact the stay rate in a similar way. The number of convergent trials -i.e., trials where prior disagreement turned into agreement a er the discussion -in each condi on is presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 2</ref>, both for pairwise and group-level convergence. Convergence was more prominent in the noise condi on, with odds ra os of 1.61 and 1.90 for groups and pairs, respec vely. Consequently, par cipants were more inclined to reach agreement on their post-conversa on decisions in the noise condi on.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Impact of noise on convergence</head><p>The interac on between confidence and convergence is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref>. Pairwise and group-level confidence differences were calculated similarly to the stay/switch analysis. confidence difference was omi ed, as it had served only to iden fy the decision direc on of the deciding member; for the convergence metric, however, there is no single deciding member, as convergence is inherently a group-level metric. In the x-axis labels of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref>, | − | quan fies the difference between the confidences of the two members in ques on, and | − | quan fies the total confidence of those favoring op on A minus the confidence of those favoring op on B.</p><p>Both the pairwise and group-level models exhibit a steeper slope in noise than in quiet, although the difference was not significant for either model. Nevertheless, especially for the pairwise model, the 90% confidence bounds of the convergence rate are dis nctly separated for all but the lowest confidence differences.</p><p>Overall, the results indicate that the convergence rate was higher in noise, with the effect being slightly more pronounced at higher levels of confidence difference.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Impact of noise on vo ng strategy</head><p>The analysis of vo ng strategies focused specifically on trials where the most confident par cipant was in the minority, cons tu ng 9.4% of the total trials (157 out of 1680). As each of these trials contributed three individual posterior decisions, a total of 471 binary decisions were used for the vo ng strategy analysis. The findings, presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 3</ref>, suggest a marginally significant effect of the condi on, with the noise condi on leading to a higher use of the confidence sla ng strategy. In the quiet condi on, both strategies were equally probable, whereas in noise, 58.6% of decisions (130 out of 222) used the confidence sla ng strategy.   confidence was larger than the total confidence of the majority (nega ve values of − ). There is substan al overlap between the regression confidence bounds, however, so this observa on warrants further inves ga on. Moreover, due to sparse data at posi ve confidence differences, the observed effect of increased confidence sla ng in noise may be valid only for nega ve values of − . It remains uncertain whether majority vo ng might be more favored in noisy condi ons when the total confidence of majority members is substan ally larger than that of the minority member, i.e. when − ≫ 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The results from all three outcome measures -stay/switch behavior, convergence and vo ng strategy -consistently indicated a similar effect: the influence of confident members on the posterior decision was more pronounced in noisy condi ons. This effect was par cularly evident in the vo ng strategy analysis, demonstra ng a stronger inclina on to align with high-confidence members in the noise condi on, even when they were in the minority. In the stay/switch analysis, the preference for highconfidence members was revealed by the steeper slope in noise across all four regression models considered (the two confidence-difference-based models, as well as the first-and second-person models). The convergence rate also increased in noise, especially when one member showed substan ally higher confidence than others or when the difference in total confidence for the two op ons was large.</p><p>It is not surprising that the analyses of confidence sla ng/majority vo ng and stay/switch decisions yielded similar results. In fact, the pairwise confidence difference model of stay/switch behavior can be viewed as a parametrized generaliza on of the binary CS/MV models. In the pairwise confidence difference model, an infinitely steep slope (i.e. a step func on at − = 0) corresponds to the CS model of dyadic decision-making, where the decision is always determined by the most confident member. In an infinitely steep confidence difference model, for − &lt; 0, the decision will switch with 100% certainty, and for − &gt; 0, the decision will stay with 100% certainty.</p><p>Conversely, if the slope is zero, stay and switch decisions are equally probable regardless of confidence levels -analogous to the MV model, which considers only the fact that there is one vote for each op on and disregards confidence levels. Therefore, any posi ve finite slope represents an opera ng point between these two extremes, MV and CS, and a larger posi ve slope in noise can be interpreted as a stronger tendency towards CS.</p><p>Like the vo ng strategy, the convergence rate is also intricately connected to stay/switch behavior. To (1 − 0.64) = 0.56 in quiet. In fact, at any given confidence difference level, if the stay rate at posi ve confidence differences is higher in noise and the stay rate at nega ve confidence differences is lower, the expected convergence rate will similarly be higher in noise, as both members are more likely to choose the same outcome.</p><p>The underlying reason for decisions being more influenced by confident members in loud background noise could be a ributed to two factors: 1) The increased effort required to communicate in loud background noise, and 2) the assump on that high confidence in a belief is related to high perceived importance in terms of solving the group task. To understand how this might explain the importance of confidence in noise, consider a trial where the group disagrees before the conversa on. During the conversa on, each group member must individually decide whether to try to convince others that their belief is correct. While ideally, all opinions would be shared and weighted based on the degree of confidence -in fact, this has been shown in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Grofman, Owen, &amp; Feld (1983)</ref> to lead to ideal decision-making under certain assump ons -this is not always the case. Par cularly, low-confidence opinions are at risk of not being voiced, as their authors may find their own convic on too low when weighed against the effort required to express it -and poten ally engage in a lengthy discussion about its validity -to be worthwhile in terms of poten al rewards (i.e. increased task performance). The decision to share an opinion is thus influenced by an interac on between the confidence level and the background noise level. Opinions held with greater confidence are more likely to be shared, as they are perceived to have a greater poten al for increasing task performance. As the noise level increases, more effort is needed to voice an opinion <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Beechey et al., 2018)</ref>. This would effec vely raise the confidence threshold at which a given opinion is judged to be important enough to share. As lowconfidence opinions will now be more likely to be considered irrelevant for solving the task, when weighed against the effort requirement, high-confidence opinions will become rela vely more likely to go unchallenged when the noise level increases. This explains the stronger influence that highconfidence individuals seem to have in noise. This explana on based on a proposed effort-importance tradeoff is supported by the dura on of the conversa ons in the present study. Groups discussed for on average 8.0 minutes in quiet but only 6.8 minutes in noise, a significant difference ( = 0.0145, = [−1.836; −0.4206]). This observa on aligns with the hypothesis that fewer disagreements were voiced in noise.</p><p>Two related effects may further enhance this phenomenon. The first can be seen as a form of anchoring effect, where the ini al member expressing an opinion may carry more weight simply by virtue of speaking first. If this holds true, noise does not necessarily have to completely suppress lowconfidence opinions to explain the importance of confidence in noise. It would be enough for the noise to merely delay the me it takes for a member to decide to voice their low-confidence opinion, thereby increasing the likelihood that the first voiced opinion is one with high-confidence one. The second effect is that periods of silence and/or backchannelling (verbal feedback given while someone else is talking, such as "uh-huh") can be interpreted as agreement. If noise prolongs the me it takes for group members to formulate a response and/or increases the frequency of backchannels between the first speaker and their addressee, these cues may be perceived by the third member as agreement.</p><p>Consequently, the third member may choose not to express a disagreeing opinion as a result of noise prolonging silences or increasing the number of backchannels. High noise levels have previously been found to be related to increased number of backchannels and changes in the response ming between interlocutors <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Petersen et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr">Watson et al., 2019)</ref>. Backchannelling may also directly impact the confidence of talkers. For example, it has been shown that a decrease in the amount of backchannelling by a listener nega vely impact various features related to good storytelling on the talker's side <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bavelas et al., 2000)</ref>. It is plausible that a similar mechanism could be responsible for increasing talkers' own confidence when there is more backchannelling.</p><p>In the present study, exploring whether the suggested tradeoff between effort and importance discourages individuals from expressing disagreements on specific ques ons has been hindered by the arrangement of ques ons into lists of transi vely related items. Effec vely labeling each spoken statement as being connected to a par cular item pair would prove challenging, if not impossible.</p><p>Furthermore, conduc ng such an analysis would demand substan al effort in terms of annota ng individual statements, a task that exceeded the scope of this study.</p><p>The task and accompanying analysis methods introduced here offer a high degree of flexibility in implementa on. Firstly, the stay/switch, convergence and vo ng strategy sta s cs can generally be derived regardless of group size, especially the group-level variants of the sta s cs. This represents a clear advantage over, for example, the commonly used diapix task, which is inherently limited by its task material to dyads. Addi onally, the general knowledge ques ons can naturally be replaced by ques ons from arbitrary knowledge domains. They can also be subs tuted with en rely different types of ques ons. For example, a 2-alterna ve perceptual task or even opinion-based ques ons with no correct answer could be employed. Both of these alterna ve ques on types have been used in the group decision-making literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bang et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Fay et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Koriat, 2012)</ref>, and the analysis tools introduced in this study can be directly applied to decisions using those kinds of ques ons as well. Different ques on types will undoubtedly yield different decision-making behaviors, and the impact of noise, hearing impairment, or other communica ve inhibi ons should be considered in the context of which type of ques on is being used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>This study introduced a novel task designed for group interaction studies, termed the group confidence judgment task. This task was employed to examine how ten triads exchanged information in both noisy and quiet environments. The outcomes of the study were twofold. Firstly, the new task was introduced along with three accompanying outcome measures to investigate communication success in task-oriented interactive communication. This task, applicable to any group size, included decision-based outcome measures that shed light on how individual group members influenced and shared information with each other. This approach, utilizing a pre-and post-conversation decision task, is widely used in the scientific literature on group decision-making, and we believe that it holds considerable promise in hearing research, where it could provide insights into how hearing impairment affects individuals' participation in -and influence on -group decision-making processes.</p><p>The second outcome pertained to the specific implementation of the task in this study. Data from ten normal-hearing triads engaged in the group decision-making task revealed significant differences in decision-making based on the background noise level during conversations. Loud background noise resulted in decisions being influenced by group members with higher prior confidence in their decisions. In contrast, conversations in quiet resulted in decisions where prior confidence played a smaller role in determining the final decision. The underlying cause may have been that the members with lower initial confidence were more likely to refrain from voicing their opinions when communicating became more challenging due to background noise. They weighed the difficulty of sharing information against the perceived benefit in terms of task performance and may have consequently chosen to abstain from voicing their opinions more often than high-confidence members did.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>of the three dis nct pairs of individuals within a group were analyzed separately, disregarding the prior decision of the third member. As an example, consider a case where the prior decisions of a group are [ ], and the posterior decisions are [ ], with and deno ng the two op ons (e.g., The Netherlands and Romania in the example shown in Figure 1). As there is no prior disagreement between members one and two, this pair is ignored. Analyzing the pair consis ng of members one and three reveals that member one stayed ([ → ]), while member three switched ([ → ]). Similarly, in the pair of members two and three, member two stayed ([ → ]) while member three switched ([ → ]).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Interac on between stay/switch behavior and the confidence difference of a pair or group. Le panel: Stay/switch behavior as a func on of the confidence difference between two disagreeing members. Posi ve values mean that the member making the decision to stay or switch is the most confident. The slope of the regression is significantly steeper in the noise condi on ( = 0.0261, = [0.286; 1.957]). There was no significant difference between the intercepts ( = 0.548, = [−0.186; 0.0860]). Right panel: Stay/switch behavior as a func on of the total confidence of those agreeing with the deciding member minus the total confidence of those disagreeing. Again, the slope is significantly steeper in the noise condi on ( = 0.0044, = [0.261; 1.026]), but there is no significant difference between the intercepts ( = 0.363, = [−0.0247; 0.0675]).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2 refer to the log-odds domain regression. When translated to percentages, the slope at the origin is 1.05 for the noise condi on and 0.77 for the quiet condi on. Thus, transi oning from equal confidence ( − = 0) to a one-point difference ( − = 1) results in a 1.05 percentage point change in the stay/switch decision in noise, compared to a 0.77 percentage point change in quiet.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Interac on between stay/switch behavior and the confidence levels of both members in a disagreeing pair. Le panel: As the confidence of the decision-maker ( ) increases, the likelihood of staying also increases. Right panel: When the confidence of the other member ( ) increases, staying becomes less likely, and switching thus more likely. In both models, the slopes are significantly steeper in noise (first-person: = 0</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3: Interac on between stay/switch behavior and the confidence levels of both members in a disagreeing pair. Le panel: As the confidence of the decision-maker ( ) increases, the likelihood of staying also increases. Right panel: When the confidence of the other member ( ) increases, staying becomes less likely, and switching thus more likely. In both models, the slopes are significantly steeper in noise (first-person: = 0.0048, = [0.744; 3.052], second-person: = 0.0028, = [−3.090; −0.819]). This indicates that the impact of both first-and second-person confidence on the decision to stay or switch is more pronounced in noisy environments compared to quiet ones. For both models, the intercept is also significantly different between the two condi ons (first-person: = 0.0045, = [−2.064; −0.505 ], second-person: = 0.0079, = [0.458; 2.001]).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Interac on between confidence and convergence rate. Le panel: Pairwise convergence as a func on of the difference in confidence for a disagreeing pair. Right panel: Group convergence as a func on of the difference in total confidence between those favoring op on A and those favoring op on B. Although both slopes are steeper in noise, the difference is not sta s cally significant (pairs: = 0.204, = [−0.0058; 0.0441], groups: = 0.250, = [−0.0054; 0.0443]). The intercepts are also not significantly different (pairs: = 0</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>shows the choice of strategy as a func on of the confidence difference. The confidence difference was computed as the sum of the prior confidences of majority members ( ) minus the confidence of the most confident member ( ). The data indicate that the tendency for confidence sla ng in noise was most pronounced in trials where the most confident member's</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Le panel: Overall prevalence of confidence sla ng and majority vo ng strategies. Right panel: Prevalence of CS and MV strategies as a func on of the difference between the total confidence of majority members and that of the most confident member. At nega ve values, the most confident member is more confident than the sum of the majority members' confidence. Only trials where the majority members and most confident member chose different op ons prior to the conversa on are included.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>illustrate this, consider the example where two disagreeing group members have confidence levels of 36 and 11, respec vely. The first member's confidence difference ( − ) is 25, while the second member's confidence difference is −25. Referring to Figure 2, at these confidence levels, member one would have a 77% chance of staying in noise, as opposed to only 73% in quiet. Conversely, member two would have a 72% chance of switching in noise, compared to only 64% in quiet. As pairwise convergence requires one member to stay and the other switch, the total probability of convergence would be 0.77 * 0.72 + (1 − 0.77) * (1 − 0.72) = 0.62 in noise, but only 0.73 * 0.64 + (1 − 0.73) *</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>This behavior was not considered as pairwise convergence. Group convergence was defined as trials where both op ons were present in prior decisions, and all group members chose the same op on a er the conversa on, e.g., [ ] → [ ]. third outcome measure examined individual's vo ng strategy. Specifically, two exis ng models of group decision-making -majority vo ng and confidence sla ng -were compared. Majority vo ng reflects the tendency of posterior decisions to follow the most popular prior decision, while confidence sla ng reflects the tendency of posterior decisions to follow the prior decision favored by the most confident individual. For example, if a groups' prior decisions are [ ], with boldface indica ng the most confident member, any member selec ng a er the conversa on will be classified as an instance of majority vo ng. Conversely, choosing would be categorized as confidence sla ng.Notably, confidence sla ng and majority vo ng are not mutually exclusive, as the most confident member can be part of a majority. The vo ng strategy analysis was thus limited to trials where the most confident member was in the minority.</figDesc><table><row><cell>The</cell></row></table><note>, [ ] → [ ]. Occasionally, pairs may "convince each other", maintaining disagreement but adop ng each other's prior decisions, e.g., [ ] → [ ].</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Stay/switch behavior as func on of noise condi on and rela ve confidence level</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>cipants staying with their ini al decision. A two-sided binomial test revealed a small but significant overall bias, with 54.2% of trials resul ng in par cipants choosing to stay.</figDesc><table><row><cell>likelihood of par</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell># decisions</cell><cell>Stay</cell><cell>Switch</cell><cell>p-value</cell><cell>Odds ra o [95% CI]</cell></row><row><cell>Most confident Least confident</cell><cell>1327 1327</cell><cell>65.6% 42.8%</cell><cell>34.4% 57.2%</cell><cell>1e-32</cell><cell>2.55 [2.18;2.98]</cell></row><row><cell>Noise (78 dB) Quiet (48 dB)</cell><cell>1284 1382</cell><cell>53.5% 54.8%</cell><cell>46.5% 45.2%</cell><cell>0.508</cell><cell>0.95 [0.81;1.10]</cell></row><row><cell>All</cell><cell>2666</cell><cell>54.2%</cell><cell>45.8%</cell><cell>1.55e-5</cell><cell>-</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>since the confidence value of the first-person member is, by defini on, always posi ve. The model yields results similar to the pairwise difference model concerning the slope and intercept parameters. There was a slight bias towards staying at a total confidence difference of zero, and the noise condi on slope was significantly steeper than the quiet condi on slope.</figDesc><table><row><cell>[</cell><cell cols="3">], and confidence levels [18 33 21], when predic ng the first member's stay rate, the total</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">confidence difference would be</cell><cell>−</cell><cell>= 18 − (33 + 21) = −36. Conversely, when</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">predic ng the second and third members' stay rates,</cell><cell>−</cell><cell>= (33 + 21) − 18 = 36. This</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">model's predic on was applied to all trials, not just those with prior disagreement. The poten al range</cell></row><row><cell>of</cell><cell>−</cell><cell cols="2">was thus [−99; 150],</cell></row></table><note>right panel). Here, the x-axis shows the sum of signed confidence values on any given trial, with a posi ve sign for each member agreeing with the deciding member and nega ve sign for those disagreeing. For example, in a trial with prior decisions</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>Convergence rate in noise and quiet</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Vo ng strategies in noise and quiet</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell># decisions</cell><cell>Majority vo ng</cell><cell>Confidence sla ng</cell><cell cols="2">p-value Odds ra o [95% CI]</cell></row><row><cell>Noise</cell><cell>222</cell><cell>41.4%</cell><cell>58.6%</cell><cell>0.052</cell><cell>1.45 [1.01; 2.08]</cell></row><row><cell>Quiet</cell><cell>249</cell><cell>50.6%</cell><cell>49.4%</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Auditory spa al analysis in reverberant mul -talker environments with congruent and incongruent audio-visual room informa on</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ahrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1121/10.0013991</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of the Acous cal Society of America</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">152</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1586" to="1594" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Olsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Latham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Roepstorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1185718</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1126/science.1185718" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Op mally Interac ng Minds</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">329</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1081" to="1085" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DiapixUK: task materials for the elicita on of mul ple spontaneous speech dialogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Hazan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-011-0075-y</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.3758/s13428-011-0075-y" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="761" to="770" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does interac on ma er? Tes ng whether a confidence heuris c can replace interac on in collec ve decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Fusaroli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tylén</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Olsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Latham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y F</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.concog.2014.02.002</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1016/j.concog.2014.02.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Consciousness and Cogni on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Listeners as co-narrators</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bavelas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Coates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1037/0022-3514.79.6.941</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="941" to="952" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring communica on difficulty through effor ul speech produc on during conversa on</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Beechey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Buchholz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Keidser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.specom.2018.04.007</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1016/j.specom.2018.04.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Speech Communica on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Elici ng Naturalis c Conversa ons: A Method for Assessing Communica on Ability, Subjec ve Experience, and the Impacts of Noise and Hearing Impairment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Beechey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Buchholz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Keidser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1044/2018_JSLHR-H-18-0107</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1044/2018_JSLHR-H-18-0107" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="484" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developing a Real-Time Test to Inves gate Conversa onal Speech Understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Buchholz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Beadle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1044/2022_JSLHR-22-00218</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4520" to="4538" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Carlile</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Keidser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1097/AUD.0000000000000939</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1097/AUD.0000000000000939" />
		<title level="m">Conversa onal Interac on Is the Brain in Ac on: Implica ons for the Evalua on of Hearing and Hearing Interven ons. Ear &amp; Hearing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="67" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Supplement 1</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Group Discussion as Interac ve Dialogue or as Serial Monologue: The Influence of Group Size</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Fay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Garrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Carle A</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1111/1467-9280.00292</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="486" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint Ac on, Interac ve Alignment, and Dialog</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Garrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pickering</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1756-8765.2009.01020.x</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1111/j.1756-8765.2009.01020.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cogni ve Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="292" to="304" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thirteen theorems in search of the truth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Grofman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Owen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Feld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1007/BF00125672</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theory and Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Speech, movement, and gaze behaviours during dyadic conversa on in noise</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Hadley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Brimijoin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Whitmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1038/s41598-019-46416-0</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scien fic Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">10451</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A review of theories and methods in the science of face-to-face social interac on</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Hadley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Naylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s44159-021-00008-w</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1038/s44159-021-00008-w" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Hadley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Whitmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Brimijoin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Naylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Conversa on in small groups: Speaking and listening strategies depend on the complexi es of the environment and group</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.3758/s13423-020-01821-9</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulle n &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="632" to="640" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Candidature for and delivery of audiological services: Special needs of older people</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kiessling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pichora-Fuller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gatehouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Stephens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Arlinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Chisolm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3109/14992020309074650</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.3109/14992020309074650" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interna onal Journal of Audiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="92" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When Are Two Heads Be er than One and Why?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Koriat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1126/science.1216549</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">336</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6079</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="360" to="362" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Livingston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huntley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sommerlad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ames</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ballard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mukadam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(20</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2020 report of the Lancet Commission</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>London, England</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="10248" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30367" to="30373" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Demen a preven on</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Group decisions based on confidence weighted majority vo ng</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Meyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M B</forename><surname>Sigg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Luxburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">.org/10.1186/s41235-021-00279-0</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Cogni ve Research: Principles and Implica ons</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Miles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Weisser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kallen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Varlet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Buchholz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral dynamics of conversa on</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-023-47396-y</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-47396-y" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scien fic Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20271</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conversa on success in one-toone and group conversa on: a group concept mapping study of adults with normal and impaired hearing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nicoras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gotowiec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Hadley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Smeds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Naylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14992027.2022.2095538</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1080/14992027.2022.2095538" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interna onal Journal of Audiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The prevalence of dyads in social life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Peperkoorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Balliet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Columbus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Molho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A M</forename><surname>Van Lange</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0244188</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0244188" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Effects of Hearing-Aid Amplifica on and Noise on Conversa onal Dynamics Between Normal-Hearing and Hearing-Impaired Talkers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Petersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J M</forename><surname>Sørensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/23312165221103340</idno>
		<ptr target="//doi.org/10.1177/23312165221103340" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Hearing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effects of noise and L2 on the ming of turn taking in</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J M</forename><surname>Sørensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fereczkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
