<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Bilingual Patient&apos;s Dilemma: Same Question, Different Answer</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michał</forename><surname>Białek</surname></persName>
							<email>michal.bialek3@uwr.edu.pl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wrocław</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Dawida 1</addrLine>
									<postCode>50-529</postCode>
									<settlement>Wrocław</settlement>
									<country key="PL">Poland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Consider</forename><surname>Maria</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wrocław</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Dawida 1</addrLine>
									<postCode>50-529</postCode>
									<settlement>Wrocław</settlement>
									<country key="PL">Poland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Bilingual Patient&apos;s Dilemma: Same Question, Different Answer</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1080/15265161.2024.2399850</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:39+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Białek</term>
					<term>M. (2024). The Bilingual Patient&apos;s Dilemma: Same Question</term>
					<term>Different Answer. The</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>a 32-year-old Spanish-speaking expectant mother who immigrated to the United States five years ago. Despite taking English classes and working in a predominantly English-speaking environment, she still struggles with medical terminology and complex</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>explanations. As she sits in her obstetrician's office, trying to understand the doctor's explanation about amniocentesis, Maria's limited English proficiency becomes a significant barrier. Without an interpreter, she grapples with unfamiliar medical terms and complex risk statistics, leaving her confused and anxious about this critical decision. This scenario, highlighting communication barriers faced by the approximately 25 million limited English proficiency (LEP) individuals in the U.S., is precisely the kind of problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chipman, Meagher, and Barwise (2023)</ref> address in their framework for improving healthcare for LEP populations. However, even if Maria could understand every word perfectly, she would face another, less obvious challenge. Recent research suggests that merely using a foreign language can alter decision-making processes, potentially leading patients to make choices that do not truly reflect their values or risk preferences. While Chipman and colleagues. provide valuable insights on improving access and communication for LEP individuals, here I explore how the cognitive effects of foreign language use might impact patient choices in critical medical decisions, even when linguistic comprehension is not an issue.</p><p>More than a decade ago, a seminal paper by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Keysar, Hayakawa, and An (2012)</ref> reported that people using their foreign language decide differently, potentially showing less bias. After years of research, we now know that using a foreign language changes the values, preferences, and information processing of individuals like Maria (Del <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Maschio et al. 2022</ref>).</p><p>Let's examine these effects and explain why such changes are potentially problematic: Maria's decisions made in a foreign language may not reflect her true preferences, as her altered information processing indirectly influences her choices. These decisions could be seen as indirectly coerced by the language context itself, and are not necessarily more rational or informed despite appearing less biased on the surface. Let us focus on risk-taking and moral judgments as examples of changes in values and preferences.</p><p>Risk aversion is a phenomenon where people refuse fair gambles (e.g., a 50% chance to win or lose $5). This is driven by the observation that -subjectively -losses loom larger than gains (Kahneman and Tversky 1979). In extreme cases, people prefer a certain $10 discount over a discount randomly set between $10 and $20 (Simonsohn 2009), valuing the risky option below its worst outcome. However, using a foreign language to eliminate this bias doesn't necessarily improve decision-making. In our recent study, across three experiments, participants like Maria were shown to select riskier prenatal tests when using a foreign language, accepting risks well beyond acceptable levels. For instance, about a 2% risk of miscarriage was deemed acceptable for detecting just three additional cases in 1,000 fetuses <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Muda et al. 2024)</ref>. This occurred despite participants fully comprehending the study materials and understanding the implications of their choices. To me, it appears to be either reckless risk-taking or greater attention to the consequences of raising a sick child over the consequences of miscarrying. Both changes beg for consideration by healthcare providers, as they significantly impact the nature of informed consent and the ethical implications of decision-making in a foreign language context.</p><p>Another robust finding on the foreign language effect is that it changes one's moral choices, making them less affected by relevant moral inclinations <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Muda et al. 2018)</ref>. In morally charged problems, which are common in healthcare, people may be more driven by non-moral considerations when using a foreign language. Using a foreign language can alter decisions in sensitive areas such as triage, resource allocation, or other ethically complex issues. Consider this scenario: A hospital director in a developing country must decide whether to break quarantine for an international student infected with a rare, highly contagious virus. The student will die without specialized treatment in her home country, but transporting her risks spreading the virus. When presented in a foreign language, decision-makers might be more inclined to maintain quarantine, prioritizing the utilitarian goal of preventing the virus's spread over the deontological principle of saving the individual patient's life <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Białek, Paruzel-Czachura, and Gawronski 2019)</ref>. This shift occurs even among fully proficient bilinguals who comprehend the decision problem and its context well, highlighting how language can subtly influence moral reasoning in critical healthcare decisions.</p><p>These examples reflect changes in people's preferences, potentially leading to decisions based on values they may not otherwise prioritize so highly. Doctors could unintentionally manipulate their patients into accepting particular treatments. For instance, if a doctor is Changing preferences is only one of the effects of deciding in a foreign language. Yet another one is distorted information processing. Consider the dual-process theory of higher-order cognition. When deciding, we often produce quick, compelling intuitions about what's right for us. Sometimes, we have several incongruent intuitions and are forced to deliberate, using our intelligence and relevant normative knowledge. Whether or not we have high cognitive capacities, we must first realize we should use them through a metacognitive process, perceived as confidence or a feeling of rightness. Using a foreign language can distort this process, leading us to think despite valid compelling intuitions and fail to reflect when needed <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Białek et al. 2020)</ref>. This results in better performance on tricky tasks designed to test reasoning or decision-making skills where intuitions are almost always wrong, making it appear that people using a foreign language are less biased. However, in cases where intuition may be fairly well-calibrated, this results in decreased performance. For example, when evaluating news, people using their foreign language are less likely to believe true news and slightly more willing to believe fake news <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Muda et al. 2023)</ref>. Particularly concerning is the reduced trust in true information. In healthcare settings, this skepticism towards accurate information provided by medical professionals could severely impede patients' ability to make fully informed decisions. Instead, they may rely on prior, less-informed beliefs, potentially compromising the quality and safety of their healthcare choices.</p><p>These findings strengthen the suggestions proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chipman et al. (2023)</ref>. While improving access and communication for LEP patients is essential, we must also consider the cognitive implications of using a foreign language in healthcare decision-making. The foreign language effect can alter risk perception, moral judgments, and information processing in ways that may not reflect patients' true preferences or best interests. Healthcare providers and policymakers must recognize that even when linguistic barriers are overcome, cognitive barriers may persist. Healthcare systems should strive to conduct critical discussions and decision-making processes in patients' native languages whenever possible. This may require expanded interpreter services and innovative technologies to facilitate real-time, high-quality translation. By addressing both the communicative and cognitive aspects of language in healthcare, we can ensure that patients like Maria make decisions that genuinely reflect their values and preferences, ultimately leading to more ethical and patient-centered care.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>interested in recruiting patients for a new experimental procedure, presenting the problem in the patient's foreign language might persuade them to accept it, creating an illusion of free choicea form of mild paternalism (Sunstein and Thaler 2003). But is consent for treatment achieved through such subtle manipulation genuinely free? This remains an open question for philosophers to explore.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thinking in a Foreign Language Distorts Allocation of Cognitive Effort: Evidence from Reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michał</forename><surname>Białek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rafał</forename><surname>Muda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaiden</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paweł</forename><surname>Niszczota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Damian</forename><surname>Pieńkosz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2020.104420</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2020.104420" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">205</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104420" to="104420" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Foreign Language Effects on Moral Dilemma Judgments: An Analysis Using the CNI Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michał</forename><surname>Białek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariola</forename><surname>Paruzel-Czachura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bertram</forename><surname>Gawronski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103855</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103855" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103855</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Public Health Ethics Framework for Populations with Limited English Proficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samantha</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Chipman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Meagher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amelia</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Barwise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/15265161.2023.2224263</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/15265161.2023.2224263" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Journal of Bioethics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2023-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-Making Depends on Language: A Meta-Analysis of the Foreign Language Effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Del</forename><surname>Maschio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Federico</forename><surname>Nicola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesca</forename><surname>Crespi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jubin</forename><surname>Peressotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Abutalebi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sulpizio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1366728921001012</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1366728921001012" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="617" to="647" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Foreign-Language Effect: Thinking in a Foreign Tongue Reduces Decision Biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Keysar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sayuri</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Boaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sun</forename><surname>Hayakawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gyu An</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="661" to="68" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reading Dilemmas in a Foreign Language Reduces Both Deontological and Utilitarian Response Tendencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rafał</forename><surname>Muda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pawel</forename><surname>Niszczota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michał</forename><surname>Białek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Conway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xlm0000447</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000447" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="347" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using a Foreign Language Increases Risk-Taking in Medical Decisions but Not Due to Attenuated Emotional Responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rafał</forename><surname>Muda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paweł</forename><surname>Niszczota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Damian</forename><surname>Pieńkosz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Bialek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/sfmq9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/sfmq9" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">People Are Worse at Detecting Fake News in Their Foreign Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rafał</forename><surname>Muda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Damian</forename><surname>Hamerski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michał</forename><surname>Białek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xap0000475</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xap0000475" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology. Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Libertarian Paternalism Is Not an Oxymoron</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cass</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1600573</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/1600573" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The University of Chicago Law Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1159</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
