<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Emotion in strategic environmental communication research: Challenges and opportunities</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Ph.D</roleName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Yale Program on Climate Change Communication</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Emotion in strategic environmental communication research: Challenges and opportunities</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1177/17540739231195533</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:48+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Emotion and affect play a central role in persuasion, decision-making, and human behavior. Because of ongoing environmental crises, there is a strong need to better understand how emotions shape selection, attention, processing, and effects of environmental communication. Here, I highlight three main areas that contain challenges and opportunities for building a synergistic relationship between the affective sciences and research on strategic environmental communication: 1) identifying the causal effects of emotions in environmental communication; 2) the role of emotions in the durability of environmental messaging effects; and 3) how closing the gap between the laboratory and the field can generate innovative research and more applicable inferences. 2 Emotion in strategic environmental communication research: Challenges and opportunities Widespread systemic and individual action is needed to address major environmental problems and transition to a healthier, more sustainable future (IPCC, 2021). Communication is an essential component to educating and motivating people to take action. A deep literature shows the important role of emotion in persuasion, decision-making, and human behavior (Slovic, &amp; Peters, 2006). There are many insightful studies that examine the role of emotion in environmental communication and public opinion, such as whether emotion makes messaging more persuasive (e.g., Gustafson et al., 2020; Wong-Parodi &amp; Feygina, 2021), or whether emotion predicts people&apos;s support for climate policy (e.g., Goldberg et al., 2021; Smith &amp; Leiserowitz, 2014). However, there is still much to learn about how emotions shape selection, attention, processing, and effects of environmental communication (Brosch &amp; Steg, 2021). Here, I highlight areas in which the affective sciences can make important contributions to our understanding of environmental communication, and how research on environmental communication can contribute to the affective sciences. First, it is important to note that I am taking a strategic communication perspective in this article. That is, the challenges and opportunities I highlight take the perspective of entities (e.g., organizations, governments, educators, public communicators; Zerfass et al., 2018) that have specific outcomes in mind: maximizing the impact of environmental communication toward achieving specific goals. To do this, interested entities have to make decisions under uncertainty about which interventions to deploy, how to deploy them, and which situational and strategic tradeoffs need to be made along the way (Goldberg &amp; Gustafson, 2023).</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Strategists and applied researchers who wish to leverage emotions in environmental communication are met with a variety of challenges. However, these challenges also present opportunities for generating more insight from research and interventions at the intersection of affective science and environmental communication. Below, I highlight three main challenges and suggest opportunities that might help us overcome them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The causal effect of emotion in environmental communication</head><p>A central question is what emotions can do to enhance environmental communication. More specifically, the goal of investigations into this question is to identify the causal effect of using emotion in environmental messaging interventions.</p><p>There are many steps between the intended effects of an emotional message, and how it is perceived, processed, and interpreted by the receiver of the message. That is, emotions are often understood as inherently an interaction between some event (or stimulus or message) and the goals, beliefs, and concerns of the person experiencing the event <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Lazarus, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Moors et al., 2013</ref>). This presents a challenge for understanding the causal effects of emotion in environmental communication because people often differ widely in those goals, beliefs, and concerns.</p><p>Researchers in the affective sciences have devised many ways to induce emotions or general affective states as a way to study the causal effects of emotion on a range of outcome measures.</p><p>For example, researchers might show respondents pictures of emotionally-evocative situations, have them read a short story that evokes a particular emotional state, or recall a personal event that produced a specific emotional reaction (for a review and meta-analysis, see <ref type="bibr">Joseph et al., 2020)</ref>. These procedures are often used to generate insights about the effects of certain affective states on the persuasiveness of a given message.</p><p>However, practitioners and applied researchers often want to know how emotions can be used in their messaging to reach a particular goal, such as increasing participation in collective action, donation behavior, or other forms of pro-environmental behavior. Researchers who seek to shed light on these types of questions often present respondents with different kinds of messages that are expected to evoke a particular emotional state. The challenge is that this confounds message content with emotion induction. When researchers test, for example, a hopeful message versus a threatening message, the messages differ on both their specific content as well as the emotions they evoke. This makes it difficult to tell whether the content, the emotion, both, or neither are driving differences between different types of messages. This is also a challenge for practitioners because it leaves unclear whether it is more effective to optimize for a particular type of content or a particular type of emotional response.</p><p>We can turn this challenge into an opportunity by experimenting with factors that are not part of the message wording but are nonetheless influential. Consider the finding that political videos have been found to have about twice the persuasive impact as the text transcript of the video <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Wittenberg et al., 2021</ref>; also see Goldberg et al., 2019 for a related finding on climate change communication). We know that in these studies the message content was identical aside from the factors that have to do with the difference in message medium, such as the video's imagery, music, or other emotionally-evocative factors that might drive these differences. There is a lot to learn from the affective sciences on the factors that are most promising for further investigation, and how we might go about studying those factors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The role of emotion in generating durable messaging effects</head><p>One important and growing area of research on environmental communication that needs more systematic attention is the durability of messaging effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Goldberg, Gustafson, &amp; van der Linden, 2020)</ref>. The overwhelming majority of messaging research in this topic area (and beyond) measures effects immediately after respondents receive a message, leaving unknown whether the effects we observe last beyond the few minutes respondents spend in the survey experiment. This challenge presents an opportunity for researchers in environmental communication and the affective sciences to learn from each other on how to generate the most insight about the durability of message effects in environmental communication.</p><p>We have good reason to believe that emotions can potentially help generate long-lasting messaging effects, which can improve environmental communication. This potential lies, in part, in the evidence that emotions can affect the extent of thinking (for a review, see Petty &amp; Briñol, 2015), which we know affects the durability of messaging effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chong &amp; Druckman, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Petty &amp; Cacioppo, 1986)</ref>. Even if the emotional response is a transient state, if it enhances the depth of processing of information, then persuasion can be more durable even long after the emotional response has subsided. Put simply, persuasion is more durable when people put more thought into the considerations raised by the message.</p><p>Another promising research area to learn more about the potential role of emotions in the durability of environmental messaging effects is research on how emotions affect motivation and information processing <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Nabi, 2003)</ref>. That is, emotions can affect the interpretation and selection of subsequent information, such as when threat messages are more persuasive when followed by a message that bolsters efficacy to address the threat <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Nabi, Gustafson, &amp; Jensen, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Witte &amp; Allen, 2000</ref>). Nabi's "emotions as frames" model proposes that instead of functioning as persuasive in themselves, emotions set the stage for how and which information is processed.</p><p>Building on the example above, threatening messages are likely to evoke fear, which might lead people to prioritize information and decisions that mitigate the threat over other available information. So it is not necessarily the fear itself that is persuasive, but instead acts as a frame that guides information seeking and processing. This has important implications for studying persuasion durability in environmental communication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Closing the gap between the lab and the field</head><p>A unique challenge for studying the effects of emotions in environmental communication is that common emotion induction procedures are difficult or impossible to apply in real-world messaging contexts. For example, if one wants to study the role of emotion in increasing persuasion, donation behavior, or collective action in real-world contexts (e.g., via field experiments), it is often not possible to have people sit and write a short essay on the deep connections between the environment and their sense of self. Our experimental capabilities outside the laboratory are usually much more constrained. Further, even if we learn how emotion can be leveraged to improve environmental communication, the world outside the laboratory includes other obstacles, such as decisions to consume or engage with the message in the first place, depending on expectations about the message's emotional content <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Skurka et al., 2022)</ref>.</p><p>This challenge presents an important opportunity for the affective sciences to study the role of emotion during real-time environmental hazards such as extreme heat <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Howe et al., 2019)</ref> or wildfires <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hazlett &amp; Mildenberger, 2020)</ref>. The constraints of doing research outside artificial conditions of the laboratory or survey environment force us to examine the communication tools at our disposal, or grapple with the need to innovate and invent new ones. Further, focusing on real-world impacts also raises important basic research questions about the role emotion plays in emerging real-world events, how long it lasts, and what kinds of impacts they have. We can generate additional insight from this research by cultivating a positive feedback loop between laboratory and field research, where laboratory data can inform real-world communication campaigns (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Falk et al., 2010)</ref>, and field research can raise important basic research questions that are better studied in the lab. Scholars in the affective sciences and in environmental communication are well-positioned to make large contributions by taking this approach.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>In this article, I have highlighted three areas where environmental communication researchers can have a mutually beneficial and synergistic relationship with researchers in the affective sciences. The challenges I raise come with significant opportunities to learn more about 1) the causal effects of emotions in environmental communication; 2) the effect of emotions on the durability of environmental messaging effects; and 3) how grappling with real-world constraints can foster innovation and more applicable inferences. The importance of emotions to human thinking and behavior makes them essential to understanding how to motivate people to take action to address our most pressing environmental problems, and this article charts some territory that outlines key paths forward.</p></div>		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>Thank you to Abel Gustafson for insightful comments on an earlier draft of this article.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging emotion for sustainable action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Brosch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Steg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.oneear.2021.11.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2021.11.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">One Earth</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1693" to="1703" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic public opinion: Communication effects over time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Druckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Political Science Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="663" to="680" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0003055410000493</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0003055410000493" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counterframing effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Druckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0022381612000837</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0022381612000837" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From neural responses to population behavior: Neural focus group predicts population-level media effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Falk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Berkman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lieberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797611434964</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797611434964" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="439" to="445" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for understanding the effects of strategic communication campaigns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gustafson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/1553118X.2022.2137674</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/1553118X.2022.2137674" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Strategic Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gustafson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ballew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leiserowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying the most important predictors of support for climate policy in the United States</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/bpp.2020.39</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/bpp.2020.39" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioural Public Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="480" to="502" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging social science to generate lasting engagement with climate change solutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gustafson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">One Earth</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="314" to="324" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.oneear.2020.08.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2020.08.011" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The experience of consensus: Video as an effective medium to communicate scientific agreement on climate change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ballew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gustafson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leiserowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1075547019874361</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1075547019874361" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="659" to="673" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personal stories can shift climate change beliefs and risk perceptions: The mediating role of emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gustafson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ballew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Cutler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leiserowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communication Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/08934215.2020.1799049</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/08934215.2020.1799049" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wildfire exposure increases pro-environment voting within Democratic but Not Republican areas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hazlett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mildenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Political Science Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0003055420000441</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0003055420000441" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Public perceptions of the health risks of extreme heat across US states, counties, and neighborhoods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Howe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Marlon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leiserowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6743" to="6748" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1813145116</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1813145116" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Climate Change 2021: The Physical Science Basis</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, United Kingdom and New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Emotion and adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lazarus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Appraisal Theories of Emotion: State of the Art and Future Development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ellsworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Scherer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Frijda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1754073912468165</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1754073912468165" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Exploring the framing effects of emotion: Do discrete emotions differentially influence information accessibility, information seeking, and policy preference? Communication Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Nabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0093650202250881</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0093650202250881" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="224" to="247" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Framing climate change: Exploring the role of emotion in generating advocacy behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Nabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gustafson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="468" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1075547018776019</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1075547018776019" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choose your own Emotion: Predictors of selective exposure to emotion-inducing climate messages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Skurka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Romero-Canyas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Joo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Niederdeppe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Environmental Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="424" to="431" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17524032.2022.2083207</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17524032.2022.2083207" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk perception and affect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-8721.2006.00461.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8721.2006.00461.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="322" to="325" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of emotion in global warming policy support and opposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leiserowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/risa.12140</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/risa.12140" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Risk Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="937" to="948" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A meta-analysis of fear appeals: Implications for effective public health campaigns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Witte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Health Education &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="591" to="615" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/109019810002700506</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/109019810002700506" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The (minimal) persuasive advantage of political video over text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wittenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tappin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2114388118</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2114388118" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">47</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Engaging people on climate change: The role of emotional responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wong-Parodi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Feygina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<publisher>Environmental Communication</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="571" to="593" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17524032.2020.1871051</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17524032.2020.1871051" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic communication: Defining the field and its contribution to research and practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zerfass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Verčič</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nothhaft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Werder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Strategic Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="487" to="505" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/1553118X.2018.1493485</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/1553118X.2018.1493485" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
