<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Mental health and risk-taking among refugees in Lebanon</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Ruggeri</surname></persName>
							<email>kai.ruggeri@columbia.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Health Policy and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Centre for Business Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Judge Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Policy Research Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannes</forename><surname>Jarke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Centre for Business Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Judge Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Policy Research Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lama</forename><surname>El-Zein</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Family and Community Medicine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University Medical Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Verdeli</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Teachers College</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Folke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Health Policy and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Centre for Business Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Judge Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Policy Research Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Mental health and risk-taking among refugees in Lebanon</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:48+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Lebanon is rapidly adapting public services meet local needs as well those of refugees from conflict regions such as Syria. However, these challenges are complicated by high volumes of individuals with poor mental health, who are also at risk of poor decision-making and may avoid use of health services due to low trust in government institutions, among other reasons. Over 700 individuals residing in Lebanon, including Syrian refugees and Palestinians from Lebanon, completed a series of measures covering decision-making with risk, mental health, and trust. Analyses focused on whether there were significant relationships between these three, and if various factors influencing those relationships could be useful for health policy in Lebanon and other regions affected by conflict-related population movement. This study finds that higher subjective well-being was associated with more risk-taking among refugees (β = 0•07, SE = 0•02, z = 4•63, p &lt; •01), but not among the Lebanese host population (β =-0•003, SE = 0•01, z =-0•32, p =•75). However, average subjective well-being did not significantly differ between the Lebanese host population and the refugees (absolute difference =-1•27, 95%CI = [-2•83, 0•29], on a 60-point scale), or between Syrian and Palestinian refugees (absolute difference =-1•53, 95%CI = [-4•16, 1•08]). There were moderate effects of behavioral interventions on risk-taking in terms of increased advantageous choices. There is a clear pattern of greater risk-taking for refugees with better subjective well-being. This is an important finding as greater risk-taking is associated with a number of negative health outcomes, particularly in vulnerable populations. While the behavioural interventions do show some effect on improving advantageous choice, these risk patterns are of clear interest to policymakers dealing with health and well-being of all residents in Lebanon.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Millions of people have been displaced and live as refugees as the result of recent conflicts in the Middle East. Lebanon currently hosts at least 1•5M Syrian refugees and 180,000 refugees from Palestine as of early 2019 <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(UN OCHA, 2019)</ref>. In such a humanitarian crisis, the primary objective and concern centers on the basic needs of those affected. With policies often geared towards short-term outcomes even in non-crisis situations <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Jacobs, 2016)</ref> and policymakers often failing to anticipate future outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Nair and Howlett, 2017)</ref>, it is important not to overlook the impact this situation has on the decision-making of ordinary people living under these circumstances.</p><p>One factor directly linked to sub-optimal decision-making is poor mental health <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Lawlor et al., 2019)</ref>. The trauma connected to conflict situations, the resulting displacement, and ongoing stressors <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Miller and Rasmussen, 2017)</ref> have negative effects on mental health <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Ellis, Winer, Murray, &amp; Barrett, 2019)</ref>, which can even be passed onto future generations <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Sangalang and Vang, 2017)</ref>. It is also connected to the emergence of mental disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Morina, Akhtar, Barth, &amp; Schnyder, 2018)</ref>. Mental health and subjective well-being (terms often used interchangeably but are distinct from mental illness) tend to be vastly underfunded and not included in crosssectoral policies in many context <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Jenkins et al., 2011a)</ref>. However, in fragile situations, these are typically also not a policy priority, even during periods after an emergency <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Jenkins et al., 2011b)</ref>.</p><p>Lebanon as a country has taken in the highest number of refugees proportional to their population <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Loesche, 2019)</ref>. With mental health services being provided to Syrian refugees by Lebanese institutions, there is an opportunity to directly understand the well-being of crisisaffected, disadvantaged populations in a way that can inform health systems. This is particularly valuable given the challenges faced in the parallel system of NGOs, private practice, and UN agencies relied on by Palestinians for healthcare, who have spent protracted periods displaced in Lebanon. This is especially true for mental health, and has come under tremendous pressure in recent years, to the point of extreme vulnerability or collapse (Medical Aid for Palestinians, 2018).</p><p>Life-altering events such as forced migration can impact decision-making in complex ways. On the one hand, the experience of recent and severe episodes of violence can trigger higher levels of risk aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Moya, 2018)</ref>. On the other hand, the huge material losses people suffer from catastrophes such as natural disasters are connected to a preference for high risk-high reward options <ref type="bibr">(Page, Savage, &amp; Torgler, 2014)</ref>, possibly with the aim of recovering some of what was lost, in line with prevailing theory on loss aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Barberis, 2013)</ref>. These changes in risk preferences should not be underestimated, given the large impact they can have on individual and population-level outcomes, in areas such as employment, healthcare, financial investments, addiction, and, most notably, migration choices (Schildberg-Hörisch, 2018).</p><p>The WHO Mental Health Action Plan (WHO, 2013) suggests these context-specific challenges should be taken into account when designing national policies on mental health. One promising method that specifically fits context-dependent policy interventions is the application of behavioural insights, which is anticipated as highly valuable in Lebanon <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(El Chammay, 2017)</ref>. Two such behavioural insights which have often shown significant effects in improving decision-making are nudges and boosts. Nudges, simple changes to the environment that influence choice without restricting any options, aim to encourage behaviours that benefit an individual <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Thaler and Sunstein, 2008)</ref>. Boosts, on the other hand, aim to empower individuals by strengthening their competence to achieve individually-preferred outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Hertwig and Grüne-Yanoff, 2017</ref>) and aim to be applicable across environments. Conflict scatters populations independent of their traits and prior status so refugees cannot be assumed to be a homogeneous group. As such, boosting can be a particularly appealing policy strategy for supporting diverse groups such as refugees, who have highly individualized needs, and holds potential to continue showing effects as their life situation continues to evolve.</p><p>In terms of decision-making, we test if nudges and boosts can illuminate meaningful choice patterns in Lebanon using a method previously employed in Serbia and the US <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Franklin, Folke, &amp; Ruggeri, 2019)</ref>. Described in full later, this procedure involved a series of decisionmaking items with varied risks and utility, which supported measuring individual ability for making optimal choices as well as general risk preferences. The data from Serbia are particularly useful given demographic and political parallels with Lebanon, as well as being similar in economic and population size.</p><p>To assess if this approach can provide meaningful insights regarding links between mental health and decision-making in disadvantaged populations, our first step was to test the validity of a ten-item well-being measure for use in Lebanon, both for local and refugee populations. This short measure, informally referred to as a multidimensional psychological well-being scale, is commonly used in other countries for macro-level policy insights <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Huppert and So, 2013)</ref>. It is based on the opposites of symptoms for depression and anxiety (i.e., positive characteristics) and can be used to screen differences in subjective well-being across populations <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Huppert and So, 2013)</ref>. We investigate differences between refugees (Syrian and Palestinian) and the Lebanese public, and then explore the relation of well-being (low, average, flourishing) to risk-taking. We expand these topics to include critical contextual factors for the situation in Lebanon, primarily measures of trust, in aiming to understand links between mental health, risky choices, and the potential impact of behavioural interventions.</p><p>We anticipated that the well-being instrument would have similar psychometric properties in Lebanon as it does in other countries, making it a good fit for linking population-level outcomes with behaviours (though it is less likely to show population-level differences between similar locations). We expected more risky choices on average for situations which were framed as losses. We further hypothesized that both interventions would increase advantageous choice, with boosts being especially effective due to their instructional nature. Finally, we expected the interventions would work by mitigating the effect of baseline risk preferences, so that naturally risk-seeking individuals will be less risk-seeking in situations when risk-taking is not beneficial, and vice versa.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study Design and Participants</head><p>Data was collected from October to November 2019 using a professional data collection service. All aspects of the protocol were administered online in Arabic to 754 people. Lebanese participants accessed the Qualtrics through an online portal, whereas refugees (N = 244) had to be approached in person due to geographic restrictions or no internet access. The total sample size exceeds the required minimum (N=552) based on our a priori power calculation (See also Appendix 1: Pre-registration). Based on past results in a similar context, we suspected that the demographic influences on well-being would have the lowest power, specifically R 2 =•025 for a regression model including income, age and relationship status. An f 2 -test suggested that 552 participants would have been required for 90% power to detect an effect of that size with an alpha threshold of •05.</p><p>Participants had to be at least 18 years old, live in Lebanon and have either Lebanese, Syrian, or Palestinian nationality. Exclusion criteria for minimum completion time were not applied as no participants failed that standard. While participants were blinded to the goals of the study, research team members who analyzed the data were not. All data were collected via the online survey platform Qualtrics using a paid collection service with offices and field staff in Lebanon. Ethical approval was granted by the Centre for Business Research, Judge Business School, University of Cambridge. Permission to collect data from vulnerable populations in Lebanon was sought and given by the Lebanese Ministry of Public Health.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure and outcomes, including randomization and masking</head><p>Participants completed 61 total items. Measures covered well-being (items provided statements such as "I have a feeling of fulfilment because of what I do", "I get help and support when I need it from people that I am close to"), decision-making, trust, and general demographics. The first 10 items assess well-being, followed by five measures of behaviours that predict wellbeing in wealthy countries (Centre for <ref type="bibr">Well-Being and NEF, 2008)</ref>. Next, all participants completed three baseline decision-making items before being randomly assigned by the survey platform Qualtrics to an intervention or control group. Once assigned, all participants responded to 16 additional decision-making items, presented in a random order varied by participant. As participants were not aware that different interventions were tested, they were blinded to the intervention by default. Data collection partners were also blinded to group allocation during the procedure.</p><p>All decision-making items involved choosing between two financial options with risk, varied between gains and losses of differing values and probabilities. For example, at baseline participants were asked "You have $1032. Which of the following would you prefer?" and could choose between "A 25% chance to keep everything and a 75% chance to lose everything" or "A 100% chance to lose $732" (loss frame), as well as "Which of the following would you prefer?" where they could choose between "A 75% chance to win $456 and a 25% chance to win nothing" or "A 100% chance to win $300" (gain frame). The use of such items is the predominant method to assess risk-taking in economics and psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Dhar and Simonson, 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Participants in the control group did not receive any form of intervention and viewed the 16 experimental items in the same format as they had seen the baseline items. Participants in both intervention groups were encouraged to pick the option with the highest expected value (the value of the outcome multiplied by its probability of occurring). The first experimental group received a disclosure nudge, which explains expected values (the sum of each possible outcome of the choice, weighted by the outcomes' probabilities of occurring) and then presents the same choices as in the control group but with both expected values included. The second experimental group received a boost intervention. This involved a more in-depth introduction to expected values and provided instructions on how to calculate them (with a suggestion to use a calculator). Boost participants were required to accurately compute the expected values for three example sets to ensure they understood the instructions before proceeding.</p><p>For all participants, each item consisted of one certain option (100% chance of occurring if chosen) and one risky option (the chance of occurring if chosen is less than 100%). Items differed along four dimensions: 1) advantage (whether the risky option had a higher expected value than the certain option), 2) monetary magnitude, 3) gain or loss framing, and 4) risk (how likely or unlikely the risky option was to happen). Half the items were framed as gains, while the other half were framed as losses. Financial choice items were randomized to avoid order effects, 18 sociodemographic items were asked last to minimize confounding from stereotype threat <ref type="bibr">(Nardi, 2018)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical Analysis</head><p>Analyses focused on validation of the well-being outcome measures in Arabic, modelling decision-making patterns, and assessing links between decision-making and mental health, including moderators for the three populations in Lebanon.</p><p>We conducted confirmatory factor analyses separately for the Lebanese group, Palestinian refugees from Lebanon, as well as Syrian refugees to determine the factor structure of the Multidimensional Psychological Well-Being Scale (MPWB). To determine differences in wellbeing between groups (Lebanese, Palestinian, Syrian), as well as to investigate how well-being relates to trust, relationship status, income, and everyday habits, we applied linear regressions. We evaluated the relationship between baseline risk-taking, well-being and ethnicity using logistic regression. Finally, generalized linear regression models were used to quantify the relative influence of choice at baseline, nationality, and interventions on risk behaviour.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Demographics</head><p>The survey commenced on 11.09.2019 and data collection concluded with the last participants on 22.11.2019. Of the 754 total participants, 510 were Lebanese, 112 were Palestinian from Lebanon, 119 were Syrian, 12 were Palestinian from Syria, and one person had another nationality. The proportion of participants was intentional given the balance within the population in Lebanon generally as well as the challenges in accessing vulnerable Syrian and Palestinians. As the Palestinians from Syria are too small a subsample to include in the main model, but we could not assume them to be identical in traits and circumstances to another group, we excluded them from the analysis. The overall sample across nationalities was roughly balanced for ages and genders (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>).</p><p>In the Lebanese population, more than 60% reported a university degree. Education levels in both refugee samples was much lower, but equally distributed in both (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>). In line with expectations, Lebanese people had both higher earnings and higher monthly expenditures than the refugee groups (for details see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Annex Table A1</ref>), and household income correlated with expenditure for all ethnicities <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>).  Lebanese participants have significantly higher incomes and monthly expenditure averages than Syrian and Palestinian participants across all brackets in the sample, indicated by the green line being entirely parallel to the red and black line.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mental health in Lebanon</head><p>Using the ten items for multi-dimensional well-being, each of the three countries have response distributions with means above the mid-point yet with meaningful proportions in the lowerend (See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). This is generally in line with expectation, in that averages are only somewhat above middle for refugee populations, and a smaller majority here are experiencing the positive end of most domains. In aggregate, there are no substantive floor or ceiling effects across groups. There are only two significant group differences across all ten dimensions, but given that is out of 30 possible contrasts, these may be spurious or noise, so we do not highlight them further. Confirmatory factor analyses (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Annex Table A2</ref>) indicate a good fit in all three populations (CFI &gt; .9) for all ten items into a single factor. When used to compute a single factor score to reduce model complexity without reducing to a single item, those values correlate 0.99 with simple sums of raw scores. This means it is appropriate to use simple sums to compute composite scores (scale 10 to 70) for all individuals and groups, while retaining the general model properties of a multidimensional measure. Those aggregates are normally distributed across all three groups.</p><p>We found no significant differences in average well-being between <ref type="bibr">Lebanese</ref>   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Risk-taking</head><p>On the whole, risk-taking at baseline did not significantly differ between nationalities. Participants took more risks in the loss-framed item relative to the other two items, though effect sizes were not extreme for Palestinians or Lebanese (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref>). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Risk-taking and subjective well-being</head><p>To examine the impact of subjective well-being on risk-taking we predicted risky choices at baseline from total MPWB scores, ethnicity and their interaction. For ethnicity, we used planned contrasts so that the first term compared Lebanese participants to the refugees and the other term compared to two refugee groups to each other. We found that higher subjective wellbeing was associated with higher risk taking for the gain frame (β = 0 . However, the link between well-being and self-reported risk was similar across the two refugee groups. The only significant difference was for the gain item, where well-being predicted risk taking more strongly for the Palestinians than the Syrians (β = 0•04, SE = 0•01, z = -2•54, p &lt; •05).</p><p>To visualize these relationships, we combined the two refugee groups together and binned wellbeing scores as poor, moderate, and flourishing. This ensured a reasonable sample size in each cell. As the overall factor structure of the well-being measure was similar, we applied the thresholds for analyses across the entire group, rather than within country (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> for within-country cutoffs). Patterns indicate clearly that the positive relationship between wellbeing and risk-taking is mostly driven by the flourishing group ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6</ref>). To see the results separated by refugee group, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>. Each point is a participant; points are quasi-randomly jittered on the y-axis to communicate density more efficiently.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trust and subjective well-being</head><p>Participants generally rated their trust of others very poorly, with Palestinians indicating the lowest overall level in trust in the standard binary items <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">(Table 5</ref>). For more granular measures, trust in family members was much higher, although Syrian and Palestinian participants trusted family members to a much greater extent than Lebanese participants. Similar patterns existed for trust in neighbours across nationalities, with greater variability in trust towards familiar people, and generally low trust in strangers <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Figure 7</ref>). Using composite well-being scores and measures of trust, we find no significant relationship between the two constructs (p=0•48).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Risk-taking and trust</head><p>Lebanese participants that report being more trusting are slightly more risk-seeking for the Baseline Gain Frame item (β = 0•09, SE = 0•04, z = 2•38, p &lt; •05). Otherwise trust does not predict risk propensity for any nationality for any item.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Intervention effects</head><p>To examine how the interventions and baseline choices impacted the post-intervention decision-making we ran linear models predicting advantageous choice (whereby the advantageous choice is the one with the higher expected value) scores in the gain frame and loss frame separately, for each of the three nationalities (Lebanese, Syrian, and Palestinians). For the Lebanese, the boost condition was associated with more advantageous choices than the control condition in both the gain frame (β=0 Though baseline choice did not directly impact advantageous choice in the gain frame (β=0.25, 95%CI=[-0.15-0.65], t=1.27, p=.21) nor the loss frame (β=0.00, 95%CI=[-0.36-0.36], t=-0.01, p=.98), it did interact with the boost intervention in the loss frame, so that participants who made advantageous choices baseline benefitted most from the intervention (β=0.61, 95%CI=[0.01-1.21], t=2.00, p&lt;.05). The disclosure condition was not associated with more advantageous choices than the control condition for either frame, nor did it interact with baseline choice. The same pattern existed for the gain frame, though only marginally significant (β=0.61, 95%CI=[-0.03-1.25], t=1.87, p=.06). In the Syrian sample none of the interventions significantly impacted advantageous choice, either in the gain frame nor the loss frame.</p><p>Baseline choices did not predict experimental choices, nor did they moderate intervention effectiveness in either frame. We had similar null-findings for Palestinians from Lebanon for the gain frame. However, for the loss frame, the disclosure nudge was associated with significantly less advantageous choices than the control condition (β=-0.88, 95%CI=[-1.44 --0.32], t=-3.17, p&lt;.01). Participants who picked the advantageous option at baseline were less negatively impacted by the disclosure intervention, however this effect was only marginally significant(β=0.72, 95%CI=[-0.08-1.52], t=1.76, p=.08).</p><p>To test if the effect of the conditions differed significantly between the different nationalities, we ran additional models on the full sample, predicting advantageous choice from nationality (treating Lebanese as baseline), baseline decision-making, the interventions and their interactions (but again keeping choices in the gain frame and loss frame separate). As expected from the prior analyses, boosts in the gain frame were significantly more effective for the Lebanese participants than for the Syrian (β=-1.13, 95%CI=  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Summary</head><p>In this study, we find a number of relevant insights, most notably the clear difference in risktaking for refugees based on mental health. The ten-item well-being measure used is especially valuable in this context: it includes dimensions such as vitality, resilience, and positive relationships. That individuals higher on those in aggregate demonstrate a higher willingness to take risks prior to any intervention may indicate a greater openness to seek opportunities to improve their current circumstances without extensive deliberation over likely outcomes.</p><p>There is no single application of the risk-flourishing insight to vulnerable populations. Instead, it broadly highlights the importance for health systems to not limit consideration to individuals with poor mental health. While poor mental health has long been associated with a number of risk factors such as alcohol and drug abuse, our findings indicate those with better mental health in displaced populations may produce another sort of risk not typically factored into healthcare reforms. Experiencing recent and severe episodes of violence is highly associated with high levels of anxiety <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Moya, 2018)</ref>. It should be kept in mind that the quality of risk-averse behaviour associated with high anxiety may be of a more holistic quality, affecting more behaviours than economic decisionspossibly including the choice to seek help. This can prove especially problematic in a population at high risk of developing clinical symptoms due to trauma and even passing these on to their children <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Santavirta, Santavirta, &amp; Gilman, 2018)</ref> We do not have data to infer how specific or global this risk preference is, nor how it may impact health, such as delaying care. Unfortunately, we also lack data to infer the extent of potential risk-taking, such as having a propensity to undertake high-risk journeys to locations further away, resort to high-risk financial options (e.g., gambling), or greater likelihood to fall victim to scams. Such data would be invaluable from future study, particularly if it can be matched with our nascent findings on effective interventions, which would directly inform policy actions.</p><p>Another noteworthy finding is the general similarity in mental health patterns between local and displaced populations in Lebanon. It is too far to infer directly that this negates the need for parallel healthcare systems that provide discrete services for locals and refugees, as has been used for Palestinians. Apart from the issue of separate funding sources for refugee healthcare and healthcare for Lebanese nationals (Medical Aid for Palestinians, 2018), the low trust we observed in refugees may also hinder uptake of mental health service, if offered. However, such information may provide useful to explore further as it may offer insight into aspects of mental health services that could overlap between those populations.</p><p>With regards to interventions targeting financial risk-taking, we found that boosts were the most effective intervention for Lebanese participants, regardless of whether the aim of the choice was to maximize gains or minimize losses. This suggests that boosts, and other interventions designed to support people to make autonomous decisions, might be particularly effective in middle-income countries. While previous research in Serbia employing the same methodology found that boosts were generally more effective for people who made initially more suboptimal choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Franklin, Folke, &amp; Ruggeri, 2019)</ref>, we find this only to be the case for Lebanese nationals in the loss condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations</head><p>The well-being measure has the benefit of being multi-faceted, but each specific domain is tested in a single item format. With regards to risk-taking, while hypothetical financial choices ('gambles') are common in behavioural research, they cannot fully approximate risk preferences in real-world contexts, particularly those relating to health behaviours or other extremely stressful, uncertain situations. As such, their generalizability to risk behaviours most relevant to a refugee population may be limited. Some group differences may also be influenced by different testing environments, as the refugee population was tested in-person rather than remotely. However, we expect this to mostly impact items with a strong social desirability component and therefore should not have impacted our main findings. Further research could provide a wider range of risk domains, and if it relates to healthcare, include choices regarding general behaviours (e.g., diet, exercise, tobacco use) and those related to system use (e.g., preventive care, vaccination, delaying treatment).</p><p>It is also important to note that neither intervention worked for the refugee groups, this might be the result of different modalities of presentation (e.g. online versus face to face), but might also suggest that vulnerable populations may require more robust decision-support. Further, we cannot assess if expected values were fully understood, especially in light of differences in education level between the groups. With the majority of refugees reporting their education to be less than high school, it is possible that many may not have been familiar with the concept of probability or multiplication, which would make it hard to understand the concept of expected values. Additional work is needed to establish which one of these explanations is correct. While we did not test this directly, there is evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Cohn, Engelmann, Fehr, &amp; Maréchal, 2015)</ref> to corroborate the finding that poorer mental health (at least in terms of heightened stress levels) can reduce risk-taking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>The decision to flee your home country in times of conflict-whether alone, with children, or in a group-is perhaps the most extreme example of a choice made under risk and uncertainty. It is taken under severe duress and, for many without strong connections outside of their home country, it may appear an equally risky option as facing the dangers at home, encouraging them to remain. The resulting impact on those choices and the ability to persevere in spite of potentially dire circumstances can have lasting impact on individuals, families, and populations. That the destination country in this case, Lebanon, has gone through substantial change over the past three decades, not least the 2005 withdrawal of Syrian troops after a 29year presence, has resulted in local challenges to economic stability while testing population resilience.</p><p>To better understand these impacts, we measured well-being and risk-taking in refugee and host populations. Our finding that refugee populations have similar well-being profiles to the host population may imply that the Lebanese systems have been unusually successful or that resilience among Syrians and Palestinians has been remarkably high (or a combination thereof). However, those conclusions need to be directly assessed and our findings need to be independently replicated. The relationship between risk-taking and well-being in refugee populations has, to the best of our knowledge, never been reported before and if mapped to a broader range of risky behaviours may provide key guidance to policymakers who try to support these vulnerable groups. Responding effectively would provide added security to the health and well-being of some of the world's most vulnerable populations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Sharing</head><p>All data, code, and materials will be posted on the Open Science Framework platform at the culmination of the grant, available no later than 1 January, 2022.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study design</head><p>The pre-registered study and analysis protocol will be available on the Open Science Framework upon publication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Role of the funding source</head><p>The study funder had no role in study design, and no involvement in data collection, data analysis, data interpretation, or writing the article. All authors had full access to all the data in the study and had final responsibility for the decision to submit for publication.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Household income and expenditure.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Distribution of ten well-being dimensions between Lebanese, Syrians, and Palestinians.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Mean total MPWB by nationality, error bars show bootstrapped confidence intervals.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Risky choice proportion at baseline.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>•04, SE = 0•01, z = 3•70, p &lt; •01) loss frame (β = 0•03, SE = 0•01, z = 2•73, p &lt; •01) and neutral (β = 0•05, SE = 0•01, z = 4•44, p &lt; •001) baseline items. The relationship between risk-taking and well-being was significantly weaker for the Lebanese nationals, relative to the refugee groups (gain: β = -0•02, SE = 0•01, z = -2•49, p &lt; •05; loss: β = -0•02, SE = 0•01, z = -2•82, p &lt; •01; neutral: β = -0•03, SE = 0•01, z = -4•25, p &lt; •001)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Subjective well-being by nationality.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Risk behaviour by subjective well-being.Thick lines represent group means. Shaded areas represent 95% bootstrapped confidence intervals.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Trust by nationality and domain. Bars represent response proportions for each trust domain.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Advantageous choices by nationality and intervention group.Codes for the baseline choice congruent with the frame of the experimental items. Error bars are 95% bootstrapped CI.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 . Participants by Lebanese governorate.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Proportion of</cell></row><row><cell>Governorate</cell><cell>n</cell><cell>sample</cell></row><row><cell>Mount Lebanon</cell><cell>311</cell><cell>41•3%</cell></row><row><cell>Beirut</cell><cell>134</cell><cell>17•8%</cell></row><row><cell>South</cell><cell>102</cell><cell>13•5%</cell></row><row><cell>North</cell><cell>81</cell><cell>10•7%</cell></row><row><cell>Akkar</cell><cell>29</cell><cell>3•9%</cell></row><row><cell>Beqaa</cell><cell>33</cell><cell>4•4%</cell></row><row><cell>Unknown</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>4•2%</cell></row><row><cell>Nabatieh</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>2•8%</cell></row><row><cell>Baalbek-Hermel</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>1•5%</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Sample demographics.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Total</cell><cell>Lebanese</cell><cell>Syrian</cell><cell>Palestinian</cell></row><row><cell>Participants</cell><cell>741</cell><cell>510</cell><cell>119</cell><cell>112</cell></row><row><cell>% of sample</cell><cell></cell><cell>68•8%</cell><cell>16•1%</cell><cell>15•1%</cell></row><row><cell>Age (med)</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>37</cell><cell>30</cell><cell>33</cell></row><row><cell>Range</cell><cell>18-69</cell><cell>19-60</cell><cell>18-67</cell><cell>18-69</cell></row><row><cell>Female</cell><cell>361</cell><cell>254</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>56</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>48•7%</cell><cell>49•8%</cell><cell>42•9%</cell><cell>50%</cell></row><row><cell>Relationship status</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Single</cell><cell></cell><cell>32•4%</cell><cell>31•9%</cell><cell>31•2%</cell></row><row><cell>In a relationship</cell><cell></cell><cell>6•5%</cell><cell>1•7%</cell><cell>6•2%</cell></row><row><cell>Married</cell><cell></cell><cell>58•6%</cell><cell>63•9%</cell><cell>58%</cell></row><row><cell>Divorced</cell><cell></cell><cell>2•2%</cell><cell>2•5%</cell><cell>1•8%</cell></row><row><cell>Widowed</cell><cell></cell><cell>0•4%</cell><cell>nul</cell><cell>2•7%</cell></row><row><cell>Education</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Less than high school</cell><cell></cell><cell>8•2%</cell><cell>73•9%</cell><cell>70•5%</cell></row><row><cell>High school</cell><cell></cell><cell>15•5%</cell><cell>14•3%</cell><cell>17•9%</cell></row><row><cell>Junior college or Vocational training</cell><cell></cell><cell>10•8%</cell><cell>1•7%</cell><cell>1•8%</cell></row><row><cell>Undergraduate degree</cell><cell></cell><cell>28%</cell><cell>4•2%</cell><cell>7•1%</cell></row><row><cell>Graduate degree</cell><cell></cell><cell>35•5%</cell><cell>5•9%</cell><cell>2•7%</cell></row><row><cell>Doctoral degree</cell><cell></cell><cell>2%</cell><cell>nul</cell><cell>nul</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 . Well-Being scores by country.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Lebanese</cell><cell cols="2">Syrian</cell><cell cols="2">Palestinian</cell><cell>All</cell></row><row><cell>Low</cell><cell>High</cell><cell>Low</cell><cell>High</cell><cell>Low</cell><cell>High</cell><cell>Low High</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4 . Participants choosing risking option at baseline by nationality and mental health.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Mental health</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 5 . General Trust by nationality.</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Lebanese</cell><cell>Syrian</cell><cell>Palestinian</cell></row><row><cell>Most people can be trusted</cell><cell>12•4%</cell><cell>13•4%</cell><cell>6•2%</cell></row><row><cell>Need to be very careful</cell><cell>87•6%</cell><cell>86•6%</cell><cell>93•8%</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thirty Years of Prospect Theory in Economics: A Review and Assessment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Barberis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Econ Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="96" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">NEF (The New Economics Foundation) (2008) A report presented to the Foresight Project on communicating the evidence base for improving people&apos;s well-being</title>
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Centre for Well-Being</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for countercyclical risk aversion: An experiment with financial professionals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Maréchal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am Econ Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="860" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Effect of Forced Choice on Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Simonson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Mark Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A policy implementer&apos;s perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>El Chammay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">(eds) The Massachusetts General Hospital Textbook on Diversity and Cultural Sensitivity in Mental Health</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Winer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">(</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Switzerland AG</title>
		<editor>Parekh, R, Trinh, NT,</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Understanding the Mental Health of Refugees: Trauma, Stress, and the Cultural Context</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimising nudges and boosts for financial decisions under uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Franklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Folke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ruggeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Palgrave Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nudging and Boosting: Steering or Empowering Good Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Grüne-Yanoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspect Psychol Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="973" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Flourishing Across Europe: Application of a New Conceptual Framework for Defining Well-Being</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Huppert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ttc</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc Indic Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="837" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Policy-Making for the Long Term in Advanced Democracies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Jacobs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu Rev Polit Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Health system challenges and solutions to improving mental health outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jenkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Baingana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ahmad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcdaid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Atun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ment Health Fam Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">International and national policy challenges in mental health</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jenkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Baingana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ahmad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcdaid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Atun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ment Health Fam Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissecting the impact of depression on decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lawlor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Webb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Wiecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lebanon Still has The Highest Refugees Density. Statista</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Loesche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.statista.com/chart/14323/countries-with-most-refugees-per-1000-inhabitants/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-06-19" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>published online</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Medical Aid for Palestinians (2020) Barriers to the health and dignity of Palestinian refugees in Lebanon</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.map.org.uk/downloads/health-in-exile--barriers-to-the-health-and-dignity-of-palestinian-refugees-in-lebanon.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-05-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The mental health of civilians displaced by armed conflict : an ecological model of refugee distress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rasmussen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychiatric Disorders in Refugees and Internally Displaced Persons After Forced Displacement : A Systematic Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Morina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Akhtar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Barth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Schnyder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">433</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Violence, psychological trauma, and risk attitudes: Evidence from victims of violence in Colombia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Dev Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">131</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Policy myopia as a source of policy failure: Adaptation and policy learning under deep uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Howlett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Policy Polit</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Doing survey research: A guide to quantitative methods (#4)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Nardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>Routledge</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Variation in risk seeking behaviour following large losses: A natural experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Torgler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur Econ Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="152" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intergenerational Trauma in Refugee Families : A Systematic Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Sangalang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Vang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Immigr Minor Heal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="745" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Association of the World War II finnish evacuation of children with psychiatric hospitalization in the next generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Santavirta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Santavirta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gilman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAMA Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are risk preferences stable?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schildberg-Hörisch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Econ Perspect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nudge: improving decisions about health, wealth, and happiness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Yale University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New Haven, CT</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">ReliefWeb Crisis Figures Data. UN OCHA</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Ocha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/0160cfdf-7dec-41a7-b0d2-8aa378f054d9" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-12-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">WHO (2013) Mental Health Action Plan</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>World Health Organization</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Geneva</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
