<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">DECISION-MAKING IN SELECTION</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marvin</forename><surname>Neumann</surname></persName>
							<email>m.neumann@rug.nl.</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychometrics and Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Behavioral and Social Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Groningen</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Susan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Niessen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychometrics and Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Behavioral and Social Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Groningen</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jorge</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tendeiro</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Office of Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Research Center for Artificial Intelligence and Data Innovation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Academia-Government-Community Collaboration</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Education</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Hiroshima University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rob</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Meijer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychometrics and Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Behavioral and Social Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Groningen</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychometrics and Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Behavioral and Social Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Groningen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Grote Kruisstraat 2/1</addrLine>
									<postCode>9712 TS</postCode>
									<settlement>Groningen</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">DECISION-MAKING IN SELECTION</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.2155</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:52+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>decision making</term>
					<term>holistic prediction</term>
					<term>mechanical prediction</term>
					<term>selection</term>
					<term>autonomy-validity dilemma</term>
					<term>decision aid</term>
					<term>algorithm aversion</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>A robust finding in psychological research is that combining information with a mechanical rule results in more valid predictions than combining information holistically in the mind. Nevertheless, information is typically combined holistically in practice, resulting in suboptimal predictions and decisions. Earlier research showed that decision makers are more likely to use mechanical prediction procedures when they retain autonomy in the decisionmaking process. However, it remains largely unknown how different autonomy-enhancing features affect predictive validity. Therefore, in two pre-registered studies (total N = 342), we investigated if and how prediction procedures can be designed such that they satisfy decisionmakers&apos; autonomy needs and acceptance without reducing predictive validity. Based on archival application data from a university admission procedure, participants predicted applicants&apos; first-year GPA and chance of dropout. The results of Bayesian analyses showed that participants preferred prediction procedures in which they retained autonomy by choosing consistent predictor weights of a mechanical rule or by holistically adjusting the predictions of an optimal regression model. In general, these prediction procedures resulted in slightly higher predictive validity compared to fully holistic prediction. Providing participants with predictor validity information slightly increased predictive validity when participants could choose predictor weights, but not when making holistic predictions or adjusting optimal model predictions. Giving decision makers a role in designing mechanical rules through choosing weights based on explicit predictive validity information could help promote the implementation and validity of mechanical prediction in practice.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>consistency and hence, results in more valid predictions than holistic prediction <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">(Yu &amp; Kuncel, 2020)</ref>, and decision-makers' autonomy is retained through control over the predictor weights <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Nolan &amp; Highhouse, 2014)</ref>. Alternatively, decision makers could choose different predictor weights for each applicant to be judged. This allows decision makers to account for suspected exceptions to the linear rule, such as interactions. For example, decision makers may weight an applicant's test score less heavily when their high school grade was excellent (for a similar example see MacDonald, 2020). However, this approach still requires decision makers to choose explicit weights, which could increase consistency compared to holistic prediction if decision makers would be consistent in a majority of cases (where they do not expect rule exceptions), while holistic predictions for these applicants may still be inconsistent due to unintentional factors such as fatigue and inattention. This approach contains components of mechanical and holistic prediction; the combination of information does not happen 'in the mind', as in holistic prediction, but is based on explicit weights.</p><p>However, because weights are not consistent across individuals, this approach does not meet the definition of mechanical prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Adjusting the Result of a Mechanical Rule</head><p>Autonomy is also retained when decision makers can holistically adjust the result after applying a mechanical rule. This procedure, which is also called clinical synthesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Kuncel, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Sawyer, 1966)</ref> allows decision makers to account for suspected rule exceptions more directly. Although not explicitly based on self-determination theory, Dietvorst et al. <ref type="formula">2018</ref>conducted a series of experiments in which participants' autonomy in using a mechanical rule to make standardized test performance predictions was varied. The results showed that participants who could adjust the rule's predictions were more confident in and more satisfied with their predictions, chose to use the rule more often, and made more accurate predictions as a result, compared to participants who could not adjust the rule's predictions.</p><p>Although predictive validity decreases when decision makers holistically adjust mechanical rule predictions <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Guay &amp; Parent, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hanson &amp; Morton-Bourgon, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hoffman et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Neumann et al., 2021)</ref>, there is some evidence that adjusting rule predictions still results in higher predictive validity than pure holistic prediction <ref type="bibr">(Dietvorst et al., 2018)</ref>. This is because a rule prediction based on appropriate weights provides a valid "anchor" <ref type="bibr">(Dietvorst et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1974)</ref>.</p><p>In sum, the results of <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Nolan and Highhouse (2014)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Dietvorst et al. (2018)</ref> suggest that the use of mechanical rules can be increased by granting decision makers autonomy over predictor weights or over the rule prediction. However, it remains unclear which of these procedures yields the most favorable results in terms of user perceptions, intentions, and predictive validity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Aim and Contribution</head><p>The aim of the current studies was to investigate the effects of different kinds of autonomy-enhancing features in using a mechanical rule on (1) user perceptions and intentions, and (2) predictive validity, to see if a satisfactory compromise between optimizing autonomy and validity can be established. The present studies extend the studies by <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Nolan and Highhouse (2014)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Dietvorst et al. (2018)</ref> in three ways. First, <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Nolan and Highhouse (2014)</ref> investigated whether autonomy in determining predictor weights affected use intentions for mechanical rules based on vignettes describing different procedures. We instead asked our participants to make actual predictions based on real data. Second, we also investigated the effect of autonomy-enhancement on predictive validity: enhancing decisionmakers' autonomy should not result in a large reduction in predictive validity to be of any practical value. Third, to our knowledge, no studies have jointly investigated autonomy in designing the rule and autonomy through adjusting rule predictions. In the current studies, we included both prediction procedures, to investigate whether attitudes and validity depend on the stage in the decision-making process in which decision makers have autonomy <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Burton et al., 2020)</ref>. In sum, we respond to the calls for investigations of how decision-makers' acceptance of mechanical prediction procedures can be increased without substantially reducing predictive validity <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Burton et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Kuncel, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kuncel et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Neumann et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Ryan et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Sackett &amp; Lievens, 2008)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>We employed a within-subjects design to ensure sufficient statistical power and to allow for a joint evaluation of the different prediction procedures. This approach yields the most representative measure of use intentions, because in practice, decisions to use certain prediction procedures are made by comparing multiple procedures jointly rather than separately <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Highhouse et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Hsee &amp; Zhang, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Nolan et al., 2020)</ref>. Furthermore,</p><p>given that many decision makers in practice are unaware of the distinction between holisticand mechanical prediction, a within-subjects design should improve the evaluability of an attribute that is difficult to evaluate due to a lack of knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Hsee &amp; Zhang, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>In the first four conditions, each participant predicted the first-year GPA and the chance of dropout of five applicants to a psychology undergraduate program, based on three predictors: high school GPA, an admission test score, and a personal statement. In the first condition, participants made holistic predictions. This condition was included so the other conditions could be compared to the prediction procedure typically used in practice. In the second and third condition, participants could design a mechanical rule by choosing general predictor weights (general weights condition) or by choosing applicant-specific predictor weights (individual weights condition), respectively. Including these conditions allowed us to test whether participants would prefer designing rules tailored to the unique individual (individual weights) over designing one consistent rule (general weights). This preference was expected because people often think information should be interpreted in the context of all other information <ref type="bibr">(Grove &amp; Meehl, 1996)</ref>, and because decontextualization seems to be a driver of algorithm aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Newman et al., 2020)</ref>. In the fourth condition -the adjustment condition -participants could adjust the prediction of a statistical model (see <ref type="bibr">Dietvorst et al., 2018)</ref>, in a similar way as in typical advice-taking studies <ref type="bibr">(Önkal et al., 2009)</ref>. Including this condition allowed us to investigate whether perceptions and use intentions, and predictive validity differ depending on whether participants design the prediction process (choosing general weights) or have the final say at the end (adjusting optimal model predictions), which are two qualitatively different types of autonomy-enhancing features. Lastly, in the fifth condition, participants did not make predictions themselves (no autonomy) but had to rely on optimal regression model predictions which they could not adjust (optimal model condition).</p><p>This condition was included to compare the previous four conditions with this optimal but least utilized procedure in practice. Based on the findings of Nolan and Highhouse <ref type="formula">(2014) and</ref>Dietvorst et al. <ref type="formula">2018</ref>, we formulated the following expectations:</p><p>Hypothesis 1: Perceived autonomy will decrease from the holistic condition (most autonomy), individual weights condition, general weights condition to the optimal model condition (least autonomy).</p><p>We had no specific hypothesis on how the adjustment condition would compare to the two weighting conditions, because participants could adjust optimal model predictions and hence had complete autonomy. Yet, seeing the model prediction may reduce autonomy perceptions compared to making holistic predictions. Therefore, we only expected that perceived autonomy will be higher compared to the optimal model condition, and lower compared to the holistic condition. For brevity, hypothesis 1 is only formulated for perceived autonomy. We expected the same results for use intentions (H2), confidence (H3), and satisfaction (H4).</p><p>Hypothesis 5: Predictive validity will increase from the holistic condition (lowest predictive validity), individual weights condition, general weights condition to the optimal model condition (highest predictive validity).</p><p>We had no specific hypothesis on how the adjustment condition would compare to the two weighting conditions, but expected lower predictive validity than in the optimal model condition and higher predictive validity than in the holistic condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method Participants</head><p>A power analysis 1 for the omnibus F test of a repeated measures ANOVA (hypotheses 1-4) resulted in a required sample size of N = 40 (assuming 1-ß &gt; .8, α = .05, number of measurements = 5, nonsphericity correction ε = 1, and a moderate effect size, f = 0.25, consistent with previous research, Nolan <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">&amp; Highhouse, 2014)</ref>. Furthermore, since we had no a priori estimate of the correlation among repeated measures, we set this correlation equal to zero, which results in the most conservative sample size estimation). To be conservative and counteract inflated effect sizes in the published literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">(Schäfer &amp; Schwarz, 2019)</ref>, we aimed to collect minimally 50 participants, and maximally as many as signed up before the planned closing-date of data collection (see the pre-registration protocol, https://osf.io/fjbvw).</p><p>1 Although we used Bayesian parameter estimation to analyze our results, we reported the results from our preregistered frequentist power analyses so that readers who are mostly familiar with frequentist testing can understand that our studies had sufficient power to detect significant differences if we had tested our hypotheses using frequentist null hypothesis significance tests.</p><p>Many more participants than minimally required signed up before the planned closingdate of data collection, which resulted in a total of N = 153 first-year psychology students who consented to take part in this study for course credit. Three participants failed one or both of two attention checks (see Appendix A) and were excluded. The final dataset consisted of N = 150 2 participants (17% male, 83% female, &lt; 1% did not want to disclose) who ranged in age from 18 to 39 years (M = 19.85, SD = 2.52). Most participants had the Dutch nationality (97%). The other four participants had German, Brazilian, Russian, and Syrian nationalities.</p><p>This study was approved by the ethics committee of the [blinded for review] for psychological research (code: 18255 -S).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>Participants were presented with anonymized archival data from applicants to the psychology undergraduate program of the University of Groningen. Application data of 192 Dutch applicants were used as stimulus material <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Niessen et al., 2018)</ref>. From this pool, five applicants were randomly allocated (without replacement within participants) to the four conditions in which participants made predictions (i.e., all conditions except the optimal model condition). Applicants were evenly sampled so that every applicant was judged. So, applicants were assigned to participants until all 192 applicants were sampled, after which a new sampling round started. Participants were presented with each applicant's high school GPA, an admission test score, and a personal statement. We used these predictors because they are commonly used in college admission procedures <ref type="bibr">(Davis et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Niessen et al., 2018</ref>).</p><p>2 We also conducted a sensitivity power analysis for a one-tailed dependent t test, given that pairwise comparisons were most important for answering our hypotheses. Given N = 150, α = .05, and 1-β = .80, the smallest effect size we could detect with sufficient power was dz = 0.20. Furthermore, for predictive validity, we also calculated the required effect size to detect a significant difference between dependent correlations, assuming 1-β &gt; .8; α = .05, and N = 750. The N resulted from 150 participants who each made five judgments in a condition. Given a correlation coefficient of rab = .4, the alternative correlation coefficient must at least be rac = .45, assuming rbc = 0.8.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>High School GPA</head><p>High school GPA was the mean of all final grades obtained at the end of secondary education (vwo), and was measured on the Dutch ten-point grading scale (1 is lowest, 10 is highest). High school GPA ranged from 5.90 to 8.55 (M = 6.61, SD = 0.46) and was a good predictor of first-year GPA (r = .45), and a moderate predictor of dropout (r = -.23) in this sample.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Admission Test</head><p>Applicants had to study two chapters from an introductory psychology book and then took an admission test of 40 multiple-choice items that covered the study material. 'Number of items correct' was transformed to the Dutch ten-point grading scale and ranged from 2.2 to 9.7 (M = 6.42, SD = 1.77). In this sample, the admission test was a good predictor of first-year GPA (r = .40), and a moderate predictor of dropout (r = -.27).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Personal Statement</head><p>Before making predictions, participants also rated on a 7-point scale (1 = very unmotivated, 7 = very motivated) applicants' personal statements, in which applicants expressed their motivation to study psychology at the university in a maximum of 250 words.</p><p>The mean rating was M = 5.47 (SD = 1.08). For the calculation of predicted scores within conditions, personal statement ratings were transformed to the Dutch 10-point grading scale.</p><p>Research suggests that inter-rater reliability of personal statements is low <ref type="bibr">(GlenMaye &amp; Oakes, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Murphy et al., 2009)</ref>. Indeed, inter-rater reliability was also low in this study (ICC = .24). The personal statement rating was a poor predictor of first-year GPA across conditions (!̅ = .05) and of dropout (!̅ = .02).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure and Conditions</head><p>Participants completed the study in a lab space at the university in groups of up to 16 participants simultaneously. The experimenter informed participants about the opportunity to earn a reward (up to €5), depending on their prediction accuracy. The reward served to simulate accountability and to encourage effort, as is common in this area of research (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Dietvorst et al., 2018)</ref>. All other instructions were presented on a computer screen. The participants were informed that they would first rate personal statements and then predict applicants' first-year GPA and chance of dropout in the first year of the psychology program.</p><p>Participants received predictor validity information. They were informed that high school GPA and the admission test were "good predictors", while the personal statement was a "poor predictor" of the outcomes. Participants also received summary statistics (mean, minimum, and maximum) for the predictors high school GPA and the admission test score, and the criteria first-year GPA and dropout as reference.</p><p>In the holistic condition, participants saw the applicants' data (i.e., high school GPA, admission test score, personal statement in qualitative form, and their quantitative rating) and holistically predicted applicants' first-year GPA and the chance of dropout.</p><p>In the individual weights condition, participants saw the applicants' data and assigned percentage weights to the predictors for each of the five applicants individually. So, participants could assign different predictor weights to different applicants. To calculate the resulting predictive score, each predictor score was multiplied by the individual weight that a participant assigned to this predictor.</p><p>In the general weights condition, participants assigned percentage weights to the predictors once, which applied to all of the five applicants to be judged in this condition. Each predictor score was multiplied by the weight that a participant assigned to this predictor.</p><p>Additionally, we also wanted to explore whether thinking about predictor importance (by choosing a set of general weights) would by itself result in more consistent and hence more valid holistic predictions that immediately follow after choosing weights, compared to predictions in the holistic condition. Therefore, after participants chose general weights and responded to the attitudinal measures, they again judged five applicants holistically, in the same manner as in the holistic condition. We present the additional details (Section S1) and the results (Section S2) in the supplementary material.</p><p>In the adjustment condition, participants saw the applicants' data and a regression model prediction of applicants' first-year GPA and chance of drop out. Participants were told that the model was based on an applicant's high school GPA and admission test score 3 .</p><p>Furthermore, they were informed that the model was quite accurate in predicting the criteria, and that it most likely gave the best prediction, better than their own, holistic prediction.</p><p>Participants could holistically adjust the model prediction. If they did not want to adjust it, they simply reproduced the model prediction.</p><p>In the optimal model condition, participants did not make predictions themselves but imagined that they had to use the regression model predictions based on the same model as in the adjustment condition, without the possibility to adjust it in any way.</p><p>Each participant completed each condition. The order of the conditions was counterbalanced 4 , except for the optimal model condition. This condition was always presented last because the adjustment condition always had to be presented before the optimal model condition. The instructions to participants per condition are shown in Appendix B. At the end of each condition, participants answered questions regarding their intentions to use, their confidence in-, their satisfaction with-, and their perceived autonomy in the prediction approach.</p><p>3 The model did not include the personal statement because ratings were not available before data collection. However, personal statements have very low predictive validity <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Murphy et al., 2009)</ref>. Therefore, we expected that personal statement ratings would not significantly improve a model that contained high school GPA and admission test scores, as indeed was the case (first-year GPA, ΔR 2 &lt; .001, F(1,746) = .18, p = .671; dropout, Nagelkerke's pseudo R 2 , ΔR 2 p = .004, c 2 (1) = 1.85, p = .173).</p><p>Finally, participants imagined that their task was to select applicants that would achieve a high first-year GPA and would be unlikely to drop out for the upcoming academic year. Participants ranked the different prediction procedures according to which procedure they were most likely to use (rank 1 = most likely, rank 5 = least likely). Participants were informed that their reward they had earned up to this point would be increased by 20% if they chose the procedure that yielded the most accurate predictions (we assumed this to be the optimal model condition, as indeed turned out to be the case). The descriptions of the five procedures were displayed in random order. The median time it took to complete the study was 39 minutes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attitudinal Measures</head><p>Perceived autonomy was measured with a translated version of the six-item scale (α = .91) from <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Nolan and Highhouse (2014)</ref>. We adapted the three-item scale from <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Nolan and Highhouse (2014)</ref> to assess the extent to which participants intend to use a certain approach for future admission decisions (α = .83). Confidence and satisfaction were assessed with oneitem measures based on Dietvorst et al. (2018). Participants responded to these measures on 5-point Likert scales. More details about the measures can be found on https://osf.io/86jfb/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures Used for Predictive Validity Hypotheses</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>First-year GPA</head><p>Participants indicated the predicted first-year GPA on a continuous scale (1 = lowest grade; 10 = highest grade), up to one decimal. The predictive validity was operationalized as the correlation between the predicted and the observed first-year GPA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chance of Dropout</head><p>Participants indicated the predicted chance that an applicant dropped out of the program on a continuous scale from 0% to 50%. This scale was chosen because the regression model did not return a chance of drop out above 50% for any of the applicants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analytical Approach</head><p>Dichotomous decision making based on p-values has received much criticism <ref type="bibr">(Cohen, 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Wasserstein et al., 2019)</ref>. Bayesian approaches have been recommended as a suitable alternative because they have several advantages over null hypothesis significance testing <ref type="bibr">(NHST, see Cohen, 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Kruschke, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Kruschke et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b82">Wagenmakers, 2007)</ref>. For example, multiple comparisons are not problematic in Bayesian approaches because prior knowledge is incorporated into the model <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Berry &amp; Hochberg, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr">Gelman, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Gelman et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Kruschke, 2015)</ref>. For these reasons, we used a Bayesian approach to analyze our data. We only conducted frequentist tests to analyze the ranks that participants assigned to the prediction procedures because, to our knowledge, there are no Bayesian alternatives for these tests. Moreover, we used Bayesian parameter estimation instead of hypothesis testing <ref type="bibr">(Kruschke &amp; Lidell, 2018)</ref> because we were primarily interested in the magnitude and uncertainty of the effects. Furthermore, the null hypothesis is unlikely to be exactly true in most contexts, so testing it against an alternative is much less informative than estimating effect sizes <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Kruschke &amp; Liddell, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>The Bayesian approach to parameter estimation allows estimating a distribution that displays the credibility of each possible parameter value <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Kruschke, 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Kruschke, , 2015</ref>. This distribution is commonly summarized by a 95% highest density interval (HDI), which is constructed in such a way that it includes the true parameter with probability .95, conditional on the model and observed data. The advantage of HDIs over the commonly misinterpreted frequentist confidence intervals <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Morey et al., 2016)</ref> is that they can be used to make the intuitive statement that there is a 95% probability that the parameter falls within the boundaries of the HDI, conditional on the model and data at hand. Therefore, we reported parameter estimates and the corresponding 95% HDIs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>All analyses were run in R (4.1.1). We had no permission to share the archival application data due to privacy reasons. Therefore, our publicly available (https://osf.io/86jfb/) R scripts and data allow re-running all reported analyses except for the results on predictive validity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attitudinal Measures</head><p>We ran two-factor mixed-effects Bayesian ANOVAs with the condition as a withinsubject factor (fixed effect) and subjects as a random effect, for each of the four dependent measures. The mean differences and the HDIs for the contrasts as stated in hypotheses 1-4 are reported. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 1</ref> displays the observed means per attitudinal measure for each condition.</p><p>Furthermore, <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows the means and standard deviations for each attitudinal measure in each condition, and <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows correlations between the attitudinal measures. As <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> and 2 show, mean patterns and correlations for the confidence-and satisfaction measure were very similar to the mean patterns and correlations of the use intentions measure. Therefore, we report the results for confidence and satisfaction, and more details of the Bayesian analysis in Section S2 of the supplementary material.</p><p>-Insert <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 1</ref> about here --Insert <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> about here --Insert <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> about here -</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Perceived Autonomy</head><p>Figure 1 suggests that perceived autonomy was very similar across prediction procedures, except for using optimal model predictions, where perceived autonomy was much lower compared to all other prediction procedures. As expected, autonomy was highest for making holistic predictions and lowest for using optimal model predictions. Participants experienced less autonomy when choosing individual weights than when making holistic predictions, but this difference was negligible in size <ref type="formula">(</ref> between the holistic-and the optimal model condition. So, hypothesis 1 was mostly unsupported. Although we observed the hypothesized ordering in perceived autonomy, differences between conditions were negligible, except for the optimal model condition, in which participants experienced much less autonomy compared to all other conditions (Cohen's ds &gt; 1.00).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Use Intentions</head><p>We found a number of unexpected results. Use intentions were not highest when making holistic predictions (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 1</ref>). Use intentions were noticeably higher when As expected, use intentions were slightly lower for using optimal model predictions than for holistic predictions (Mholistic -Moptimal = 0.22, 95% HDI [0.05, 0.39], d = 0.26), and slightly lower for using individual weights than holistic predictions (Mholistic -Mindividual = 0.17, 95% HDI [0.01, 0.34], d = 0.23). Also, use intentions were markedly lower when using optimal model predictions than when choosing general weights (Mgeneral -Moptimal = 0.46, 95% HDI [0.30, 0.63], d = 0.54). In sum, hypothesis 2 was also mostly unsupported, as we did not observe the hypothesized decrease in use intentions from the holistic-to the optimal condition. However, our results suggest that decision makers welcome prediction procedures in which they can choose general weights or adjust optimal model predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure Ranking</head><p>Participants also ranked the prediction procedures according to which procedure they were most likely to use. The resulting mean preference ranks and rank frequencies per procedure are displayed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. The majority of participants (56%) preferred using the adjustment procedure for future admission decisions the most. Of interest was that only 10% preferred making holistic predictions the most and few participants preferred choosing predictor weights the most (individual weights 10%; general weights 11%). Also, few participants (13%) preferred optimal model predictions the most, although they were informed that these predictions would likely be most valid. A Friedman test revealed significant differences in mean ranks between the procedures (χ 2 (4) = 83.781, p &lt; .001). To determine whether participants significantly preferred the adjustment procedure, we compared it to the general weights procedure (second smallest rank) using a Wilcoxon signed rank test.</p><p>This difference in mean ranks was moderate to large (z = -5.77, p &lt; .001, r = -.47, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-.59, -.33]</ref>). So, when participants had to choose a procedure for making valid future admission decisions, they clearly preferred adjusting optimal model predictions.</p><p>-Insert <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> about here -</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Use of Autonomy-enhancing Features</head><p>The results in the supplementary material (Section S2) show that almost all participants used the autonomy-enhancing features. Furthermore, we investigated how participants weighted the predictors, by regressing their predictions on the predictors and subsequently calculating relative weights <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">(Tonidandel &amp; LeBreton, 2015)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure S1</ref> in the supplementary material shows relative weights for the holistic-, adjustment-, and optimal model condition, and the averaged weights in the general weights condition. Compared to the optimal model, participants weighted the personal statement more heavily in all conditions, and the difference was larger when predicting chance of dropout.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predictive Validity</head><p>For each condition, we computed the correlation coefficient between the predicted scores and the two outcomes (first-year GPA and drop out). We also computed a multiple correlation coefficient based on an optimal regression model for each condition. Because the applicants that were judged differed per condition due to random allocation of applicants to participants, the multiple R based on an optimal regression model differed slightly between conditions. Therefore, we always compared the validity of condition-specific participants' predictions with the validity of a condition-specific optimal regression model 5 . We compared correlations by computing posterior distributions of differences between correlations using the BayesFactor package (0.9.12 -4.2), and we reported the 95% highest density intervals 6 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>First-year GPA</head><p>The correlation coefficients are presented in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. The predictive validity of participants' predictions was similar across conditions. However, as expected, the optimal model resulted in the highest predictive validity in each condition (!̅ = .50) 7 . Contrary to 5 Cross-validated multiple Rs of the optimal regression models are reported in the supplementary material because they barely deviated from the original multiple Rs. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> We had to deviate from our pre-registration here due to an oversight and misunderstanding among the authors with regard to the pre-registered analysis plan. 7 Correlational differences and 95% HDIs between the validity of participants' predictions and optimal model predictions per condition for first-year GPA: Holistic -optimal = -.10, 95% HDI [-.18, -.03]; Individual -expectations, the holistic predictions did not result in the lowest predictive validity (r = .43).</p><p>The holistic predictions had higher validity than predictions made based on individual weights (r = .36), and similar validity to predictions made based on general weights (r = .41) and holistically adjusted model predictions (r = .39). Only the optimal model (r = .54) resulted in higher predictive validity than holistic predictions. Other conditions than the optimal condition resulted in slightly lower validity than the holistic condition. These differences were in the opposite direction of our hypothesis.</p><p>-Insert <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> about here -</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dropout</head><p>The results for predicting dropout mostly aligned with those for predicting first-year GPA (see <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>). The holistic predictions did not result in the lowest predictive validity (r = .21), but in validity similar to those based on individual weights (r = .18) and general weights (r = .19). Again, the optimal model had by far the largest predictive validity (!̅ = .39) 8 . Furthermore, adjusted optimal model predictions (r = .30) also resulted in higher validity than holistic predictions (rdiff = -.11, 95% HDI [-.20, -.03]). So, of all autonomyenhancing procedures, only holistically adjusted optimal model predictions were more valid than holistic predictions. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory Analyses</head><p>In the general weights condition, weights were only consistent for the five applicants that were judged by a single participant. However, each participant chose different weights, which reduced consistency within the entire sample of predictions. We also averaged all participants' weights (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure S1</ref> in the supplementary material) to check whether full consistency would increase predictive validity. Averaging weights barely increased the validity for first-year GPA (from r = .41 to r = .42) and dropout (from r = .19 to r = .22). As <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure S1</ref> also shows, there was relatively little variance in the weights that participants chose, which explains why averaged weights did not increase predictive validity much.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The results of Study 1 showed that, contrary to expectations, differences in perceived autonomy between all autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures were negligible, as were differences between making holistic predictions and all autonomy-enhancing prediction</p><p>procedures. Yet, as predicted, decision makers experienced much more autonomy when making holistic predictions and when using autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures than when using prescribed optimal model predictions. This suggests that participants were relatively insensitive to how autonomy was enhanced (by choosing individual/general weights or by adjusting optimal model predictions). So, hypothesis 1 was mostly unsupported. The results were different for use intentions. Although holistic prediction is predominantly used in practice, participants unexpectedly preferred choosing general predictor weights and adjusting optimal model predictions over all other prediction procedures. So, hypothesis 2 was also mostly unsupported. One explanation may be that these two autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures require less effort than making holistic predictions <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Nolan &amp; Highhouse, 2014)</ref>, which may also explain why participants disliked choosing weights for each specific applicant. Yet, the optimal model condition, which required the least effort, was also disliked the most.</p><p>Choosing one set of predictor weights and holistically adjusting optimal model predictions resulted in high use intentions. However, contrary to expectations, predictive validity barely increased compared to holistic predictions. For predicting first-year GPA, choosing predictor weights and adjusting optimal model predictions resulted in very similar predictive validity compared to holistic predictions. For predicting dropout, only adjusting optimal model predictions resulted in slightly higher predictive validity than holistic predictions. Furthermore, our finding that letting participants choose one set of predictor weights did not result in higher validity than holistic predictions cannot be explained by a lack of consistency between participants <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">(Yu &amp; Kuncel, 2020)</ref>, as averaging weights across participants barely increased predictive validity. An alternative explanation may be that participants weighted the personal statement more heavily when choosing general weights than when making holistic predictions (as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure S1</ref> in the supplementary material).</p><p>In general, our findings are only partially in line with results presented by Dietvorst et al.</p><p>(2018), who found that holistically adjusting optimal model predictions resulted in higher validity than fully holistic predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>The aim of Study 2 was to answer a number of questions that were raised by Study 1.</p><p>In Study 1, holistic predictions were surprisingly valid. This may have been a result of providing participants with predictor validity information, which generally increases validity <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Balzer et al., 1989)</ref>, likely due to increased consistency. However, in practice, predictor validity information may be unavailable, or less salient than it was for the participants in Study 1. Therefore, we randomly varied between subjects whether participants received predictor validity information (presented in the same way as in Study 1) or not, expecting that participants would make more valid predictions when validity information is available. <ref type="bibr">Dietvorst et al. (2018)</ref> found that decision makers used mechanical rule predictions as long as they could adjust them holistically, regardless of the extent of allowed adjustments. Therefore, to improve predictive validity in the adjustment condition, we restricted the extent to which participants could adjust optimal model predictions. Participants could adjust model predictions of first-year GPA by 0.5 grade points (upward or downward), and model predictions of the chance of dropout by 5%. Restricting participants' adjustment behavior allowed us, together with the results from Study 1, to formulate more specific hypotheses. We expected that participants would perceive less autonomy when restrictedly adjusting optimal model predictions compared to choosing predictor weights (cf. hypothesis 6). Yet, based on the results presented by Dietvorst et al. <ref type="formula">2018</ref>, we expected that use intentions would be similar to Study 1, where adjustment was unrestricted. Furthermore, we expected that restrictedly adjusting optimal model predictions would result in more valid predictions than freely choosing consistent predictor weights without valid reference points (cf. hypothesis 11).</p><p>A couple of changes were made to investigate attitudes towards prediction procedures more elaborately. At the end of the general weights condition, participants completed the attitudinal measures twice, assuming that (1) their own weights would be used and (2) their weights would be averaged with the weights from other participants. This was done to explore how decision makers would perceive a procedure in which solely their own weights are used, compared to a procedure where their weights are averaged with weights of other decision makers. Participants could also choose this "averaged weights procedure" when rank-ordering the prediction procedures according to which procedure they would most likely use. We also asked participants to report how valid they thought each predictor was. This was done because decision-makers' beliefs in predictor validities do not always align with empirical validities <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">(Rynes et al., 2002)</ref>. However, such differences between beliefs and empirical validities are important to investigate because beliefs may partly determine how decision makers weight predictors <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Kuncel, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>In contrast to Study 1, Study 2 was conducted online, and each condition included ten predictions and a prediction trial to familiarize participants with the task before their prediction was rewarded (as in Study 1, participants could earn a reward up to €5).</p><p>Furthermore, to reduce the duration of the study, we dropped the holistic predictions at the end of the general weights condition as well as the individual weights condition, which was disliked by participants and resulted in low validity. Moreover, in the optimal model condition, we actually showed participants the regression model predictions that they could not adjust. This allowed us to counterbalance all conditions 9 . The median time it took to complete the study was 64 minutes.</p><p>Hypothesis 6: Perceived autonomy will decrease from the holistic condition (most autonomy), general weights condition, adjustment condition, to the optimal model condition (least autonomy).</p><p>Hypothesis 7: Participants will report higher use intentions in the general weights condition and the adjustment condition than in the optimal model condition, and higher use intentions in the holistic condition than in the optimal model condition.</p><p>We had the same hypotheses for confidence (H8) and satisfaction (H9).</p><p>9 As in Study 1, the order of conditions had a negligible effect on participants' behavior and differences in predictive validity were in the opposite direction of expectations. We present the results in the supplementary material (Section S3).</p><p>Hypothesis 10: Participants who receive predictor validity information will make predictions that result in higher predictive validity in each condition (except for the optimal model condition), than participants who do not receive predictor validity information.</p><p>Hypothesis 11: Predictive validity will increase from the holistic condition (lowest predictive validity), general weights condition, adjustment condition to the optimal model condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method Participants</head><p>We conducted power analyses for the repeated measures ANOVAs (hypotheses 6-9) and for the difference tests between two independent correlations (hypothesis 10). The latter power analysis required the highest sample size (N = 192), assuming 1-ß &gt; .8, α = .05, allocation ratio N2/N1 = 1, predictions per condition = 10, and an effect size of q = 0.11 based on the results from Study 1. We recruited participants in two ways. Participants recruited via the research platform of the University of Groningen received €10 compensation for their participation. Participants from the first-year psychology student pool took part for course credit. In total, 269 participants completed the experiment. No participants from Study 1 participated in Study 2. We excluded participants who failed at least one of three attention checks (see Appendix A) or completed the study in less than 20 minutes (n = 77). The mean age of the final sample (N = 192) was M = 21.69 (SD = 6.04, range 16-64) and the majority of participants was female (77%) and Dutch (93%). All other participants had another European nationality (7%). Furthermore, 88% were enrolled as a student, 11% were employed and 1% was unemployed. This study was approved by the ethics committee of the [blinded for review] for psychological research (code: PSY-1920-S-0120).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures and Stimulus Material</head><p>We used the exact same attitudinal measures as in Study 1. The scales for use intentions and autonomy showed good reliability (α = .87 and α = .92). Furthermore, we used a one-item measure to assess how effective participants considered each predictor to be (1 = not effective; 5 = very effective). As in Study 1, the inter-rater reliability for the personal statement ratings was low (ICC = .11). The personal statement rating was a poor predictor of first-year GPA (!̅ = .06) and dropout (!̅ = -.02).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attitudinal Measures</head><p>We ran two-factor mixed-effects Bayesian ANOVAs with the condition as a withinsubject factor (fixed effect) and subjects as a random effect, for each of the four dependent measures. The between-subjects factor was not included in the ANOVAs 10 because we only hypothesized differences between the two levels of the between-subjects factor for predictive validity. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 4</ref> displays the observed means per attitudinal measure for each condition.</p><p>Means and standard deviations for each attitudinal measure in each condition are reported in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> and correlations between attitudinal measures in <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>. As in Study 1, mean patterns and correlations for the confidence-and satisfaction measures were very similar to the mean patterns and correlations of the use intentions measure. Therefore, we report the results for confidence and satisfaction in the supplementary material (Section S3).</p><p>-Insert <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 4</ref> about here --Insert <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> about here --Insert <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> about here -</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Perceived Autonomy</head><p>In general, we observed the decreasing trend in perceived autonomy in line with hypothesis 6. Although perceived autonomy was very similar for making holistic predictions and for choosing predictor weights (Mholistic -Mgeneral = 0.002, 95% HDI <ref type="bibr">[-0.12, 0.12]</ref>, d = 0.004), it was higher for choosing predictor weights than for adjusting optimal model predictions (Mgeneral -Madjust = 0.25, 95% HDI [0.12, 0.37], d = 0.41). This was expected (cf. hypothesis 6) because we restricted the range in which participants could adjust optimal model predictions, but not the range of predictor weights they could choose. Furthermore, as expected, participants perceived much more autonomy when they could adjust optimal model predictions than when they had to use optimal model predictions (Madjust -Moptimal = 0.79, 95% HDI [0.67, 0.92], d = 1.03). So, hypothesis 6 was mostly supported.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Use intentions</head><p>As expected, participants' use intentions were much higher for choosing predictor weights than for using optimal model predictions (Mgeneral -Moptimal = 0.65, 95% HDI [0.53, 0.79], d = 0.81), and higher for adjusting optimal model predictions than for using optimal model predictions (Madjust -Moptimal = 0.49, 95% HDI [0.36, 0.62], d = 0.58). Furthermore, participants showed higher intentions to use holistic predictions compared to optimal model predictions (Mholistic -Moptimal = 0.25, 95% HDI [0.12, 0.38], d = 0.29). Therefore, hypothesis 7 was fully supported.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure Ranking</head><p>The mean ranks and rank frequencies per procedure are displayed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. The adjustment procedure was most often (44%) ranked as most preferred for making future admission decisions. In contrast, only 14% of participants preferred to use optimal model predictions the most, although, as in Study 1, they were informed that this procedure would likely be most valid. Also, only a minority (11%) preferred the holistic procedure the most.</p><p>Interestingly, participants ranked the "averaged weights procedure" first more often than the procedure where solely their own weights were used, although this difference was small <ref type="bibr">(19% vs. 13%)</ref>. A Friedman test revealed significant differences in mean ranks between the procedures, χ 2 (4) = 112.83, p &lt; .001. A follow-up Wilcoxon signed rank test showed that participants moderately preferred to adjust optimal model predictions compared to using averaged weights (second smallest rank, z = -3.70, p &lt; .001, r = -.27, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-.40, -.13]</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Validity Beliefs</head><p>To investigate whether participants actually believed in the presented predictor validity information, we compared beliefs between participants who did and those who did  <ref type="bibr">11</ref> We had pre-registered that we would also provide Bayes Factors for differences in validity beliefs. For simplicity and consistency reasons, we decided to stick to Bayesian parameter estimation throughout the paper and therefore reported mean differences and 95% highest density intervals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Use of Autonomy-enhancing Features</head><p>The results presented in the supplementary material (Section S3) show that, as in Study 1, almost all participants made use of the autonomy-enhancing features. Furthermore, the relative weights analysis showed that, compared to the optimal model, participants weighted the personal statement more heavily in all conditions, and the difference was larger when predicting chance of dropout (see <ref type="figure">Figure S2)</ref>. Moreover, participants who did not receive validity information weighted the personal statement slightly more heavily than participants who received validity information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predictive Validity</head><p>First-year GPA <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 5</ref> displays the validity of participants' predictions for those who did and did not receive validity information separately, and the optimal model validity. In the holistic-and adjustment condition, predictive validity was very similar between participants who received validity information and participants who did not receive validity information (holistic: r = .31 and r = .32; rdiff = -.01, 95% HDI [-.09, .07] and adjustment: r = .34 and r = .36; rdiff = -.02, 95% HDI [-.10, .05], respectively). However, in the general weights condition, participants who received validity information made slightly more accurate predictions than participants who did not receive validity information (r = .41 and r = .34; rdiff = .07, 95% HDI <ref type="bibr">[-.01, .15]</ref>). So, presenting participants with validity information only increased predictive validity in the general weights condition, albeit only slightly (partial support for hypothesis 10).</p><p>Hypothesis 11 stated that predictive validity increases from the holistic condition to the general weights condition to the adjustment condition to the optimal model condition. For participants who did not receive predictor validity information, predictive validity slightly increased from the holistic condition (r = .32) to the general weights condition (r = .34) to the adjustment condition (r = .36) to the optimal model condition (!̅ = .41). For participants who received predictor validity information, predictive validity increased markedly from the holistic condition (r = .31) to the general weights condition (r = .41). However, predictive validity in the adjustment condition (r = .34) was not higher than predictive validity in the general weights condition. Furthermore, optimal model predictions were as valid (!̅ = .41) as predictions in the general weights condition. So, we found some evidence for the predicted increase in predictive validity from the holistic condition to the optimal model condition, although the general weights condition resulted in higher predictive validity than the adjustment condition when participants had predictor validity information (partial support for H11).</p><p>-Insert <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 5</ref> about here -Dropout <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> displays the validity of participants' predictions and the optimal model validity for predicting dropout. These results are quite different from the results obtained for predicting first-year GPA. Unexpectedly, in the holistic condition, participants who had validity information made less accurate predictions than participants without validity information (r = .18 and r = .25; rdiff = -.07, 95% HDI <ref type="bibr">[-.16, .01]</ref>). In the general weights-and adjustment condition, participants with validity information made similarly accurate predictions as participants without validity information (general: r = .23 and r = .20; rdiff = .03, 95% HDI <ref type="bibr">[-.06, .11]</ref> and adjustment: r = .35 and r = .37; rdiff = -.03, 95% HDI <ref type="bibr">[-.11, .05</ref>], respectively).</p><p>For participants who did not receive predictor validity information, predictive validity decreased from the holistic condition (r = .25) to the general weights condition (r = .20).</p><p>However, the adjustment condition (r = .37) resulted in more accurate predictions than the general weights condition. Furthermore, optimal model predictions (!̅ = .36) were as valid as predictions in the adjustment condition. For participants who received predictor validity information, predictive validity increased from the holistic condition (r = .17) to the general weights condition (r = .23) to the adjustment condition (r = .35). So, support for hypothesis 11 differed depending on whether validity information was provided. We found support for hypothesis 11 when validity information was provided, but inconsistent results when validity information was not provided.</p><p>-Insert <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> about here -</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Averaged General Weights Condition</head><p>If decision makers determine predictor weights in practice, it is likely that multiple decision makers are involved. To resemble this scenario, we also asked participants to report their attitudes towards using weights that are averaged across participants. In contrast to the results from the ranking procedure, these results showed that participants liked the idea to use averaged weights less than using their own weights. Compared to using their own weights, participants experienced less autonomy in an approach where weights would be averaged using averaged weights did not increase predictive validity compared to using participants' own weights when validity information was present (r = .41 and r = .41 for first-year GPA and r = .23 and r = .23 for dropout). When validity information was absent, averaging weights only slightly increased predictive validity (from r = .34 to r = .39 for first-year GPA and from r = .20 to r = .24 for dropout). In sum, using averaged weights resulted in more negative attitudes, but in very similar predictive validity compared to using participants' own weights.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In line with the results from Study 1 and our expectations, participants experienced much more autonomy when making holistic predictions and when using autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures than when using optimal model predictions. Furthermore, as expected, participants perceived less autonomy when restrictedly adjusting optimal model predictions than when freely choosing predictor weights. Like in Study 1, participants were more likely to use autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures compared to using holistic-and optimal model predictions. In terms of validity, presenting participants with validity information only increased validity when choosing predictor weights for predicting first-year GPA, albeit only slightly. So, the unexpectedly high validity in the holistic condition does not seem to be fully explained by the availability of validity information. Furthermore, the expectation that validity would increase from the holistic condition, general weights condition, adjustment condition to the optimal condition (hypothesis 11) was mostly unsupported; we found this pattern for dropout predictions, but only when validity information was available.</p><p>While we did not have an a priori hypothesis, our results suggest that it may be somewhat easier for decision makers to translate validity information into explicit predictor weights than to use this information holistically, although earlier research suggests that validity information also helps when making holistic predictions <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Balzer et al., 1989)</ref>. Our results also showed that predictor validity beliefs were better aligned with actual predictor validities when participants received validity information, which was also reflected in the predictor weights that participants chose (see <ref type="figure">Figure S2</ref>). Interestingly though, even when validity information was present, participants considered the personal statement to be more important for dropout predictions than for first-year GPA predictions. This underscores that, besides criterion-related validity, face validity can play an important role in decision making (also see <ref type="bibr">Kuncel, 2018, p. 475</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>In two studies, we investigated the effect of several autonomy-enhancing features that participants had when making predictions on perceptions and predictive validity. In contrast to expectations, most of our hypotheses were not supported. Yet, in both studies, perceived autonomy was much higher in all autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures than when using optimal model predictions. In line with earlier findings by <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Nolan and Highhouse (2014)</ref> and Dietvorst et al. <ref type="formula">2018</ref>, we found clear evidence that participants preferred choosing their own, consistent (but not applicant-specific) predictor weights and adjusting optimal model predictions over holistic-and optimal model predictions. So, although perceived autonomy was similar for holistic predictions and autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures, use intentions differed between these conditions, suggesting that other factors besides autonomy affect use intentions.</p><p>We found mixed evidence that autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures resulted in higher validity than holistic predictions. In Study 1, only adjusted optimal model predictions of dropout were more valid than holistic predictions. In Study 2, restrictedly adjusting optimal model predictions resulted in slightly higher validity than holistic predictions, as did choosing predictor weights, but only for predicting first-year GPA and only when predictor validity information was available. So, our results tentatively suggest that the tradeoff between autonomy need satisfaction and validity is optimized when decision makers can restrictedly adjust optimal model predictions or choose consistent predictor weights when validity information is available to decision makers.</p><p>In earlier research, choosing predictor weights <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Nolan &amp; Highhouse, 2014</ref>) and adjusting optimal model predictions (Dietvorst et al., 2018) as a means to overcome algorithm aversion have been investigated in separate studies. We investigated both prediction procedures to allow for a comparison in attitudes and validity. Extending earlier research, we showed that use intentions for these two autonomy-enhancing prediction procedures were similar, although ranking the different prediction procedures resulted in a preference for adjusting optimal model predictions. One reason why these results were different may be that we explicitly asked and incentivized participants to rank the prediction procedures according to predictive validity, while the use intentions scale items were generic and did not explicitly ask participants to evaluate the procedures with regard to predictive validity. Aside from predictive validity, decision makers also consider other aspects of selection procedures, such as costs, effort, and fairness <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(König et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Neumann et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Pyburn et al., 2008)</ref>. It may be that decision makers prefer adjusting optimal model predictions when predictive validity is the most important aspect, because they are confident that they can find valid rule exceptions <ref type="bibr">(Dietvorst et al., 2018)</ref>. When also considering other aspects, choosing predictor weights may be preferred because this procedure does not require judging each applicant individually and treats each applicant equally <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Nolan et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Relatedly, results based on the use intentions scale suggested that participants preferred solely using their own weights over the averaged weights procedure. In contrast, results based on the ranking procedure showed that participants had a small preference for the averaged weights procedure over solely using their own weights. This suggests that decision makers may trust 'the wisdom of the crowd' when predictive validity is most important.</p><p>Another explanation for these findings may be that the joint evaluation mode in the ranking task allowed participants to differentiate more easily between prediction procedures than the separate evaluation mode of the use intentions measure <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Hsee &amp; Zhang, 2010)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations and Future Research</head><p>Compared to our student samples, experienced professionals may evaluate prediction procedures such as choosing predictor weights and adjusting optimal model predictions more negatively, as they may feel less need for prediction support <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Arkes et al., 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dawes, 1976</ref>). Therefore, a replication with experienced professionals such admission officers, HR professionals, or clinical psychologists would be very valuable.</p><p>Our choice to use a within-subjects design had advantages and disadvantages. Besides increasing power, it allowed for a joint evaluation of prediction procedures <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Nolan et al., 2020)</ref>. This is most representative of decision making in practice when deciding on what procedure to adopt. Yet, it is plausible that smaller effect sizes would have been observed for our attitudinal measures in a between-subjects design (i.e., in separate evaluation) because prediction procedures could not be easily compared. Furthermore, the within-subjects design required us to vary the stimuli (applicants) between conditions, which resulted in small variations in the optimal model validity. Therefore, validity differences between prediction procedures could be partly due to sampling error variance. Another consequence of our within-subjects design may have been that participants applied the prediction procedure they experienced first also in later conditions, although our results in the supplementary material suggest that the condition order had a negligible effect on participants' behavior. In any case, it should be noted that earlier studies utilized a between-subjects design, which may explain why our results were only partially in line with the results found by <ref type="bibr">Dietvorst et al. (2018)</ref>.</p><p>For these reasons, future studies could use a between-subjects design and the same applicants across conditions. Lastly, in the adjustment condition, participants knew that the regression model predictions did not include the personal statement. Although adding the personal statement ratings as a predictor would have barely changed the model predictions, participants may have adjusted model predictions less if this predictor was included.</p><p>In our studies, we labelled predictors as "good" or "bad" for ease of communication.</p><p>These descriptions were rather unspecific and may explain why decision makers still assigned a non-trivial weight to the personal statement. Therefore, validity information may be presented more specifically and in different formats, such as in the form of suggested percentage predictor weights or even in a narrative manner. Alternatively, in future studies, decision-makers' choice in predictor weights may be restricted to avoid that poor predictors receive a substantial weight. However, restricting the choice of weights or the adjustment of rule predictions requires someone to set these restrictions and to control whether decision makers adhere to it, which may be difficult in practice.</p><p>Researchers are also encouraged to investigate predictive validity of-and decisionmakers' attitudes towards a prediction procedure that combines autonomy in the design of a mechanical rule and in the adjustment of the rule's result. Based on cognitive dissonance theory <ref type="bibr">(Festinger, 1957)</ref>, it may be expected that decision makers are less likely to adjust a rule's prediction when they have designed the rule themselves.</p><p>Moreover, the nature of predictors may influence the effort that is required to process information, which could affect intentions to use certain prediction procedures and how decision makers weight information when making predictions. Therefore, the nature of predictors could be varied in future studies. For example, predictors could be presented quantitatively (e.g., test scores or interview ratings) or qualitatively (e.g., recordings of an interview, written personal statements). Also, researchers may investigate other selection contexts than admission to higher education, and vary the manner in which the criteria are predicted. For example, in personnel selection, decision makers may predict applicants' job performance by classifying them into more general categories (e.g., red, yellow, green; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hoffman et al., 2017)</ref>. When decision makers are restricted in adjusting optimal model predictions, they may experience restrictions on shifts between categories as more consequential than on adjustments to continuous performance predictions.</p><p>Lastly, researchers may investigate how alternative prediction procedures satisfy decision-makers' competence-and relatedness needs. There exists some evidence that competence needs are less satisfied in mechanical prediction, compared to holistic prediction <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Nolan, 2013)</ref> because decision makers cannot demonstrate their assumed expertise in combining information <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Nolan et al., 2016)</ref>. Relatedness needs may be reduced in mechanical prediction because holistic prediction often takes place in group settings <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Bolander &amp; Sandberg, 2013)</ref>. In future research, it could be investigated how relatedness needs are satisfied when decision makers design a mechanical rule in a group setting rather than individually as in our studies. Relatedly, it should be investigated whether stakeholders give more credit to decision makers who use a self-designed, rather than an existing mechanical rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Nolan et al., 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Nolan et al., , 2020</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Practical Recommendations</head><p>Our results suggest that, compared to holistic prediction, slightly more valid predictions were made when decision makers could restrictedly adjust optimal model predictions. This approach requires that an optimal rule is available, which is not always the case in practice. Alternatively, decision makers could choose a consistent set of predictor weights themselves. Yet, when predictors substantially differ in predictive validity, which is often the case in practice, care should be taken that decision makers choose appropriate weights. Our results suggest that one way to support decision makers in designing their own mechanical rules effectively is to provide them with predictor validity information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>One reason for the underutilization of mechanical prediction is that it restricts decision-makers' autonomy in the decision-making process. We contribute to the literature on interventions to promote the use of mechanical prediction in practice <ref type="bibr">(Dietvorst et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Neumann et al., 2020)</ref> by showing that decision makers are much more likely to use mechanical prediction procedures when their autonomy is enhanced by the option to choose their own, consistent predictor weights or to adjust mechanical rule predictions. However, contrary to expectations, we found inconclusive evidence that these autonomy-enhancing mechanical prediction procedures resulted in higher predictive validity than holistic predictions, and the increase in predictive validity was rather small. To close the sciencepractice gap in decision making, more research is needed to identify ways to increase the validity of autonomy-enhancing mechanical prediction procedures.       Note. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Some jittering was added to the plot to improve readability. Validity for the Prediction of Dropout in Study 2</p><p>Note. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attention Checks</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>Participants answered two attention checks. After reading the study instructions, the first attention check required participants to indicate the maximum reward they could earn in the study. The second attention check required participants to indicate for each predictor (high school GPA, admission test score, and personal statement) whether it is a good or bad predictor of study success.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>Participants answered three attention checks. After reading the study instructions, the first attention check required participants to indicate the maximum reward they could earn in the study. For participants who received validity information, the second attention check was the same as in Study 1. Participants who did not receive validity information had to choose which predictor they would not use for making predictions (answer options: mean high school GPA, admission test score, personal statement, sex). The third attention check was administered before participants ranked the prediction procedures and required them to answer by how much their reward earned up to that point would increase if they chose the most valid procedure (correct answer: 20%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions to Participants</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table B1</head><p>Instructions given to Participants in Study 1 per Condition (translated from Dutch to English)</p><p>Condition Instructions</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Holistic</head><p>In this condition, we first ask you to rate a student's personal statement. After you have given your rating, you will see a student's score on the admission test, high school GPA, and your personal statement rating.</p><p>Individual weights In this condition, we first ask you to rate a student's personal statement. After you have given your rating, you will see a student's admission test score, high school GPA, and your personal statement rating. Based on this information, you indicate how you would like to weight the admission test score, high school GPA, and personal statement rating to predict a student's study success. The higher the weight that you assign, the more the information determines your prediction. If you, for example, assign a weight of 33.3% to the admission test score, high school GPA, and the personal statement rating, then your prediction of a student's first-year GPA will be determined with 33.3% by the admission test score, the high school GPA and the personal statement rating, respectively.</p><p>In this condition, you assign weights to the information for each of the five students separately.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General weights</head><p>In this condition, we first ask you to indicate how you would like to weight the information for making predictions. We would like you to indicate how you want to weight the admission test score, high school GPA, and personal statement rating to predict a student's study success. The higher the weight that you assign, the more the information determines your prediction. If you, for example, assign a weight of 33.3% to the admission test score, high school GPA, and the personal statement rating, then your prediction of a student's first-year GPA will be determined with 33.3% by the admission test score, the high school GPA and the personal statement rating, respectively.</p><p>In this condition, you assign weights to the information, which will apply to all five students that you evaluate in this condition.</p><p>After you have done this, you will answer some questions about your thoughts and opinion with regard to this prediction procedure.</p><p>Afterwards, you will rate a student's personal statement, after which you will make predictions for each of the five students separately.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Adjustment</head><p>In this condition, we first ask you to rate a student's personal statement. After you have given your rating, you will see a prediction of the student's study success based on a statistical model. The statistical model is based on the student's high school GPA and admission test score, and applies weights to this information such that the prediction based on this information is as optimal as possible. The personal statement is not taken into account.</p><p>The statistical model is quite accurate in predicting a student's firstyear GPA and chance of dropout in the psychology bachelor</p><p>program. The statistical model most likely gives the best prediction possible, better than a human prediction. The prediction based on this model is not perfect though. You can adjust the model prediction in case you want to do so. If you do not want to adjust the model prediction, you simply indicate the model prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Optimal model</head><p>Imagine that your predictions would be solely determined by the statistical model, and that you could not adjust the model predictions.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Mholistic -Mindividual = 0.03, 95% HDI [-0.10, 0.16], d = 0.05). Similarly, the difference in perceived autonomy between choosing general-and individual weights was negligible (Mindividual -Mgeneral = 0.05, 95% HDI [-0.09, 0.18], d = 0.07). However, participants experienced much less autonomy when using optimal model predictions compared to choosing general weights (Mgeneral -Moptimal = 0.96, 95% HDI [0.84, 1.09], d = 1.18). Furthermore, perceived autonomy in the adjustment condition fell</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>choosing general-rather than individual weights (Mindividual -Mgeneral = -0.42, 95% HDI [-0.58, -0.25], d = -0.54), and also slightly higher for adjusting optimal model predictions than for making holistic predictions (Mholistic -Madjust = -0.19, 95% HDI [-0.35, -0.03], d = -0.24). Although, as expected, using optimal model predictions resulted in the lowest use intentions, the difference was practically indistinguishable (d = 0.05) from the intentions to use individual weights.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>-</head><label></label><figDesc>Insert Figure 3 about hereoptimal = -.09, 95% HDI [-.18, -.01]; General -optimal = -.13, 95% HDI [-.21, -.05]; Adjust -optimal = -.11, 95% HDI [-.20, -.04].8 Correlational differences and 95% HDIs between the validity of participants' predictions and optimal model predictions per condition for dropout: Holistic -optimal = -.20, 95% HDI[-.28, -.10]; Individual -optimal = -.12, 95% HDI[-.22, -.03]; General -optimal = -.12, 95% HDI[-.22, -.03]; Adjust -optimal = -.09, 95% HDI[- .18, -.01].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>not receive predictor validity information 11 . Participants who received validity information considered the predictor high school grade to be more effective (M = 3.97, SD = 0.68) than participants who did not receive validity information (M = 3.67, SD = 0.74, Mdiff = 0.29, 95% HDI [0.09, 0.49], d = 0.41). Validity beliefs regarding the effectiveness of the admission test score were similar for participants who received validity information (M = 4.16, SD = 0.64) and those who did not receive validity information (M = 4.21, SD = 0.76, Mdiff = -0.05, 95% HDI [-0.25, 0.14], d = -0.08). Lastly, participants who received validity information considered the personal statement to be much less effective (M = 2.45, SD = 0.92) than participants who did not receive validity information (M = 3.39, SD = 1.05, Mdiff = -0.92, 95% HDI [-1.21, -0.63], d = -0.95). This shows that predictor validity beliefs were more aligned with actual predictor validities when participants received validity information.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>Mdiff = 0.29, 95% HDI [0.19, 0.39], d = 0.45). We obtained similar results for use intentions (Mdiff = 0.20, 95% HDI [0.09, 0.31], d = 0.29), confidence (Mdiff = 0.18, 95% HDI [0.06, 0.29], d = 0.25), and satisfaction (Mdiff = 0.22, 95% HDI [0.11, 0.33], d = 0.32). Furthermore,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Observed Means (Descriptives) for all Conditions per Attitude Measure in Study 1 Note. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Some jittering was added to the plot to improve readability.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 2 Figure 3</head><label>23</label><figDesc>Validity for the Prediction of First-year GPA in Study 1 Note. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. DECISION-MAKING IN SELECTION 57 Validity for the Prediction of Dropout in Study 1 Note. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Observed Means (Descriptives) for all Conditions per Attitude Measure in Study 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Validity for the Prediction of First-year GPA in Study 2Note. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Means and Standard Deviations per Condition and Attitudinal Measure in Study 1</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Perceived autonomy Use intentions</cell><cell cols="2">Confidence</cell><cell cols="2">Satisfaction</cell></row><row><cell>Condition</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>SD</cell></row><row><cell>Holistic</cell><cell>3.43</cell><cell>0.57</cell><cell>2.98</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>3.11</cell><cell>0.67</cell><cell>3.30</cell><cell>0.73</cell></row><row><cell>Individual</cell><cell>3.40</cell><cell>0.63</cell><cell>2.80</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>3.01</cell><cell>0.75</cell><cell>3.13</cell><cell>0.81</cell></row><row><cell>General</cell><cell>3.36</cell><cell>0.65</cell><cell>3.20</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>3.33</cell><cell>0.69</cell><cell>3.45</cell><cell>0.68</cell></row><row><cell>Adjust</cell><cell>3.21</cell><cell>0.64</cell><cell>3.17</cell><cell>0.80</cell><cell>3.37</cell><cell>0.69</cell><cell>3.41</cell><cell>0.73</cell></row><row><cell>Optimal</cell><cell>2.39</cell><cell>0.95</cell><cell>2.76</cell><cell>0.94</cell><cell>3.13</cell><cell>0.90</cell><cell>2.99</cell><cell>1.00</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Correlations between Attitudinal Measures Autonomy, Use Intentions, Confidence, and</figDesc><table><row><cell>Satisfaction in Study 1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Measure</cell><cell>Autonomy</cell><cell>Use intentions</cell><cell>Confidence</cell><cell>Satisfaction</cell></row><row><cell>Autonomy</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Use intentions</cell><cell>.33*</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Confidence</cell><cell>.27*</cell><cell>.63*</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Satisfaction</cell><cell>.40*</cell><cell>.70*</cell><cell>.66*</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Note. Correlations were averaged across conditions using Fisher's z transformation.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Correlations between attitudinal measures per condition are reported in the supplementary</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">material in Table S1. * p &lt; .05.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Mean Rank per Condition and Rank Frequencies in Study 1 and Study 2</figDesc><table><row><cell>Study</cell><cell>Condition</cell><cell>Mean rank</cell><cell>Rank 1</cell><cell>Rank 2</cell><cell>Rank 3</cell><cell>Rank 4</cell><cell>Rank 5</cell></row><row><cell>Study 1</cell><cell>Holistic</cell><cell>3.53</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>27</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>50</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Individual</cell><cell>3.13</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>37</cell><cell>44</cell><cell>20</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>General</cell><cell>3.11</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>31</cell><cell>47</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>24</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Adjust</cell><cell>1.99</cell><cell>84</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>7</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Optimal</cell><cell>3.23</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>40</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>49</cell></row><row><cell>Study 2</cell><cell>Holistic</cell><cell>3.75</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>82</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>General</cell><cell>3.14</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>43</cell><cell>62</cell><cell>25</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>General averaged</cell><cell>2.70</cell><cell>36</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>59</cell><cell>29</cell><cell>18</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Adjust</cell><cell>2.15</cell><cell>84</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>25</cell><cell>27</cell><cell>11</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Optimal</cell><cell>3.27</cell><cell>27</cell><cell>43</cell><cell>30</cell><cell>36</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Means and Standard Deviations per Condition and Attitudinal Measure in Study 2 Correlations between Attitudinal Measures Autonomy, Use Intentions, Confidence, and Satisfaction in Study 2Note. Correlations were averaged across conditions using Fisher's z transformation.Correlations between attitudinal measures per condition are reported in the supplementary material inTable S3. * p &lt; .05.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Perceived autonomy Use intentions</cell><cell cols="2">Confidence</cell><cell cols="2">Satisfaction</cell></row><row><cell>Condition</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>SD</cell></row><row><cell>Holistic</cell><cell>3.65</cell><cell>0.70</cell><cell>2.97</cell><cell>0.80</cell><cell>3.15</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>3.29</cell><cell>0.82</cell></row><row><cell>General</cell><cell>3.65</cell><cell>0.61</cell><cell>3.37</cell><cell>0.73</cell><cell>3.51</cell><cell>0.73</cell><cell>3.56</cell><cell>0.71</cell></row><row><cell>Adjust</cell><cell>3.40</cell><cell>0.61</cell><cell>3.20</cell><cell>0.81</cell><cell>3.47</cell><cell>0.77</cell><cell>3.52</cell><cell>0.79</cell></row><row><cell>Optimal</cell><cell>2.61</cell><cell>0.90</cell><cell>2.72</cell><cell>0.87</cell><cell>3.08</cell><cell>0.79</cell><cell>2.96</cell><cell>0.97</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">We checked for order effects for predictive validity. The order of conditions had a negligible effect on participants' behavior and differences in predictive validity were in the opposite direction of expectations. We present the results in the supplementary material (Section S2).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">We also ran the ANOVAs with the between-subjects factor included. The main effect for the between-subjects factor and the interaction effect showed negligible effect sizes (η 2 ps ≤ .014).</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A</head><p>Appendix B</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The meta-analysis of clinical judgment project: Fifty-six years of accumulated research on clinical versus statistical prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aegisdóttir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Spengler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Maugherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Lampropoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rush</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0011000005285875</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0011000005285875" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Counseling Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="382" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Being an advocate for linear models of judgment is not an easy life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Arkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rationality and social responsibility: Essays in honor of Robyn Mason Dawes</title>
		<editor>I. Krueger</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="70" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factors influencing the use of a decision rule in a probabilistic task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Arkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dawes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0749-5978</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0749-5978" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90046" to="90050" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of cognitive feedback on performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Balzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-2909.106.3.410</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.106.3.410" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="410" to="433" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian perspectives on multiple comparisons</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Berry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hochberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Planning and Inference</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0378-3758(99)00044-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0378-3758(99)00044-0" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The usefulness of unit weights in creating composite scores: A literature review, application to content validity, and metaanalysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bobko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Buster</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="689" to="709" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1094428106294734</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1094428106294734" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How employee selection decisions are made in practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bolander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sandberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0170840612464757</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840612464757" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organization Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="311" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A systematic review of algorithm aversion in augmented decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Burton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Jensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinical-Statistical Controversy. Psychology, Public Policy, and Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/1076-8971.2.2.293</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/1076-8971.2.2.293" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clinical versus mechanical prediction: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Grove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Zald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lebow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Snitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/1040-3590.12.1.19</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/1040-3590.12.1.19" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Broken legs, clinical overrides, and recidivism risk: An analysis of decisions to adjust risk levels with the LS/CMI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Guay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Parent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0093854817719482</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0093854817719482" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Criminal Justice and Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The accuracy of recidivism risk assessments for sexual offenders: A meta-analysis of 118 prediction studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Morton-Bourgon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0014421</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0014421" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stubborn reliance on intuition and subjectivity in employee selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Highhouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1754-9434.2008.00058.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1754-9434.2008.00058.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Industrial and Organizational Psychology: Perspectives on Science and Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="342" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is a .51 validity coefficient good? Value sensitivity for interview validity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Highhouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Brooks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nesnidol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/ijsa.12192</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/ijsa.12192" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Selection and Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discretion in hiring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/qje/qjx042</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/qje/qjx042" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="765" to="800" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinction bias: Misprediction and mischoice due to joint evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="680" to="695" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.86.5.680</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.86.5.680" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">General evaluability theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691610374586</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691610374586" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of predictive ability information, locus of control, and decision maker involvement on decision aid reliance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Reneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Whitecotton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/1099-0771</idno>
		<idno>1&lt;35::AID-BDM364&gt;3.0.CO;2-D</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/1099-0771" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="200101" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determinants of linear judgment: A meta-analysis of lens model studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Karelaia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hogarth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="404" to="426" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-2909.134.3.404</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.134.3.404" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overconfidence in personnel selection: When and why unstructured interview information can hurt hiring decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kausel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Culbertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Madrid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.obhdp.2016.07.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.obhdp.2016.07.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transforming admissions: The gateway to medicine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kirch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAMA: Journal of the American Medical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">308</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2250" to="2251" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1001/jama.2012.74126</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2012.74126" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reasons for being selective when choosing personnel selection procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>König</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Klehe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Berchtold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kleinmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1468-2389.2010.00485.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-2389.2010.00485.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Selection and Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian assessment of null values via parameter estimation and model comparison</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691611406925</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691611406925" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Doing Bayesian data analysis: A tutorial with</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jags</forename><surname>; R</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-0-12-405888-0.09999-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-405888-0.09999-2" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The time has come: Bayesian methods for data analysis in the organizational sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Aguinis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Joo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1094428112457829</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1094428112457829" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="722" to="752" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Bayesian new statistics: Hypothesis testing, estimation, meta-analysis, and power analysis from a Bayesian perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Liddell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-016-1221-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-016-1221-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin and Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="178" to="206" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Judgment and decision making in staffing research and practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kuncel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The sage handbook of industrial, work and organizational psychology</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4135/9781473914940</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.4135/9781473914940" />
		<editor>S. Ones, N. Anderson, C. Viswesvaran, &amp; H. K. Sinangil</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>SAGE Publications Ltd</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="487" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mechanical versus clinical data combination in selection and admissions decisions: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kuncel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Klieger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Connelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0034156</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0034156" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1060" to="1072" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resistance to medical artificial intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Longoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bonezzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Morewedge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="650" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">OPINION: Tests are not the problem; how they are used can be</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://hechingerreport.org/opinion-tests-are-not-the-problem-how-they-are-used-can-be/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Empirical comparisons of clinical and actuarial prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Meehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>P. E</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Clinical versus statistical prediction: A theoretical analysis and a review of the evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Meehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>University of Minnesota Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/11281-008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/doi:10.1037/11281-008" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The special powers of the clinician. In Clinical versus statistical prediction: A theoretical analysis and a review of the evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Meehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/11281-004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/11281-004" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
			<publisher>University of Minnesota Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Continued misinterpretation of confidence intervals: Response to Miller and Ulrich</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Morey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hoekstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rouder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-015-0955-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-015-0955-8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subject matter expert judgments regarding the relative importance of competencies are not useful for choosing the test batteries that best predict performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Deckert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kinney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Kung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/ijsa.12051</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/ijsa.12051" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Selection and Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The predictive power of personal statements in admissions: A meta-analysis and cautionary tale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Klieger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Borneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kuncel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="86" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>College and University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Neumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hengeveld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S M</forename><surname>Niessen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tendeiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Meijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Education increases decision-rule use: An investigation of education and incentives to improve decision making</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xap0000372</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xap0000372" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied. Advance Online Publication</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implementing evidence-based assessment and selection in organizations: A review and an agenda for future research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Neumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S M</forename><surname>Niessen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Meijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<publisher>Advance Online Publication</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/2041386620983419</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/2041386620983419" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When eliminating bias isn&apos;t fair: Algorithmic reductionism and procedural justice in human resource decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Harmon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">160</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.obhdp.2020.03.008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.obhdp.2020.03.008" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Admission testing for higher education: A multi-cohort study on the validity of high-fidelity curriculum-sampling tests</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S M</forename><surname>Niessen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Meijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tendeiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0198746</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0198746" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Article e0198746</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Basic psychological need fulfillment and user resistance to objective and analytical decision-making practices in employee selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Nolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Doctoral dissertation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Threat of technological unemployment: Are hiring managers discounted for using standardized employee selection practices?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Nolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dalal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personnel Assessment and Decisions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.25035/pad.2016.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.25035/pad.2016.004" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Threat of technological unemployment, use intentions, and the promotion of structured interviews in personnel selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Nolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dalal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personnel Assessment and Decisions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.25035/pad.2020.02.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.25035/pad.2020.02.006" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Need for autonomy and resistance to standardized employee selection practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Nolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Highhouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="328" to="346" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/08959285.2014.929691</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/08959285.2014.929691" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relative influence of advice from human experts and statistical methods on forecast adjustments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Önkal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Goodwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gönül</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pollock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="390" to="409" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.637</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.637" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diversity-validity dilemma: Overview and legal context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M J</forename><surname>Pyburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Ployhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kravitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personnel Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1744-6570.2008.00108.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1744-6570.2008.00108.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trends in testing: Highlights of a global survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Inceoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bartram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Golubovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Grand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Reeder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Derous</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Nikolaou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>I</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Employee recruitment, selection, and assessment: Contemporary issues for theory and practice</title>
		<editor>Nikolaou &amp; J. Oostrom</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="153" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of individual assessment practices by I/O psychologists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sackett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personnel Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="488" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1744-6570.1987.tb00610.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1744-6570.1987.tb00610.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The research-practice gap in I/O psychology and related fields: Challenges and potential solutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Oxford handbook of organizational psychology</title>
		<editor>S. W. J. Kozlowski</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="452" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HR professionals&apos; beliefs about effective human resource practices: Correspondence between research and practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Colbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/hrm.10029</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/hrm.10029" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Resource Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personnel selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sackett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lievens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev.psych.59.103006.093716</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.59.103006.093716" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="450" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A contribution to the study of actuarial and individual methods of prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sarbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="593" to="602" />
			<date type="published" when="1943" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1086/219248</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1086/219248" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measurement and prediction, clinical and statistical</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sawyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0023624</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0023624" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="178" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The meaningfulness of effect sizes in psychological research: Differences between sub-disciplines and the impact of potential biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schäfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2019.00813</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.00813" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The recalcitrance of overconfidence and its contribution to decision aid neglect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sieck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Arkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.486</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.486" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">RWA web: A free, comprehensive, web-based, and user-friendly tool for relative weight analyses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tonidandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10869-014-9351-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10869-014-9351-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business and Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgment under uncertainty: Heuristics and biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.185.4157.1124</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.185.4157.1124" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">185</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1124" to="1131" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Survey on the use of clinical and mechanical prediction methods in clinical psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Vrieze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Grove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0014693</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0014693" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Professional Psychology: Research and Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="525" to="531" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A practical solution to the pervasive problems of p values</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03194105</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03194105" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="779" to="804" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moving to a world beyond</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wasserstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Schirm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>p &lt; 0.05</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Statistician</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">sup1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00031305.2019.1583913</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/00031305.2019.1583913" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pushing the limits for judgmental consistency: Comparing random weighting schemes with expert judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kuncel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personnel Assessment and Decisions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
