<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Thinking Beyond RV CN : Addressing the Complexity of Replication Target Selection</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Merle-Marie</forename><surname>Pittelkow</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">QUEST Center for Responsible Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Berlin Institute of Health at Charité -Universitätsmedizin Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sarahanne</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Field</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Pedagogy</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Behavioral and Social Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Groningen</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Groningen</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Don</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychometrics and Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Behavioral and Social Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Groningen</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Groningen</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Thinking Beyond RV CN : Addressing the Complexity of Replication Target Selection</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:54+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Isager, van &apos;t Veer and Lakens (2021) proposed a quantitative operationalization of replication value (denoted RVCN), using average yearly citation count and sample size as proxies for value and uncertainty, respectively. In this commentary, we suggest that the approach of Isager et al., while a good theoretical departure point, oversimplifies the complex decision-making process that underpins replication target selection in practice. We present what we view as some issues with RVCN, notably the use of citation count and ambiguity as to whether RVCN is prescriptive or descriptive. We also present preliminary empirical evidence that RVCN diverges on its performance as a replication target selection method, compared with existing selection methods (such as those published by us in the past). We conclude with the recommendation that going forward, approaches should emphasize the multifaceted nature of replication target selection to maximize their practical utility. Note: This paper has been accepted by Meta-Psychology and will be published after reproducibility check and copy-editing.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> <ref type="bibr">Isager, van 't Veer, and Lakens (2021)</ref> <p>[IVL21] put forth a proposal to quantify replication value. Replication value, denoted as RVCN, is calculated as the product of the average yearly citation count of a given article in which the original effect was reported (value) and the sample size used to investigate the original study <ref type="bibr">(uncertainty)</ref>. The authors further suggest that replication targets should be identified using a four-step selection procedure including: (1) curation of an initial set of candidate studies, (2) calculation of RVCN for the candidate studies, (3) in-depth evaluation of the subset of studies with the highest RVCN, and (4) selection of the most suitable candidate based on RVCN and the in-depth evaluation.</p><p>We agree with the notion that replication value is best thought of as a function of value and uncertainty. However, we view the proposal of IVL21 as a starting point for a much-needed expert discussion about the conceptualization and potential quantification of replication value as well as other assessment strategies for replication targets. In this commentary, we identify what we believe to be some issues with RVCN before comparing it to our own selection procedures <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Field et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Pittelkow et al., 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Pittelkow et al., , 2023</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RVCN fails to capture the complexity of replication target selection in practice</head><p>Our primary point of critique is that the conceptualization of what makes up value and uncertainty, operationalized by just one measure each, oversimplifies the multifaceted approach typically employed in practice for choosing replication targets. Results from surveying researchers who have conducted, or plan to conduct a replication suggest that they typically consider additional aspects such as feasibility and methodology when deciding what to replicate <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Pittelkow et al., 2023)</ref>. Feasibility, while not related to the concepts of value and uncertainty, is considered very important by replicating authors because replication is only possible when the necessary resources (e.g., money, time, staff, expertise) are available. (In-)appropriate methodology informs both value and uncertainty. Although IVL21 refer to additional qualitative assessments for studies with the largest RVCN, we argue that it is premature to speak of the formula as assessing replication value without including these important additional concepts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>It is unclear whether RVCN is prescriptive or descriptive</head><p>An overarching question central to the utility of measures such as RVCN is whether it is meant to be prescriptive (what ought to be selected) or descriptive (what is selected in practice). The first half of the article by IVL21 suggests RVCN is prescriptive, as the aim of the article is to develop a measurement model of a study selection metric aiming to maximize the expected utility gain of a single replication. From the section "Preliminary validation […] studies" on, the distinction between RVCN as a prescriptive and descriptive measure becomes murkier. In this section, the authors propose validating the RVCN metric by correlating actual study selection behaviour with what RVCN suggests researchers should have selected. In our assessment, this correlation only makes sense when evaluating RVCN as a descriptive measure. If researchers already select studies with the largest utility gain for replication, there would be no need for a measure like RVCN. Our own work suggests that replication study selection in practice is often content-driven (e.g., based on interest) and not utility-based <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Pittelkow et al., 2023)</ref>. Thus, we argue that the preliminary validation strategy of correlating RVCN to actual replication behaviour is unlikely to be particularly informative.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Indicators depend on their specification</head><p>Citation count is an imperfect indicator of scientific value. As the authors mention in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, there are many reasons why articles might get cited that have little to do with the scientific value of an article, such as studies which have had a lot of social media attention for being novel or controversial (and not necessarily reliable or valid). Examples include scandals surrounding the authors, methodological flaws, or citation practices (self-citations by authors or by journals, and citation bias). Citation counts also vary considerably between scientific subfields <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Patience et al., 2017)</ref> making RVCN unsuitable for assessments or comparisons across fields.</p><p>Every metric has faults, but accepting the premise that citation count might possess some utility as a metric for scientific value, we turn to the specific version the authors use in their preliminary validation, which closely follows the predicted citation count of articles as described in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2A</ref> of IVL21 (i.e., a uniform distribution). The authors acknowledge that the actual trajectory of citations through time might be better approximated by <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2B</ref> of IVL21 (i.e., a gamma distribution). We agree with this observation and to assess robustness of the chosen distribution for predicting citation count, we have redone the preliminary validation of IVL21, using their parametrization of the gamma distribution instead 1 . To this end, we adjusted the citation counts by assuming x is gamma distributed with a shape parameter of 2 and a rate parameter of 0.8. Parameter x is defined as years since publication + 1 divided by 5 (see IVL21). This distribution produces a corrected citation count accounting for the expected increase in citations over time thus normalizing the citation count in relation to the age of the publication (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1B)</ref>. This impacted the values of RVCN leading to less overlap between RVCN values for replicated and non-replicated studies (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> panel D). This demonstrates the dependency of RVCN on the distributional assumptions for citation count and underscores the need for follow-up work on the best way to quantify 'value'.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The suitability of the validation data set is unclear.</head><p>Good validation is key to establish that RVCN is a useful measure of replication value. However, we contend that the authors' validation strategy falls short of demonstrating their indicator's effectiveness in measuring the target feature. While doing manual checks for our re-analysis of the results we realised that the Psychological Bulletin dataset relied on data reported in meta-analysis. These effects encompass not only primary outcomes from original studies but also secondary outcomes and results from additional analyses based on internally shared data. We argue that a study's replication value should be determined primarily by the effects considered in the original study. We believe it typically makes sense to focus on the main effect because it reflects the most accessible and transparent information for potential replication authors, as well as usually being the most central claim of a study. While a comprehensive manual check of the validation dataset to determine the proportion of non-primary effects is beyond the scope of this commentary, we question the dataset's suitability for validating replication values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Comparison of RVCN to previous suggestions</head><p>In this section, we compare RVCN to replication target selection procedures outlined in our earlier publications <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Field et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Pittelkow et al., 2021)</ref>. A full description of these procedures is beyond the scope of this commentary. Briefly, we proposed that studies with uncertain evidence are in greater need of corroboration than studies with strong evidence either for or against a particular effect. To quantify this uncertainty, we advocated for the use of Bayes Factors (BFs), which assess the relative strength of evidence supporting two competing hypotheses, thereby providing a quantitative and continuous measure of uncertainty. Studies identified as having ambiguous evidence were subsequently assessed based on qualitative criteria, as illustrated in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> and recommendations for possible replication targets were made. Following these projects, we conducted a large-scale initiative involving a survey and a Delphi consensus method to develop a comprehensive set of qualitative criteria (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table  1</ref>) for replication target selection in practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Pittelkow et al., 2023)</ref>.</p><p>Our assessment of the proposal by IVL21 is that RVCN acts as a filter to make a preselection based on a set of candidate studies. As such it resembles the function of the Bayes Factor (BF) 2 as described in our earlier publications <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Field et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Pittelkow et al., 2021)</ref>.We therefore decided to compare the performance of RVCN to the BF and the results of <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Field et al. (2019)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Pittelkow et al. (2023)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Field et al. (2019)</ref> extracted data for 57 results from 30 Psychological Science articles published between 2015-2016, that reported significant statistical tests (one-sample, paired, and independent t-tests), associated with primary research questions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Pittelkow et al. (2021)</ref> extracted data for 97 results from 78 articles published in the Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology published between 2012 and 2016, which supported their primary outcome by a statistically significant t-test. We had previously extracted the sample size. To calculate RVCN we collected additional data on citation count from Crossref on January 16 th 2025 following the method proposed by IVL21. Importantly, our data includes information from additional qualitative analyses assessing the value of the replication targets. If RVCN captures 'replication value', the studies identified by qualitative assessment should also present relatively larger RVCN values. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> presents the results of our re-analysis.  There was no clear relationship between RVCN and BFs (rField = -0.09, rPittelkow = -0.12), suggesting that the two measures capture distinct aspects of replication value. Furthermore, RVCN scores did not differ between studies identified as replication targets through qualitative assessment and those that did not (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>). For the dataset from <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Field et al. (2019)</ref>, RVCN values were even lower for studies suggested as replication targets compared to those not identified as replication targets. This implies that potentially important replication targets might be prematurely excluded from consideration based solely on RVCN scores. However, this does not mean that these studies are unsuitable replication targets. Every selection procedure has its strengths and limitations, but the minimal overlap between our qualitative suggestions and RVCN -based selections, particularly in the <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Field et al. (2019)</ref> dataset, begs the question of why two different selection procedures come to such different conclusions. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Distribution of overall citation count and RVCN in the comparison sample of psychological findings (red) and the sample of replicated findings in psychology (blue).Following IVL21, the scale in all plots has been transformed by taking the cube root of the true values, which preserves the overall shape of the distribution but compresses the scale towards 1.(A) Overall citation count as reported in IVL21. (B) Overall citation count as estimated based on the gamma distribution. (C) RVCN as reported by IVL21 (D) RVCN based on total predicted citation count based on the gamma parameterization as specified by IVL21 in</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Scatterplots plotting replication value (RVcn) against Bayes Factors (BF).BFs are presented on a reversed log 10 scale. The dotted lines indicate BF = 1 and BF = 3. We excluded very largeBFs and RVcns (BF&gt; 10^10; RVcn &gt; 10).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Qualitative criteria proposed in previous work. Please note that this is not a row-by-row comparison but a listing of the different criteria; OS = original study equivalent to original claim.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Field et al. 2019</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Pittelkow et al. 2021</cell><cell></cell><cell>Pittelkow et al. (2023)</cell></row><row><cell>relevance</cell><cell cols="2">relevance clinical</cell><cell>interventional study</cell><cell>interest</cell><cell>relevance of the OS for your current line of</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>relevance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>research or the field you work in</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>clinical sample</cell><cell>doubt</cell><cell>current strength of evidence in favour of the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>OS</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>severity of the condition</cell><cell></cell><cell>the (un)clarity and (un)replicability of the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>original protocol</cell></row><row><cell>insufficient</cell><cell></cell><cell>scientific</cell><cell>evidence base</cell><cell>impact</cell><cell>the importance of the OS for research</cell></row><row><cell>investigation</cell><cell></cell><cell>relevance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>theoretical</cell><cell>quality</cell><cell>theory</cell><cell>scientific background</cell><cell></cell><cell>the theoretical relevance of the OS</cell></row><row><cell>importance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>sound</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>clear rational</cell><cell></cell><cell>implications of the OS (e.g. for practice,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>policy or clinical work).</cell></row><row><cell>methodology</cell><cell></cell><cell>methodology</cell><cell>CONSORT criteria</cell><cell cols="2">methodology sample size</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>statistical method</cell><cell></cell><cell>flaws of the OS</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>appropriate</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>interpretation</cell><cell>interpretation and</cell><cell></cell><cell>operationalization of the OS's measures</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>conclusion follow logically</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>generalizability</cell><cell></cell><cell>concerns about questionable research</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>practices</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>robustness</cell><cell></cell><cell>generalizability of the OS</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>feasibility</cell><cell>the resources available for replicating the OS</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>the replicating team's presence or absence</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>of previous experience or expertise on the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>OS</cell></row><row><cell>Note:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Average RVCN scores for studies suggested and not suggested as replication targets based on previous analyses.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">While this exact parametrization is to some extent arbitrary, we agree with the authors that "Figure 2Bdisplays a more realistic 50-year citation trajectory (Parolo et al., 2015)".</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">In contrast to RVCN , the BF is used as a function of uncertainty only.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Replication</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Concluding remarks</head><p>We hope that this commentary can provide some nuance and multidimensionality to the perspective of IVL21. While their approach to assessing replication values facilitates the evaluation of large sets of potential targets, it risks oversimplifying a complex reality. However, we believe the IVL21 approach provides a systematic starting point that is preferable to having no structured methodology at all. Simplification by quantitative approximation does carry risks, but these need to be weighed against the practical benefits of transparent and systematic approximations.</p><p>Still, we argue that failing to emphasize the complexity of replication target selection may compromise the utility of their method. Although we have previously proposed partially quantitative methods ourselves, our recent work has shifted towards more qualitative and open approaches for describing replication value, exemplified by the checklist for transparent replication target selection (for more details please review <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Pittelkow et al. 2023)</ref>. We contend that such flexible methodologies offer greater practical utility in the nuanced landscape of replication research. At the same time, we caution against definitive conclusions about the superiority of any one method in capturing replication value. By continuing to assess these approaches critically, we can refine strategies for replication target selection.</p><p>Data availability: The data and code that support the findings of this study are openly available on the Open Science Framework (OSF) at [https://osf.io/hnsry/; DOI 10.17605/OSF.IO/HNSRY]</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conflict of Interest:</head><p>The authors declare no conflict of interests.</p><p>Funding: This research did not receive any specific grant from funding agencies in the public, commercial, or not-for-profit sectors. </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">When and Why to Replicate: As Easy as 1, 2, 3? Collabra: Psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Field</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hoekstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bringmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1525/collabra.218</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1525/collabra.218" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deciding what to replicate: A decision model for replication study selection under resource and knowledge constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Isager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C M</forename><surname>Van Aert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Š</forename><surname>Bahník</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Desoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Giner-Sorolla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Krueger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Perugini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ropovik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Veer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vranka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lakens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/met0000438</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/met0000438" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Replication value as a function of citation impact and sample size</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Isager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Veer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lakens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31222/osf.io/knjea</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/knjea" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Citation analysis of scientific categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Patience</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Patience</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Blais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bertrand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.heliyon.2017.e00300</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2017.e00300" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Heliyon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The process of replication target selection in psychology: What to consider</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-M</forename><surname>Pittelkow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Field</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Isager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Veer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Dominik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Giner-Sorolla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Heyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jekel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Luke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Peels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pendrous</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sarrazin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Schauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Specker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rsos.210586</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.210586" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Royal Society Open Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">210586</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Replication target selection in clinical psychology: A Bayesian and qualitative reevaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-M</forename><surname>Pittelkow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hoekstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Karsten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/CPS0000013</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/CPS0000013" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinical Psychology: Science and Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="210" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
