<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">COVID-Dynamic: A large-scale multifaceted longitudinal study of socioemotional and behavioral change across the pandemic Authors</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1498">1498 1391 1282 1178 1165 1046</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tessa</forename><surname>Rusch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Humanities and Social Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">California Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Pasadena</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanting</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Biology and Biological Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">California Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Pasadena</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dehua</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Interdisciplinary Brain and Behavioral Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Crean College of Health and Behavioral Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Schmid College of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Chapman University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Orange</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amber</forename><surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Interdisciplinary Brain and Behavioral Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Crean College of Health and Behavioral Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Schmid College of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Chapman University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Orange</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Yale Law School</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>New Haven</settlement>
									<region>CT</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uri</forename><surname>Maoz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Biology and Biological Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">California Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Pasadena</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Interdisciplinary Brain and Behavioral Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Crean College of Health and Behavioral Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Schmid College of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Chapman University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Orange</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lynn</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Paul</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Humanities and Social Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">California Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Pasadena</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Damian</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Stanley</surname></persName>
							<email>dstanley@adelphi.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Derner School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Adelphi University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1 South Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>11530</postCode>
									<settlement>Garden City</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<address>
									<addrLine>4 5 6 7 8 9 11 12 13 15 16</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Beck Depression Inventory -II Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department">Iowa Personality Disorder Screen 24</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>25</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">COVID-Dynamic: A large-scale multifaceted longitudinal study of socioemotional and behavioral change across the pandemic Authors</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1498">1498 1391 1282 1178 1165 1046</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:56+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Alcohol</term>
					<term>Smoking</term>
					<term>Substance Involvement Screening Test 15</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The COVID-19 pandemic is a catastrophe that has caused societal upheaval globally. In the US, it triggered an economic shock and laid bare societal inequities. However, it also afforded a unique opportunity to elucidate the dynamics of psychosocial processes during extreme and volatile conditions. From April 2020 through January 2021, we conducted a within-participant longitudinal study-in 16 waves-to capture the COVID-19 experiences of &gt;1000 US residents, together with curated, external data to contextualize participants&apos; responses. Each hour-long wave combined standard psychological assessments with surveys of emotion, social/political/moral attitudes, COVID-19-related behaviors, and tasks assessing implicit attitudes and social decision-making. Here we characterize the sample, assess data quality, and showcase examples to demonstrate the promise of this dataset, which is intended to be a resource for researchers interested in a multitude of psychological questions, as well as clinicians and policy makers looking to mitigate the psychological effects of future calamities. Significance Statement In the coming years, much will come to light about the impacts of the personal, social, economic, and public-health challenges of 2020. Given that human memory is fallible, it is critical to record the psychological and social experiences of individuals, in real-time, during periods of high societal volatility. Here we introduce, describe, and assess the COVID-Dynamic dataset, a rich collection of within-participant longitudinal data that captures the psychological states, personality traits, attitudes, beliefs, and behaviors of more than 1000 US residents from April 2020 to January 2021. These data constitute a unique resource for scientists interested in both COVID-19-specific research questions and basic psychological phenomena, as well as policymakers interested in how we might do better in future disasters.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>The COVID-19 pandemic has been a devastating and ubiquitous global catastrophe. As of early 2021, ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>) the pandemic had triggered tremendous societal upheaval in the United States with over 400,000 COVID-19-related deaths, an economic downturn not seen since the Great Depression <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2</ref> and prolonged social-isolation, the detrimental effects of which will take years to understand. In mid-March of 2020, it was already clear that the societal effects of COVID-19 would be extreme, idiosyncratic, and highly dynamic, providing a unique opportunity to better understand the human psychological response to crisis. To capture this psychological moment in extensive detail, we developed the COVID-Dynamic longitudinal study (www.coviddynamic.caltech.edu): a multifaceted set of survey-and task-based measures <ref type="table">(Table 1</ref>; see also https://osf.io/sb6qx for pre-registration), designed to characterize and quantify the dynamics of psychological, emotional, moral, attitudinal, and behavioral change over the COVID-19 pandemic. We were motivated by the following specific goals:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1)</head><p>Characterizing within-participant psychological dynamics. To what extent do individual characteristics (e.g., states, traits, attitudes, etc.) change in the face of severe environmental stress? This question has clear clinical relevance and also addresses more basic questions about the stability of psychological characteristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2)</head><p>Breadth of assessment. It was clear that, in addition to mental health, the pandemic would impact many other aspects of personal and social life in an unpredictable manner. Therefore, we were inclusive in our selection of measures. We assessed mental and physical health, behavior, personality, emotion, racial and political attitudes (implicit and explicit), social and moral decision-making, along with demographic detail, and more (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). To situate these data in context, we compiled a variety of state-and county-level measures (e.g., COVID-19-and restriction-related metrics, unemployment numbers, antiracism-protest counts).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3)</head><p>Methodological diversity. Recent work <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">3</ref> highlights the importance of methodological diversity for psychological studies. We therefore balanced standardized self-report psychological measures (clinical and basic), with novel targeted surveys, implicit measures, consequential social decision-making tasks, free response measures, and behavioral reports. As such, the dataset also provides a rare opportunity to explore within-subject differences related to measurement modality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4)</head><p>Sample representativeness. We tailored the survey recruitment to balance logistical feasibility with the goal of enrolling a representative sample. Recruitment was limited to the United States to optimize sampling density across geographic areas given funding constraints and researcher sensitivity to societal context. Recognizing that an exact representative sample was unattainable, we conducted a thorough audit of biases in our sample and calculated 'raking' weights, a post-stratification method to 'correct' for biases in sample demographics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5)</head><p>Rigor, Transparency, and Open Science. We strongly value scientific rigor, openness, and transparency. Extensive data quality metrics obtained during and after data collection are provided alongside the raw data. All materials pertaining to the study are archived with the study preregistration (https://osf.io/sb6qx). Because urgency rendered full preregistration of specific hypotheses impossible, we implemented a formal system to propose and register analyses prior to data access (see https://osf.io/sb6qx). Finally, after a 1-year period of embargo, these data will be publicly available.</p><p>The resulting COVID-Dynamic dataset is a unique, exceptionally rich, and inclusive longitudinal inventory ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2</ref>) of the psychological, emotional, moral, attitudinal, and behavioral changes, as well as the personal experiences, of a large (1000+) cohort of U.S. residents from all 50 states during this unparalleled time. Here we describe the study design and methodology, detail the demographic composition of the sample, assess data quality, and characterize participant loss. We also showcase example data to demonstrate the promise of the dataset <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figure 4</ref>; and http://coviddynamicdash.caltech.edu/shiny/coviddash/). These data will greatly improve our understanding of how traits, states, attitudes, beliefs, and behaviors are influenced by a year of profound individual, societal, and global events, and will be a valuable resource for researchers, clinicians, and policymakers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1: Timeline of Real-World Events and COVID-Dynamic Wave Administrations.</head><p>Visualization of the COVID-Dynamic data collection schedule in the context of the events of January 2020 to January 2021. Orange triangles denote each wave administration (black tick marks depict weekly intervals). The gray curve indicates the daily 7-day average of new, confirmed COVID-19 cases in the U.S. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">4</ref> , black encircled X's on top of the curve mark grim U.S. COVID-19-related death milestones (100,000 to 400,000 dead). The green line shows the monthly unemployment rate 2 . The upper gradient (yellow-red) indicates the daily count of states with active stay-at-home restrictions (peak=41) <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">3</ref> . The lower gradient (blue-purple) shows the daily count of U.S. anti-racism crowd events <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">5</ref> . Colored triangles below the gradients indicate local maxima for the various measures. All these external data (aligned to our data collection) are included in the dataset. Events of interest are indicated with vertical blue lines. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2</ref>: Summary of 376 COVID-Related Psychological Studies. Snapshot of COVID-19related psychological studies publicly available as of August 11 th , 2020 (see Methods for details on study identification) along 5 dimensions: (1) average follow-up frequency (y-axis; 'cross-sectional' denotes studies with a single time-point), (2) number of domains assessed (x-axis), (3) sample size (circle size; log-scale), (4) study location (circle color; within US in orange, non-US based in grey), and (5) inclusion of task-based (as opposed to survey-only) measures (circle opacity; opaque = tasks included, transparent = no tasks). Each circle represents an individual study; the COVID-Dynamic study is highlighted with a star. Note that in contrast to the COVID-Dynamic study consisting of 16 discrete waves spread across 10 months, the vast majority of all summarized studies were conducted cross sectional, i.e., include only a single time point, or with very few repetitions, e.g., half or quarter-yearly. A dynamic interactive figure with detailed study information is available at https://coviddynamic.caltech.edu/documents/16453/summary_jittered.html.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Participant inclusion criteria: participants were recruited and screened through Prolific (www.prolific.co) based on the following inclusion criteria: aged 18-100, English fluency, United States residency (50 states), Prolific approval rating of 98% or higher, and minimum of 5 Prolific studies completed. To avoid drawing heavily from one geographic location, recruitment from the 50 states was spread equally across 3 areas (East Coast, Middle US, West Coast). To counteract a bias towards younger adults, present in online studies, a portion of the recruitment specifically targeted individuals aged 45-100. In total, 1797 participants completed Wave 1 of the study (of the 1831 study openings made available on Prolific).</p><p>Participant exclusion criteria: To ensure study efficiency and data quality, for Waves 1-5 those participants who showed low levels of commitment and/or for whom data were deemed of poor quality, were excluded from continued recruitment following each wave. The exclusion criteria were as follows: unable to fully complete the experimental tasks in Wave 1 (27 participants), flagged on quality measures provided by Prolific (6 participants), missed &gt;1 attention-check questions (15 participants); responded with less than 90% commitment to participation in future waves (94 participants; queried at beginning and end of each wave); and overall completion time below our minimum threshold (25, 30 or 35 minutes as determined for each wave through visual inspection of the study duration distribution and consensus among the COVID-Dynamic group) (94 participants). Two participants requested to be excluded from further data collection after Wave 3. From Wave 5 on, no participants were excluded. Application of these criteria resulted in the reduction of the study invitation list from 1797 to 1576 by the end of Wave 5.</p><p>Core participants: To provide an overview of the data from the 16 waves presented here, a core sample was created containing only those participants who had completed at least 50% of the waves and who had not met any of the exclusion criteria described above. This core sample consisted of 1177 participants (51.2 % female, median age = 39.4, age range = 18-77). Detailed demographic information for the Core sample is presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref>. Information about participants excluded from the Core Sample (i.e., the excluded and low-completion rate groups) is presented in the Results section. Sub-sample specific counts (core, exclude and low completion rate sample) are shown in Figure SI-1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures</head><p>Self-Report Questionnaires The full battery of questionnaires and tasks administered across the 16 waves is presented in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> along with frequency of administration (see <ref type="table">Table SI</ref>-1 for detailed descriptions of each measure). The self-report questionnaire battery included commonly used, published psychological assessment instruments and race-related surveys in addition to 2 publicly-available COVID19-specific instruments (Epidemic -Pandemic Impacts Inventory <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">6</ref> , Scales from the Social Psychological Measurements of COVID-19 <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">7</ref> ). We also administered a variety of self-report questionnaires created specifically for this study to characterize experiences and attitudes related to COVID-19 and the BLM protests <ref type="table">(Table 1, COVID &amp; Protest Questionnaires), as well as   demographic surveys and experimental questionnaires related to new and ongoing research   (Table 1</ref>, Experimental Measures). A sample survey (including a randomly selected subset of items from the questionnaires and tasks) is also available for exploration (https://emotioncaltech.co1.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_ctBqoufCi2MKnbv). <ref type="table">Table SI-1 contains   detailed descriptions of each measure and Table SI</ref>-2 contains a data dictionary of all survey items including possible responses for each item and scores generated for each measure. A continuously updated data dictionary for this study and an overview of measures included in ongoing data collection are presented on our website (https://coviddynamic.caltech.edu/researchprojects).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tasks</head><p>In addition to questionnaires, participants completed a series of computer-based tasks designed to assess implicit social attitudes towards race (specifically Black/White/Asian) and pro-sociality, as well as estimations of COVID-related trustworthiness, and social decisions related to prosociality, group-cohesion, and altruism. The specific tasks included were:</p><p>• Pro-social Implicit Association Task (IAT): a version of the standard implicit association test 8 that assesses implicit associations between self-identity (ME/THEY words) and prosociality (SERVICE/PROFIT words).</p><p>• Multi-category Brief Implicit Association Task (BIAT): a brief form of the implicit association test <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">9</ref> that assesses implicit associations in 3 subtests (administered in random order): 1) self-identity (ME/THEY words) and pro-sociality (SERVICE/PROFIT words); 2) evaluative (GOOD/BAD words) and White/Black People (WHITE/BLACK faces); and 3) evaluative (GOOD/BAD words) and White/Asian People (WHITE/ASIAN faces)</p><p>• Multi-race Affective Misattribution Procedure (AMP): this adaptation of the Multi-race Affect Misattribution Procedure 10 assesses evaluative (PLEASANT/UNPLEASANT) implicit associations with different races (Asian, Black, and White).</p><p>• COVID-related Trustworthiness Rating Task: in this adaptation of the Trustworthiness Rating Task 11 , participants are shown pictures of Asian/Black/White/other race faces and are asked to rate "How much do you trust this person to act responsibly with respect to the COVID-19 pandemic?" on a scale from 1 (not-at-all) to 9 (completely).</p><p>• Altruism Task: in this adaptation of the Altruism Task 12 , participants make monetary decisions to distribute money equally or unequally (generous/selfish) amongst themselves and partners who vary with regard to age, race, occupation, and political identity.</p><p>• Public Goods Game 13 : a standard task from behavioral economics that assesses the tension between self-interest and group cohesion in an anonymous group fund-sharing scenario. Instructions for the public goods game were adapted from Wills et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">14</ref> . <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Prolific Testing Waves = W1-W16; 2 weeks = 2 dark lines between columns; 3 weeks = 3 dark lines between column; 4 weeks = wide dark line between columns; 7 weeks = wavy line between columns; Measurement domains: daily life impact of COVID pandemic, implicit attitude task, explicit attitudes and beliefs, emotion and mental health, social behaviors, decision making task, physical health, and participant demographics and background.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>External Measures</head><p>In addition to data collected from participants, we have aggregated data from a variety of external sources that can be used to understand the participant data in context. This includes:</p><p>1. State-wide coronavirus-related legal restrictions imposed to mitigate the spread of Covid-19. These included stay-at-home or shelter-in-place orders, limits on gathering size, mask mandates, restrictions on business or retail, and closures of public parks and playgrounds. We gathered this data by evaluating the language in executive orders, public health orders, and official statements by parks departments in place during each wave. Specifically, we measured whether the restrictions were mandatory (often indicated by the imposition of fines or punishments or language stating that citizens "shall" or "must" comply) or suggested (often indicated by language stating that the restrictions were "recommended"). All were coded at the state level. If different counties imposed different restrictions, we noted the predominant restrictions in the state for that wave. Where these statements were uninformative, we supplemented with contemporaneous news headlines and by checking live resources maintained by the New York Times <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">45</ref> or National Public Radio 46 . Masks and stay-at-home orders were coded as mandatory if an official executive or public health order required them or imposed a fine for violation and recommended if that state's governor or public health department encouraged compliance, either in an official order or in a press conference or online but did not formally impose the restriction. Size restrictions of gatherings were coded on a scale of 1 to 11, borrowing aspects of MultiState's methodology <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">47</ref> . We assigned larger scores to states that recommended rather than mandated the restriction, as assessed by language used in the executive order; instituted larger actual gathering sizes; or opted to delegate gathering restrictions to municipalities rather than setting a statewide limit. 3. Anti-racism political crowd data from the Crowd Counting Consortium (CCC), which collates publicly reported occurrences of political crowds in the United States (e.g., marches, protests, riots, or demonstrations) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">5</ref> . The CCC provides pre-sorted anti-racism crowd data from May 2020 through July 2020. Additionally, we extracted anti-racism crowd data for August 2020 through December 2020: Crowds whose description contained 'raci' were taken from the raw crowd data from the CCC database for these months and then counter-protest crowds with 'against anti-racism' in their descriptions (22 crowds) were removed.</p><p>Figure provides an overview of COVID cases, key events in the US, stay-at-home restrictions, anti-racist crowd data, and other pertinent information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedures</head><p>The study procedures were preregistered on the Open Science Framework website (https://osf.io/sb6qx) to ensure transparency. Participants were paid at a standard rate of approximately $10/h. Additionally, to reduce attrition, from Wave 5 onwards, 50 participants were randomly selected to receive a bonus of $10 times the proportion of total waves they had completed. After each completed month, all participants were entered into a lottery for ten $50 bonuses. Odds were determined by their choices in the public goods game and the altruism task.</p><p>A researcher monitored the data collection in real time on Saturdays and Sundays between 10am EDT and midnight EDT and Mondays from 8am EDT until the closing of the wave. Monitors provided feedback to participants through Prolific's anonymous messaging system and addressed any technical difficulties as they arose. From Wave 3 on, participants received two reminders to complete the wave during data collection (morning and afternoon on Sunday).</p><p>Waves 1 through 4 were conducted weekly (April 4, 11, 18, and 25 2020), followed by bi-weekly administration of Waves 5 through 7 (May 9 and 23, June 6, 2020) and Wave 8, 3-weeks later (June 27, 2020) (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). Subsequent waves have been administered at tri-weekly intervals and then once every 4 weeks.</p><p>Testing was administered using a combination of the Qualtrics survey platform (questionnaires) and Pavlovia 48 (tasks). While the specific content varied from wave to wave (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>), the general sequence remained consistent. Participants first consented to participate and endorsed a level of commitment to the ongoing study. Next, they completed questionnaires regarding background, COVID experiences &amp; mask use, experiences related to protests and racial discrimination, and the Emotion-Space experimental measure. This was followed by the COVID Vignettes (implicit assessment of COVID norms), then the experimental tasks (in randomized order with the BIAT always last), the Responsibility Vignettes, and then various standardized and experimental questionnaires in randomized order. Toward the end, the participants answered 3 questions about explicit norms related to COVID-19. In some waves, they also answered questions about how and where they believed COVID-19 originated. Finally, they were presented with the debriefing and a list of resources to aid with mental health issues, acute mental health crises and food shortages. Participants were also provided with a PDF file containing a resource list at the beginning of the survey.</p><p>To provide a comparison between our COVID-DYNAMIC project and other COVID-related psychological studies, we compiled information <ref type="table">(Table SI-</ref> We identified 565 psychological studies that collected, or are collecting, data from human participants. <ref type="table">Table SI</ref>-3 provides a summary of the 376 studies which met these criteria: a) an Englishlanguage website was available with additional information, b) sample size was clear, and c) follow-up frequency was clear. The table includes the following information for each study, if applicable: study name; authors and affiliations; short summary; country of data collection; sample size (we tried to distinguish between planned sample size, sample size currently tested and core sample size across sessions for longitudinal studies whenever possible); characteristics about the population; psychological measures (which were further divided into several domains: demographics and background information; daily life impact; attitudes and beliefs; emotion and mental health; physical health; social behaviors; decision making tasks; implicit attitude tasks and other tasks); timeline of data collection; duration/follow up frequency; recruitment method; nature of participation (voluntary/paid/existing cohort); data availability and additional notes if not covered already. The visualization together with the summary list allows researchers to quickly identify and locate studies of interest.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis</head><p>All data processing, analysis and visualization was conducted in Python 3.7 <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">53,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">54</ref> and R <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">55</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Quality</head><p>To characterize the data quality, 15 quality indices (described below; 16 in Wave 1) were calculated for each wave and each participant and then compared to index-specific thresholds. A summary score for each participant of the percentage of quality indices deemed 'passed' was then calculated. Results for each individual index (both index value and the binary pass/fail outcome; 1=fail) are provided in the data release. Note, these quality metrics were not used for participant exclusion. Participant exclusion was based solely on the criteria detailed in</p><p>Participants and applied only to the first 5 waves. All quality metrics described below are provided with the data and researchers can apply those metrics for exclusion at their own discretion.</p><p>Several data quality indices were based on the mean number of consecutive identical responses in questionnaires and tasks (i.e., the mean response-string length). Each participant's mean response-string length was computed for each questionnaire/task in each wave. Participants with mean response-string length outside the range defined by the 1st quartile-3*IQR and the 3rd quartile+3*IQR were deemed outliers. The same criterion was applied to identify outliers in response consistency (see data quality index 9: "Response consistency" below). Data quality indices for each participant and each wave included:</p><p>1.</p><p>[Wave 1 only] Mismatch between the age the participant provided to Prolific when registering with the platform (continuously updated based on year of birth) and the age they indicated in Wave 1 of our study.</p><p>2. Completed less than 50% of waves (i.e., &lt;8 waves). a. Valid responses present in less than 50% of the questions asking participants to list stressors in their life.</p><p>b. Valid responses present in less than 50% of the questions asking participants to list memorable news items.</p><p>8. Frequency of missing (i.e., NA) responses greater than 50% in questions that include NA response options (e.g., "does not apply", "prefer not to disclose", or similar).</p><p>9. Response consistency: Response consistency was quantified via the mean difference score between regular and reverse scored items in STAI, SEE, and the Disgust Scale-Revised (DS-R) and mean score differences between PANAS positive and negative items and PANAS positive and PSS scores. Participants that were deemed an outlier (defined via the IQR, see above) in less than 50% of included comparisons are considered to pass this quality measure. Survey responses, calculated scores, task performance indices, and data quality measures are available for data request.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Identification of Distinct Individual Participants for Visualization:</head><p>A key strength of this longitudinal dataset is that it facilitates studying individual differences in temporal variation of responses. To illustrate this potential, data from 5 individual participants from the core sample were selected for visualization in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4</ref>. The particular set of 5 participants was selected using a maximum variation sampling procedure <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">58</ref> , which sampled participants by maximizing the sum of Euclidean distances between their scores on the five NEO-FFI subscales reflecting their personality traits. Specifically, the first participant in a set was one from the core sample. Subsequent participants were selected so that each new participant maximized the Euclidean distances from the previously selected participants in the 5-dimensional personality vector space. We repeated the sampling process for all possible initializations and selected the specific sample with the maximum sum of Euclidean distances. The patterns of each of the selected 5 participants' NEO-FFI scores are illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4A</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sample Loss</head><p>To understand the factors that contributed to sample loss, we characterized participants that did not continue with the longitudinal study by comparing three participant sub-samples: (1) excluded participants -those who were excluded from further participation (Waves 1-5 only) based on the exclusion criteria listed in the participants section above; (2) participants with a low-completion rate -individuals that were not excluded, but completed less than 8 out of 16 waves; and (3) the core sample of participants -those who do not fall within the excluded or low-completion rate categories.</p><p>To assess if the participants in the excluded (N = 221) and low-completion rate (N = 399) groups differed in meaningful ways from the core sample (N = 1117), we compared the two omitted groups to the core sample on a number of demographic and psychological variables.</p><p>Demographic measures include age, birth sex, political party self-identification, highest education, weekly income bracket, and race and ethnicity. Psychological variables comprise STAI-trait, Beck Depression Inventory-II (BDI-II) and NEO-FFI scores.</p><p>For each of the omitted groups (excluded and low-completion rate), we quantified the difference between that group and the core sample by calculating the Euclidean distance between the samples using vectors representing the categories of each demographic factor and the difference in mean scores for each psychological factor. The true Euclidean distances and mean difference scores between the omitted groups and the core sample were compared against bootstrapped distributions of distances and mean scores of sub-samples drawn from the core sample (N samples = 10,000, N participants in bootstrapped samples <ref type="bibr">[</ref> Data Raking Data raking is a common post-stratification method used by survey researchers to "correct" for biases in sample demographics to make the sample more representative of the relevant population-the US population in this case. For researchers who wish to correct the sample in this manner, we provide raking weights for sex, age bracket, race and ethnicity for the core sample (N = 1177) according to their marginal distributions as given in the American Community Survey 5-Year Data <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">59</ref> . Weights were computed in R 55 using the anesrake package <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">60</ref> with a 5% discrepancy limit and no trimming cap. Following the recommendations of Battaglia et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">61</ref> , we collapsed variable categories with less than 5% in the sample (race: American Indian/Alaska Native (0.09%), Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander (0.09%), Multiracial (3.14%), Other (0.42%) and Prefer not to disclose (0.33%); age: 18-19 (3.2%; collapsed with 20-24) 1 ) and all age brackets ≧65 (summing to 5.3%). Further, we imputed missing ethnicity data (0.99% Prefer not to disclose) by randomly sampling from the two variable categories (Hispanic or Latinx and Not Hispanic or Latinx).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overall Data Quality</head><p>To summarize overall data quality, we calculated the number of participants that passed increasing percentages of our 15 data quality indices (16 indices in Wave 1; see Methods) per wave <ref type="table">(Table 2)</ref>. In all waves, the majority of participants (mean70.59%; min=60.01%) passed all data quality metrics. Pass rates increased as the percentage threshold decreased, plateauing between 80% and 70% thresholds. Across all waves all participants passed at least 50% of all data quality metrics. Participant-and wave-wise scores for all quality measures as well as flags for missing task data are provided in the data release.  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Summary of Participant Performance on Data Quality Metrics. For each wave (table rows) the count of participants that completed that wave is displayed in the "Total Completed" column. The remaining columns show the percentage of participants in that wave that passed increasing percentages (50% to 100% in increments of 5%) of our 15 data quality indices. In each wave, more than half of all participants passed all quality measures and all participants passed at least 50% of our quality measures. From Wave 1 to 4, the proportion of participants that contributed high quality data monotonically increased. This can be attributed to the exclusion of participants based on three control measures in the first five waves (see Methods).  <ref type="table">(Table SI-7)</ref>. As expected, likely due to age-related differences in internet usage, older participants (&gt;45) are systematically under-represented in our sample, despite our efforts during recruitment (see Methods) <ref type="table">(Table SI-</ref> <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">8)</ref>. With regards to political party affiliation, our sample contains an overrepresentation of Democrats with corresponding under-representation of Republicans and Independents. Political leanings (liberal/conservative) were skewed according to party affiliation, i.e., Democrats leaned more liberal and Republicans more conservative, with Independents endorsing a more balanced range of leanings. Finally, regarding race and ethnicity, White, Asian, and non-Hispanic/Latinx participants were over-represented in our core sample relative to the US population, whereas Black, Multiracial and Hispanic/Latinx participants were under-represented <ref type="table">(Table SI-</ref>  . At the top left, the state-wise population proportion is shown sorted in descending order according to the 2018 American Community Survey (ACS) estimate (blue) together with the proportions of state representation in the core sample (orange). On the map inset, zip-code data (collected in Wave 8) are displayed which, due to attrition, comprise only 77% of the core sample. At the top right, the age distribution for males and females in the core sample is displayed along with that of the US population. Age brackets follow the ACS brackets (Note: all study participants were over 18). On the bottom row, pie charts of Political Affiliation and Political Leaning (left), Race (middle), and Ethnicity (right) are displayed for the US population (inner circle) and for our core sample (outer ring; except for bottom left panel, where the outermost ring designates political leaning in our core sample in grayscale).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results: Core Sample</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4: Group and Individual Temporal Trends from an Example Variable in Each Domain</head><p>Assessed A) NEO-FFI scores (five-factor personality inventory -N: Neuroticism, E: Extraversion, O: openness to experience, A: Agreeableness, C: Conscientiousness) from five participants with maximally distant personality profiles (see Methods). B-H) Results at the individual-(5 exemplary participants; left) and group-(entire participant sample; right) levels for a single measure from each of the study domains. Measure scores are represented on the y-axis, time since beginning of data collection (in weeks) is represented on the x-axis). Orange triangles indicate weeks in which data were collected. In "Individuals' Scores" graphs, shaded violin plots show the distribution of all 1000+ participant's responses in each wave, overlaid colored lines indicate the individual scores from each of the five participants described in panel A. In "Average Scores" graphs, the black line indicates the mean response across all 1000+ participants in each wave, with 95% confidence intervals denoted by the shaded region. Panels B-H present one example measure from each domain. In each panel description below, the meaning of higher values for the presented score is given in parentheses: B) implicit attitudes, Asian/White + Good/Bad brief implicit association test (IAT), IAT D score (higher anti-Asian attitudes); C) daily life impact, COVID-19 related changes in daily behaviors, sum total of 9 items (greater changes in behavior); D) explicit attitudes and beliefs, very short authoritarianism (VSA) scale, VSA raw summary score (higher authoritarian tendencies); E) emotion and mental health, State-Trait Anxiety Inventory state scale (STAI-state), STAI-state raw summary score (higher state anxiety); F) social behaviors -National institutes of Health Loneliness scale, T-score (increased loneliness); G) decision making, Public Goods Game group-investments, tokens (amount invested with the group);H) physical health -Epidemic-Pandemic Inventory (EPII) physical health total, sum of 8 items (higher number of non-COVID health problems endorsed).</p><p>To illustrate the richness of these data, and in particular the breadth of included measures and the variation over time and across individuals, we selected a subset of representative measures for visualization. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4</ref> depicts results for the entire sample of 1000+ participants and for five participants with maximally divergent personality profiles (see Methods) for one representative measure (i.e., item or summary score) from each measurement domain assessed in the study (i.e. daily life impact, attitudes and beliefs, emotion and mental health, physical health, social behaviors, decision making tasks, and implicit attitudes; note: demographics are omitted as these are visualized in detail in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref>). For each measure ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4B-4H</ref>) and wave (x-axis), the distribution of individual scores (left panels) is depicted in a violin plot with the individual scores from the five exemplary participants superimposed (NEO-FFI profiles for each of the five individuals are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4A)</ref>. The group-level plot for each measure (right panels) shows the mean response across all participants in each wave. Note: not all measures were collected every wave. Collectively, the data in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4</ref> demonstrate there exist substantial and meaningful variations in the data across the waves, both on average across participants and for individual participants. Hence, each measure has a clear pattern of evolution on average across participants over the time period displayed. Moreover, individual participants with distinct personalities and life situations had distinct trajectories within each measure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Shiny App</head><p>This online visualization tool (http://coviddynamicdash.caltech.edu/shiny/coviddash/) aims to provide researchers with a firsthand glimpse at the dataset. This tool was built using the Shinyapp framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">63</ref> in R. It. Users have the option to filter the sample using demographic variables, visualize group mean temporal trends on a subset of measures included in this study, and examine within-wave Pearson correlations of any two measures in a selected wave. We encourage all users of the data to explicitly detail any data-exploration using this tool preceding formal analyses and hypothesis testing in their pre-registrations and publications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Characterization of Excluded and Low-Completion Rate Participants</head><p>To understand what might distinguish the excluded and low-completion rate groups from the core sample, we examined their demographic (i.e., age, birth sex, race/ethnicity, political affiliation, education, and weekly income) and psychological (STAI-Trait and NEO-FFI acquired in Wave 1; BDI-II acquired in Wave 2) characteristics (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figures SI-1, SI-2</ref> and Tables SI-4 and SI-5 for detailed results). The analyses of the demographic data (see Methods for details) revealed that both male and female participants in the excluded and the low-completion group differed significantly from the core sample in age, with the core sample including significantly less participants in the lowest age brackets (18-29) than the other two groups. Excluded participants further differed from the core sample in racial and ethnical composition. The excluded group contained more Asian and American Indian/ Alaskan Native individuals than the core sample. Participants that completed less than 8 out of 16 waves further differed from the core sample in highest education level and weekly income: The proportion of participants with some college education was significantly higher than in the core sample; and more participants from the low completion group fell in the lowest income bracket ($250-499 per week) while in the core sample a larger proportion of participants fell in the second lowest income bracket ($500-999 per week). With respect to psychological characteristics, the low completion group scored higher values of depressive symptoms (BDI-II) than the core sample, as well as lower levels of conscientiousness and agreeableness, and higher levels of Neuroticism in the NEO-FFI. The excluded group endorsed less openness to experience, conscientiousness and agreeableness, and higher levels of neuroticism and on the NEO-FFI than the core sample, but no evidence of significant difference was found on any of the other tested psychological variables (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure SI-3</ref> and Table SI-5).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Raking</head><p>For comparison with US population parameters and to facilitate post-hoc stratification, we determined summary raking weights for birth sex, age bracket, race, and ethnicity of the core sample according to their marginal proportions as given in the American Community Survey 5-Year Data <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">59</ref> (see Methods). In addition to enabling us to account for sampling bias by 'adjusting' our data, this analysis also allowed us to quantify the areas in which representation in our core sample deviated most from the American population <ref type="table">(Table SI-6</ref> to SI-9). Raking weights revealed considerable age differences between our core sample and the US population. While 45 to 49year-old individuals are most overrepresented in the sample (+11.8%), over 60-year-old residents are most underrepresented (-17.8%). Across races, sample-Census differences were largest in the Asian (-5.4%) and Black (+5.5%) groups. Ethnicity (Hispanic or Latinx/ not Hispanic pr Latinx) was misrepresented by (+/-7.9%). The US-population's female/male proportion was well represented in the sample (+/-1.7% female/male). Participant-specific raking weights (mean = 1; SD = 0.89; min = 0.3; max = 5) are provided with the data release for those researchers who wish to utilize this.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>By mid-March of 2020, epidemiological predictions indicated that the COVID-19 pandemic would alter-if not define-our lives for years to come. Realizing that the psychological effects of this would be complex and far-reaching, but also highly dynamic and long-lasting, we launched a large, within-participant longitudinal study of the human psychological response to COVID-19. Many other studies have queried the psychological effects of the pandemic but, to our knowledge, none have captured a comparable breadth, sample size, testing frequency, and duration as the COVID-Dynamic study (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2</ref>, <ref type="table">Tables 1 &amp; SI-3)</ref>. As such, the COVID-Dynamic dataset constitutes a unique resource for probing individual variation across many psychological constructs and relating that variation to a trove of information, ranging from individuals' demographic and psychological contexts to their personal-and societal-level pandemic experiences. The pandemic was also not the sole stressor of 2020. Sharp racial and ethnic disparities in pandemic-related health and economic outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">64,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">65</ref> , the horrific killing of George Floyd <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">66</ref> , and increased Anti-Asian harassment 67 , both highlighted and likely exacerbated long-existing societal fissures, fueling large anti-racism protests. Partisanship greatly increased during the 2020 presidential election culminating in an attack on the US capitol. From its inception the COVID-Dynamic study cast a wide net, assessing political beliefs, racial attitudes, social and moral norms, and social biases. The dataset documents individual variation in these highly societally relevant domains not only as the pandemic evolved, but also as racial and political tensions mounted across 2020. A good illustration of the dataset's potential for relating real world events to temporal variation in psychological measures can be found in mean state anxiety (STAI-state; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4E right panel)</ref>. State anxiety peaked around Wave 2, shortly after the initial peak of new United States COVID-19 case-counts (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). However, despite consistently elevated COVID-19 rates, mean anxiety scores decreased from Wave 2 to 5, perhaps reflecting overall psychological adjustment (e.g., coping and/or numbing). A second spike comes at Wave 7, following the killing of George Floyd. The qualitative relationship between this exemplary psychological variable and concurrent societal events speaks to the general value of this dataset. Second, on top of sample-level temporal variation, the dataset reveals large inter-individual differences, as illustrated across seven exemplary measures across five distinct individuals <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figure 4)</ref>. Differences across measures in initial value and response trajectories from these five participants indicate substantial variation in their subjective experience of 2020. Once again state anxiety scores (STAI-state; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4E</ref> left panel) reveal distinct individual patterns across time, with none resembling the sample trajectories. These individual patterns suggest that, in addition to societal-level events, individuals were influenced by a multitude of personal factors. Given the sample size and breadth of measures in this longitudinal dataset, the inclusion of self-reported personal experiences at each wave, as well as external data on collective events (e.g., COVID-case-rates, unemployment), researchers can explore these inter-individual differences and relate them to both personal and collective experiences. The COVID-Dynamic project has prioritized scientific rigor throughout study design and data collection and has engaged multiple practices to ensure statistically sound and transparent analysis (see Methods and Results, SI-4 to SI-9, and https://osf.io/uenc5/). The data, procedures and preprocessing protocols have been carefully documented to facilitate data-sharing, and a formal proposal-based system for requesting access to subsets of the data was implemented (osf.io/uenc5). To-date more than 16 distinct projects have been approved by the COVID-Dynamic Team including: a published law essay on anti-masking laws and their contribution to racial disparities in usage of personal protective equipment <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">68</ref> , a longitudinal assessment of emotional experience across the pandemic (osf.io/t9p25), a characterization of change in attitudes towards Black-and Asian-Americans across 2020 (osf.io/q5jpb), a basic research study of the characteristics of states versus traits (osf.io/fhqp2), and an investigation of substance use trajectories and their relation to mental health (osf.io/5hbws). While the strengths of these data are numerous, we also note limitations. The dataset does not contain within-participant pre-pandemic baseline measures apart from retrospective self-reports. Thus, some initial effects (e.g., acute initial increases in anxiety) are likely not captured by these data. However, the period of coverage includes multiple devastating local and national peaks of COVID-19 cases, deaths, and restrictions, as well as many national events (e.g., BLM protests, US-presidential elections), and extensive documentation of personal experiences, yielding ample subjective variance to probe. Second, due to practical constraints, the data were sampled at irregular expanding intervals and a number of measures were not sampled every wave, posing unique analysis challenges. There are multiple methods for addressing these issues (e.g., data imputation <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">69,</ref><ref type="bibr">70</ref> and advanced linear modeling methods <ref type="bibr">71,</ref><ref type="bibr">72</ref> ) which should be applied cautiously by individual researchers analyzing the data. Additional limitations, particularly prevalent in anonymous online and longitudinal studies, include poor data-quality and spurious results driven by inattentive or fraudulent responders <ref type="bibr">73,</ref><ref type="bibr">74</ref> , as well as recruitment and retention biases. To ensure high data-quality, participants who were obviously inattentive or responded fraudulently in early waves were expelled. Further, we conducted detailed data quality assessments, provided with the dataset (see Methods and Results). Additional biases resulted from non-random, self-selected sampling and attrition (see Methods and Supplement). While these limit the generalizability of the COVID-Dynamic data to a broader population they have less impact on analyses addressing within-participant variation over time and relations between variables and psychological constructs. Nevertheless, we took steps to reduce recruitment and retention biases, including pseudo-stratification of recruitment (age and location), above-average study compensation, bonuses for continued participation, and continuous participant support during data-collection. Additionally, we compared our sample to the US census (see <ref type="table">Tables SI-6</ref> and SI-9) identifying recruitment biases in location, age, racial, ethnic, and political composition of the sample (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref> and Results), as well as retention biases with regards to age and race. For researchers wishing to conduct post-stratification adjustments on the sample we provide "raking" weights. We encourage researchers to take these factors into consideration during data analysis and interpretation. Finally, as the declared goal of this study was to track psychological change across the pandemic, it is important to consider psychological biases in the sample. In accordance with previous research 75 , we found the low completion rate group to be more anxious and depressed than the core sample. Furthermore, excluded and low completion rate samples were less conscientious and agreeable, and more neurotic than the core sample ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure SI-3</ref>, Table SI-5). However, it is noteworthy that, relative to the community-based norms, the NEO personality factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">29</ref> , trait anxiety (STAI <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">38</ref> ) and depression index (BDI-II <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">16</ref> ) averages for all groups (attrition and core) were within the normal range. By providing this detailed characterization of our sample, we aim to constrain interpretation as well as to situate our study in context and thereby provide a basis on which to integrate it with other valuable COVID-19-related psychological datasets (e.g. the APS Global Collaboration on COVID-19 76 ). In the face of the extraordinary events of 2020, it is crucial that we, as a society, document the objective and subjective experiences of those affected-both to understand what happened and to plan for the future. The COVID-Dynamic dataset facilitates exactly that and is uniquely positioned to tackle myriad exciting and unanswered questions across many distinct psychological and social domains. Moreover, the insights gained-both across our participant population and within individual participants-may provide a knowledge base upon which to form policy and organize action. Hence, on top of its contributions to basic psychological science, this dataset may also contribute to two clear goals of applied psychological research: mitigation of the impact of trauma and promotion of resilience in the face of adversity.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Published Measures</head><p>Alcohol, Smoking, Substance Involvement Screening Test (ASSIST) -a self-report, culturally neutral instrument that measures degree of personal risk related to use of the following substances: tobacco products, alcohol, cannabis, cocaine, amphetamine-type stimulants (ATS), sedatives and sleeping pills (benzodiazepines), hallucinogens, inhalants, opioids, and 'other' drugs. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">16</ref> -a 12-item self-report questionnaire that examines depressive symptomatology over the prior 2 weeks. Total scores indicate general level of depression: none, mild, moderate, severe. <ref type="figure">(CD-RISC-10)</ref> 17 -a self-report index of resilience based on Likertscale ratings of coping responses during the prior month. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">19</ref> -a 27-item self-report questionnaire that measures an individual's sensitivity to disgust. It provides an index of core disgust (including food, animals, and body products), animal-reminder disgust (addressing death and organism violations) and contamination disgust (concerns about interpersonal transmission of materials). <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">20</ref> -a brief selfreport questionnaire, 10 items, that assesses the degree to which an individual's attitudes and prejudice toward a designated racial group are motivated by internal values or external social pressures. The instrument was administered twice, once focused on blacks and once on Asians. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">6</ref> -a 92-item self-report instrument used to identify how the current pandemic has impacted various aspects of one's life including: work / employment, education / training, home life, social activities, economic, emotional health and well-being, physical health, physical distancing / quarantine, infection history, and positive change.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Beck Depression Inventory -II (BDI-II)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale -10 Item</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Disgust Scale -Revised (DS-R)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>External/Internal Motivation to Respond without Prejudice Scale (EMS / IMS): Black &amp; Asian</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Epidemic -Pandemic Impacts Inventory (EPII)</head><p>Everyday Discrimination Scale 21 -a self-report measure of how frequently one experiences 9 types of discrimination in day-to-day life. For each type of discrimination that occurs "a few times a year" or more frequently, the individual indicates the main trait that is eliciting the discrimination. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">22</ref> -a self-report questionnaire in which individuals report how strongly they believe in free will, determinism, and dualism (15 items that produce a score for each of the 3 categories), as well as beliefs regarding relationships between free will, choice, responsibility, punishment, scientific prediction, and dualism (14 items).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Free Will Inventory (FWI)</head><p>Humanitarianism-Egalitarianism 23 -a 10-item self-report questionnaire that assesses the extent to which an individual adheres to ideals of equality, social justice, and concern for the well-being of others, i.e., humanitarianegalitarian values). <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">25</ref> -an 11-item screening questionnaire used to identify the presence of personality disorder in nonclinical samples. A score of 2 or more on items 1 and 3-8 provides optimal sensitivity and specificity for screening. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">26</ref> -a self-report questionnaire which asks about an individual's lifetime experiences of 17 types of trauma.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Iowa Personality Disorder Screen (IPDS)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Life Events Checklist for DSM-5 (LEC-5)</head><p>Major Experiences of Discrimination -Abbreviated 27 -a self-report, lifetime frequency index of experiencing 6 types of major discrimination and the individual trait that elicited discrimination. <ref type="figure">Inventory (NEO-FFI)</ref> 28,29 -a self-report questionnaire in which an individual rates how well each of the 60-items describes his/her behaviors, feelings, experiences and beliefs. In combination, these ratings indicate the degree to which the individual exhibits each of these 5 personality traits: extraversion, neuroticism, openness, conscientiousness, and agreeableness. Scoring algorithm and norms used for z-score conversion at http://www.uoregon.edu/~gsaucier/NEO-FFI%20subcomponent%20norms%20and%20scoring.htm. <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">30</ref> -brief self-report indices of how often an individual had access to emotional support (8 items) and felt lonely or alone in the past month (5 items). These measures are part of the NIH Toolbox and outcomes are reported as T-scores normed to the general population (based on 2010 US Census). <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">31</ref> -a ten-item self-response questionnaire that measures the extent to which a participant perceives personal life events in the previous month as stressful.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NEO Five-Factor Personality</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NIH toolbox: Emotional Support &amp; Loneliness</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Perceived Stress Scale (PSS)</head><p>COVID Mask Questions -self-reported description of mask-usage before and during the pandemic, as well as beliefs regarding mask-usage to address the pandemic.</p><p>COVID Public Policy Knowledge -a 12-item questionnaire that assesses the participants' knowledge of current state-enacted COVID-related policies.</p><p>COVID Theories -very brief questionnaire about beliefs regarding the existence and origins of COVID-19.</p><p>COVID Vaccination -survey created to assess experiences, attitudes, and beliefs related to COVID-19 vaccines.</p><p>COVID Vignettes -Implicit Normsimplicit assessment of how participants attribute responsibility / blame regarding the spread of COVID-19. Participants read one out of 9 brief vignettes describing how the behavior of two people may contribute to transmitting COVID-19 to a pharmacist. then answer questions regarding responsibility of the people in the vignette.</p><p>Post-Election 2020 -survey created to characterize voting behavior in November 2020 election, as well as beliefs and attitudes regarding voting and the election outcome.</p><p>Protest Surveys (Race) -surveys created to assess experiences, attitudes, and beliefs related to the racial protests that occurred in June 2020. Peaceful protests, looting, and violence are assessed independently.</p><p>Protest Survey (Election) -survey created to assess experiences, attitudes, and beliefs related to the electionrelated protests that occurred in January 2021.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental Measures</head><p>Personal background at enrollment -demographic questionnaire administered at enrollment.</p><p>Personal background updates -questions regarding relationship status, work changes, finances, political activities / affiliations, psychological treatment, religion, and current stressors.</p><p>Consensus Task -questionnaire that assesses individual values, beliefs, and preferences across a wide range of topics including COVID-19, social issues, political policies, and hobbies, among others.</p><p>Emotion Space -self-report questionnaire regarding current emotional experience.</p><p>Egocentric-Allocentric Task -perspective tasking task in which participant responds to spatial questions regarding a photo of a political leader.</p><p>Monthly Substance Use Questionnaire -survey created to assess substance-use frequency during the prior month. Race Thermometer -participants use a slider to indicate how they feel toward 6 racial/ethnic groups: Black/African Americans, Asian Americans, Hispanic/Latino Americans, White/Caucasian Americans, Chinese People, and European People. The scale ranges from 0 (Very Cold or Unfavorable) to 100 (Very Warm or Favorable).</p><p>Responsibility Vignettes -implicit assessment of how participants attribute responsibility / blame in a common, low-risk social interaction. Participants read one out of 3 brief vignettes describing how the behavior of two people in a reception area inconveniences an important client that arrives after them, then answer questions regarding responsibility of the people in the vignette.</p><p>Restriction Severity -scale that assesses how severe an individual finds various restrictions that may be enforced or encouraged during the pandemic.</p><p>Self-Continuity 40 -this measure asks individuals to rate changes in self-perception, behavior, and emotional experiences resulting from events during 2020. Participants retrospectively rated changes in these 3 domains as of March, June and September 2020.</p><p>Verbal Self-Fluency <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">42</ref> -in this measure, individuals are asked to provide up to 30 statements that "describe you as a unique individual." These free text responses are evaluated for</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tasks</head><p>Pro-social Implicit Association Task (IAT) 8,44 -a version of the standard implicit association test <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">15</ref> that assesses implicit associations between self-identity (ME/THEY words) and pro-sociality (SERVICE/PROFIT words) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">16</ref> Multi-category Brief Implicit Association Task (BIAT) 9,43 -a brief form of the implicit association test that assesses implicit associations in 3 subtests (administered in random order): 1) self-identity (ME/THEY words) and pro-sociality (SERVICE/PROFIT words); 2) evaluative (GOOD/BAD words) and White/Black People (WHITE/BLACK faces); and 3) evaluative (GOOD/BAD words) and White/Asian People (WHITE/ASIAN faces)</p><p>Multi-race Affective Misattribution Procedure (AMP) 10 -this adaptation of the Multi-race Affect Misattribution Procedure <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">18</ref> assesses evaluative (PLEASANT/UNPLEASANT) implicit associations with different races (Asian, Black, and White). <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">11</ref> -in this adaptation of the Trustworthiness Rating Task <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">18</ref> , participants are shown pictures of Asian/Black/White/other race faces and are asked to rate "How much do you trust this person to act responsibly with respect to the COVID-19 pandemic?" on a scale from 1 (not-at-all) to 9 (completely).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>COVID-related Trustworthiness Rating Task</head><p>Altruism Task 12 -in this adaptation of the Altruism Task, participants make monetary decisions to distribute money equally or unequally (generous/selfish) amongst themselves and partners who vary with regard to age, race, occupation, and political identity.</p><p>Public Goods Game 13,14 -a standard task from behavioral economics that assesses cooperation and selfinterest and group cohesion in an anonymous group fund-sharing scenario. Instructions for the public goods game were adapted from Wills et al. <ref type="table">Table SI</ref>-2: Complete Data Dictionary. Data dictionary of all survey items including possible responses for each item and scores generated for each measure. The dictionary is too large for display here. A continuously updated data dictionary for this study, an overview of all measures, and pdfdocuments of tests as administered are presented on our website (https://coviddynamic.caltech.edu/research-projects). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table SI-1: COVID-DYNAMIC Test Battery. COVID-Dynamic Data Dictionary (download link)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sample Loss</head><p>To characterize the factors that contributed to sample loss we compared three groups: (1) participants excluded due to poor data quality, (2) participants with a low-completion rate, and (3) the core sample of participants (see Methods section Analysis -Sample Loss for details). This section illustrates and summarizes the difference between the excluded and the core sample, and the low-completion-rate and the core sample, respectively. Two groups of participants were not included in the analyses of the Core Sample: individuals excluded (excluded) due to data quality indices in Waves 1-5 (NOTE: after Wave 5 no more participants were excluded), and participants that did not return for repeated testing (low-completion rate, &lt;8 out of 16 waves). To test for sample selection biases in age and sex (A, B), political affiliation (C, D), highest education (E, F), weekly income (G, H), and race and ethnicity (I, J), we compared the excluded (left column) and low-completion rate (right column) groups to the core sample. Histograms show the Euclidean distance between bootstrapped excluded and low completion samples and the core sample. Black vertical dotted lines mark the 2.5 th and 97.5 th percentile of the differences between the bootstrapped samples and the core sample, respectively. Vertical red lines mark true Euclideandistances between the excluded or low-completion sample and the core sample, respectively. Butterfly charts superimpose age and sex in the core sample with the excluded (A) and low-completion rate (B) samples. Nested pie charts show all other demographic variables (C-J) with the core sample's proportions presented in the center and the comparison group (excluded on left, low-completion-rate on right) in the outer circles.  <ref type="table">Table SI-</ref> For all demographic features that differed significantly between the core and low completion or the core and excluded sample, respectively (see <ref type="figure">Figure SI</ref>-2), we compared the proportion of participants in each feature bracket between the groups using post-hoc two-proportion z-tests (critical p-value Bonferroni corrected for each feature). Each table lists the within group (core, excluded, low completion) distribution of participants across the respective feature brackets (proportion of sample per bracket), absolute proportion differences per bracket between the core and excluded, and core and low-completion group, and lastly the z-and p-scores for twoproportion z-tests comparing the core sample against excluded and low completion sample. Significant differences between samples are highlighted in bold. NOTE: prop. = proportion; excl. = excluded; compl. = completion; abs. diff. = absolute difference <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure SI-3</ref></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>: Psychological Characteristic Comparison of Excluded and Low-Completion</head><p>Rate Samples to Core Sample. The core sample was compared to the excluded and the lowcompletion rate samples using seven psychological variables: trait anxiety (STAI trait; top left), depression (BDI-II; top right), and personality (NEO-FFI subscales N=neuroticism, E=extraversion, O=openness, A=agreeableness, C=conscientiousness; bottom). Violin and strip plots show mean scores bootstrapped from the core sample for the low-completion rate (left, blue) and the excluded sample (right, green). NOTE: the only difference in bootstrapped distributions for the low completion rate and the excluded sample is the size of the bootstrapped samples. Black horizontal lines mark the 2.5 th and 97.5 th percentile of the bootstrapped distributions, respectively. Orange circles mark the true mean scores in the excluded and low-completion rate samples. Compared to the core sample, excluded participants did not differ from the core sample on trait anxiety scores or depression symptomscores but differed in four personality subscales: lower on agreeableness, conscientiousness and openness to experience; higher on neuroticism. The low-completion-rate sample showed higher trait anxiety, depression symptoms, and neuroticism scores on the NEO and were lower on the agreeableness and conscientiousness personality scores than the core sample. Importantly, despite differing from the core sample on select factors, average personality scores for both comparison groups and the core sample were within the normal range (1 SD from the mean of a community sample on the NEO <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">37,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">38</ref> ) and both STAI trait <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">47</ref> and BDI-II 25 scores were below the cut-off for clinical significance. Some of the differences from the core group are not surprising (e.g., that those scoring low on conscientiousness and agreeableness were more likely to be excluded due to poor data quality or low completion rate). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Raking</head><p>A common post-stratification technique to account for biases in sample demographics is dataraking. Here, we provide raking weight for sex, age, race, and ethnicity to make the core sample more comparable to the US-population. Summary weights for each demographic variable are presented in <ref type="table">Tables SI-7 to Table SI</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description of Conte Sample</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Currently active Caltech Conte Center participants (n = 105) were notified of this study on April 14 via email and 62 expressed interest in participating; of those, 58 had completed at least one testing wave by the end of June 2020. Conte Center participants were 18-50 years old, fluent in English, and had Full Scale Intelligence Quotient (FSIQ) &gt;=90. Exclusion criteria at Conte Center enrollment included a first-degree relative with schizophrenia or ASD, currently taking psychotropic medication, uncorrected vision or hearing impairment, and moderate-severe depression on the Beck Depression Inventory. Additional exclusionary criteria included history of any of the following: premature birth, epilepsy, major medical condition, metabolic disorder, chemotherapy or radiation, brain surgery, head injury, eating disorder, neurological condition, psychosis, bipolar disorder, autism, suicide attempt, substance dependence or abuse, alcoholism, color blindness or strabismus. In addition to the data collected in this study, Conte participants have been tested in a large variety of behavioral and fMRI studies. During the seven years prior to this study, all Conte Center participants completed a battery of psychological questionnaires (see <ref type="table">Table SI</ref>-10 for full list). Previously collected Conte Data is available on request. For the COVID-Dynamic study, the Conte Center sample completed 13 waves of testing (labeled A -M) which correspond to Waves 3 and 5-16 of the Prolific data. Unlike the Prolific sample, Conte participants completed only one wave during April (on the 15th). Table SI-10 provides a full list of measures administered each wave. The data reported here are from a core group of 45 participants who completed at least 50% (7 out of 13) of these waves. This Core Conte Sample is 50% female, with mean age = 33.7, and age range = 25-48. Details about demographics of the Core Conte Sample are presented in <ref type="table">Table SI-</ref> Verbal Self-Fluency <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">42</ref> Tasks Multicategory Brief Implicit Association Task <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">43</ref> Prosocial Implicit Association Task <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">44</ref> Multi-race Affective Misattribution Procedure 10</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>COVID-related Trust Rating Task 11</head><p>Public Goods Game <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">14</ref> Altruism Task 12 Table SI-10: COVID-Dynamic Test Battery for Conte Waves A -M WA -WM = Conte testing Waves; 2 weeks = 2 dark lines between columns; 3 weeks = 3 dark lines between column; 4 weeks = wide dark line between columns; 7 weeks = wavy line between columns; Measurement domains: daily life impact of COVID pandemic, implicit attitude task, explicit attitudes and beliefs, emotion and mental health, social behaviors, decision making task, physical health, and participant demographics and background Table SI-11: Demographics of Participants Recruited through the Conte Center. No participants in the Conte sample were excluded due to poor data quality. NOTE: low comp. rate = lowcompletion rate group.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>To summarize overall data quality, we calculated the number of participants in the Conte Sample that passed increasing percentages of our 15 data quality indices per wave <ref type="table">(Table SI-</ref> <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">12)</ref>. Overall, in all waves the majority of participants (mean=65%; min=51%) passed all data quality metrics. Pass rates increased as the percentage threshold decreased, plateauing between 80% and 70% thresholds. Except for Wave K, all participants passed at least 50% of all data quality metrics across all waves. Participant-and wave-wise scores for all quality measures, as well as flags for missing task data, are provided in the data release.  To illustrate the richness of these data, including variation over time and across individuals and similarity to the Prolific sample, <ref type="figure">Figure SI</ref>-4 depicts mean response for the core sample of Conte participants on the measures used in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4</ref>: one representative measure (i.e. item or summary score) from each measurement domain assessed in the study other than demographics (i.e. daily life impact-A, emotion and mental health-B, decision making tasks-C, implicit attitudes-D, attitudes and beliefs-E, social behaviors-F, and physical health-G; note: not all measures were collected every wave). Collectively, the data in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure SI-4</ref> demonstrate that there exists substantial meaningful variation in the dataset both across and within waves and participants. In addition, each measure has a clear pattern of evolution over the time period displayed, which is similar to the pattern seen in the Prolific core sample <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figure 4</ref>). As this analysis is meant only to qualitatively showcase a subset of the data, we refrain from further reporting on group means and individual trajectories here. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3) and created a visualization (Figure 2) of relevant studies from the following sources: a) longitudinal studies open for recruitment on the COVID-MINDS website as of August 11th, 2020 49 , b) empirical papers related to COVID-19 on the COVID-MINDS website as of July 13 50 , c) COVID-19 international social science research project tracker as of July 13 51 and d) COVID-19 mental health preprints as of July 2 52 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>sampled without replacement] = N participants in excluded sample/ sample with low-completion rate). Results of these analyses are presented in Supplemental Materials (Figure SI-2 and Figure SI-3).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The core sample of 1177 participants (51.23 % female, median age = 39.38; age range = 18-77) includes participants from all 50 states.Figure 3 compares core sample demographic distributions to the overall US population 59,62 , including: US state of residence at Wave 1 (top left), distribution of age and birth sex at Wave 1 (top right), political self-identification (bottom left), race (bottom middle), and ethnicity (bottom right) at Wave 1. The distribution of participants' state of residence was reflective of the overall US population with a few notable instances of over-representation (California, Oregon, and Washington) counterbalanced by more distributed under-representation. The participant distribution of sex at birth reflected that of the US population</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>9 &amp; 10).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>: Core Sample Demographics Compared Against US Population. Core sample demographics collected at Wave 1 compared to the overall US population (census</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>: Contribution Table. The main authors' contributions are displayed in the left section of the table in the same order as the author list. The contributions of COVID-Dynamic-team members that are not listed individually in the author list are displayed in the right section of the table in alphabetical order. Contribution strengths are indicated numerically: 0 (no contribution), 1 (support), 2 (medium), 3 (lead); and color-coded with darker colors indicating stronger contributions. Affiliations: a Division of Humanities and Social Sciences, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA; b Division of Biology and Biological Engineering, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA; c Institute for Interdisciplinary Brain and Behavioral Sciences, Crean College of Health and Behavioral Sciences, Schmid College of Science and Technology, Chapman University, Orange, CA, USA; d Yale Law School, New Haven, CT, USA; e Derner School of Psychology, Adelphi University, Garden City, NY, USA; f Center of Alcohol &amp; Substance Use Studies, Graduate School of Applied and Professional Psychology, Rutgers University-New Brunswick, Piscataway, NJ, USA; g Department of Psychology and Brain Sciences, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH, USA; United States of America; h Psychology Department, The City College of New York, New York, NY; i Arts and Science Faculty, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH, USA; United States of America.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Resourcesa)</head><label></label><figDesc>Web-based data explorer: http://coviddynamicdash.caltech.edu/shiny/coviddash/ b) Information about accessing data: https://coviddynamic.caltech.edu/data-sharing c) Summary of COVID-19 Psychological Studies:https://coviddynamic.caltech.edu/resources/other-covid-studies70. Huque, M. H., Carlin, J. B., Simpson, J. A. &amp; Lee, K. J. A comparison of multiple imputation methods for missing data in longitudinal studies. BMC Med. Res. Methodol. 18, (2018). 71. Liu, X. Methods and applications of longitudinal data analysis. (Elsevier, 2015). 72. Fine, K. L., Suk, H. W. &amp; Grimm, K. J. An Examination of a Functional Mixed-Effects Modeling Approach to the Analysis of Longitudinal Data. Multivar. Behav. Res. 54, 475-491 (2019). 73. Zorowitz, S., Niv, Y. &amp; Bennett, D. Inattentive responding can induce spurious associations between task behavior and symptom measures. (2021) doi:10.31234/osf.io/rynhk. 74. Ward, M. K., Meade, A. W., Allred, C. M., Pappalardo, G. &amp; Stoughton, J. W. Careless response and attrition as sources of bias in online survey assessments of personality traits and performance. Comput. Hum. Behav. 76, 417-430 (2017). 75. McCredie, M. N. &amp; Morey, L. C. Who Are the Turkers? A Characterization of MTurk Workers Using the Personality Assessment Inventory. Assessment 26, 759-766 (2019). 76. APS Global Collaboration on COVID-19. Association for Psychological Science -APS https://www.psychologicalscience.org/covid-initiative.Supplemental InformationParticipants Figure SI-1: Sample Composition across Waves.The figure summarizes the count of participants invited to complete each wave via Prolific, and the count of participants included in the core, low completion rate, and excluded sample that completed each wave.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure SI- 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>: Demographic Comparison of Excluded and Low-Completion Rate Samples to the Core Sample</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>: Proportion of Participants in (A) Age, (B) Education, (C) Income, and (D) Race and Ethnicity Brackets compared between Core and Excluded, and Core and Low-Completion Sample.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">11</ref>, along with demographics of the group of participants with low-completion rates (n = 13). All procedures were reviewed and approved by the Internal Review Board of the California Institute of Technology (protocol 16-0692B)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure SI- 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>: Group Temporal Trends in the Conte Sample from a Sample Variable in Each Domain. The same seven measures as in Figure 4 are depicted here. Orange triangles indicate weeks in which data were collected. Small triangles indicate that in the respective wave we collected data from the Prolific sample only. Large triangles indicate data collection in the Prolific and the Conte sample. Prolific waves are designated 1-16 and Conte are A-M. Line plots indicate the mean response across subjects in each wave, with 95% confidence intervals denoted by the shaded</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Free text responses: Valid free text responses were defined as responses that included at least one verb or noun per response. The number of nouns and verbs was automatically extracted using the Natural Language Toolkit<ref type="bibr" target="#b52">57</ref> .</figDesc><table /><note>3. Failed 2 or more attention questions.4. Repetitive response behavior: a. Mean response-string length deemed an outlier in greater than 50% of all questionnaires with more than 4 items b. Mean response-string length deemed an outlier in greater than 50% of "core" questionnaires: Positive and Negative Affect Scales (PANAS), State Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI, state and trait), NEO Five-Factor Personality Inventory (NEO- FFI), Very Short Authoritarianism (VSA), and Scale of Ethnocultural Empathy (SEE) c. Mean response-string length deemed an outlier in the Multi-race Affective Misattribution Procedure d. Mean response-string length was deemed an outlier in the Altruism Task (from Wave 4 on, prior to Wave 4 response key associations were not randomized and long response strings were considered plausible behavior).5. Response speed: a. More than 10% of RTs &lt; 300ms in COVID-related Trust Rating Task b. More than 10% of RTs &lt; 300ms in Altruism Task c. More than 10% of RTs &lt; 300ms in Multi-race Affective Misattribution Procedure 6. Task data quality: a. Excluded from Pro-social Implicit Association Task based on recommended IAT analysis criteria 56 b. Excluded from Multi-category Brief Implicit Association Task based on recommended BIAT analysis criteria 43 7.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table SI-3: Summary of 376 COVID-Related Psychological Studies.</head><label></label><figDesc>//coviddynamic.caltech.edu/resources/other-covid-studies for a link to the complete table.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">The table summarizing</cell></row><row><cell>details</cell><cell>of</cell><cell>all</cell><cell>376</cell><cell>studies</cell><cell>is</cell><cell>too</cell><cell>large</cell><cell>for</cell><cell>display</cell><cell>here.</cell><cell>See</cell></row><row><cell>https:/</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>For readability, labels are only displayed for the excluded and lowcompletion rate samples and values &lt;1% are dropped from the pie charts. A</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>45-49 less than $249</cell><cell>0.084 0.393</cell><cell>0.055 0.434</cell><cell>0.059 0.514</cell><cell>0.029 0.041</cell><cell>0.025 0.12</cell><cell>1.036 -1.142</cell><cell>0.3 0.253</cell><cell>1.14 -4.206</cell><cell>0.254 &gt;0.001*</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>50-54 don't know</cell><cell>0.064 0.031</cell><cell>0.073 0.032</cell><cell>0.044 0.025</cell><cell>0.008 0.001</cell><cell>0.02 0.006</cell><cell>-0.32 -0.086</cell><cell>0.749 0.932</cell><cell>1.058 0.566</cell><cell>0.29 0.571</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">*p Bonferroni = 0.007</cell></row><row><cell>D</cell><cell>55-59</cell><cell>0.064</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.029</cell><cell>0.037</cell><cell>0.035</cell><cell>1.523</cell><cell>0.128</cell><cell>1.882</cell><cell>0.06</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>60-64 race/ethnicity</cell><cell>0.038 prop.</cell><cell>0.018 prop.</cell><cell>0.02 prop.</cell><cell>0.02 abs.. diff.</cell><cell>0.019 abs. diff.</cell><cell>1.052 z-value</cell><cell>0.293 p-value</cell><cell>1.278 z-value</cell><cell>0.201 p-value</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>core</cell><cell>excl..</cell><cell>low compl.</cell><cell>core -excl.</cell><cell>core -low compl.</cell><cell>(core/excl.)</cell><cell>(core/excl.)</cell><cell>(core/low compl.)</cell><cell>(core/low compl.)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>65-69</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>0.028</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">American Indian/Alaska Native</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.014</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>0.013</cell><cell>0.004</cell><cell>-3.25</cell><cell>&gt;0.001*</cell><cell>-1.649</cell><cell>0.099</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>age female</cell><cell>prop.</cell><cell>prop.</cell><cell>prop.</cell><cell>abs. diff.</cell><cell>abs. diff.</cell><cell>z-value</cell><cell>p-value</cell><cell>z-value</cell><cell>p-value</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>70-74</cell><cell>core 0.014</cell><cell>excl. 0.009</cell><cell>low compl. NA</cell><cell>core -excl. 0.005</cell><cell>core -low compl. 0.014</cell><cell>(core/excl.) 0.409</cell><cell>(core/excl.) 0.683</cell><cell>(core/low compl.) 1.695</cell><cell>(core/low compl.) 0.09</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Asian</cell><cell>0.101</cell><cell>0.167</cell><cell>0.088</cell><cell>0.066</cell><cell>0.013</cell><cell>-2.873</cell><cell>0.004*</cell><cell>0.778</cell><cell>0.436</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>18-19 75-79</cell><cell>0.033 0.005</cell><cell>0.108 NA</cell><cell>0.103 NA</cell><cell>0.075 NA</cell><cell>0.069 NA</cell><cell>-3.507 NA</cell><cell>&gt;0.001* NA</cell><cell>-3.861 NA</cell><cell>&gt;0.001* NA</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Black or African American</cell><cell>0.071</cell><cell>0.054</cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>0.017</cell><cell>0.011</cell><cell>0.921</cell><cell>0.357</cell><cell>-0.747</cell><cell>0.455</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>20-24 80-84</cell><cell>0.148 NA</cell><cell>0.162 NA</cell><cell>0.154 0.005</cell><cell>0.015 NA</cell><cell>0.006 NA</cell><cell>-0.395 NA</cell><cell>0.693 NA</cell><cell>-0.213 NA</cell><cell>0.831 NA</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Hispanic/Latinx</cell><cell>0.094</cell><cell>0.072</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>0.022</cell><cell>0.016</cell><cell>1.04</cell><cell>0.298</cell><cell>-0.926</cell><cell>0.355</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell>25-29 Multiracial</cell><cell>0.106 0.031</cell><cell>0.198 0.041</cell><cell>0.200 0.045</cell><cell>0.092 0.009</cell><cell>0.094 0.014</cell><cell>-2.739 -0.71</cell><cell>0.006 0.478</cell><cell cols="2">-3.398 *p Bonferroni = 0.003 0.001* -1.286 0.198</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">30-34 highest education level prop. 0.116 core Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander 0.001</cell><cell>0.09 prop. excl.. 0.005</cell><cell>0.149 prop. low compl. 0.003</cell><cell>0.026 abs. diff. core -excl. 0.004</cell><cell>0.033 abs. diff. core -low compl. 0.002</cell><cell>0.798 z-value (core/excl.) -1.326</cell><cell>0.425 p-value (core/excl.) 0.185</cell><cell>-1.202 z-value (core/low compl.) -0.803</cell><cell>0.23 p-value (core/low compl.) 0.422</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>35-39</cell><cell>0.088</cell><cell>0.072</cell><cell>0.056</cell><cell>0.016</cell><cell>0.031</cell><cell>0.548</cell><cell>0.584</cell><cell>1.407</cell><cell>0.159</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PhD other</cell><cell>0.015 0.004</cell><cell>0.018 0.014</cell><cell>0.005 0.003</cell><cell>0.003 0.009</cell><cell>0.01 0.002</cell><cell>-0.308 -1.687</cell><cell>0.758 0.092</cell><cell>1.585 0.488</cell><cell>0.113 0.625</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>40-44</cell><cell>0.121</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell>0.123</cell><cell>0.031</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.936</cell><cell>0.349</cell><cell>-0.075</cell><cell>0.94</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>master's degree prefer not to disclose</cell><cell>0.138 0.003</cell><cell>0.086 0.018</cell><cell>0.088 0.003</cell><cell>0.052 0.015</cell><cell>0.05 0.001</cell><cell>2.099 -2.658</cell><cell>0.036 0.008</cell><cell>2.606 0.274</cell><cell>0.009 0.784</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>45-49</cell><cell>0.109</cell><cell>0.054</cell><cell>0.077</cell><cell>0.055</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>1.781</cell><cell>0.075</cell><cell>1.308</cell><cell>0.191</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>some graduate education White</cell><cell>0.033 0.692</cell><cell>0.05 0.615</cell><cell>0.045 0.662</cell><cell>0.017 0.077</cell><cell>0.012 0.031</cell><cell>-1.222 2.254</cell><cell>0.222 0.024</cell><cell>-1.107 1.144</cell><cell>0.268 0.253</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>50-54 bachelor's degree</cell><cell>0.075 0.332</cell><cell>0.108 0.339</cell><cell>0.062 0.291</cell><cell>0.033 0.007</cell><cell>0.013 0.041</cell><cell>-1.196 -0.207</cell><cell>0.232 0.836</cell><cell cols="2">0.617 1.533 *p Bonferroni = 0.0006 0.537 0.125</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>55-59</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.054</cell><cell>0.041</cell><cell>0.026</cell><cell>0.039</cell><cell>0.936</cell><cell>0.35</cell><cell>1.833</cell><cell>0.067</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>professional degree</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>0.023</cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.003</cell><cell>-0.214</cell><cell>0.831</cell><cell>0.354</cell><cell>0.723</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>60-64</cell><cell>0.071</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.015</cell><cell>0.044</cell><cell>0.056</cell><cell>1.746</cell><cell>0.081</cell><cell>2.913</cell><cell>0.004</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>associate degree</cell><cell>0.109</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell>0.123</cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.014</cell><cell>0.809</cell><cell>0.418</cell><cell>-0.768</cell><cell>0.442</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>65-69</cell><cell>0.045</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.035</cell><cell>0.857</cell><cell>0.392</cell><cell>2.239</cell><cell>0.025</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>some college</cell><cell>0.232</cell><cell>0.24</cell><cell>0.323</cell><cell>0.008</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>-0.254</cell><cell>0.8</cell><cell>-3.618</cell><cell>&gt;0.001*</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>70-74</cell><cell>0.008</cell><cell>0.009</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>-0.076</cell><cell>0.939</cell><cell>-0.256</cell><cell>0.798</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>high school</cell><cell>0.111</cell><cell>0.136</cell><cell>0.095</cell><cell>0.024</cell><cell>0.016</cell><cell>-1.045</cell><cell>0.296</cell><cell>0.896</cell><cell>0.37</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>75-79</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>some high school</cell><cell>0.008</cell><cell>0.014</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>-0.722</cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell>-0.281</cell><cell>0.779</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>80-84</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>other</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>0.003</cell><cell>0.004</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>-1.326</cell><cell>0.185</cell><cell>-0.803</cell><cell>0.422</cell></row><row><cell>C</cell><cell>age male</cell><cell>prop. core</cell><cell>prop. excl.</cell><cell>prop. low compl.</cell><cell>abs. diff. core -excl.</cell><cell>abs. diff. core -low compl.</cell><cell>z-value (core/excl.)</cell><cell>p-value (core/excl.)</cell><cell cols="2">z-value (core/low compl.) *p Bonferroni = 0.005 p-value (core/low compl.)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>18-19 weekly income</cell><cell>0.031 prop.</cell><cell>0.164 prop.</cell><cell>0.098 prop.</cell><cell>0.132 abs.. diff.</cell><cell>0.067 abs. diff.</cell><cell>-5.692 z-value</cell><cell>&gt;0.001* p-value</cell><cell>-3.795 z-value</cell><cell>&gt;0.001* p-value</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>core</cell><cell>excl..</cell><cell>low compl.</cell><cell>core -excl.</cell><cell>core -low compl.</cell><cell>(core/excl.)</cell><cell>(core/excl.)</cell><cell>(core/low compl.)</cell><cell>(core/low compl.)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>20-24</cell><cell>0.111</cell><cell>0.164</cell><cell>0.235</cell><cell>0.052</cell><cell>0.124</cell><cell>-1.542</cell><cell>0.123</cell><cell>-4.326</cell><cell>&gt;0.001*</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>more than $3000</cell><cell>0.034</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>0.007</cell><cell>0.014</cell><cell>0.523</cell><cell>0.601</cell><cell>1.4</cell><cell>0.162</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>25-29</cell><cell>0.185</cell><cell>0.191</cell><cell>0.211</cell><cell>0.006</cell><cell>0.026</cell><cell>-0.154</cell><cell>0.877</cell><cell>-0.814</cell><cell>0.416</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$1500 -$2999</cell><cell>0.095</cell><cell>0.054</cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>0.041</cell><cell>0.012</cell><cell>1.96</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>0.744</cell><cell>0.457</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>30-34</cell><cell>0.145</cell><cell>0.173</cell><cell>0.123</cell><cell>0.028</cell><cell>0.022</cell><cell>-0.759</cell><cell>0.448</cell><cell>0.782</cell><cell>0.434</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$1000 -$1499</cell><cell>0.128</cell><cell>0.122</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell>0.006</cell><cell>0.038</cell><cell>0.25</cell><cell>0.802</cell><cell>2.032</cell><cell>0.042</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>35-39</cell><cell>0.131</cell><cell>0.082</cell><cell>0.093</cell><cell>0.049</cell><cell>0.038</cell><cell>1.43</cell><cell>0.153</cell><cell>1.412</cell><cell>0.158</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$500 -$999</cell><cell>0.169</cell><cell>0.176</cell><cell>0.185</cell><cell>0.007</cell><cell>0.016</cell><cell>-0.268</cell><cell>0.788</cell><cell>-0.748</cell><cell>0.455</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>40-44</cell><cell>0.094</cell><cell>0.045</cell><cell>0.078</cell><cell>0.049</cell><cell>0.016</cell><cell>1.664</cell><cell>0.096</cell><cell>0.671</cell><cell>0.502</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$250 -$499</cell><cell>0.15</cell><cell>0.154</cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>0.004</cell><cell>0.067</cell><cell>-0.165</cell><cell>0.869</cell><cell>3.401</cell><cell>&gt;0.001*</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table SI-5: Psychological Mean Test Scores and Bootstrapped Means and Percentiles from the Excluded and Low-Completion Rate Sample Groups.</head><label></label><figDesc>Bold mean values are significantly different (*p &lt; .05; two sided) from the bootstrapped null distribution. NOTE: excl. = excluded; bootstr. = bootstrap; perc. = percentile; compl. = completion; BDI-II = Beck Depression Inventory -II; STAI = State Trait Anxiety Inventory; NEO = NEO-Five Factor</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>excl.</cell><cell>excl.</cell><cell>excl.</cell><cell>excl.</cell><cell>low</cell><cell>low compl.</cell><cell>low compl.</cell><cell>low compl.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>bootstr.</cell><cell>bootstr.</cell><cell>bootstr.</cell><cell>compl.</cell><cell>bootstr.</cell><cell>bootstr.</cell><cell>bootstr.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>2.5th</cell><cell>97.5th</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>2.5th perc.</cell><cell>97.5th perc.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>perc.</cell><cell>perc.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>STAI trait T-score</cell><cell>60.353</cell><cell>59.404</cell><cell>57.718</cell><cell>61.091</cell><cell>61.198*</cell><cell>59.383</cell><cell>57.703</cell><cell>61.078</cell></row><row><cell>BDI-II</cell><cell>12.836</cell><cell>12.712</cell><cell>11.439</cell><cell>14.014</cell><cell>14.865*</cell><cell>12.723</cell><cell>11.452</cell><cell>14.018</cell></row><row><cell>NEO-O z-score</cell><cell>-0.455*</cell><cell>-0.229</cell><cell>-0.35</cell><cell>-0.111</cell><cell>-0.224</cell><cell>-0.228</cell><cell>-0.347</cell><cell>-0.108</cell></row><row><cell>NEO-C z-score</cell><cell>-0.586*</cell><cell>-0.238</cell><cell>-0.399</cell><cell>-0.078</cell><cell>-0.737*</cell><cell>-0.238</cell><cell>-0.399</cell><cell>-0.078</cell></row><row><cell>NEO-E z-score</cell><cell>-0.739</cell><cell>-0.871</cell><cell>-1.046</cell><cell>-0.697</cell><cell>-0.696</cell><cell>-0.871</cell><cell>-1.047</cell><cell>-0.696</cell></row><row><cell>NEO-A z-score</cell><cell>-0.585*</cell><cell>-0.075</cell><cell>-0.236</cell><cell>0.087</cell><cell>-0.38*</cell><cell>-0.075</cell><cell>-0.23</cell><cell>0.082</cell></row><row><cell>NEO-N z-score</cell><cell>0.576*</cell><cell>0.314</cell><cell>0.143</cell><cell>0.485</cell><cell>0.725*</cell><cell>0.315</cell><cell>0.141</cell><cell>0.489</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>*p=0.05</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table SI-6: Summary Weights for Data Raking by Sex.Table SI-7: Summary Weights for Data Raking by Age Range.Table SI-8: Summary Weights for Data Raking by Race.Table SI-9: Summary Weights for Data Raking by Ethnicity.</head><label></label><figDesc>SI-10. NOTE: prop. = proportion; wtd = weighted; resid. disc. = residual discrepancy after weighting; orig. disc. = original discrepancy before weighting NOTE: prop. = proportion; wtd = weighted; resid. disc. = residual discrepancy after weighting; orig. disc. = original discrepancy before weighting NOTE: prop. = proportion; wtd = weighted; resid. disc = residual discrepancy after weighting; orig. disc. = original discrepancy before weighting NOTE: prop. = proportion; wtd = weighted; resid. disc. = residual discrepancy after weighting; orig. disc. = original discrepancy before weighting</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>target prop.</cell><cell cols="2">unweighted N</cell><cell cols="2">unweighted prop.</cell><cell cols="2">wtd N</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">wtd Prop.</cell><cell>change in prop.</cell><cell>resid. disc.</cell><cell>orig. disc.</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">American Indian/Alaska</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Native, Native Hawaiian</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">or Other Pacific Islander, Multiracial,</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>85</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.072</cell><cell cols="2">107.214</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.091</cell><cell>0.019</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.019</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">other, prefer not to</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">disclose</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">target prop.</cell><cell cols="2">unweighted N Asian 0.054</cell><cell cols="2">unweighted prop. 121</cell><cell cols="2">wtd N 0.103</cell><cell cols="3">wtd prop. 63.622</cell><cell cols="3">change in prop. 0.054</cell><cell>resid. disc. -0.049</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>orig. disc. -0.049</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">female 0.508</cell><cell cols="2">603 Black 0.127</cell><cell cols="2">0.512 85</cell><cell cols="2">623.027 0.072</cell><cell cols="2">0.529 149.629</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.017 0.127</cell><cell>0.055</cell><cell>-0.021</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>-0.004</cell><cell>0.055</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">male 0.492</cell><cell cols="2">574 White 0.728</cell><cell cols="2">0.488 886</cell><cell cols="2">553.973 0.753</cell><cell cols="2">0.471 856.536</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">-0.017 0.728</cell><cell>-0.025</cell><cell>0.021</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.004</cell><cell>-0.025</cell></row><row><cell>sum</cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell>sum</cell><cell>1177 1</cell><cell cols="2">1 1177</cell><cell cols="2">1177 1</cell><cell cols="2">1 1177</cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.034</cell><cell>0.148</cell><cell>0.043</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.009</cell><cell>0.148</cell></row><row><cell>age range</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">target prop. target prop.</cell><cell cols="2">unweighted N unweighted N</cell><cell cols="2">unweighted prop. unweighted prop.</cell><cell cols="2">wtd N wtd N</cell><cell cols="5">wtd prop. prop. change in prop. wtd change in resid. disc. orig. disc. prop. resid. disc. orig. disc.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">18-24 25-29 Hispanic or Latinx</cell><cell cols="2">0.093 0.095 0.178</cell><cell cols="2">191 170 114</cell><cell cols="2">0.162 0.144 0.097</cell><cell cols="2">109.011 112.17 209.506</cell><cell cols="3">0.093 0.095 0.178</cell><cell cols="2">-0.07 -0.049 0.081</cell><cell>0 0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>-0.07 -0.049</cell><cell>0.081</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">30-34 or Latinx Not Hispanic</cell><cell cols="2">0.09 0.822</cell><cell cols="2">119 1063</cell><cell cols="2">0.101 0.903</cell><cell cols="2">105.851 967.494</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell cols="2">0.822</cell><cell cols="2">-0.011 -0.081</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>-0.011</cell><cell>-0.081</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">35-39 sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.086 1</cell><cell cols="2">34 1177</cell><cell cols="2">0.029 1</cell><cell cols="2">101.111 1177</cell><cell cols="2">0.086</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.057</cell><cell>0.162</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.057</cell><cell>0.162</cell></row><row><cell>40-44</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.083</cell><cell>128</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.109</cell><cell cols="2">97.952</cell><cell cols="2">0.083</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-0.026</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>-0.026</cell></row><row><cell>45-49</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.087</cell><cell>241</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.205</cell><cell cols="2">102.691</cell><cell cols="2">0.087</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-0.118</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>-0.118</cell></row><row><cell>50-54</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.09</cell><cell>82</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">105.851</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.02</cell></row><row><cell>55-59</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.09</cell><cell>85</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.072</cell><cell cols="2">105.851</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.018</cell></row><row><cell>60-100</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.286</cell><cell>127</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">0.108</cell><cell cols="2">336.511</cell><cell cols="2">0.286</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.178</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.178</cell></row><row><cell>sum</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1177</cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell>1177</cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.546</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.546</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table SI-12: Core Conte Sample Data Quality Metrics for Each Wave.</head><label></label><figDesc>For each wave the table shows the percentage of Conte participants that passed different percentages (100% to 50% in decrements of 5%) of our 15 data quality indices. Apart from Wave K, all Conte participants passed &gt;50% of all quality measures in all waves.</figDesc><table><row><cell>J</cell><cell>69.77</cell><cell>69.77</cell><cell>83.72</cell><cell>88.37</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>43</cell></row><row><cell>K</cell><cell>63.16</cell><cell>63.16</cell><cell>78.95</cell><cell>84.21</cell><cell>92.11</cell><cell>92.11</cell><cell>94.74</cell><cell>94.74</cell><cell>94.74</cell><cell>97.37</cell><cell>97.37</cell><cell>38</cell></row><row><cell>L</cell><cell>61.90</cell><cell>61.90</cell><cell>80.95</cell><cell>83.33</cell><cell>97.62</cell><cell>97.62</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>42</cell></row><row><cell>M</cell><cell>61.90</cell><cell>61.90</cell><cell>76.19</cell><cell>80.95</cell><cell>97.62</cell><cell>97.62</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>42</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>53.33</cell><cell>53.33</cell><cell>80</cell><cell>82.22</cell><cell>91.11</cell><cell>95.56</cell><cell>97.78</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>45</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell>71.43</cell><cell>71.43</cell><cell>91.84</cell><cell>91.84</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>49</cell></row><row><cell>C</cell><cell>75.51</cell><cell>75.51</cell><cell>93.88</cell><cell>93.88</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>49</cell></row><row><cell>D</cell><cell>57.14</cell><cell>57.14</cell><cell>81.63</cell><cell>83.67</cell><cell>89.80</cell><cell>91.84</cell><cell>91.84</cell><cell>93.88</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>49</cell></row><row><cell>E</cell><cell>77.78</cell><cell>77.78</cell><cell>93.33</cell><cell>93.33</cell><cell>95.56</cell><cell>95.56</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>45</cell></row><row><cell>F</cell><cell>79.59</cell><cell>79.59</cell><cell>93.88</cell><cell>93.88</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>97.96</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100.00</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>49</cell></row><row><cell>G</cell><cell>65.12</cell><cell>65.12</cell><cell>83.72</cell><cell>86.05</cell><cell>97.67</cell><cell>97.67</cell><cell>97.67</cell><cell>97.67</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>43</cell></row><row><cell>H</cell><cell>60.61</cell><cell>60.61</cell><cell>72.73</cell><cell>78.79</cell><cell>90.91</cell><cell>90.91</cell><cell>96.97</cell><cell>96.97</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>33</cell></row><row><cell>I</cell><cell>57.14</cell><cell>57.14</cell><cell>71.43</cell><cell>74.29</cell><cell>94.29</cell><cell>94.29</cell><cell>97.14</cell><cell>97.14</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>35</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Note that the US-census age data is provided in 5-year age brackets. That means our youngest participants<ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(18)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(19)</ref> fall within the 15-19 bracket but cover only a small subset of that bracket. To account for the large mismatch between target and sample variable we used the census 20-24 bracket as target for the collapsed 18-24 age bracket in the sample.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Positive and Negative Affect Scales (PANAS) -a 20-item self-report measure designed to assess the subjects' current affective state. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">33</ref> -a self-report questionnaire which asks about the degree to which 20 posttraumatic stress disorder symptoms were experienced during the prior month.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5)</head><p>Primary Care-PTSD Screen (PC-PTSD) <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">34</ref> -a brief self-report questionnaire in which participants are asked to report the presence of five post-traumatic stress disorder symptoms during the past month. Scores of 4 or 5 indicate probable PTSD. <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">35</ref> -a 32-item, self-report measure of how strongly one empathizes with people of other racial and ethnic backgrounds. It provides 4 indices: Empathic Feeling and Expression, Empathic Perspective Taking, Acceptance of Cultural Differences, and Empathic Awareness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Scale of Ethnocultural Empathy (SEE)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Scales from the Social Psychological Measurements of COVID-19: City, State and Federal Government</head><p>Response to Coronavirus Questionnaire 7 -self-report surveys of beliefs and opinions regarding how city, state, and federal government is, and should be, addressing the COVID-19 pandemic. Includes items related to personal restrictions, punishment for violating restrictions, emotional reactions, advocating for research, economic stimulus, and distrust of public information.</p><p>Social Dominance Orientation 36 -a 16-item self-report index of preference for social inequality vs. hierarch attenuation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">37</ref> -a self-report questionnaire used to quantify the extent of one's social connections during a specific timeframe. Outcome variables include: a) Number of High-Contact Roles / Network Diversity (number of social roles in which the respondent has contact with one person or more at least once every 2 weeks; maximum is 12 including spouse, parent, child, child-in-law, close relative, close friend, church/temple member, student, employee, neighbor, volunteer, and group member), b) Number of People in Social Network (measures the total number of people which whom respondent maintains contact at least once every 2 weeks --reflecting overall network size), and c) Number of Embedded Networks (measures the number of different groups these contacts belong to, reflecting network complexity; maximum is 8., including family, friends, church/temple, school, work, neighbors, volunteering, and groups). <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">38</ref> -a self-report questionnaire that differentiates between the temporary condition of "state anxiety" and the more general and long-standing quality of "trait anxiety." State anxiety is characterized by feelings of apprehension, tension, nervousness, and worry. Elevated trait anxiety is characterized by an overall pattern of increased arousal response to physical danger and psychological stress. Trait anxiety is typically high in people with depression or other psychiatric conditions. Very Short Authoritarianism Scale (VSA) 39 -a six-item self-report questionnaire that assesses right-wing authoritarianism. VSA scores have been shown to predict other factors including nationalism, ethnocentrism, political orientation, political party/candidate support, attitudes towards ingroups or outgroups and anti-minority bias. The measure addresses three facets of authoritarianism: authoritarian submission, authoritarian aggression and conventionalism.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social Network Index (SNI) Extended (current &amp; 2019 version)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>State Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI, state &amp; trait)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures Created by COVID-Dynamic Team</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>COVID &amp; Protest Questionnaires</head><p>COVID Disgust &amp; Fear -brief questionnaires regarding strength of current disgust (9 items) and fear (7 items) responses when faced with various COVID-related events.</p><p>COVID Expectation Bias -instrument that aims to identify bias in predicting 3 COVID-related outcomes (diagnosis of COVID-19, severe illness from COVID-19 and severe financial distress). For each outcome, the participant is asked to rate how likely this is for a randomly selected group. Groups are designated according to race/ethnicity, socioeconomic status, and other factors (elderly, immigrants, healthcare workers, etc …).</p><p>COVID Experiences -questionnaire used to identify COVID-related experiences (e.g., diagnosis, illness, treatment), impact of pandemic on daily activities, engagement with news media, and judgment of leadership responses to the pandemic.</p><p>COVID Explicit Norms -participants rate the importance of 3 specific COVID=19 prevention tactics (social isolation, social distancing and use of personal protective equipment). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Humanitarianism-Egalitarianism 23</head><p>Iowa Personality Disorder Screen <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">25</ref> Life Events Checklist for DSM-5 <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">26</ref> Monthly Substance Use Questionnaire 15</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Major Experiences of Discrimination -Abbreviated 27</head><p>NEO-FFI <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">29</ref> NIH toolbox: Emotional Support &amp; Loneliness 30</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Perceived Stress Scale 31</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Positive and Negative Affect Scales 32</head><p>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM-5 <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">33</ref> Primary Care-PTSD Screen 34 </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Scale of Ethnocultural Empathy 35</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Scales</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Here, we include concurrently collected data from the 13 waves (A-M; April 15 to January 23, 2021) of a smaller (N=45), but extremely well-characterized, group of participants from the Caltech Conte Center. During the seven years prior to this study, these participants completed a battery of psychological questionnaires; many experimental tasks assessing social processing and decision-making; as well as structural, resting, and task-based MRI data. Many of the psychological measures previously acquired overlap with those collected in the current study, including personality and social measures (SNI), trait emotional measures (STAI-trait, BDI-II) and state emotional measures (PSS, STAI-state, PANAS). As such, these data can serve as valuable pre-COVID-19 baseline measures to which we can compare the distinct ways in which these individuals have responded to the pandemic and other events of 2020. In addition, the availability of brain imaging data for the individuals in this cohort adds another dimension to our data set, enabling us to link neurobiological mechanisms to 2020-related psychological outcomes.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why We Can&apos;t Foresee the Pandemic&apos;s Long-Term Effects. The New York Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.bls.gov/data/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bureau of Labor and Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncovering the structure of self-regulation through data-driven ontology discovery</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Eisenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2319</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Coronavirus in the U.S.: Latest Map and Case Count. The New York Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">N Y</forename><surname>Times</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Crowd Counting Consortium</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Epidemic-Pandemic Impacts Inventory (EPII)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Grasso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Briggs-Gowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Ford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social Psychological Measurements of COVID-19: Coronavirus Perceived Threat, Government Response, Impacts, and Experiences Questionnaires</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">I I</forename><surname>Conway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lucian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Woodard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zubrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring individual differences in implicit cognition: the implicit association test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mcghee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1464" to="1480" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Brief Implicit Association Test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sriram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Exp Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An inkblot for attitudes: Affect misattribution as implicit measurement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Govorun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="293" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implicit race attitudes predict trustworthiness judgments and economic trust decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Stanley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sokol-Hessner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Banaji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Natl Acad Sci U A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7710" to="7715" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Neurocomputational Model of Altruistic Choice and Its Implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hutcherson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bushong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="462" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Public Goods: A Survey of Experimental Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Ledyard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissociable contributions of the prefrontal cortex in group-based cooperation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wills</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc Cogn Affect Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Screening for Substance Use Disorder Among Incarcerated Men with the Alcohol, Smoking, Substance Involvement Screening Test (ASSIST): A Comparative Analysis of Computer-Administered and Interviewer-Administered Modalities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Wolff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Subst Abuse Treat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Steer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bdi-Ii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Beck Depression Inventory: Manual</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Psychological Corporation</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of a new resilience scale: The Connor-Davidson resilience scale (CD-RISC)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Depress Anxiety</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="82" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual differences in sensitivity to disgust: A scale sampling seven domains of disgust elicitors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Haidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mccauley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rozin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Individ Dif</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="701" to="713" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Disgust Scale: item analysis, factor structure, and suggestions for refinement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Olatunji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Assess</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internal and external motivation to respond without prejudice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Plant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Devine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Soc Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="811" to="832" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Racial Differences in Physical and Mental Health: Socio-economic Status, Stress and Discrimination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Health Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The free will inventory: measuring beliefs about agency and responsibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nadelhoffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shepard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Nahmias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sripada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Conscious Cogn</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Racial ambivalence and American value conflict: Correlational and priming studies of dual cognitive structures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Hass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Soc Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="893" to="905" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Iowa Personality Disorder Screen: development and preliminary validation of a brief screening interview</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Langbehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diagnostic efficiency of the Iowa personality disorder screen items in a nonclinical sample</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Trull</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Amdur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="357" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The life events checklist for DSM-5 (LEC-5). (Instrument available from the National Center for PTSD at www</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Weathers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target=".ptsd.va.gov" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sternthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Slopen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Disparities</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Health</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bois Rev. Soc. Sci. Res. Race</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The NEO-PI/NEO-FFI manual supplement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mccrae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Costa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Odessa FL Psychol. Assess. Resour. Google Sch</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Neo-Ffi Subcomponents</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://pages.uoregon.edu/gsaucier/NEO-FFI%20subcomponent%20norms%20and%20scoring.htm" />
		<title level="m">Norms and scoring</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NIH toolbox for assessment of neurological and behavioral function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gershon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="6" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A global measure of perceived stress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kamarck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mermelstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Health Soc. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="385" to="396" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Positive and negative affectivity and their relation to anxiety and depressive disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Carey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Abnorm Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="346" to="353" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The PTSD checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Weathers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scale Available Natl. Cent. PTSD Www Ptsd Va Gov</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Primary Care PTSD Screen for DSM-5 (PC-PTSD-5): Development and Evaluation Within a Veteran Primary Care Sample</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Prins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Gen Intern Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1206" to="1211" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Scale of Ethnocultural Empathy: Development, validation, and reliability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y.-W</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Counseling Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The nature of social dominance orientation: Theorizing and measuring preferences for intergroup inequality using the new SDO₇ scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1003" to="1028" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social ties and susceptibility to the common cold</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Doyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Skoner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gwaltney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAMA</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">277</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1940" to="1944" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Manual for the State-trait Anxiety Inventory (form Y) (&quot;self-evaluation Questionnaire&quot;)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Spielberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<publisher>(Consulting Psychologists Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating right wing authoritarianism with a very short authoritarianism scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bizumic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Duckitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Soc Polit Psych</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="150" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From armchair to wheelchair: how patients with a locked-in syndrome integrate bodily changes in experienced identity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-C</forename><surname>Nizzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Conscious. Cogn</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="431" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identity confusion in complicated grief: A closer look</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bellet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Abnorm. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="397" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing the sense of self (Unpublished doctoral dissertation)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-C</forename><surname>Nizzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dep. Psychol. Harv. Univ. Camb. MA</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding and Using the Brief Implicit Association Test: Recommended Scoring Procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nosek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bar-Anan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sriram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Axt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">110938</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Unconscious Drive to Help Others? Using the Implicit Association Test to Measure Prosocial Motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Marvel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Resh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. Public Manag. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Treisman, R. West: Coronavirus-Related Restrictions By State</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.npr.org/2020/05/01/847416108/west-coronavirus-related-restrictions-by-state" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">See Coronavirus Restrictions and Mask Mandates for All 50 States -The New York Times</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">COVID-19 State Reopening Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Multistate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.multistate.us/issues/covid-19-state-reopening-guide.48.Pavlovia.https://pavlovia.org/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<ptr target="https://www.covidminds.org/empiricalpapers.51.COVID-19internationalsocialscienceresearchprojecttracker" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COVID Minds Longitudinal Studies</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">XU/edit?ts=5e73b15d#gid=60477339</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">COVID-19 mental health preprints. medRxiv: The Preprint Server for Health Science</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.medrxiv.org/search/mental%252Bhealth%252BCOVID" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Python 3 Reference Manual: (Python Documentation Manual Part 2)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Van Rossum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Drake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>CreateSpace Independent Publishing Platform</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Van Rossum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Drake</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Introduction to Python</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>CreateSpace Independent Publishing Platform</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Python Documentation Manual Part 1</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Vienna, Austria</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding and Using the Implicit Association Test: IV: What We Know (So Far) about the Method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Banaji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nosek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Implicit measures of attitudes</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>The Guilford Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="102" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Natural Language Processing with Python: Analyzing Text with the Natural Language Toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>O&apos;Reilly Media</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://us.sagepub.com/en-us/nam/qualitative-research-evaluation-methods/book232962" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Qualitative Research &amp; Evaluation Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<publisher>SAGE Publications Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Selected housing characteristics: 2013-2017 American community survey 5-year estimates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">S C</forename><surname>Bureau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pasek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">ANES raking implementation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 0. 80.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical Considerations in Raking Survey Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Battaglia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hoaglin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Frankel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Surv. Pract</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2953</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://news.gallup.com/poll/15370/Party-Affiliation.aspx" />
		<title level="m">Gallup. Gallup Historical Trends: Party Affiliation. Gallup</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Studio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shiny</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://shiny.rstudio.com/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disparities in the Population at Risk of Severe Illness From COVID-19 by Race/Ethnicity and Income</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Raifman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Raifman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. J. Prev. Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="139" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/community/health-equity/race-ethnicity.html" />
		<title level="m">Health Equity Considerations &amp; Racial &amp; Ethnic Minority Groups</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Floyd</forename><surname>How George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.csusb.edu/sites/default/files/FACT%20SHEET-%20Anti-Asian%20Hate%202020%20rev%203.21.21.pdf" />
		<title level="m">FACT SHEET: Anti-Asian Prejudice March 2021 &amp; Center for the Study of Hate &amp; Extremism. FACT SHEET: Anti-Asian Prejudice</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A COVID-19 Face-off between Anti-Mask Laws and Mandatory Mask Orders for Black Americans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">Masking</forename><surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Up</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.3695257</idno>
		<ptr target="https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=3695257" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multiple Imputation: A Review of Practical and Theoretical Findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ArXiv180104058 Stat</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
