<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Motivated misremembering of selfish decisions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
							<email>ryan.carlson@yale.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Maréchal</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Zurich</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bastiaan</forename><surname>Oud</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Zurich</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ernst</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Zurich</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Molly</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
							<email>molly.crockett@yale.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>2 Hillhouse Avenue New Haven</addrLine>
									<postCode>06511</postCode>
									<region>CT</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Motivated misremembering of selfish decisions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">Accepted at Nature Communications</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:57+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Social Sciences</term>
					<term>Psychological and Cognitive Sciences memory</term>
					<term>motivation</term>
					<term>morality</term>
					<term>generosity</term>
					<term>decision-making MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 2</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>People often prioritize their own interests, but also like to see themselves as moral. How do individuals resolve this tension? One way to both pursue personal gain and preserve a moral self-image is to misremember the extent of one&apos;s selfishness. Here, we test this possibility. Across five experiments (N=3190), we find that people tend to recall being more generous in the past than they actually were, even when they are incentivized to recall their decisions accurately. Crucially, this motivated misremembering effect occurs chiefly for individuals whose choices violate their own fairness standards, irrespective of how high or low those standards are. Moreover, this effect disappears under conditions where people no longer perceive themselves as responsible for their fairness violations. Together, these findings suggest that when people&apos;s actions fall short of their personal standards, they may misremember the extent of their selfishness, thereby potentially warding off threats to their moral self-image.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Humans tend to see themselves as fair and honest <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> , and often behave accordingly. Yet some are tempted to stray from such ideals when they can get away with it <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> . This suggests that, at least in some cases, people prioritize appearing moral to themselves and others over truly aligning their actions with moral principles <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> . This seems to be an effective strategy as well. Maintaining a positive moral self-image not only bolsters psychological well-being and physical health <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> , but also yields downstream social benefits. Individuals who appear committed to moral rules are viewed as more attractive social partners <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12</ref> -and one dependable strategy for convincing others of one's morality is to first convince oneself of it <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14</ref> .</p><p>How can people preserve their moral self-image while simultaneously behaving selfishly? Social scientists have often credited our ability to engage in motivated reasoning <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15</ref> -that is, we form self-serving beliefs and attitudes to justify immoral acts to ourselves before or after the events unfold <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> . This feat is accomplished in a number of ways. For one, people tend to strike a justifiable balance between self-interest and their moral values-for instance, lying just enough to profit financially, but not so much as to harm their moral self-image <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7</ref> . In addition, people psychologically distance themselves from their unethical actions-attributing past misdeeds to situational pressures <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17</ref> , or having been a "different person" at the time <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19</ref> . Moreover, people exploit uncertaintybehaving more selfishly when the consequences for others are ambiguous <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20</ref> , making selfserving mistakes <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">21</ref> , and avoiding information about how their actions may have harmed others <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23</ref> . A common thread in each of these self-serving strategies is that they operate over abstract beliefs and attitudes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 4</head><p>Another possibility that has received less attention is that our desire to believe we are moral may distort memories of our concrete experiences. When people's actions fall short of their personal standards, they might misremember having acted in line with those standards. Misremembering past immoral behavior as moral would pre-empt the need to rationalize one's actions, as actions that fall short of one's personal standards would instead be revised in memory. This possibility coheres with evidence that people are able to "suppress" awareness of unwanted memories at both encoding and retrieval <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> . It is also consistent with recent evidence that memories for dishonest behavior (e.g., cheating) are less subjectively vivid than memories of honest actions <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25</ref> , and that memories are less accurate when recounting relevant moral rules after cheating <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> , relevant story details after hypothetical acts of cheating ( 25 , but see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28</ref> ), and selfish relative to altruistic behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29</ref> . However, it remains an open question whether people who violate their own moral standards actually misremember their behavior in a self-serving direction. Importantly, impaired vividness or accuracy (e.g., fuzzy recollection of the moment you tipped a barista yesterday) does not necessarily imply memory distortion (e.g., misremembering tipping the barista more than you actually did), and vice-versa <ref type="bibr">18,30,31 .</ref> This leaves open the question of whether memory distortion may serve as another mechanism through which individuals can act selfishly and ultimately still feel moral.</p><p>When behaving unfairly (e.g., giving a stingy tip), people may misremember behaving more fairly than they actually were, thus preserving the view that they treat others equitably.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 5</head><p>Here, we test this possibility by leveraging experiments in which motivated reasoning should have a minimal influence-recalling a recently performed action for which one's standard of fairness is explicitly declared. If one engages in motivated reasoning before or after engaging in unethical behavior, there should be no reason to misremember a justified action. If people instead tend to engage in motivated misremembering, such biases should be evident at recall.</p><p>Another key focus of this work concerns whether misremembering is in fact motivated. A rich, long-standing debate in social psychology concerns whether selfserving biases require motivation <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33</ref> . For instance, many seemingly 'motivated' social comparative biases (e.g., above-average effects) can arise from rational inference processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">34</ref> . Although the moral domain is one where motivated effects are wellsupported <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref> , it is nonetheless crucial to rule out the possibility that rational inference processes may produce misremembering that only seems morally motivated. For instance, since people tend to be fair across many social situations, it is reasonable for them to infer they behaved fairly in the past. Thus, if memory for recent behavior is weak or incomplete, people may tend to rely on knowledge of what they normally do to inform recall.</p><p>We predicted that motivated misremembering would be specific to fairness "violators", as we posited that this process serves chiefly to reduce discomfort when an individual's actions threaten their moral self-image <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">37</ref> . By focusing on personal standards of fairness in four of our experiments, we accounted for an important feature of social decision-making: even when people's overt behavior appears self-serving, people may not subjectively perceive their behavior as selfish <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">38</ref> . Crucially, here, we measured MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 6 each individual's subjective threshold for what counts as a fair (versus selfish) choice, and examined how this subjective threshold shapes motivated misremembering of past social choices.</p><p>In line with the predictions above, across two lab experiments (Experiments 1 and 2) and three online experiments (Experiments 3, 4a, and 4b), we find evidence that selfish decisions are more generous in hindsight. After deciding how to split money with anonymous partners, people tend to recall being more generous in the past than they actually were. Crucially, this misremembering effect occurs chiefly among people who initially give less than what they personally believe is fair (Experiments 2, 3, 4a, and 4b).</p><p>Moreover, this effect disappears under conditions where fairness violations no longer pose a self-threat (Experiment 4b)-supporting the view that this misremembering effect is motivated. Together, these findings suggest that when people perceive their own actions as selfish, they are motivated to misremember having acted more equitably, thereby preserving their moral self-image.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Misremembering stingy behavior</head><p>In all experiments, participants made a series of five decisions, in which they chose how to allocate money between themselves and a unique anonymous partner.</p><p>Later, in a surprise memory test, we asked participants to report how much they remembered giving on average across their five decisions, and financially incentivized them to be accurate. In Experiment 1, we predicted that participants would misremember being more generous than they actually were, and that this effect would be driven by MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 7 relatively stingy participants (since generous participants should have no reason to misremember their generosity). To test this hypothesis, we examined the direction of participants' memory errors (i.e., discrepancies between recalled generosity and actual generosity). If our hypothesis is correct, then memory errors should tend to be selfserving: that is, recalled generosity should on average be greater than actual generosity.</p><p>Across all five experiments, memory errors were non-normally distributed (W=.53-78, p&lt;.001; Shapiro-Wilk test), thus we report non-parametric statistics for all key comparisons. All reported p-values are two-tailed.</p><p>In line with our predictions, in Experiment 1, we found that participants overall showed a systematic bias towards self-serving memory errors, such that recalled generosity was significantly greater than actual generosity (V=1345.5, p=.021, d=.23, Cliff's δ=.14; Wilcoxon signed-rank test; means and standard deviations are reported in <ref type="table">Supplementary Table 1</ref>).</p><p>Since we predicted that misremembering would occur chiefly among more stingy participants, we performed a median split based on participants' average level of generosity across their five decisions, dividing them into a behaviorally stingy group (N=53) and a behaviorally generous group (N=56). As predicted, more stingy participants showed a bias towards self-serving memory errors, such that they remembered giving significantly more than they actually did (V=335.5, p=.003, d=.34, δ=.23; Wilcoxon signed-rank test; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 1a</ref>), whereas more generous participants showed no such difference (V=353, p=.54, d=.13, δ=.05; Wilcoxon signed-rank test). However, stingy participants and generous participants did not significantly differ in the extent of their self-serving memory errors (W=1292.5, p=. <ref type="bibr">23, d=.19, δ=.13</ref>; Mann-Whitney U test).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 8</head><p>Fig. 1. Self-serving memory errors. Differences between the mean percent participants recalled giving, versus how much they actually gave. Positive values reflect "self-serving" memory errors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(A)</head><p>In Experiment 1, relatively stingy-behaving participants recalled being more generous than they actually were, but not generous-behaving participants. (B) In Experiment 2, we show that specifically individuals who violated their own personal standard of fairness (violators) recall being more generous than they actually were, but not those upholding their own fairness standard (upholders). In Experiment 3 (C) and Experiment 4a (D), we replicate the finding that violators, but not upholders, recall being more generous than they truly were. Error bars represent standard error of the mean (SEM).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Misremembering depends on violating personal standards</head><p>Experiment 1 showed that more stingy individuals recall being more generous than they truly were, while more generous individuals recall their choices accurately.   <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref> . Indeed, feelings of responsibility for an action serve as a bridge between the action and one's self-concept <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">43</ref> . As such, only if people feel MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 14 personally responsible for their fairness violation should they experience a moral selfthreat, and become motivated to reduce it via misremembering.</p><p>Second, motivated misremembering should be largely choice-independent. That is, it should be independent of any peculiarities of the choices that violators and upholders tend to make. Indeed, one possible alternative explanation for our findings is that there is something about the pattern of violators' choices that makes their choices more prone to being misremembered-for instance, that the amount they gave across their choices varied more. Thus, it is important to rule out the possibility that the sets of choices made by violators are just inherently more prone to being misremembered than the sets of choices made by upholders.</p><p>In a final pair of experiments (Experiments 4a and 4b), we examined these two hypotheses to directly test the motivated nature of misremembering. In Experiment 4a, an initial wave of participants (free-choice deciders) freely decided how to split money with anonymous partners, and later recalled their choices (as in prior experiments). Next, in Experiment 4b, a second wave of participants (forced-choice deciders) were each yoked to a randomly selected free-choice decider from Experiment 4a, and were forced to make (and later recall) the exact same set of transfer choices as their yoked free-choice decider (See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2a</ref>). Crucially, in Experiment 4b, forced-choice deciders (as well as the recipients of their transfers) were instructed that the decider had no responsibility for their transfer choices-thereby removing any incentive to misremember their choices.</p><p>Moreover, we confirmed that feelings of personal responsibility were lower among forced-choice (versus free-choice) deciders (See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2b</ref> and 2c for distributions of reported personal responsibility). We made the following key predictions. Based on the motive-dependence hypothesis, we predicted that those who freely violated their own standards would make self-serving memory errors, whereas those who were forced to violate their own standards and perceived no personal responsibility for their actions would show no such bias toward self-serving memory errors.</p><p>Similarly, based on the choice-independence hypothesis, we predicted that while violators in the free-choice condition would make self-serving memory errors, their yoked counterparts in the forced-choice condition, who had to recall exactly the same choices, would not make such errors. Since Experiment 4a was structured the same as Experiments 2 and 3, we first conducted all key tests that were reported in Experiments 2 and 3. We replicated all of the key results reported above (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Results)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Misremembering is motive-dependent</head><p>To evaluate the efficacy of our manipulation, we first assessed how responsible We predicted that while those who freely violated their own standards would make self-serving memory errors, those who were forced to violate their standards (and consequently perceived no personal responsibility for their actions) should show no such bias toward self-serving memory errors.</p><p>Consistent with our prior experiments, in Experiment 4a, free-choice participants showed a systematic bias towards self-serving memory errors (V=29581, p&lt;.001, d=.18, δ=.08; Wilcoxon ranked-sum test). Violators (N=231) recalled being more generous than they actually were (V=8609.5, p&lt;.001, d=.40, δ=.26; Wilcoxon ranked-sum test; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig.   1d</ref>), but upholders (N=478) showed no such bias (V=6102.5, p=.92, d=.02, δ=-.01;</p><p>Wilcoxon ranked-sum test). Furthermore, violators showed a greater bias toward selfserving memory errors than upholders (W=42117, p&lt;.001, d=. <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">43</ref> Thus, while our forced-choice manipulation eliminated the main effect of misremembering, there remained a significant, albeit diminished, misremembering effect for forced-choice violators. One possibility is that, despite our instructions that sought to minimize feelings of responsibility in the forced-choice experiment, some forced-choice violators may have still felt some degree of personal responsibility, and thus were motivated to misremember. This prediction follows from work showing that while following orders or instructions can reduce feelings of responsibility, it does not eliminate them entirely (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">44</ref> ). Supporting our prediction, around 30% of forcedchoice participants reported feeling some degree of responsibility for their choices.</p><p>Crucially, the motive dependence hypothesis predicts that the forced-choice manipulation should eliminate motivated misremembering only in those violators who viewed themselves as not personally responsible for their actions, whereas forced-choice violators who viewed themselves as personally responsible should remain motivated to make self-serving memory errors. To test this possibility, we independently assessed the memories of those who reported being "not at all responsible" for their actions (i.e., 1 out of 7 on our personal responsibility measure; N=408), and those who self-reported some degree of personal responsibility for their actions (i.e., greater than 1 out of 7 on our personal responsibility measure; M=4.87, SD=1.84; N=171).</p><p>Consistent with the motive-dependence hypothesis, forced-choice deciders who nonetheless perceived themselves as responsible for their actions showed a significant bias toward self-serving memory errors (V=3206. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> Wilcoxon ranked-sum test; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 3b</ref>), whereas upholders (N=92) showed no such bias (V=372, p=.066, d=.08, δ=-.13; Wilcoxon ranked-sum test). We also found that violators showed a greater bias toward self-serving memory errors than upholders (W=2010, p&lt;.001, d=.61, δ=.45; Mann-Whitney U test). In contrast, forced-choice participants who reported feeling no responsibility for their actions showed no bias toward self-serving memory errors (V=4802.5, p=. <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">68</ref>   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Misremembering is choice-independent</head><p>We also predicted that while those who freely violate their own standards should tend to make self-serving memory errors, those forced to make the same choices would  In contrast, yoked forced-choice deciders-who were forced to make, and then remember, the exact same choice sets as free-choice deciders-showed no significant bias toward self-serving memory errors (V=16087.5, p=. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In The Descent of Man, Darwin wrote "A moral being is one who is capable of reflecting on his past actions and their motives-of approving of some and disapproving of others" <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45</ref> . Here we offer one account of how people may fall short of Darwin's moral criterion. Across five experiments, we found that people tend to recall being more generous than they actually were. This occurred even when participants could receive a monetary bonus that directly scaled with their memory accuracy. Crucially, this effect was driven by a subset of individuals whose generosity fell short of what they personally believed was fair, independent of their absolute level of giving. Such individuals not only showed more self-serving memory errors, but were also less confident in their memories compared to individuals who upheld their personal fairness standards. Further analyses revealed that this phenomenon is in fact motivated, as opposed to arising from rational inference processes. Specifically, misremembering only occurred when violating fairness standards posed a self-threat-i.e., when people perceived themselves as personally responsible for their actions. Together, our findings highlight the importance of assessing selfishness as it is perceived by social decision-makers-that is, relative to their own, subjective moral beliefs. More crucially, these findings contribute to a growing literature on the motivated nature of memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[46]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[47]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[48]</ref> by supporting the idea that people can misremember not just rules, or hypothetical situations, but also concrete actions.</p><p>Specifically, these findings suggest that those who violate (as opposed to uphold) their personal standards misremember the extent of their selfishness. Moreover, they highlight the key motivational role of perceived responsibility for norm violationsconsistent with classic accounts from social psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">42</ref> , and recent evidence from MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 23 experimental economics <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29</ref> . However, since we focused specifically on those who reported no responsibility, it is also conceivable that other factors might have differed between the participants who felt responsible and those who did not.</p><p>We interpret these results as evidence of motivated memory distortion, however an alternative account would hold that these individuals were aware of their true level of generosity at recall, yet were willing to pay a cost to claim having been more generous.</p><p>While this account is not inconsistent with prior work <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7</ref> , it should be less likely in a context which is anonymous, involves no future interaction with any partners, and requires memories to be verified by an experimenter <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">49</ref> . Accordingly, we found little to no effect of trait social desirability on peoples' reported memories. Together, these points suggest that people were actually misremembering their choices, rather than consciously lying about them.</p><p>A related literature suggests that memory is enhanced for emotional events <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">50</ref> and violating fairness standards may immediately induce negative emotions such as guilt <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">52</ref> . From this literature, one would expect fairness violations to be more memorable than morally-consistent choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28</ref> . This may be especially true of extreme moral transgressions (e.g., physical harm), which may remain memorable to transgressors long after they occurred <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">53</ref> , or when one's moral transgression was witnessed by others-which could elicit social emotions such as shame or embarrassment <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">54</ref> . Such contexts may indeed elicit a different self-serving strategy. If one's moral conduct were witnessed by, or directly comparable to, the conduct of one's peers, individuals might instead distort their moral view of others (e.g., viewing peers as being less moral than they truly are <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">55</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> .</p><p>Below we propose three possibilities, however it is important to note that it is plausible that numerous memory mechanisms could contribute to misremembering in our experiments <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">56,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">57</ref> .</p><p>One possibility is that selfish individuals misremember their choices via mechanisms that unfold at encoding. Memory encoding is chiefly determined by attention <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">58</ref> , which in turn is guided by our goals <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">59</ref> . Upon first becoming aware of the intention to make a selfish choice, individuals may attend less to episodic details, and strategically downregulate the depth of processing of such episodes via inhibitory control processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> . As a consequence, violators may misremember at recall due to their most selfish choices being less available in memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">60,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">61</ref> -that is, selfish choices are less richly encoded, and thus more generous choices loom larger at recall.</p><p>Another possibility is that selfish choices are accurately stored in memory, but later distorted via retrieval-related processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref>  Importantly, these cognitive mechanisms of misremembering are neurally dissociable <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">64,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">65</ref> . For instance, an encoding account of misremembering would be more consistent with decreased functional connectivity between midbrain dopaminergic targets and hippocampus immediately following selfish choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">64</ref> . In contrast, a retrieval account of misremembering would predict increased dorsolateral prefrontal activation and reduced hippocampal activation beyond the encoding phase, reflecting retrieval-related top-down control over memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">62,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">66</ref> . completed Experiment 2, respectively. In both experiments, participants were recruited from the University of Zürich participant database. We focused our recruitment on individuals who had not previously participated in experiments involving dictator games.</p><p>Though, due to an administrative oversight in Experiment 2, there were five participants who did not meet this criterion but nonetheless participated in the experiment, which was discovered after data collection. These five participants were excluded from further analysis.</p><p>In Experiment 1, three participants were excluded for being extreme outliers (i.e., &gt; 4 standard deviations from the mean) in the size of their memory errors-our key dependent measure. This left a total sample of 109 participants. In Experiment 2, four participants were excluded for being extreme outliers (i.e., &gt; 4 standard deviations from the mean) in the size of their memory errors, leaving a total sample of 234 participants.</p><p>To test the robustness of our results, we confirmed that our findings remained consistent when we additionally exclude subjects who never chose to give money in our task (Nexp.1=18; Nexp.2=51), as well as when we include all participants in our analyses (see In both experiments, participants were instructed that they would be playing a dictator game in which they would be paired anonymously with another participant. They were further instructed that one of the participants (Participant 1) would decide how to divide a sum of money between themselves and the other participant (Participant 2), and were informed that their role would be revealed to them at a later point in time.</p><p>One key difference between Experiment 1 and Experiment 2 is that, at this point In Experiment 3, participants reported the percentage they recalled transferring on a sliding scale (the "Slider" Question type and "Bars" subtype in Qualtrics). They could report their recalled average in 1% increments on this scale. Furthermore, we used a slightly different scale/depiction from the format in which choices were made. Choices were made also using a similar but visually distinct slider scale (the "Slider" question type and "Sliders" subtype in Qualtrics), and were instead made in 10% increments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiments 4a and 4b: Online participants</head><p>In Experiment 4a, and 4b, we determined our sample size by focusing on achieving sufficient power within our main group of interest: violators. A minimum sample size of N=298 (N=149 per group) was needed to attain approximately 95% power to detect the key group difference observed in Experiment and an additional 317 participants whose data were collected (within 3 days of the initial data collection period) to ensure sufficient power for paired analyses after exclusions. All participants were recruited from Amazon Mechanical Turk.</p><p>In Experiment 4a, we excluded 266 participants who failed at least one of our comprehension checks, as well as 163 participants who reported any suspicion about key aspects of the task. Finally, 14 participants were excluded for being extreme outliers (i.e., &gt; 4 standard deviations from the mean) in the size of their memory errors. This left a total sample of 709 participants in Experiment 4a. Importantly, our key findings remain the same when also excluding non-givers (N=78), as well as when including all participants in the analyses (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Results)</ref>. The choices made by each of these 709 freechoice participants formed the 'choice sets' that were subsequently provided to forcedchoice participants in Experiment 4b.</p><p>In Experiment 4b, we excluded 268 participants who failed at least one of our comprehension checks, and 181 participants who reported suspicion about key aspects of the task. Finally, 8 participants were also excluded for being extreme outliers (i.e., &gt; 4 standard deviations from the mean) in the size of their memory errors. This left a total </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiments 4a and 4b: Online procedures</head><p>The procedure of Experiment 4a was nearly identical to Experiment 3.</p><p>Participants were informed of the allocation task, reported their fairness standard, and then made five choices about how to allocate an endowment of money between themselves and anonymous partners. Later, they received a surprise memory test and were paid for accuracy using the same incentive scheme as in Experiment 3.</p><p>In Experiment 4b, participants initially received the same instructions as those Experiment 4a-including the same details for the allocation task. This was to ensure that they reported their fairness standard under the assumption of free-choice (as in Experiment 4a). After reporting their fairness standard, they were subsequently informed that they had been assigned to complete an alternate version of the task in the role of Participant 1. Specifically, participants were instructed that in the alternate version of the task, they would not be able to choose what proportion of the endowment to transfer to Participant 2, and that transfer amounts would instead be randomly predetermined. On each transfer trial, participants used the same slider to make their transfer choices, however they were instructed to "Please move the slider to transfer X% to Participant 2 this round". To advance to the next round, participants had to move the slider to the </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Memory measures: All experiments</head><p>Of central interest in all experiments was the difference between the actual average percentage each participant gave, and their memory of the average percentage they gave. To address this, we conducted two complementary analyses:</p><p>We were specifically interested in whether people would remember giving more than they actually gave-that is, if they would make self-serving memory errors. We operationalize motivated misremembering as the occurrence of self-serving memory errors in our task. These two terms are used interchangeably throughout the paper.</p><p>We measured this tendency by taking into account the direction of participants' memory errors: positive values indicated a participant recalled giving more than they actually gave (i.e., a self-serving memory error), and negative values indicated that they recalled giving less than they actually gave (i.e., a self-defeating memory error).</p><p>In addition, we examined memory inaccuracy. To do so we computed the absolute difference between participant's actual and recalled generosity (i.e., the absolute size of memory errors). This allowed us to assess which group tended to make larger memory errors (independent of whether they remembered giving more or less than they actually gave). Results for this measure are reported in the Supplementary Information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 35</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Control measures: All Experiments</head><p>We also assessed several factors that we predicted would impact memory inaccuracy: (i) choice speed-the average reaction time of each participant's five choices, (ii) choice variance-the standard deviation of their five choices, (iii) non-givingwhether or not they ever gave a positive amount across their five choices, and (iv) their performance on the numeracy test described above. Our key results remain the same controlling for these factors, as such we report analyses of these measures in the Supplementary Information (see <ref type="table">Supplementary Tables 3 and 4</ref>).</p><p>Since choice variance could directly impact the memorability of one's choices, we also confirmed that all key findings remain consistent when excluding 'static' decidersthat is, those participants who always made identical allocation choices (See Supplementary Results and Discussion).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Personal responsibility: Experiment 4a and 4b</head><p>To assess personal responsibility in Experiments 4a and 4b, we asked people how responsible they felt for the amount of money that was transferred to the receiver on a scale ranging from 1 ("Not at all responsible") to 7 ("Extremely responsible").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Internal validity of fairness standards measure: Experiments 2, 3, and 4a</head><p>To support the validity of our measure of personal standards of fairness, we tested how well this measure tracked with people's actual behavior. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Socially desirable responding: Experiment 3</head><p>In Experiment 3, we probed participants' tendency to engage in socially desirable responding using a short-form (10-item) version of the Marlowe-Crowne Social Desirability Scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">70</ref> . This measure allowed us to rule out the possibility that motivated misremembering can be reduced to socially desirable responding. Our results remain the same when controlling for this factor (See <ref type="table">Supplementary Table 6</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Memory confidence: Experiments 3, 4a, and 4b</head><p>After participants recalled their average generosity, we asked them to rate how confident they were in their recalled generosity on a 7-point Likert scale ranging from 1</p><p>("Not at all confident") to 7 ("Extremely confident"). Spearman rank correlation tests showed that self-reported memory confidence was negatively correlated with the size of participants' actual memory errors in Experiment 3 (rs=-.64, p&lt;.001), Experiment 4a</p><p>(rs=-.55, p&lt;.001), and Experiment 4b (rs=-.57, p&lt;.001).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Psychological consequences: Experiments 3, 4a, and 4b</head><p>In Experiment 3, we explored two factors that could shift as a function of whether </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Manipulation of responsibility in Experiments 4a and 4b. The top panel (a) shows an example of a yoked pair of deciders making a free-choice transfer (Experiment 4a) and a forcedchoice transfer (Experiment 4b). The amount (and order) of each of the five transfer choices were identical for yoked deciders. The bottom panel shows self-reported personal responsibility from 1 ("Not at all responsible") to 7 ("Extremely responsible") among deciders in Experiments 4a (free-choice; b) and Experiment 4b (forced-choice; c).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Round 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Please move the slider to transfer 40% to Participant 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>participants perceived themselves to be for their actions under free-choice (Experiment 4a) and forced-choice (Experiment 4b) conditions. As predicted, free-choice participants reported a high degree of responsibility for their actions (M=6.28, SD=1.18), with 64% (N=452/709) reporting the highest level of responsibility possible for their actions (7="Extremely responsible";Fig. 2b). In contrast, forced-choice participants reported a low degree of responsibility for their actions (M=2.14, SD=2.03), with 70% (N=408/580) reporting the lowest level of responsibility possible for their actions (1="Not at all responsible";Fig. 2c). The difference in ratings between these two groups was significant (W= 375501.5, p&lt;.001, d=2.56, δ=.83; Mann-Whitney U test). Nevertheless, some participants in the forced-choice condition indicated they felt some degree of responsibility for their choices despite not making them freely. This is plausible in the context of our experiments because participants ultimately had to still move the slider to register the predetermined choice.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Motive-dependence of self-serving memory errors. (A) In Experiment 4b, forcedchoice violators who perceived no responsibility for their actions showed no self-serving memory errors. (B) In contrast, forced-choice violators who nonetheless still perceived themselves as responsible for their actions exhibited self-serving memory errors. Error bars represent standard error of the mean (SEM).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Choice-independence of self-serving memory errors. (A) In Experiment 4a, free-choice violators exhibited self-serving memory errors. (B) In contrast, in Experiment 4b, participants forced to make identical choices as violators exhibited no such bias toward self-serving memory errors. Error bars represent standard error of the mean (SEM).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Teasing apart the influences of such mechanisms may be fruitfully pursued by examining how neural representations of ethical and unethical memories change over time 67 . Such work could allow for a deeper understanding of the mechanisms by which memory operates in the service of one's goals, and specifically, how the malleability of memory helps us maintain ethically 57 female, 50 male, 5 did not specify; mean age=22.0), completed Experiment 1, and 243 participants (118 female, 125 male; mean age=22.8)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Supplementary 27 Experiments 1 and 2 :</head><label>272</label><figDesc>Results). The University of Zurich Ethics Commission approved the procedures in Experiments 1 and 2. Both experiments complied with all relevant ethical regulations for work with human participants and all participants provided written informed consent. MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING Lab procedures Experiments 1 and 2 were conducted in the Experimental Laboratory at the Department of Economics, University of Zurich. In Experiment 1, data were collected across five experimental sessions, with the number of participants per session ranging from 11 to 30. In Experiment 2, data were collected across 13 experimental sessions, with the number of participants per session ranging from 10 to 31. Participants provided informed consent and then received instructions for the experiment. They were instructed that their responses would remain confidential and anonymous and that they would receive a payment of CHF 10 for participation in the experiment, as well as an additional payment based on one of their choices during the experiment, which they would receive in cash at the end of the session.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>sample of 579 participants in Experiment 4b, and ultimately 579 unique yoked pairs of free-choice and forced-choice deciders-though our key findings again remain the same when we run our analyses using all 709 unique yoked pairs, and when excluding yoked pairs of non-givers (see Supplementary Results). The Yale University Human Investigation Committee approved the procedures for Experiments 4a and 4b. Both MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 33 experiments complied with all relevant ethical regulations for work with human participants and all participants provided informed consent.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>specified amount. Crucially, the amount displayed on each of the five trials matched the exact amount and order of transfers made by a yoked free-choice participant from Experiment 4a. After making their allocation choices, the experiment proceeded MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 34 identically to Experiment 4a. After completing the surprise memory quiz, participants in Experiments 4a &amp; 4b completed a measure of memory confidence (as in Experiment 3), a measure of personal responsibility, and exploratory measures of psychological discomfort.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>9</head><label></label><figDesc>However, the extent of misremembering did not significantly differ between these groups. One possibility is that by only measuring overt behavior, we failed to capture the extent to which people's choices truly upheld, versus violated, their personal standards of Vexp.2=332.5, p=.42, d=.02, δ=-.04; Vexp.3=122.5, p=.11, d=.10, δ=-Next, we sought evidence that the misremembering we observe here is in fact motivated (i.e., driven by a desire to preserve one's moral self-image) rather than based on a rational inference (i.e., reconstructed from past behavior based on an inference from their fairness beliefs). If participants, when faced with difficulty recalling their true choices, simply reconstruct those choices based on an inference from what they believe is fair, we would predict that those who gave less than their personal standard (i.e., For this analysis, we were limited to a smallersample as we were only able to analyze data from those violators (Nexp.2=58; Nexp.3=64) and exceeders (Nexp.2=51; Nexp.3=82) who in fact made memory errors. A binomial test indicated that, whereas the proportion of violators who made norm-directed memory errors was greater than chance (pexp.2&lt;.001, 95% CI[.59, .83]; pexp.3=.008, 95% CI[.54, .78]), the proportion of exceeders who made norm-directed memory errors was no different than that expected by chance (pexp.2=.78, 95% CI [.33, .62]; pexp.3=.91, 95%</figDesc><table><row><cell>MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING</cell><cell>10 11 12</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">To test whether this effect is driven by violating one's personal standards, we separately assessed memory errors in participants who (on average) gave less than what generous upholders (.02; Wilcoxon signed-rank tests). Moreover, we found no difference between</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">they indicated was fair (violators; Nexp.2=69; Nexp.3=143), versus those who (on average) behaviorally stingy versus generous upholders in their tendency to make self-serving</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">fairness for the situation. If misremembering is primarily driven by a desire to reduce gave at least as much as what they indicated was fair (upholders, Nexp.2=165; Nexp.3=461). memory errors (Wexp.2=3179, p=.39, d=.09, δ=.07; Wexp.3=24742.5, p=.073, d=.24, δ=.07;</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">threats to one's moral self-image, self-serving memory errors should occur chiefly when As predicted, violators recalled being significantly more generous than they actually were Mann-Whitney U tests).</cell></row><row><cell>people's actions fall short of their own personal standards, independent of how (Vexp.2=1396.5, p&lt;.001, d=.54, δ=.38; Vexp.3=1558.5, p&lt;.001, d=.30, δ=.15; Wilcoxon These results provide initial support for the idea that personal standards can</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>objectively high or low those standards may be. signed-rank tests; Fig. 1b &amp; Fig. 1c), but this was not the case for upholders influence how people remember their generosity. If this is the case, then recalled</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">In Experiments 2 and 3, we tested this possibility by explicitly probing (Vexp.2=838, p=.89, d=.02, δ&lt;.001; Vexp.3=2439, p=.69, d=.04, δ=.01; Wilcoxon signed-generosity should be accounted for not just by actual generosity, but also by the extent to</cell></row><row><cell>participants' subjective beliefs about what would count as a fair amount to give, before rank tests). In addition, when comparing the two groups directly, violators showed a which actual generosity deviates from personal standards. To formally test this</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">they made their decisions. We predicted that, independent of how much participants significantly greater bias toward self-serving memory errors (Wexp.2=3710, p&lt;.001, possibility, we compared a model predicting recalled generosity from actual generosity,</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">actually gave, misremembering would occur specifically among those participants whose d=.68, δ=.35; Wexp.3=28390.5, p=.001, d=.43, δ=.14; Mann-Whitney U tests).</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">true generosity fell short of what they personally believed was fair. To confirm that misremembering is driven primarily by violating one's personal</cell></row><row><cell>In addition, we tested whether this effect persists when we introduce a stronger standard of fairness, rather than their overt level of giving, we next assessed whether</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">incentive to be accurate. In Experiments 1 and 2, accurate recall was incentivized with a participants' objective level of generosity would still show an influence on memory when</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">fixed bonus, such that participants received a bonus if their recalled generosity was within excluding violators from analyses. In other words, does misremembering occur among</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">10% of their true average. To up the stakes, in Experiment 3, we offered a monetary those who give objectively lower amounts, but do not violate their own fairness standard?</cell></row><row><cell>bonus that scaled directly with accuracy, such that even a 1% deviation in recalled To test this, we performed a median split on the generosity of only upholders, dividing</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">generosity would reduce the participant's bonus. them into a behaviorally stingy group (Nexp.2=82; Nexp.3=230) and a behaviorally generous</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Across Experiments 2 and 3, participants again showed a systematic bias towards group (Nexp.2=83; Nexp.3=231; see Supplementary Table 2).</cell></row><row><cell>self-serving memory errors, such that their recalled generosity was significantly greater In support of our hypothesis that violating one's personal standards drives</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">than their actual generosity (Vexp.2=4450, p=.003, d=.21, δ=.11; Vexp.3=7990.5, misremembering, we found no evidence of a bias towards self-serving memory errors in</cell></row><row><cell>p=.008, d=.13, δ=.05; Wilcoxon signed-rank tests; Supplementary Table 1). either behaviorally stingy upholders (Vexp.2=112, p=.51, d=.07, δ=.04;</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Vexp.3=1476.5, p=.11, d=.14, δ=.05, Wilcoxon signed-rank tests), nor behaviorally Misremembering as a motivated phenomenon</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>with one predicting recalled generosity from both actual generosity and the deviation between actual generosity and personal standards. Importantly, we controlled for four other predictors of memory in each model: choice speed (the average time participants took to make their choices), choice variance (the standard deviation of their choices), non-giving (whether or not they ever gave a positive amount across their choices), and numeracy (their performance on a numeracy task between making and recalling their choices). As predicted, we found that the model which additionally included fairness deviations accounted for recalled generosity better than the simpler model that did not include fairness deviations as a predictor (ΔAICexp.2=11.47, ΔBIC=8.02, χ2 (1)=13.47, p&lt;.001; ΔAICexp.3=6.33, ΔBIC=1.92, χ2(1)=8.33, p=.004; likelihood-ratio tests; Supplementary Tables 5 and 6).violators) would tend to recall giving more than they actually did, while those who gave more than their personal standard (i.e., exceeders) would tend to recall giving less than they actually did. However, if misremembering is in fact motivated, we would only expect misremembering to occur among violators, whereas exceeders should tend to recall their choices accurately. To test these possibilities, across Experiments 2 and 3, we examined memory errors in exceeders (Nexp.2=69; Nexp.3=207; see Supplementary Table 2)-a group that showed a similar degree of norm deviation and choice variance as violators (see Supplementary Results). In support of our hypothesis that misremembering is motivated, we found no evidence of misremembering towards the norm in exceeders (Vexp.2= 587.5, p=.48, d &lt;.001, δ = -0.04; Vexp.3=1704.5, p=.99, d=.04, δ=.01; Wilcoxon signed-rank tests), and violators misremembered to a significantly greater degree than exceeders (Wexp.2= 1537, p&lt;.001, d=.57, δ=.35; Wexp.3=12767.5, p=.015, d=.31, δ=.14; Mann-Whitney U tests). Nevertheless, even if exceeders show no bias on average, a rational inference account would still find partial support if exceeders were more likely to make errors in the direction of their norm (i.e., norm-directed memory errors) than in the opposite direction. To address this question, we compared the frequency of errors made in each MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 13 direction by exceeders and violators.CI[.40, .62])). These results are inconsistent with a rational inference account, but consistent with a motivated account of misremembering. Motive-dependence and choice-independence The findings of Experiments 2 and 3 cohere with the possibility that the memory bias we observe is a motivated phenomenon. However, they only demonstrate this phenomenon indirectly. A motivated account of misremembering would receive compelling evidence over a rational inference account with direct evidence for two key conditions. First, motivated misremembering should be motive-dependent. That is, misremembering should occur only when people have a motive to misremember, and should cease to occur if motives to misremember are removed. In particular, a rich, long standing literature on motivated cognition suggests that when people no longer view themselves as personally responsible for a dissonance-inducing action, they no longer experience dissonance motivation</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, δ=.24; Mann-Whitney U test). By contrast, in Experiment 4b, forced-choice participants did not show a significant bias towards self-serving memory errors (V=16087.5, p=.16, d=.11, δ=.05, Wilcoxon ranked-sum test; Supplementary Table 1). Further analyses revealed that similar to free-choice upholders, forced-choice upholders (N=362) did not exhibit selfserving memory errors (V=3393, p=.14, d=.02, δ=-.02; Wilcoxon ranked-sum test). Forced-choice violators (N=217)-despite not freely choosing to violate their normnevertheless did recall on average being more generous than they actually were (V=4580.5, p&lt;.001; d=.28, δ=.15, Wilcoxon ranked-sum test). However, the magnitude of misremembering was smaller in forced-choice violators (d=.28, δ=.15) than freechoice violators (d=.40, δ=.26). We also found that forced-choice violators showed a greater bias toward self-serving memory errors than upholders (W=33105.5, p&lt;.001, d=.34, δ=.16, Mann-Whitney U test), though again this effect was smaller than the difference between free-choice violators and upholders in Experiment 4a (d=.43, δ=.24).</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, p=.019, d=.20, δ=.14; Wilcoxon ranked-sum test; Supplementary Table 1). More specifically, violators (N=79) showed a significant bias toward self-serving memory errors (V=1258.5, p&lt;.001, d=.50, δ=.46;</figDesc><table><row><cell>MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING</cell><cell>19</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, d=.03, δ=.01; Wilcoxon ranked-sum test; Supplementary Table 1). In particular, neither violators in this group of participants (N=138; V=874, p=.61, d=.05, δ=-.02; Wilcoxon ranked-sum test; Fig. 3a) nor upholders (N=270; V=1600.5, p=.93, d=.03, δ=.02, Wilcoxon rankedsum test) showed any bias toward self-serving memory errors. Moreover, violators and upholders did not differ in the extent of their self-serving memory errors</figDesc><table /><note>(W=19171.5, p=.57, d=.01, δ=.03; Mann-Whitney U test).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>20Crucially, forced-choice violators who felt responsible reported significantly larger self-serving memory errors than forced-choice violators who did not feel responsible (W=3222, p&lt;.001, d=.60, δ=.41; Mann-Whitney U test). Moreover, free-</figDesc><table><row><cell>choice violators in Experiment 4a made significantly larger self-serving memory errors</cell></row><row><cell>than forced-choice violators in Experiment 4b who did not feel responsible (W=</cell></row><row><cell>19925.5, p&lt;.001, d=.44, δ=.25; Mann-Whitney U test).</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>).Crucially, here we focused on relatively minor fairness violations, which occurred anonymously. As such, we anticipated that the intensity of negative emotion experienced by agents would not be strong enough to elicit preferential encoding of their own actions-a prediction supported by the presence of self-serving memory errors across our three experiments. Ultimately, uncovering how memory for selfishness shifts as a function of (i) the degree of harm caused by the choice and (ii) the presence of others remain exciting and important directions for future work to explore.</figDesc><table><row><cell>If we accept the possibility that people can misremember their misdeeds, what</cell></row><row><cell>cognitive and neural mechanisms might facilitate this effect? Motivated misremembering</cell></row></table><note>could plausibly emerge at any stage of memory (encoding, consolidation, or retrieval)</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. To this end, individuals might suppress retrieving their more selfish choices. Engaging in this form of motivated control over MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 25 memory-suppression-induced forgetting-has been shown to not only prevent the suppressed memory from entering conscious awareness, but also reduce its accessibility during subsequent retrieval attempts<ref type="bibr" target="#b61">62,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">63</ref> . Such findings suggest that even if selfish and fair choices are stored with equal fidelity, selfish choices may nonetheless become less accessible over time, leading one to preferentially recall choices that better align with one's moral self-view. This raises at least one key direction for future work: since misremembering was more likely to occur when people varied in their choices, it could be strategic to vary the specific amount one gives each time to facilitate motivated misremembering.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>in Experiment 2, we probed participants' fairness standards by asking them to indicate what they believed to be the "maximum acceptable share" for Participant 1 (the decider) to keep. Half of participants indicated their fairness standards before learning they were assigned the role of Participant 1, and the other half indicated their fairness standard after learning their role. The timing of the fairness standards question had no influence on the MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 28 results, and thus we collapsed across these conditions in all analyses for Experiment 2 (see Supplementary Results for more details).In both experiments, participants were ultimately assigned to the role of dictator average, they transferred to the recipient. Participants were asked to record their response on a provided answer sheet. To motivate participants to recall their choices accurately, they were informed that they would receive an additional CHF 5 if their response was within 10% of their actual average transfer. This setup ensured that participants had no incentive to consciously lie. At the recall phase, participants knew that there would be no future interactions with any partners. They also knew that their reported memories were accessible by the research team-who also had access to the participants true choices in order to determine their accuracy bonus. Such knowledge is known to reduce lying<ref type="bibr" target="#b48">49</ref> . . 28 participants were excluded for failing at least one of our comprehension checks. Moreover, 5 participants were excluded for reporting suspicion about key aspects of the task. Finally, 11 participants were excluded for being extreme outliers (i.e., &gt; 4 standard deviations from the mean) in the size of their memory errors. This left a total sample of Unlike the prior experiments, participants were not informed of the size of this bonus until after the experiment. In addition, all participants in this experiment made fairness judgements without prior knowledge of whether they would be assigned as Participant 1 (the decider) or Participant 2 (the receiver). Here, we probed fairness standards by asking participants to report what they believed to be the minimum acceptable share for Participant 1 (the decider) to transfer to Participant 2 (the receiver).</figDesc><table><row><cell>MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING</cell><cell>29 30 31</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">(Participant 1) for a series of five modified dictator games, each with a unique anonymous partner. As dictators, participants made choices about an endowment that could range in size from CHF 10 to CHF 30, however its size was unknown at the time of choice. For each of their five choices, participants had to select what percentage of the endowment they would like to keep for themselves, and what percentage they would transfer to the anonymous recipient, in 10% increments ranging from [Keep 100%, Send 0%] to [Keep 0%, Send 100%]. They were informed that one of their choices would be randomly selected and implemented, and that the size of the endowment would also be never chose to give money in our task (N=100), as well as when we include all participants in our analyses (see Supplementary Results). The Yale University Human Investigation Committee approved the procedures for Experiment 3. The experiment complied with all relevant ethical regulations for work with human participants and all participants provided informed consent. endowment, on Experiments 3: Online participants task)604 participants. Our findings remain consistent when we also exclude subjects who actual average transfer rate.</cell></row><row><cell>randomly determined and revealed at the end of the experiment. Importantly, it was In Experiment 3, we determined our sample size by focusing on achieving Experiments 3: Online procedure</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">emphasized to participants that there would be no further interaction with the recipient sufficient power within our main groups of interest: violators and upholders. For The experimental protocol for Experiment 3 was largely identical to Experiment</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">after making their choices. Experiment 3, a power analysis showed that a minimum sample size of N=128 would be 2, with a few exceptions. Like Experiments 1 and 2, choices were made consecutively on</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Choices were made consecutively on separate screens (for further details on needed to attain approximately 95% power to detect a small to medium-sized effect (d ≈ separate screens. Before each choice screen, participants saw an intermediary screen for 3</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">choice format, see Supplementary Methods). After the participant selected and confirmed 0.30) at an alpha level of 0.05. We predicted that at least 25% of participants would seconds that said "Round # will now begin."</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">their choice, the screen advanced to the next choice after a 1-second delay. After making violate their personal standard of fairness based on Experiment 2, and thus determined As dictators, participants made choices about an endowment that could range in</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">their five choices, participants completed demographic measures (age, gender, education) that a minimum total sample size of 128 x 4=512 participants would be needed. size from 10 to 30 cents. Like before, the size of this endowment was unknown at the</cell></row><row><cell>as well as a test of numeracy 68 . The numeracy test took approximately 5 minutes, 647 participants (344 female, 301 male, 2 did not specify; mean age=36.4) time of choice.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ensuring that participants' previous dictator game choices would no longer be in their completed Experiment 3. All participants were recruited from Amazon Mechanical Turk. One crucial difference from prior experiments was how we incentivized the</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">short-term memory 69 . Since this experiment was conducted online, we also included a series of comprehension surprise memory test: participants were informed at the test that they would receive a</cell></row><row><cell>Finally, participants were presented with a surprise incentivized memory test in checks and attention probes (including transcribing several sentences of text, as well as scaling monetary bonus for accurately recalling their generosity, such that they would</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">which they were asked to recall their previous choices and indicate what percent of the two binary questions in which we asked participants if they understood key aspects of the lose 2% of their bonus for each 1% their recalled average transfer rate deviated from their</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>People's reported standard of fairness were highly correlated with their actual behavior in Experiment 2 (rs=.78, p&lt;.001), Experiment 3 (rs=.55, p&lt;.001), and Experiment 4a (rs=.72, p&lt;.001)-suggesting MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 36 that such standards reflected a meaningful guide for people's actual behavior (see Supplementary Text for additional analyses). Since participants did not freely make choices in Experiment 4b, we did not test internal validity in this experiment.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>an individual engaged in motivated misremembering or not: their affective state and their moral self-view. Moreover, in Experiments 4a and 4b, we explored an additional factor MOTIVATED MISREMEMBERING 37 that could shift as a function of whether an individual engaged in motivated misremembering or not: psychological discomfort. For further details, see Supplementary Methods and Results.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Marcia Johnson for providing thoughtful comments on earlier versions of the manuscript. We also thank members of the Crockett Lab-and especially Jen Siegel, Vlad Chituc, Daniel Yudkin, Clara Colombatto, and Xanni Brown-for scientific discussions and helpful feedback on this work.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability</head><p>Raw data for all experiments are publicly available in an Open Science Framework (OSF) repository (osf.io/pzwt7/; [DOI 10.17605/OSF.IO/PZWT7]). A reporting summary for this Article is available as a Supplementary Information file.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Code availability</head><p>Analysis code for all experiments are also publicly available in the same OSF repository (osf.io/pzwt7/). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contributions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conflict of interest statement</head><p>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivated recruitment of autobiographical memories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sanitioso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Kunda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">229</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The totalitarian ego: Fabrication and revision of personal history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="603" to="618" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lying in everyday life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Depaulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kashy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kirkendol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">979</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dictator games: A meta study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Exp. Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="583" to="610" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incentives and prosocial behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bénabou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. Econ. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1652" to="1678" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting moral wiggle room: experiments demonstrating an illusory preference for fairness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Kuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econ. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="80" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dishonesty of honest people: A theory of selfconcept maintenance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Amir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mark. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="633" to="644" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Our evolving beliefs about evolved misbelief</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mckay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Brain Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="541" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On happiness and human potentials: A review of research on hedonic and eudaimonic well-being</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Deci</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu. Rev. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="166" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Illusion and well-being: a social psychological perspective on mental health</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">193</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why do we hate hypocrites? Evidence for a theory of false signaling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sommers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bloom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="356" to="368" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sexual selection for moral virtues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Q. Rev. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-deception facilitates interpersonal persuasion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Trivers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Von Hippel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econ. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reflections on self-deception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Von</forename><surname>Hippel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Trivers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Brain Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The case for motivated reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Kunda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">480</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-serving justifications: Doing wrong and feeling moral</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shalvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Barkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ayal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Dir. Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The actor-observer asymmetry in attribution: A (surprising) metaanalysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Malle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">132</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">895</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I&apos;m not the person I used to be: The self and autobiographical memories of immoral actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stanley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Henne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Sinnott-Armstrong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>De Brigard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Psychol. Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">146</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">884</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Autobiographical memory and conceptions of self: Getting better all the time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Dir. Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="69" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Excusing selfishness in charitable giving: The role of risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Exley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econ. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="587" to="628" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Motivated Errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Exley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kessler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3511305" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing models of information avoidance with binary choice dictator games</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Feiler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econ. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting moral wiggle room: Illusory preference for fairness? A comment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Capra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgm. Decis. Mak</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">467</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural mechanisms of motivated forgetting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hanslmayr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memories of unethical actions become obfuscated over time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kouchaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6166" to="6171" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sweeping dishonesty under the rug: How unethical actions lead to forgetting of moral rules</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Shu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1164</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dishonest deed, clear conscience: When cheating leads to moral disengagement and motivated forgetting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Shu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bazerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pers. Soc. Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="330" to="349" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">No evidence for unethical amnesia for imagined actions: A failed replication and extension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stanley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brigard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13421-018-0803-y</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mem. Cognit</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivated memory in dictator games</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Saucet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Villeval</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games Econ. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="275" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Belief and recollection of autobiographical memories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Schrauf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mem. Cognit</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="887" to="901" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accurate forced-choice recognition without awareness of memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Baym</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Paller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Learn. Mem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="454" to="459" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-perception theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in experimental social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biases in social comparative judgments: the role of nonmotivated factors in above-average and comparative-optimism effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Windschitl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">813</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lake Wobegon be gone! The&quot; below-average effect&quot; and the egocentric nature of comparative ability judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kruger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">221</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The benefits and costs of a rose-colored hindsight</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kappes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="644" to="646" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ethical dissonance, justifications, and moral behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Barkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ayal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="157" to="161" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ethical mirage: A temporal explanation as to why we are not as ethical as we think we are</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tenbrunsel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Diekmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wade-Benzoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bazerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Res. Organ. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="173" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fair shares: Accountability and cognitive dissonance in allocation decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Konow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. Econ. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1072" to="1091" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new look at dissonance theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Fazio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in experimental social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="266" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Denial of responsibility: a new mode of dissonance reduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Gosling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Denizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Oberlé</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">722</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivational basis of dissonance: The singular role of behavioral consequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Scher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">899</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wicklund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Brehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on cognitive dissonance</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taking a closer look: Reasserting the role of the selfconcept in dissonance theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thibodeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pers. Soc. Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="591" to="602" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Obedience and responsibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mantell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Panzarella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br. J. Soc. Clin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="245" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The descent of man and selection in relation to sex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Darwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1888" />
			<publisher>Murray</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A self-serving bias in children&apos;s memories?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tasimi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Psychol. Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">144</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">528</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivated to &quot;forget&quot; the effects of in-group wrongdoing on memory and collective guilt</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rotella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Richeson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Psychol. Personal. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="730" to="737" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The illusion of moral superiority</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tappin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mckay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Psychol. Personal. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="623" to="631" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lying Aversion and the Size of the Lie</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kajackaite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. Econ. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Amygdala Activity Is Associated with the Successful Encoding of Item, But Not Source, Information for Positive and Negative Stimuli</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kensinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Schacter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2564" to="2570" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guilt following transgression: An attribution of responsibility approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mcgraw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">247</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motives matter: The emotional consequences of recalled self-and other-focused prosocial acts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wiwad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Aknin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Motiv. Emot</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="730" to="740" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Autobiographical memory for shame or guilt provoking events: Association with psychological symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinaugh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcnally</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Res. Ther</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="646" to="652" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of public exposure in moral and nonmoral shame and guilt</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Webster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Parrott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Eyre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">138</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conveniently upset: Avoiding altruism by distorting beliefs about others&apos; altruism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Di Tella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Perez-Truglia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Babino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sigman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. Econ. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3416" to="3458" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Principles of learning and memory: Classic edition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Crowder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social Cognition 2.0: An Interactive Memory Systems Account</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Amodio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interactions between attention and memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Turk-Browne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Neurobiol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="184" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Top-down attention switches coupling between low-level and high-level areas of human visual cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Al-Aidroos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Said</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Turk-Browne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14675" to="14680" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wishful thinking and source monitoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Franklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mem. Cognit</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="418" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Memory</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Reality</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">760</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Suppressing unwanted memories reduces their unconscious influence via targeted cortical inhibition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Gagnepain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Henson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1310" to="1319" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Suppressing unwanted memories by executive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">410</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">366</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Post-learning Hippocampal Dynamics Promote Preferential Retention of Rewarding Events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gruber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ritchey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-F</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Doss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ranganath</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1110" to="1120" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A neural signature of contextually mediated intentional forgetting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychon. Bull. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1534" to="1542" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opposing mechanisms support the voluntary forgetting of unwanted memories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Benoit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="450" to="460" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two years later-Revisiting autobiographical memory representations in vmPFC and hippocampus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bonnici</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Maguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Numeracy and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="407" to="413" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The control of short-term memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shiffrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Am</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">225</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">homogeneous versions of the Marlow-Crowne Social Desirability Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Strahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gerbasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Short</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Clin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="191" to="193" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Motivated Misremembering</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
