<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic changes in task preparation in a multi-task environment: The task transformation paradigm</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mengqiao</forename><surname>Chai</surname></persName>
							<email>mengqiao.chai@ugent.be</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ghent University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Henri Dunantlaan 2</addrLine>
									<postCode>9000</postCode>
									<settlement>Ghent</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clay</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Holroyd</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ghent University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Henri Dunantlaan 2</addrLine>
									<postCode>9000</postCode>
									<settlement>Ghent</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcel</forename><surname>Brass</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ghent University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Henri Dunantlaan 2</addrLine>
									<postCode>9000</postCode>
									<settlement>Ghent</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Mind and Brain</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Luisenstraße 56, Haus 1</addrLine>
									<postCode>10117</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin, Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Senne</forename><surname>Braem</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ghent University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Henri Dunantlaan 2</addrLine>
									<postCode>9000</postCode>
									<settlement>Ghent</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ghent University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic changes in task preparation in a multi-task environment: The task transformation paradigm</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:58+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A key element of human flexible behavior concerns the ability to continuously predict and prepare for sudden changes in tasks or actions. Here, we tested whether people can dynamically modulate task preparation processes and decision-making strategies when the identity of a to-be-performed task becomes uncertain. To this end, we developed a new paradigm where participants need to prepare for one of nine tasks on each trial. Crucially, in some blocks, the task being prepared could suddenly shift to a different task after a longer cue-target interval, by changing either the stimulus category or categorization rule that defined the initial task. We found that participants were able to dynamically modulate task preparation in the face of this task uncertainty. A second experiment shows that these changes in behavior were not simply a function of decreasing task expectancy, but rather of increasing switch expectancy. Finally, in the third and fourth experiment, we demonstrate that these dynamic modulations can be applied in a compositional manner, depending on whether either only the stimulus category or categorization rule would be expected to switch.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Humans show remarkable flexibility in adaptively adjusting and controling their intentions, as often required in a fast-changing world with high levels of uncertainty. For instance, imagine being a basketball player and suddenly seeing the opposite team running towards you with the ball. By monitoring potential moves, passes, and ball trajectories, you have to actively prepare different defensive strategies, while at the same time being prepared to switch from defense to offense, whenever you or a teammate would catch the ball. The need for cognitive flexibility is remarkable considering all the potential ball trajectories and the corresponding tactics the player has to prepare for in a such rapidly changing condition, all within a matter of seconds. Daily examples as these truly highlight the need for agents to actively draw inferences on the state-of-the-world, and, in accordance, dynamically prepare and implement the appropriate task to achieve their goals. As we will motivate below, we believe the literature is in need for a new experimental paradigm that allows us to investigate such dynamic task preparation in the context of multi-task environments.</p><p>In the lab, researchers have used various paradigms to study task preparation. One of the most frequently used paradigms is task switching, wherein participants are usually asked to perform two different tasks throughout the experiment. Although countless variations of this paradigm have been used (for reviews, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Monsell, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Kiesel et al., 2010)</ref>, one shared finding is that people typically perform worse, responding both slower and less accurately, when switching to a different task (switch trials) compared to repeating a task (repetition trials), which is often referred to as the switch cost <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Rogers &amp; Monsell, 1995)</ref>. In the task switching literature, the evidence for active task preparation mainly comes from studies that manipulated the length of the interval between the task cue and stimulus onset, namely the cue-target interval (CTI). A common finding is that prolonging the CTI tends to reduce the switch cost (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Meiran, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Koch, 2001)</ref>, indicating task switching benefited from DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 4 advance preparation. However, although task switching offers a useful paradigm to study task preparation in multi-task environments, it typically does not allow for the time-evolving investigation of dynamic changes in behavior and performance when the to-be-performed task is uncertain. That is, first, because task switching studies usually involve only two tasks, they cannot distinguish the preparation for task switching, and its associated task uncertainty, from the configuration of the specific task to switch to. Second, they typically do not allow for investigating dynamic variations of task uncertainty. We will first discuss each of these limitations in detail.</p><p>Classic task switching paradigms typically include two tasks, e.g. a parity and a magnitude judgement on number stimuli (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Sudevan &amp; Taylor, 1987)</ref>. However, the fact that only two tasks are involved means that the preparation for a task switch, or its associated indices of task uncertainty (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Dreisbach &amp; Haider, 2006)</ref>, typically imply configuring the other task. While useful for other research questions, these paradigms cannot be used to address the research questions on task uncertainty in general, as, in daily life, oftentimes we are not sure what specific task is coming, or there can be simply too many alternatives to prepare for at the same time. To address this caveat, some studies made efforts to explore the possibility of preparing for non-specific task switching by working with task switching paradigms which include more than two tasks. For example, Karayandis and colleagues (2009) designed a cued task switching paradigm in which participants categorized compound stimuli based on one of three possible task rules (Color, Letter, or Digit task). Importantly, they used task cues specifying if the next trial would be either a repeat trial, a switch-to trial (in which a specific non-repeating task was cued), a switch-away trial (in which the two nonrepeating tasks were equally likely), or a non-informative trial where either a repeat or specific non-repeat task was possible. <ref type="bibr">Karayanidis and colleagues (2009)</ref> hypothesized that if participants were able to prepare for task switching, without knowing which task to switch to, DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 5 performance should be better in switch-away trials compared to non-informative trials, which was what they observed. Thus, it seems that participants could prepare for task switching without knowing the specific task to switch to (also see <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Nicholson et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Karayanidis et al., 2010)</ref>. However, another study that also included more than two tasks found that cuing participants about a likely task switch did not help their performance on the actual switch trials, thus challenging the possibility of preparing for non-specific switching <ref type="bibr">(Dreisbach, Haider, and Kluwe, 2002, Experiment 5)</ref>. Therefore, whether or not people can prepare for a non-specific switch remains, to a certain degree, an open debate.</p><p>Moreover, although these above-mentioned studies offered an important new window on how people might prepare for task uncertainty in general by including more than two tasks, their alternative task space remained rather limited. For instance, after encountering a switchaway cue in <ref type="bibr">Karayadinis et al. (2009)</ref>, it is conceivable that both alternative tasks could still be prepared for in a specific manner. Furthermore, considering the fact that participants went through extensive training on these three uni-dimensional tasks (almost 1500 trials before the testing session), the specific task information could be highly accessible in their long-term memory, thereby facilitating specific task preparation. Thus, a larger task space or more complex task design are needed to further rule out the possibility of specific task preparation.</p><p>Second, in previous studies, the task switches are usually explicitly cued, which does not reflect well the varying degrees of task uncertainty and switching likelihoods we often experience in daily life. As discussed above, in reality, oftentimes we have to actively draw inferences from the environment, and continuously update our beliefs about the likelihoods of switching. In fact, active inference about one's current state is considered critical for adaptive behavior in a fast-changing world <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bartolo &amp; Averbeck, 2021)</ref>. Along those lines, a recent study by <ref type="bibr">Aufschnaiter and colleauges (2021)</ref> showed that participants were able to exploit the contingency between time (i.e., the length of an inter-trial interval) and the likelihood of task DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 6 switching to better prepare for the switching, indicating that people could update their beliefs based on the elapsed time to better prepare for the incoming task. However, this study used only three tasks and two interval lengths (either short or long ITI), limiting the temporal resolution and, more importantly, inferences in terms of task switching uncertainty versus specific preparation of the alternative task.</p><p>In this study, we wanted to address the above-mentioned limitations by designing a novel paradigm in which participants would experience dynamic variations in task uncertainty.</p><p>Specifically, we created a multi-task environment where participants had to perform nine different image categorization tasks throughout the experiment. These nine tasks were created by factorially combining the stimulus type they needed to focus on (an image depicting either animal, vehicle or place), and the task rule that they had to categorize them on (i.e., identify the subject of the images being old versus young, big versus small, or aquatic versus terrestrial). Crucially, while participants received a new task cue on each trial, we induced time-evolving uncertainty about whether they would actually perform this task, or switch to another one before stimulus onset. Namely, in some blocks, hereafter referred to as transform blocks, long CTIs were associated with a sudden transformation of the task before stimulus presentation, by changing either the stimulus type or categorization rule, essentially requiring a task switch or "transformation" (inspired by a similar manipulation by <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Starkweather et al., 2017</ref>, which investigated the firing of dopaminergic neurons of rodents in anticipation of reward). In order to prepare for this potential task transformation, participants had to actively update their predictions on transformation probability based on the time elapsed during CTI and prepare for this transformation in a non-specific way since participants were not able to predict which task it would be transformed into.</p><p>We believe that this paradigm provides a more precise window to test hypothesized, strategic modulations of task preparation in the face of task uncertaintywhich traditionally DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 7 have been the topic of many classic task switching studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Braem &amp; Egner, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dreisbach &amp; Fröber, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Dreisbach &amp; Haider, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Musslick &amp; Cohen, 2021)</ref>. Specifically, previous empirical and theoretical works on task switching often proposed that under conditions of high task uncertainty, individuals might lower their threshold for updating the contents of working memory (e.g,. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Goschke &amp; Bolte, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dreisbach, &amp; Fröber, 2019)</ref>, relying on relatively shallow instead of deep attractor states (potentially reflecting reduced neural gain, <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Musslick &amp; Cohen, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Ueltzhöffer et al., 2015)</ref>, or less separable task representations (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Musslick et al., 2017)</ref>. In doing do, the to-be-performed task would become destabilized due to less shielded and more noisy task representations. In fact, in <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Karayanidis et al (2009)</ref>, the EEG data indeed suggested the possible inhibition of the previously active but no longer relevant task, thus supporting this hypothesis on strategic task destabilization.</p><p>Notably, there have also been seemingly opposing observations that highlighted the stubbornness of task set activations once being prepared. For example, it has been suggested that, when people prepare for a given task, they tend to rely on procedural, reflex-like representations that are ballistic in nature and resistant to be removed unless a new task instruction is given <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abrahamse et al., 2022)</ref>. This fits well with conclusions from <ref type="bibr">Dreisbach and colleagues (2002)</ref>, who argued that people can only prepare for a task switch, and "inhibit" the previous task, if they know what the incoming task is. Taking together, whether or not people are able to strategically modulate their task preparation in the face of task uncertainty is still unclear. We believe our paradigm will provide an important new testbed for these theories and hypotheses. We predict that if people do adaptively modulate their task preparation, they will exhibit slower and more error-prone responses when the task uncertainty increased, possibly realized by actively destabilizing task representation in anticipation of a potential sudden task switch (i.e. task transformation in the current study).</p><p>Moreover, we expected that participants would be more likely to be distracted by irrelevant DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 8 task information when the task uncertainty increased, potentially reflecting less shielded task representation.</p><p>Over four experiments, we first investigated whether participants could actively modulate their task preparations in a dynamic way based on inferred probability of task transformation (Experiment 1). In Experiment 2, we aimed to distinguish this active modulation on task preparation from passive task degradation by means of a control experiment where participants had to prepare for a task omission instead of a task transformation. In Experiment 3 and 4, we further examined if and how participants actively prepared for a task transformation when only one dimension of the task was subject to transformation (i.e., either stimulus type or task rule).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>9</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1</head><p>As mentioned above, one of the objectives of the current study was to investigate if people can prepare for task uncertainty in general (e.g., by lowering a general updating threshold). To this end, we created a larger task space than the typical use of two tasks in task switching research by factorially combining two task dimensions (i.e., stimulus type and task rule), with three options each, into nine different tasks (see Panel A of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). This multidimensional task design was inspired by studies using rapid instructed task learning <ref type="bibr">(RITL)</ref> paradigms (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Cole, Laurent, &amp; Stocco, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Cole et al., 2018)</ref>. Unlike task switching paradigms in which participants are able to predict which task to perform next when expecting a task switch, the large number of tasks we created precluded participants from predicting and preparing for any specific task even if a task transformation was expected.</p><p>The outline of the paradigm is presented in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Each trial started with a task cue specifying both task dimensions. The task cue was followed by a variable cue-target interval (CTI), during which participants were encouraged to prepare for the task. At the end of CTI, three, vertically aligned images appeared on screen depicting different stimulus types: an animal, a place, and a vehicle. Participants were asked to respond to the stimuli based on the task cue presented at the beginning of the trial. For example, when the task cue was "place" and "big | small" (see regular trial on Panel B of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>), this meant that participants would have to respond based on whether the place image could be categorized as either big or small, by pressing left or right key. In this example on <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, participants were required to press the left key because the place image portrayed a large multi-storey office building.</p><p>Two block types were created as two separate contexts in the current study (see panel D of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). In "regular blocks", all trials would proceed as described above (as regular trials). However, on "transform blocks", people could also encounter "transform trials" on DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 10 9% of the trials. On these transform trials, the initial task cue would be followed by a second task cue, once the CTI was near its maximum interval (see the transform trial on Panel B of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). When this second task cue appeared, participants were required to respond to the stimuli based on the second cue instead of the first one, meaning the first task cue became obsolete. We hypothesized that the inclusion of these small amount of transform trials (i.e., 9% of the trials in transform blocks), would impose a need for flexible modulation of task preparation throughout transform blocks. In contrast, there was no such need in the regular blocks. Specifically, we hypothesized that, during the CTI, participants would first actively prepare for the original task, and then dynamically modulate this task preparation as the CTI progressed, because task transformation, if it happened, could only appear during the later intervals. Such modulation could be realized by destabilizing the original task set. Moreover, the manipulation of both block type (regular versus transform blocks) and CTI length further allowed us to test whether such modulation manifested itself in a more tonic manner, as indexed by a main effect of block type, or also in a more dynamic manner, by examining the interaction effect between CTI and block type.</p><p>In addition to the CTI effect predicted above, we also looked for potential modulation of congruency effects as another indicator of whether increased task uncertainty would destabilize the current task under preparation. Previous studies already established the association between the integrity of a task set and the strength of congruency effects (e.g. That is, when the strength of to-be-performed task set is weaker, participants tend to be more caught up by irrelevant task information, thus leading to stronger congruency effects. In the current study, we predict that if the original task is destabilized when the task transformation is expected in transform blocks, participants' responses would be more strongly influenced DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 11 by both irrelevant images and irrelevant task rules, thus giving rise to stronger "stimulus-"</p><p>and "task-rule-" congruency effects.</p><p>In short, by manipulating the broader context (i.e., transform blocks versus regular blocks) and the relevance of the CTI (i.e., as task transformation would only appear on later intervals in transform blocks), we could investigate whether people were able to dynamically infer the level of task uncertainty based on the context they are in, and modulate their task preparations accordingly to achieve optimal performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1. A schematic illustration of the task transform paradigm</head><p>Note. A. Nine different image categorization tasks were created by factorially combining two task dimensions (i.e., stimulus type and task rule), with three options each. The specific response mapping (e.g. either "young | old" or "old | young") was randomly assigned between participants for each task rule independently. B. A regular trial, shown on the top of the panel, started with a task cue, followed by a cue target interval (CTI) showing three fixation crosses, after which three images depicting an animal, a place, and a vehicle appeared on screen until participant generated a response by pressing either left or right key. In this example, participants would have to respond based on whether the place DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 12 image could be categorized as either big or small. In comparison, in transform trials, what followed the CTI would be another task cue showing a different to-be-performed task. In this case, after the stimulus onset, participants had to perform this new task instead of the original one. C. The length of CTIs were varied across trials. Importantly, the length of CTI was predictive of how likely the task would be transformed (P(transform)). Specifically, the CTIs were put in six bins based on their lengths, with 1 st bin being the shortest, and 6 th bin being the longest. The transform would only happen during the 6 th bin, and the likelihood of transform on this bin is 55.56%. D. Two block types were created, with regular blocks including only regular trials, and transform blocks including both regular trials (91%) and transform trials (9%). Thus, only in the transform blocks, the length of CTI was indicative of the likelihood of task transform.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>All 60 participants (55 females, average age 18.27) were first-year Psychology students with normal or corrected-to-normal vision who study at Ghent University and participated in exchange for course credits. Sample size was determined in order to be able to detect with 80% statistical power the effect size of the interaction term between CTI length and block type from the previous pilot study which had a similar experimental design as the current experiment (see Supplementary Material <ref type="figure">Figure S1</ref>), resulting in a required sample size between 40 -45 participants 1 . Thus, for each experiment, we aimed for around 50 useable participant datasets to make sure we had enough power. Following the data exclusion procedure described below, 51 participants were eligible for data analysis (47 females, average age: 18.29). All participants gave their informed consent before participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Material</head><p>The task stimuli consisted of three vertically aligned stimuli, each of them consisting of a "stimulus type". The three types of stimuli were animals, places, and vehicles. For each stimulus type, there are three possible task rules that can be applied. Therefore, eight images (2*2*2) were needed for each stimulus type. In total, there were twenty-four images (3*8), all of which were collected from freely available online resources. The stimuli can be found on our osf project page (https://osf.io/zyfb9/). All images were decoloured as grayscale and cropped into the same size. Stimulus presentation, and the whole task more generally, was programmed in JsPsych version 6.1 (de Leeuw, J. R., 2015).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task and procedure</head><p>Participants were first required to give informed consent and provide demographic information, including age, sex, and handedness. Next, they were presented with the general task instructions. To ensure all participants knew how to correctly categorize all twenty-four stimuli according to the three rules, each participant went through a training phase where all stimulus-rule combinations were practiced before starting the main experiment. For example, an image of modern cruise ship had to be categorized as big in terms of size, young in terms of age, and aquatic in terms of habitat. Participants were required to categorize each image correctly before moving on to the main experiment.</p><p>The main experiment included three regular and three transform blocks. In regular blocks, all trials were regular trials, whereas, in transform blocks, 91% of trials were regular trials and the remaining 9% were transform trials ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, Panel D). Participants were informed about these two block types, and the presence of transform trials in the transform blocks. They were not instructed on the specific number of transform trials, to ensure that they would always prepare for possible transform trials throughout the transform block. The DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 14 experiment either started with three consecutive regular blocks, followed by three transform blocks, or vice versa, counterbalanced across participants. This design choice was motivated by pilot data suggesting that participants experienced more difficulties with switching back and forth between the different strategies if the two block types constantly alternated.</p><p>Participants were reminded of the block type they were in at the beginning of each block.</p><p>Each block was composed of 54 trials. Each trial started with a task cue specifying which task that needed to be performed on this trial. The task cue was shown in the centre of screen for 1000 ms, with stimulus type on the top and task rule below (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1)</ref>. The exact task was randomly drawn from a discrete uniform distribution with each compound task (nine of them in total) being equally likely.</p><p>The task cue was followed by a fixation cross that gradually increased in size as time passed, which provided visual feedback to the participants on the passage of time. The length of the CTI was sampled from a quasi-exponential distribution (M = 2891 ms) between 1000 ms and 7000 ms, with more trials with shorter CTIs than longer ones to encourage participants to actively prepare for the task as early as possible. To further remind participants of the block type they were in, the fixation cross during the CTI was displayed in a different hue, either purple(#B200ED) or green(#3BB143). The hue to block type assignment was randomly determined across participants.</p><p>On regular trials, three images depicting an animal, a place, and a vehicle were displayed on screen. The location (top, middle or bottom) of each stimulus type was randomly determined per trial, which means that the location of each stimulus type could not be predicted. Participants were asked to perform an image categorization task based on the preceding task cue, and to respond by pressing either the left ("F") or the right ("J") key within 2000 ms. The response mapping of each task rule was randomly assigned across DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 15 participants. Following the response or (if no response was made) the response deadline, feedback was presented for 750 ms. Feedback consisted of the message "well done!", "incorrect!", or "too slow!", depending on whether the response was correct, incorrect, or missing, respectively.</p><p>On transform trials, the CTI was followed by a new and different task cue for 750 ms before the stimulus onset. All the transform trials had relatively long CTIs. Specifically, all 54 possible CTIs per block were rank-ordered and put into six bins of nine values per bin, with the first bin being the shortest CTIs and the sixth bin being the longest CTIs. In each transform block, five transform trials were then randomly selected from the sixth bin of CTIs.</p><p>In other words, the five transform trials were always among the nine trials with the longest CTIs.</p><p>After each block, participants were informed of their overall accuracy on the previous block. If their performance was below 80%, feedback was provided encouraging them to put in more effort in order to perform better. The whole experiment took around one hour.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analysis</head><p>The analysis pipeline was pre-registered on OSF (https://osf.io/tmx4r). All data processing and analyses were conducted using R (R Core Team, 2017). Participants whose overall accuracy was below 60% in either regular trials (across both block types) or transform trials were removed from the analyses. Similarly, participants whose average RT or error rate (ER) exceeded ± 2.5 standard deviation (SD) from the group mean were also discarded. Next, trials following errors or with a RT faster than 200 ms were removed from analyses. Error trials were also excluded from RT analysis. Finally, trials with RTs ±2.5 SD from the individual mean were also excluded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>16</head><p>We also quantified an incongruency level for both stimulus type and task rule, separately for each trial. Stimulus type incongruency was defined as the number of images on display that afforded a different response for the current task rule. Specifically, among the three images displayed during stimuli presentation, two of them were always task-irrelevant.</p><p>Stimulus type incongruency was 0 if both irrelevant pictures required the same responses as the target image did, 1 if only one of the irrelevant images afforded a different response, and 2 if both irrelevant images afforded different responses. Higher levels of incongruency would give rise to stronger response conflict that participants needed to overcome in order to respond correctly. An example is illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. Task rule incongruency, on the other hand, stems from the fact that the target image was also trivalent, meaning that it could be used for all three task rules. The activation of the two currently irrelevant task rules could trigger their own responses that could either be compatible or incompatible with the response of the currently relevant task rule. Similar to the stimulus type incongruency, task rule incongruency was 0 when the responses were the same across the three task rules of the target image, 1 if one of the irrelevant task rules afforded a different response, and 2 if both irrelevant task rules afforded different responses than that of the currently relevant task rule (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). Note. Response conflicts on each trial come from two sources: the irrelevant images and irrelevant task rules. The stimulus type incongruency was used to quantity the response conflicts induced by irrelevant images. In the example, the correct response is the left key press ("big" in black) based on the task cue, the irrelevant images afforded one left key press ("big" in orange) and one right key press ("small" in orange). Thus, the stimulus type incongruency equals to 1. On the other hand, the task rule incongruency quantities the response conflicts induced by irrelevant task rules. Since both irrelevant task rules required a left key press ("young" and "land" in purple) in this example, the task rule incongruency equals 2.</p><p>The RT and accuracy data of the regular trials were analysed using linear mixed effect models, using lme4 for R <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bates et al, 2014)</ref>. RT and accuracy were regressed on the interaction between block type (regular block vs. transform block), and CTI length, stimulus type incongruency, as well as task rule incongruency. A random intercept was included in the model to account for the random effect of participants (lme formular: RT ~ (CTI + stimulus type incongruency + task rule incongruency) * block type + (1 | subject)). Note that although <ref type="bibr">Barr and colleagues (2013)</ref> proposed that the maximal random effect structure for the model should be reported, previous attempts to include maximal random effect structure oftentimes resulted in failed convergence, which required differential treatments in order for them to converge (e.g. steps suggested in https://rpubs.com/bbolker/lme4trouble1). Moreover, it has also been argued that models with maximal random effect structure could lead to significant loss of power (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Bates et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Matuschek et al., 2017)</ref>. For these reasons, we report the statistical results with only random intercept in the model, as preregistered. However, the results of the maximal models of all experiments that did converge were included in the supplementary material <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table S1</ref> to S4) as an effort to rule out potential inflation of Type 1 errors. Linear regression was used to model the RT data, whereas logistic regression was used to model the accuracy data. Note that only the regular trials in both block types were included in the analysis, so we could study the effect of the block context on task preparation using the DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 18 exact same trial types. The statistical significance of the linear mixed effect model was determined by running the F-test with Satterthwaite approximation for degrees of freedom, which is implemented by package lmerTest <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Kuznetsova, Brockhoff, &amp; Christensen, 2017)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The results of the mixed linear effect model on RT are displayed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>, but here we only discuss main findings. The analysis revealed a significant main effect of CTI, β = -8.889, SE = 1.898, p &lt; .001, with longer CTIs yielding faster responses, indicating that, in general, participants actively prepared for the task during the CTI window. Moreover, we found evidence that participants' reaction times were sensitive to the task rule incongruency, as its main effect was significant, β = 22.738, SE = 3.825, p &lt; .001, showing slower responses for more incongruent trials. Critically, we observed the significant interaction between CTI length and block type, β = -7.296, SE = 1.898, p &lt; .001, as presented in the upper panel of <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>. In the regular blocks, there was a strong linear effect of CTI length, β = -16.185, SE = 2.393, p &lt; .001, with longer CTI yielding faster response. In comparison, such linear effect of CTI length in transform block was not significant, β = -1.593, SE = 2.946, p = .589. As demonstrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>, there was actually a linearly decreasing trend in transform blocks, similar to regular blocks, but only until between 3 and 4 seconds. From then onwards, RT increased when the CTI was longer, forming a U-shaped pattern in the transform blocks. In fact, when fitting a linear mixed effect model with a quadratic term for CTI length as an exploratory analysis, the quadratic term turned out to be significant in the transform block, β = 13.277, SE = 3.556, p &lt; .001, but not in the regular block, β = 4.322, SE = 2.970, p = .146, which further confirmed the diverging RT pattern as a function of CTI length between these two block types.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>19</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3. Mean RTs of Experiment 1 and Control Experiment as a function of CTI length and block type</head><p>Note. The colored dots represent the mean RT for each CTI length, which was further fitted into a smooth dashed line for each block type using the loess smoothing method, with the surrounding grey band denoting 95% confidence level interval for predictions from the loess regression. The loess smoothing was solely used to better visualize the data, and not used for any statistical analysis. The vertical dashed line denotes the CTI of 4642 ms, longer than which the task could be transformed in the transform block.</p><p>The results of the logistic regression on the accuracy data revealed a main effect of CTI, β = 0.072, SE = 0.021, p = .001, with longer CTI being associated with higher accuracy, DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 20 indicating that task preparation benefited from longer CTIs in general. Unlike the RT result, there was no significant interaction between CTI and block type on accuracy, β = -0.022, SE = 0.021, p &lt; .285. We also observed a significant main effect of task rule incongruency, β = -0.351, SE = 0.040, p &lt; .001, with higher levels of incongruency yielding lower accuracy.</p><p>There was also a marginally significant interaction between task rule incongruency and block type, β = 0.076, SE = 0.040, p = .060, suggesting a stronger congruency effect in transform blocks, β = -0.427, SE = 0.059, p &lt; .001, compared to the regular blocks, β = -0.275, SE = 0.055, p &lt; .001. Although this effect was not significant, the trend is numerically in line with our hypothesis that task representations in transform blocks were destabilized in order to prepare for potential task transformations, thus making them more susceptible to the influence from irrelevant task rules. The main effect of stimulus type incongruency was also significant, β = -0.134, SE = 0.039, p&lt; .001, indicating participants tended to make more errors when irrelevant images afforded different responses from the target image. The interaction between stimulus type incongruency and block type did not reach significance, β = 0.052, SE = 0.039, p= .187. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The aim of the Experiment 1 was to investigate whether participants could dynamically modulate their task preparation under increased levels of task uncertainty (i.e. increased likelihood of the task transformation associated with longer CTIs). The significant interaction between CTI length and block type in RT supported our hypothesis that participants were able to dynamically update their beliefs on the likelihood of task transformation based on the time elapsed during the CTI window, and actively modulated their task preparation accordingly, leading to slower reaction times when a task transformation was expected but did not actually occur. These results are in line with previous studies that similarly suggested that people could prepare for switching, either on the basis of explicit switching cues (e,g, <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Nicholson et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Karayanidis et al., 2009)</ref>, or implicit cues such as the time elapsed between trials <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Aufschnaiter et al., 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Aufschnaiter et al., , 2021</ref>. However, these previous studies typically included only a few simple tasks, and thus cannot fully exclude the possibility of preparing specifically for the task(s) to switch to. Here, by creating a larger task space with an arguably more complex task structure, it is unlikely that people prepared for all possible alternative tasks. Hence, our results demonstrated more convincingly that participants do in fact prepare for non-specific switching, possibly by destabilizing the task representation of tasks that are increasingly likely to be transformed.</p><p>We also quantified how much response conflict participants experienced between the different stimuli and different task rules. The observation of significant congruency effects in both RT and accuracy demonstrated that participants were indeed susceptible to both stimulus and task rule congruency, leading to either slower or less accurate responses for higher levels of incongruency. A marginally significant interaction between task rule incongruency and block type in accuracy further suggested that participants were also more susceptible to task rule congruency in transform blocks compared to regular blocks, suggesting that the task uncertainty embedded in the transform block affected participants' overall task preparation throughout the block, making it harder to suppress task-irrelevant rules during the decisionmaking stage. This modulation of the congruency effect further suggests that, in transform blocks, the task set being prepared was generally destabilized compared to regular blocks.</p><p>That is, the relatively high level of task uncertainty in transform blocks prevented participants from fully preparing for the original task, thus leading to less stable task representations. This result is in line with previous studies demonstrating an association between the integrity of We will further investigate this modulation of the congruency effect in Experiments 3 and 4.</p><p>Although the results from Experiment 1 supported the proposal that participants actively modulate their task preparation when facing varying degrees of task uncertainty, the results can also be interpreted differently. That is, the same RT pattern would also be compatible DYNAMIC</p><note type="other">TASK PREPARATION 23</note><p>with an alternative interpretation that participants merely stopped preparing for the original task due to the decreased likelihood that they would still have to perform it. In this case, the task was not actively destabilized. Instead, the task just naturally lost its strength as time passed during the CTI. To control for this potential interpretation of passive task set degradation, we designed a Control Experiment to examine whether we would observe the same pattern as in Experiment 1, when longer CTIs only signalled that they would no longer have to perform the task, instead of having to perform a transformed task as in Experiment 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2: Control Experiment</head><p>In this Control Experiment, we created a task omit condition, as a comparison to the task transform condition in Experiment 1. In the task omit condition, the length of CTI did not predict the likelihood of a task transformation. Instead, the CTI length was associated with a higher likelihood of task omission, which meant the trial would terminate without the need to respond at all. In other words, the task performance would be omitted in this case, as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>. Similar to Experiment 1, two block types were created: regular blocks and omit blocks. The regular blocks was constructed exactly the same as in Experiment 1. In omit blocks, 9% (i.e. 5 trials) of the trials were omit trials, leaving the majority of the trials (49 trials) still being regular trials. We thus created two block contexts in which participants expected either task omission (the omit block) or not (regular block). In other words, the design of the Control Experiment was comparable to that of Experiment 1, except that the task transform trials were replaced with the task omit trials. We hypothesized that, as participants did not need to prepare for a task transformation in this Control Experiment, they would not show the preparatory slow-down in anticipation of a task transformation. </p><note type="other">TASK PREPARATION 24</note><p>Note. A schematic outline of an omit trial in the Control Experiment. In the omit trial, a pseudo-cue appeared on the screen after the CTI, with "X"s replacing all the letters of a valid task cue. Thus, the pseudo-cue signalled that the task no longer needed to be performed, and the next trial would start immediately after the pseudo-cue. The regular trials in the Control Experiment were exactly the same as in Experiment 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Fifty participants (44 females, average age 18.44) were recruited to participate in the Control Experiment. Similar to Experiment 1, all participants were first-year Psychology students with normal or corrected-to-normal vision who studied at Ghent University and participated in exchange for course credit. Sample size was determined to be comparable to Experiment 1. Following the data exclusion procedure described below, 49 participants (43 females, average age: 18.29) remained. All participants gave their informed consent before participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task and procedure</head><p>The experiment was programmed in JsPsych version 6.1 (de Leeuw, J. R., 2015). The task materials and general procedure were the same as in Experiment 1, apart from replacing the transform condition with the omit condition. Participants were explicitly instructed about the task omit condition, as well as the association between CTI length and likelihood of an omit trial in the omit block. In each omit block, five trials were selected as the omit trials, and the CTIs of the omit trials were determined by using the same procedure as Experiment 1.</p><p>Critically, in omit trials, a pseudo-cue appeared in the centre of the screen for 750 ms following the CTI. The pseudo-cue was displayed in the same composition as the task cue, but with "X" replacing each letter, thus containing no information (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4)</ref>, indicating that they no longer would have to perform the trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The results of the mixed linear effect model on RT and accuracy are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>The analysis on RT revealed a significant main effect of CTI length, β = -11.461, SE = 1.878, p &lt; .001, showing participants were able to prepare for the task during CTI. In addition, the task rule congruency effect was again significant, β = 27.223, SE = 3.738, p &lt; .001, indicating participants' responses tended to slow down when irrelevant task rules afforded different responses. Both main effects were significant in Experiment 1 and this Control Experiment, which demonstrates the reliability of the paradigm. Critically, the interaction between CTI length and block type, which was significant in Experiment 1, β =-7.296, SE = 1.898, p&lt; .001, was not significant in the Control Experiment 2 , β = -0.757, SE = 1.878, p = 0.687, as shown in the lower panel of <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>. An additional across-experiments analysis was conducted to compare the CTI by block type interaction between Experiment 1 and the Control Experiment by including the variable Experiment (Experiment 1 versus Control Experiment) in the linear mixed effect model (the lme formula is : RT ~ (CTI + stimulus type incongruency + task rule incongruency) * block type * experiment + (1 | subject)). The result revealed a significant 3-way interaction between CTI length, block type, and experiment 3 , β = 4.027, SE = 1.336, p= .002, confirming the distinct RT pattern between these two experiments.</p><p>The accuracy data, similar to Experiment 1, exhibited a significant main effect of both stimulus type, β = -0.163, SE = 0.040, p&lt; .001, and task rule, β = -0.406, SE = 0.041, p&lt; .001, incongruency, with higher levels of incongruency yielding lower accuracy. None of the other main effects or interactions reached significance.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The RT results provided evidence against the interpretation that the effect we observed in Experiment 1 was merely due to passive task set degradation. Therefore, the active modulation of task preparation in anticipation of a potential task transformation likely plays a key role on the RT slowdown we observed in Experiment 1. In fact, our result is in line with previous studies claiming that working memory content does not decay simply due to a passage of time <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Lewandowsky, Oberauer, &amp; Brown, 2009)</ref>. Instead, active removal of the content is a crucial process in working memory updating <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Ecker, Lewandowsky, &amp; Oberauer, 2014)</ref>. Similarly, in our Control Experiment, we did not find a significant difference between regular and omit blocks in either RT or accuracy, suggesting that the task already being formed did not just decay in strength with passage of time even if participants predicted no task performance was needed when a omit trial was expected. Therefore, the anticipation of a potential task transformation seems critical in producing the observed changes in performance in Experiment 1, which is also in line with recent evidence showing that preparing for a new task rule is crucial for detaching from the influence of a previous task rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abrahamse et al., 2022)</ref>. However, unlike the claim made by <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Dreisbach, Haider, and Kluwe (2002)</ref> that specific information about the relevant task is needed to inhibit the irrelevant task, we here show that non-specific information about the likelihood of task DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 28 transformation (i.e., the CTI), without informing which task to transform into, already suffices to impact the original task preparation.</p><p>The next question we wanted to explore further is whether participants could partially modulate their task preparation or not. That is, when expecting a certain dimension of the task to be transformed, could participants modulate their task preparation on this particular dimension and leave the other dimension relatively intact? Previous studies proposed that compositionality of cognitive tasks enables us to combine elementary sensory, cognitive, and motor processes, which is a key feature of cognitive flexibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Cole, Laurent, &amp; Stocco, 2013)</ref>. Evidence coming from both empirical and theoretical works has supported such notion by showing that compositionality can be represented in both the human brain and artificial neural networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Reverberi, Görgen, &amp; Haynes, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Yang et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Ito et al., 2022)</ref>.</p><p>Notably, the bi-dimensional nature of the tasks (i.e. stimulus type and task rule) that we employed permits testing whether participants can selectively modulate task preparation on certain dimensions of task. The following Experiments 3 and 4 were conducted specifically to address this question.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiments 3 and 4</head><p>The aim of Experiments 3 and 4 were two-fold. First, we intended to examine if participants were able to prepare for a partial task transformation. In the task transform paradigm, the tasks we employed included two dimensions: stimulus type and task rule. In the transform blocks of Experiment 1, participants expected task transformation in both dimensions. In the following two experiments, only one task dimension was subject to transformation. Specifically, in Experiment 3 (rule transform paradigm), only the task rule could be transformed, whereas in Experiment 4 (stimulus transform paradigm), only the stimulus type could be transformed. By introducing such single dimensional transformation, DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 29 participants were encouraged to prepare for a "partial" task transformation. We hypothesized that, when the CTI is getting longer in transform blocks, participants would selectively modulate their task preparation on the task rule dimension and leave the stimulus dimension relatively intact in the rule transform experiment (Experiment 3), and vice versa in the stimulus transform experiment (Experiment 4). If the same RT patterns observed in Experiment 1 re-emerged in both Experiment 3 and 4, then that would indicate that the participants were able to prepare for task transformation in each of these task dimensions.</p><p>We also had a special interest to further investigate the congruency effect of each task dimension. The results of Experiment 1 suggested that the task rule congruency effect could be modulated in transform blocks, possibly due to a selective destabilization of the task rule representation. Based on our hypothesis that participants might be able to prepare for a partial task transformation by only destabilizing one dimension and leaving the other relatively intact, we expected a stronger congruency effect of the task dimension that was subject to transformation compared to the dimension that was not. Specifically, we expect to observe a stronger task rule congruency effect in transform blocks of the rule transform experiment (Experiment 3) compared to the stimulus transform experiment (Experiment 4), whereas a stronger stimulus type congruency effect was expected in Experiment 4 compared to Experiment 3.</p><p>A second, related objective of these two additional experiments was to see whether we would observe a more robust block type modulation on the congruency effect. As described above, a marginally significant interaction between task rule incongruency and block type was observed in Experiment 1. However, this effect was not significant. Potentially, since either of the two task dimensions could be transformed in Experiment 1, participants' strategies about whether to modulate their task preparation on either or both of the task dimensions might have varied across trials, blocks, and even participants. In contrast, in DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 30 Experiment 3 and Experiment 4, participants were told explicitly which of the two dimensions would be transformed. Therefore, a specific task dimension could be targeted whenever a task transformation was expected, allowing for the adoption of a stronger and more targeted strategy throughout the transform block. Therefore, stronger block type modulations on congruency effects were expected in Experiment 3 and 4. That is, a larger task rule congruency effect was expected in transform blocks versus regular blocks in Experiment 3, as well as a stronger stimulus congruency effect in transform blocks versus regular blocks in Experiment 4. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task and procedures</head><p>Both experiments were conducted online. The structure, procedure, and materials used in Experiment 3 and 4 were the same as in Experiment 1, except that on the transform blocks only one specific task dimension could be transformed (i.e. partial task transform). In Experiment 3 only the task rule dimension could be transformed, whereas in Experiment 4</p><p>only the stimulus type could be transformed. Participants were explicitly instructed about this in the beginning of the experiment. The structure of the partial transform trial is illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref>. In all partial transform trials, a new task cue would appear on screen following the CTI. Specifically in Experiment 3, the new task cue was featured with a new task rule shown on the bottom line, as well as a pseudo-cue on the top line signalling that the stimulus dimension stayed the same as indicated by the original task cue. The new task rule was randomly selected from the two alternative task rules for each partial transform trial. On the other hand, in Experiment 4, the new task cue was displayed with a new stimulus type presented on the top line and a pseudo-cue presented on the bottom line, signalling that the task rule remained unchanged. The association between a partial task transform and CTI length was determined using the same procedure described in Experiment 1, with longer CTI length predicting a higher likelihood of partial task transformation. Both experiments included six testing blocks of 54 trials in each block, with three of them being regular blocks leaving the other three being transform blocks. The experiment started with either regular or transform blocks without interleaving between them. The type of the starting block was counterbalanced across participants. Note. In the partial transform trial of Experiment 3, since only the task rule was subject to transformation, the new task cue specified the new task rule (as "young | old" in this case, bottom line), and a pseudo-cue indicated that the stimulus dimension would not transform ("XXXXX", top line). In comparison, in Experiment 4, the new task cue only specified the new stimulus type ("animal" in this case, top line), and the pseudo-cue on the bottom line indicated that the task rule remained the same as the original task cue ("XXXXX", bottom line).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3</head><p>The full results of the mixed linear effect model are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 3</ref>. In the RT analysis, consistent with the findings of Experiment 1, a significant main effect of CTI length, β = -6.831, SE = 1.856, p &lt; .001, and task rule incongruency, β = 31.721, SE = 3.664, p &lt; .001, were observed. The interaction between CTI length and block type also reached significance, β = -4.803, SE = 1.856, p = .010, indicating participants were again able to exploit the time-based expectancy to prepare for a partial task transformation (see upper panel of <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). The interaction of interest between task rule congruency effect and block type, β = -0.571, SE = 3.660, p= .876, was not significant (see Panel A of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 7</ref>), meaning the reaction times showed no evidence of stronger task rule congruency effect in rule transform blocks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>33</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 6. Mean RTs of Experiment 3 and Experiment 4 as a function of CTI length and block type</head><p>Note. The colored dots represent the mean RT for each CTI length, which was further fitted into a smooth dashed line for each block type using the loess smoothing method, with the surrounding grey band denoting 95% confidence level interval for predictions from the loess regression. The loess smoothing was solely used to better visualize the data, and not used for any statistical analysis. The vertical dashed line denotes the CTI of 4642 ms, longer than which the task could be transformed in the rule transform block.  <ref type="bibr">SE =0.031,</ref><ref type="bibr">p= .727</ref>. Combined with the evidence of a significant interaction between CTI length and block type in RT, the data clearly showed that participants performed better (both faster and more accurately) when the CTI was longer in regular blocks, possibly due to continual task preparation, but not in rule transform blocks. Again, similar to the RT result, no significant interaction between task rule incongruency and block type was found in the accuracy data (see Panel B of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 7)</ref>, β = 0.010, SE = 0.040, p= .805. Thus, neither the RT nor accuracy results supported our hypothesis that task rule dimension would be selectively modulated during task preparation in the rule transform blocks. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head><p>36 </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 4</head><p>The full results of the mixed linear effect model are displayed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 4</ref>. Similar to the previous three experiments, the RT results of Experiment 4 showed a main effect of task rule <ref type="bibr">incongruency,</ref><ref type="bibr">β = 18.689,</ref><ref type="bibr">SE = 3.946,</ref><ref type="bibr">p&lt; .001</ref>. The results also showed the same interaction between CTI length and block type, β = -9.283, SE = 1.987, p= &lt;.001, as observed in Experiments 1 and 3 (see lower panel of <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). Neither the main effect of stimulus type incongruency, β = -0.208, SE = 3.908, p = .958, nor the interaction between stimulus type DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 37 incongruency and block type (see Panel C of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 8</ref>), β = 3.080, <ref type="bibr">SE = 3.910,</ref><ref type="bibr">p= .431,</ref><ref type="bibr">was</ref> significant.</p><p>The accuracy data, consistent with previous experiments, showed a significant main effect of task rule incongruency, β <ref type="bibr">SE = 0.038,</ref><ref type="bibr">p &lt; .001,</ref><ref type="bibr">and stimulus type incongruency,</ref><ref type="bibr">SE = 0.038,</ref><ref type="bibr">p &lt; .001</ref>. Interestingly, we also observed a significant main effect of block type, β = -0.238, SE = 0.084, p = .004, with stimulus transform blocks showing a higher accuracy, M = 0.878, <ref type="bibr">SE = 0.007,</ref><ref type="bibr">p &lt; .001,</ref><ref type="bibr">than regular blocks,</ref><ref type="bibr">M = 0.865,</ref><ref type="bibr">SE = 0.008,</ref><ref type="bibr">p &lt; .001</ref>. Importantly, a significant interaction between stimulus type incongruency and block type, β = 0.094, SE = 0.038, p = .014, was found (see Panel D of  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head><p>39 </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional between-experiment analysis</head><p>In order to further compare the strength of the two types of congruency effects between Experiment 3 and 4, an additional between-experiment analysis was conducted on both RT and accuracy data by including the experiment identity (either Experiment 3 or Experiment 4)</p><p>in the linear mixed effect model (e.g. in the RT analysis , the LME formular is: RT ~ (CTI + stimulus type incongruency + task rule incongruency) * block type * experiment + (1 | subject)).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>40</head><p>In line with our hypothesis, the task rule congruency effect was stronger in Experiment 3 than Experiment 4, in both <ref type="bibr">RT,</ref><ref type="bibr">β = 6.520,</ref><ref type="bibr">SE = 2.688,</ref><ref type="bibr">p = .015,</ref><ref type="bibr">and accuracy,</ref><ref type="bibr">SE = 0.028,</ref><ref type="bibr">p = .005</ref>, meaning that participants were overall more caught up by the irrelevant task rules in Experiment 3, where only task rule could be transformed, than Experiment 4, wherein the task rule was never transformed.</p><p>In contrast, we did not find any evidence for a similar between-experiment difference on the stimulus type dimension. It is possible that the non-significant finding was due to the fact that between-experiment analysis conducted above also included regular blocks, in which no modulation on task preparation was needed. In other words, the inclusion of regular blocks in the analysis might render the between-experimental comparison less contrasting. Thus, as a follow-up analysis, we only included the transform blocks of both experiments in the between-experiment analysis as an effort to increase the power of the analysis. As a result, the RT analysis still showed no significant interaction between stimulus type congruency effect and experiments, β = 0.250, SE = 3.780, p = .947. However, the accuracy data did hint a stronger stimulus type congruency effect in Experiment 4 than Experiment 3, β = 0.078, SE = 0.040, p = .051, suggesting that stimulus type dimension was modulated more strongly in Experiment 4 than Experiment 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The significant interaction between CTI and block type observed in Experiment 3 and 4 corroborated the findings of Experiment 1, indicating that, when participants were instructed that only a certain component of a task would transform in the transform block, they still modulate their task preparation dynamically depending on their expectation of a task transformation. Our results further showed that the task rule congruency effect was more DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 41 pronounced on both RT and accuracy in Experiment 3, suggesting that people selectively modulated the task rule dimension in Experiment 3, probably by destabilizing the task rule representation, based on previous findings that that a weaker representation of relevant task rule would lead to less inhibition of irrelevant task rules during the decision-making stage <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Liefooghe, De Houwer &amp; Wenke, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Whitehead &amp;Egner, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abrahamse et al, 2022)</ref>.</p><p>As an additional effort to better understand this between-experiment differences in task rule congruency effect, we also fitted the behavioral data to a drift diffusion model (DDM) to further elucidate the underlying evidence accumulation process (for more details, see</p><p>Supplementary Material Text S1). The result demonstrated that the drift rate parameter, in particular, was more strongly modulated by the task rule incongruency in Experiment 3 than Experiment 4, corroborating our interpretation of a stronger influence of irrelevant task rules on the decision-making process when the relevant task rule was uncertain in Experiment 3, but not in Experiment 4.</p><p>On the other hand, the stimulus type congruency effect seemed to be stronger in Experiment 4 than Experiment 3 after we constrained our analysis only based on participants' performances on transform blocks. In addition to this between-experiment difference, we also found an effect of block type in modulating the stimulus congruency effect in Experiment 4.Exploratory DDM modelling on this interaction (see Supplementary Material Text S1, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S2</ref>) again pointed to drift rate as the main parameter that explained this interaction, indicating that the speed of evidence accumulation was more strongly biased by the irrelevant images in the stimulus transform blocks than in regular blocks, suggesting a less shielded goal representation regarding which image should be focused on when this information was uncertain in stimulus transform blocks. All of the above findings suggested that participants could modulate their task preparation partially and specifically on the stimulus type DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 42 dimension when the environment (either within a certain block or a certain experiment) required so.</p><p>Taking together, the behavioral results from Experiments 3 and 4 supported our hypothesis that people could adaptively modulate their task preparation based on the uncertainty level of specific task components.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>The overarching objective of our study was to investigate whether people can dynamically modulate task preparation in the face of time-evolving changes in task uncertainty. In reality, humans show striking flexibility in quickly establishing and actively adjusting task goals based on environmental needs. However, most standard cognitive tasks do not target this cognitive process. To fill this empirical gap, we designed a novel experimental paradigm that we utilized in a series of four experiments. The results of these experiments converged on two main findings. First, participants were capable of autonomously and adaptively modulating task preparation when the level of task uncertainty varied across time. This was mainly evidenced by a time-resolved slow-down in task performance in the blocks of Experiments 1, 3, and 4 where time progression was associated with greater probability of a task transformation. Second, we found that participants were more influenced by the task irrelevant information, evidenced by the stronger congruency effect of either stimulus type or task rule, in a certain block or experiment when the task relevant information was uncertain.</p><p>In general, our results are in line with previous studies on strategic control over task preparation (e.g. <ref type="bibr">Karayanidis er al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Whitehead &amp; Egner, 2018</ref>) that demonstrated that both task set and specific S-R mappings can be modulated adaptively after having already DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 43 been established. Our findings contribute to this line of research by showing that task preparation can be continuously and selectively regulated in a fast-paced and dynamic manner. Moreover, unlike task switching paradigms, this strategic control process was not explicitly cued. Instead, the likelihood of a task transformation was based on participants' own active inference of the time elapsed during CTI. Further, the relatively large task space (nine tasks) and factorial task structure ensured that, when expecting a task transformation, participants could not predict the task into which it would be transformed. Thus, the modulation of the original task was unlikely to be confounded with the preparation for a specific other task. Lastly, results from the Control Experiment further distinguished this active task modulation from passive task degradation, highlighting that these dynamic changes were in service of the prospective task transformation.</p><p>Theoretically, our results fit with recent working memory models like those proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Oberauer (2009)</ref>. In this framework, working memory, as a general-purpose mechanism designed to support complex cognition, is endowed with the property of flexible reconfiguration guided by executive function. <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Oberauer (2009)</ref> proposed that executive function would run in parallel to the primary processing of working memory content, flexibly intervening and guiding the primary processing. This proposition delineates well the interaction between the active inference on the likelihood of task transformation ("executive function") and task modulation ("primary processing") in the current study. Whenever a higher likelihood of task transformation was detected by monitoring the CTI length in transform blocks, an intervening signal could be sent to systems responsible for primary processing in order to modulate task preparation.</p><p>Following this line of reasoning, our experimental design and results emphasized the need for a hierarchical cognitive control architecture <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Badre &amp; Nee, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Holroyd &amp; McClure, 2015</ref>). There are at least three levels of control that can be identified in the task transform DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 44 paradigm: a lower level corresponding to task set preparation, a middle level that actively monitors the time elapsed during CTI in order to predict a potential task transformation, and a higher level contextual representation that holds the context information regarding which block type the agent was in. Throughout the experiment, the up-and down-regulation of the strength of a task set was guided by the middle level monitoring time passage during the CTI. In the meantime, this middle level was further harnessed by the higher level of contextual information which determined whether the task transformation could occur or not. It has been proposed that hierarchical cognitive control can be mapped onto different sub-regions in the human prefrontal cortex <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Badre, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Badre &amp; Nee, 2018)</ref>. Thus, future studies could leverage brain imaging techniques to further shed light upon the underlying neural mechanism of this hierarchical and flexible control system.</p><p>Our behavioral results further suggested that participants were able to destabilize task representations when a task transformation was expected, which is in line with previous theoretical work proposing that cognitive flexibility during task switching can be enhanced by lowering the threshold on working memory updating so that the goal or task at hand are less shielded when the environment requires frequent switching between tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Goschke &amp; Bolte, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dreisbach &amp; Fröber, 2019)</ref>. In our paradigm, reduced shielding of task representations during the CTI in anticipation of a potential task transformation would naturally render the task more vulnerable, thus requiring more time for reconfiguration and evidence accumulation, as reflected by the RT cost in transform blocks when the CTI got longer in Experiments 1, 3 and 4.</p><p>Mechanistically, working memory gating control has been proposed to be responsible for modulating this updating threshold <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Braver &amp; Cohen, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">D'Ardenne et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">O'Reilly, &amp; Frank, 2006)</ref>. Without the gate opening for afferent information, the task representation is shielded from distraction. However, when the gate opens, incoming DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 45 information can affect working memory representations and guide the agent's behavior.</p><p>According to one version of this gating hypothesis, midbrain dopamine (DA) would serve as the gating signal driving the information being updated in the working memory <ref type="bibr">(Braver &amp; Cohen,2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Frank, Loughry, &amp; O'Reilly, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Montague, Hyman, &amp; Cohen, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Durstewitz &amp;Seamans, 2002)</ref>. In the task transform paradigm, it could be the case that, when the task transformation was expected in the longer CTI condition, the gating control was modulated based on participants' prediction on the likelihood of a task transformation. That is, the working memory gate could already be open to prepare for encoding novel task information when a task transformation is anticipated. In line with this idea, previous neurobiological evidence demonstrated that midbrain DA can be modulated by the temporal expectation of reward delivery likelihood in a continuous manner <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Starkweather et al., 2017)</ref>, suggesting the gating control could be modulated by agents' active prediction of the environment. Thus, the gating state might not be binary, namely, either on or off. Instead, it could be modulated parametrically based on agents' inference on the need to encode novel information.</p><p>Apart from phasic modulations of task representations, our behavioral results also suggested tonic destabilization of task representations, as evidenced by the between-block differences in stimulus type congruency effect in Experiment 4, as well as by the betweenexperiment differences in task rule congruency effect in Experiment 3 and 4, indicating that the tasks were represented more feebly throughout a certain block or experiment. These results are in line with recent computational work examining the separability of task representations in service of cognitive flexibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Herd et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr">O'Reilly, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Musslick et al., 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Musslick et al., , 2019</ref>.</p><p>For instance, <ref type="bibr">colleagues (2018, 2019)</ref> have simulated task switching behavior using recurrent neural networks and compared the gain modulation, which is a global control parameter, between different environments in terms of the need for flexibility. Both simulated and empirical data suggested that a lower gain parameter is an optimal strategy when higher DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 46 level of flexibility are needed, resulting in less separable (or "more nearby") task representations. Thus, according to this line of research, it is likely that participants strategically used less stable or less distant stimulus type representations within the transform blocks of Experiment 4 to respond more efficiently to potential stimulus type transformations, rendering them susceptible to stronger stimulus type congruency effects. The same reasoning can be applied to the stronger task rule congruency effects observed in Experiment 3 versus 4.</p><p>Importantly, almost all of the above mentioned theoretical and empirical studies have emphasized the trade-off between cognitive flexibility and stability. On one hand, humans need to maintain and shield the task representation from any distraction in order to focus on the task at hand. On the other hand, the oftentimes unpredictable environment we live in require us to quickly react to unexpected events <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Musslick &amp; Cohen, 2021)</ref>. Thus, this fundamental tradeoff prescribed that being flexible can be a double-edged sword. In the current study, reduced shielding of task representations in working memory during the CTI could prepare participants well for potential incoming task transformations. However, in the meantime, it also renders participants more susceptible to irrelevant task information. Indeed, this hypothesis is confirmed by our result showing a stronger congruency effect on transform blocks, which indicates that the participants were more distracted by the task-irrelevant information when being cognitively flexible was required. Another hypothesis regarding the stability-flexibility trade-off concerns the performance on the transform trials, which should reflect the benefit of being flexible. We would expect that people who destabilized the task representation stronger during CTI would perform better on transform trials. However, our current design was underpowered to test this hypothesis because there were too few transform trials (only 9 percent).</p><p>Thus, a follow-up study including more transform trials could be used to investigate this question more directly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>47</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>To conclude, the current study demonstrated that people can dynamically modulate task preparation when a to-be-performed task becomes uncertain, in both a tonic and phasic manner. Such modulation is adaptive in terms of facilitating flexible behavior, at the cost of increasing susceptibility to task irrelevant information. Remarkably, this dynamic modulation of task preparation was dependent on the compositional structure the task, in that task uncertainty selectively affected the task component that was likely to transform.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Liefooghe,</head><label></label><figDesc>De Houwer &amp; Wenke, 2013; Whitehead &amp; Egner, 2018; Abrahamse et al, 2022).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>illustration of stimulus and task rule congruency effect DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 17</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>task sets and the strength of congruency effects (e.g. Braem, Deltomme &amp; Liefooghe, 2019; Liefooghe, De Houwer &amp; Wenke, 2013; Whitehead &amp; Egner, 2018; Abrahamse et al, 2022).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>illustration of a omit trial in the Control ExperimentDYNAMIC</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>A schematic outline of a partial transform trial in Experiment 3 and Experiment 4 DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 32</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Mean RT and accuracy rate of Experiment 3 as a function of block type and incongruency level DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 35 Note. Panel A and B demonstrated the interaction between block types and task rule incongruency of Experiment 3 in both RT (Panel A) and accuracy rate (Panel B). Task rule incongruency quantifies the level of response conflict between relevant and irrelevant task rules on the target image. Panel C and D displayed the interaction between block types and stimulus type incongruency of Experiment 3 in both RT (Panel C) and accuracy rate (Panel D). Stimulus type incongruency quantifies how much response conflict there was between relevant and irrelevant images. Error bars denote standard errors.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 8 )</head><label>8</label><figDesc>, with stimulus transform blocks showing more pronounced stimulus type congruency effect, β = -0.266, SE = 0.057, p&lt; .001, than regular blocks, β = -0.078, SE = 0.051, p = .130, which supported our hypothesis that the task dimension of stimulus type would be selectively destabilized in stimulus transform blocks.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Mean RT and accuracy rate of Experiment 4 as a function of block type and incongruency level DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 38 Note. Panel A and B demonstrated the interaction between block types and task rule incongruency of Experiment 4 in both RT (Panel A) and accuracy rate (Panel B). Task rule incongruency quantifies the level of response conflict between relevant and irrelevant task rules on the target image. Panel C and D displayed the interaction between block types and stimulus type incongruency of Experiment 4 in both RT (Panel C) and accuracy rate (Panel D). Stimulus type incongruency quantifies how much response conflict there was between relevant and irrelevant images. Error bars denote standard errors.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>The result of mixed effect regression model on RT and accuracy in Experiment 1The result of mixed effect regression model on RT and accuracy in Experiment 1</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>RT</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ACC</cell></row><row><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell cols="2">p value Estimate</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell></row><row><cell>(Intercept)</cell><cell cols="3">1161.650 17.204 &lt; .001 ***</cell><cell>2.413</cell><cell cols="2">0.105 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>block type</cell><cell>5.293</cell><cell>7.943</cell><cell>.505</cell><cell cols="2">-0.089 0.088</cell><cell>.312</cell></row><row><cell>CTI</cell><cell>-8.889</cell><cell cols="2">1.898 &lt; .001 ***</cell><cell>0.072</cell><cell cols="2">0.021 .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>CTI:block type</cell><cell>-7.296</cell><cell cols="4">1.898 &lt; .001 *** -0.022 0.021</cell><cell>.285</cell></row></table><note>Note. RT = reaction time, ACC = accuracy, SE = standard error.* denotes p &lt; .05, ** denotes p &lt; .01, *** denotes p &lt; .001</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The result of mixed effect regression model on RT and accuracy in Control Experiment</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>RT</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ACC</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Estimat</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell><cell></cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>e</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>(Intercept)</cell><cell>1126.244</cell><cell cols="3">15.694 &lt; .001 *** 2.631</cell><cell cols="2">0.106 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>block type</cell><cell>8.502</cell><cell>7.801</cell><cell>.276</cell><cell>0.071</cell><cell>0.089</cell><cell>.424</cell></row><row><cell>CTI</cell><cell>-11.461</cell><cell cols="3">1.878 &lt; .001 *** 0.023</cell><cell>0.020</cell><cell>.250</cell></row><row><cell>CTI:block type</cell><cell>-0.757</cell><cell>1.878</cell><cell>.687</cell><cell cols="2">-0.011 0.020</cell><cell>.593</cell></row><row><cell>Stimulus type incongruency</cell><cell>-2.578</cell><cell>3.702</cell><cell>.486</cell><cell cols="3">-0.163 0.040 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>Stimulus type incongruency:block type</cell><cell>2.479</cell><cell>3.703</cell><cell>.503</cell><cell cols="2">-0.004 0.040</cell><cell>.920</cell></row><row><cell>Task rule incongruency</cell><cell>27.223</cell><cell cols="5">3.738 &lt; .001 *** -0.406 0.041 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>Task rule incongruency:block type</cell><cell>-3.247</cell><cell>3.733</cell><cell>.384</cell><cell cols="2">-0.049 0.041</cell><cell>.227</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Note. RT = reaction time, ACC = accuracy, SE = standard error.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">* denotes p &lt; .05, ** denotes p &lt; .01, *** denotes p &lt; .001</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>3 The result was still significant after adding the quadratic term in the model.DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 27</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The result of mixed effect regression model on RT and accuracy in Control Experiment</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>RT</cell><cell></cell><cell>ACC</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell><cell>Estimat</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>e</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Participants58 participants (52 females, average age 18.90) were recruited for Experiment 3. After data exclusion based on the criterion specified above, the data sets of 7 participants were excluded due to poor performances, leaving those of 51 participants (47 females, average age 18.39) included in the analysis. Another group of 52 participants (47 females, average age18.92) were recruited for Experiment 4. After data exclusion, the data belonging to 49 participants (44 females, average age 18.90) remained in the analysis. All participants, as in the previous two experiments, were first-year Psychology student with normal or correctedto-normal vision at Ghent University who participated in exchange for course credit. Sample size was determined to be comparable to Experiment 1 and Control Experiment. All participants gave their informed consent prior to participation.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>block type also reached significance, β =0.044, SE =0.020, p= .029, with accuracy significantly being enhanced when CTI got longer in regular blocks, β =0.077, SE =0.026, p= .003, but not in rule transform blocks, β =</figDesc><table><row><cell>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</cell></row><row><cell>The accuracy data, again similar to Experiment 1, showed a significant task rule</cell></row><row><cell>congruency effect, β = -0.462, SE = 0.040, p&lt; .001, as well as a stimulus type congruency</cell></row><row><cell>effect, β = -0.117, SE = 0.039, p= .003. Interestingly, the interaction between CTI length and</cell></row></table><note>34</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>The result of mixed effect regression model on RT and accuracy in Experiment 3</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>RT</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ACC</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell></row><row><cell>(Intercept)</cell><cell cols="3">1108.403 18.036 &lt; .001 ***</cell><cell>2.564</cell><cell cols="2">0.105 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>block type</cell><cell>1.675</cell><cell>7.612</cell><cell>.826</cell><cell>-0.083</cell><cell>0.086</cell><cell>.334</cell></row><row><cell>CTI</cell><cell>-6.831</cell><cell>1.856</cell><cell>&lt; .001 ***</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>0.020</cell><cell>.098</cell></row><row><cell>CTI:block type</cell><cell>-4.803</cell><cell>1.856</cell><cell>.010 **</cell><cell>0.044</cell><cell>0.020</cell><cell>.029 *</cell></row><row><cell>stimulus type incongruency</cell><cell>-0.152</cell><cell>3.635</cell><cell>.967</cell><cell>-0.117</cell><cell>0.039</cell><cell>.003 **</cell></row><row><cell>stimulus type incongruency:block type</cell><cell>2.136</cell><cell>3.635</cell><cell>.557</cell><cell>-0.005</cell><cell>0.039</cell><cell>.894</cell></row><row><cell>task rule incongruency</cell><cell>31.721</cell><cell>3.664</cell><cell>&lt; .001 ***</cell><cell>-0.462</cell><cell cols="2">0.040 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>task rule incongruency:block type</cell><cell>-0.571</cell><cell>3.660</cell><cell>.876</cell><cell>0.010</cell><cell>0.040</cell><cell>.805</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Note. RT = reaction time, ACC = accuracy, SE = standard error.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">* denotes p &lt; .05, ** denotes p &lt; .01, *** denotes p &lt; .001</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>The result of mixed effect regression model onRT and accuracy in Experiment 4    </figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>RT</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ACC</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Coefficient</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell><cell>Estimate</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p value</cell></row><row><cell>(Intercept)</cell><cell cols="3">1120.620 17.689 &lt; .001 ***</cell><cell>2.339</cell><cell cols="2">0.100 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>block type</cell><cell>-5.890</cell><cell>8.172</cell><cell>.471</cell><cell>-0.238</cell><cell>0.084</cell><cell>.004 **</cell></row><row><cell>CTI</cell><cell>-3.875</cell><cell>1.987</cell><cell>.051</cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.019</cell><cell>.360</cell></row><row><cell>CTI:block type</cell><cell>-9.283</cell><cell>1.987</cell><cell>&lt; .001 ***</cell><cell>0.011</cell><cell>0.019</cell><cell>.561</cell></row><row><cell>stimulus type incongruency</cell><cell>-0.208</cell><cell>3.908</cell><cell>.958</cell><cell>-0.172</cell><cell cols="2">0.038 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>stimulus type incongruency:block type</cell><cell>3.080</cell><cell>3.910</cell><cell>.431</cell><cell>0.094</cell><cell>0.038</cell><cell>.014 *</cell></row><row><cell>task rule incongruency</cell><cell>18.689</cell><cell>3.946</cell><cell>&lt; .001 ***</cell><cell>-0.307</cell><cell cols="2">0.038 &lt; .001 ***</cell></row><row><cell>task rule incongruency:block type</cell><cell>4.071</cell><cell>3.940</cell><cell>.302</cell><cell>0.055</cell><cell>0.038</cell><cell>.149</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Note. RT = reaction time, ACC = accuracy, SE = standard error.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">* denotes p &lt; .05, ** denotes p &lt; .01, *** denotes p &lt; .001</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">In the pre-registration (https://osf.io/tmx4r), the sample size (36 participants) was derived based on the design of eight blocks. However, the design was later changed to six blocks in order to keep the whole experiment less than one hour. Thus, we ran the power analysis again based on the design of six blocks, resulting in updated sample size of 40-45 participants.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Adding the quadratic term of CTIs in the model did not change the finding of non-significant interaction.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was supported by an ERC Starting grant awarded to S.B. (European Union's Horizon 2020 research and innovation program, Grant agreement 852570).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tenacious instructions: How to dismantle newly instructed task rules?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Abrahamse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Braem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>De Houwer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Liefooghe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Timebased expectancy in temporally structured task switching</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aufschnaiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kiesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dreisbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wenke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thomaschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">856</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time-based transition expectancy in task switching: do we need to know the task to switch to?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aufschnaiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kiesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thomaschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive control, hierarchy, and the rostro-caudal organization of the frontal lobes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Badre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="193" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontal cortex and the hierarchical control of behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Badre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="170" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Random effects structure for confirmatory hypothesis testing: Keep it maximal</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Barr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Scheepers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tily</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of memory and language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Inference as a fundamental process in behavior. Current opinion in behavioral sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bartolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Averbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mächler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bolker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1406.5823</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kliegl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vasishth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Baayen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1506.04967</idno>
		<title level="m">Parsimonious mixed models</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the control of control: The role of dopamine in regulating prefrontal function and working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Braver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Control of cognitive processes: Attention and performance XVIII</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The instruction-based congruency effect predicts task execution efficiency: Evidence from inter-and intra-individual differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Braem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Deltomme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Liefooghe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1582" to="1591" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Getting a grip on cognitive flexibility. Current directions in psychological science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Braem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Egner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="476" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rapid instructed task learning: A new window into the human brain&apos;s unique capacity for flexible cognitive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Laurent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Stocco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A role for proactive control in rapid instructed task learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Patrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Meiran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Braver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">184</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Role of prefrontal cortex and the midbrain dopamine system in working memory updating</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>D'ardenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Eshel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Luka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lenartowicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nystrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19900" to="19909" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">jsPsych: A JavaScript library for creating behavioral experiments in a Web browser</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>De Leeuw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior research methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On how to be flexible (or not): Modulation of the stability-flexibility balance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dreisbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Fröber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preparatory processes in the taskswitching paradigm: evidence from the use of probability cues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dreisbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Haider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kluwe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>468. DYNAMIC TASK PREPARATION 50</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preparatory adjustment of cognitive control in the task switching paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dreisbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Haider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="334" to="338" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The computational role of dopamine D1 receptors in working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Durstewitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Seamans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4-6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="561" to="572" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Removal of information from working memory: A specific updating process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ecker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Memory and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interactions between frontal cortex and basal ganglia in working memory: a computational model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Loughry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Reilly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="160" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional modulation of control dilemmas: The role of positive affect, reward, and dopamine in cognitive stability and flexibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Goschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bolte</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="423" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A neural network model of individual differences in task switching abilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Herd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hazy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chatham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Brant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="375" to="389" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical control over effortful behavior by rodent medial frontal cortex: A computational model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Holroyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mcclure</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">54</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compositional generalization through abstract representations in human and artificial neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Klinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rigotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32225" to="32239" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advance preparation in task-switching: converging evidence from behavioral, brain activation, and model-based approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Karayanidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jamadar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ruge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Phillips</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">25</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anticipatory reconfiguration elicited by fully and partially informative cues that validly predict a switch in task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Karayanidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mansfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Galloway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Provost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="202" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Control and interference in task switching-A review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kiesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steinhauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wendt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Falkenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Philipp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">136</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">849</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic and intentional activation of task sets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1474" to="1486" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">lmerTest package: Tests in linear mixed effects models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kuznetsova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Brockhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H B</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">No temporal decay in verbal shortterm memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Instruction-based response activation depends on task preparation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Liefooghe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>De Houwer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wenke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin&amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="487" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Balancing Type I error and power in linear mixed models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Matuschek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kliegl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vasishth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Baayen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of memory and language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reconfiguration of processing mode prior to task performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Meiran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1423" to="1442" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task switching</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Monsell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational roles for dopamine in behavioural control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Montague</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7010</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="760" to="767" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rationalizing constraints on the capacity for cognitive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Musslick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="757" to="775" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Musslick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Saxe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Özcimder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Dey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Henselman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multitasking capability versus learning efficiency in neural network architectures</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constraints associated with cognitive control and the stability-flexibility dilemma</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Musslick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shvartsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CogSci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stabilityflexibility dilemma in cognitive control: A dynamical system perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Musslick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bizyaeva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Agaron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Leonard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Components of task-set reconfiguration: Differential effects of &apos;switch-to&apos;and &apos;switch-away&apos;cues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nicholson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Karayanidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Michie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design for a working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology of learning and motivation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Biologically based computational models of high-level cognition. science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>O'reilly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">314</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="94" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making working memory work: a computational model of learning in the prefrontal cortex and basal ganglia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>O'reilly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="328" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compositionality of rule representations in human prefrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Reverberi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Görgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cerebral cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1237" to="1246" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine reward prediction errors reflect hidden-state inference across time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Monsell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Starkweather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Babayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Uchida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of experimental psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="581" to="589" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Nature neuroscience</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine reward prediction errors reflect hidden-state inference across time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Starkweather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Babayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Uchida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="581" to="589" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The cuing and priming of cognitive operations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sudevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human perception and performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">89</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ueltzhöffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Armbruster-Genç</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fiebach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Stochastic dynamics underlying cognitive stability and flexibility</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1004331</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive control over prospective task-set interference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Whitehead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Egner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">741</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task representations in neural networks trained to perform many cognitive tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Joglekar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Newsome</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
