<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The elusive effects of incidental anxiety on reinforcementlearning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chih-Chung</forename><surname>Ting</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">CREED</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Economics (ASE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universiteit van Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam, Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">the Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Département d&apos;Études Cognitives</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">École Normale Supérieure</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Human Reinforcement Learning team</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>INSERM U960</postCode>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Institut d&apos;Etude de la Cognition</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Recherche Paris Sciences et Lettres</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maël</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
							<email>mael.lebreton@unige.ch</email>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Neurology and Imaging of Cognition</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Basic Neurosciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Geneva</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Geneva</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Swiss Center for Affective Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Geneva</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Geneva</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
							<email>j.b.engelmann@uva.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">CREED</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Economics (ASE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universiteit van Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam, Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">the Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Amsterdam Brain and Cognition (ABC)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universiteit van Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">the Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="institution">The Tinbergen Institute</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">the Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The elusive effects of incidental anxiety on reinforcementlearning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:58+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>anxiety</term>
					<term>threat-of-shock</term>
					<term>reinforcement-leaning</term>
					<term>computational modelling</term>
					<term>valenceinduced bias</term>
					<term>context-dependent learning</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Anxiety is a common affective state, characterized by the subjectively unpleasant feelings of dread over an anticipated event. Anxiety is suspected to have important negative consequences on cognition, decision-making and learning. Yet, despite a recent surge in studies investigating the specific effects of anxiety on reinforcement-learning, no coherent picture has emerged. Here, we investigated the effects of incidental anxiety on instrumental reinforcement learning, while addressing several issues and defaults identified in a focused literature review. We used a rich experimental design, featuring both a learning and a transfer phase, and a manipulation of outcomes valence (gains vs losses). In two variants (N = 2x50) of this experimental paradigm, incidental anxiety was induced with an established threat-of-shock paradigm. Model-free results show that incidental anxiety effects seem limited to a small, but specific increase in post-learning performance measured by a transfer task. A comprehensive modelling effort revealed that, irrespective of the effects of anxiety, individuals give more weight to positive than negative outcomes, and tend to experience the omission of a loss as a gain (and vice versa). However, in line with results from our targeted literature survey, isolating specific computational effects of anxiety on learning per se proved to be challenging. Overall, our results suggest that learning mechanisms are more complex than traditionally presumed, and raise important concerns about the robustness of the effects of anxiety previously identified in simple reinforcement-learning studies.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>The occurrence of negative events carries important information for an organism, enabling the adjustment of future behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(Trapp et al., 2018</ref>). Yet, unpredictable negative events can also cause prolonged anxiety and adversely impact otherwise well-adjusted behaviors, including decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Hartley &amp; Phelps, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Schmitz &amp; Grillon, 2012)</ref>. For example, anxiety is usually associated with higher risk-aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Charpentier et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Cohn et al., 2015)</ref>, as well as increased reliance on habituated behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Browning et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Schwabe and Wolf, 2009)</ref>. Moreover, anxiety also impacts the cognitive processes that fundamentally support decision-making, including attention <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bar-Haim et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Bradley et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Cisler and Koster, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">MacLeod and Mathews, 1988)</ref>, memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Balderston et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bolton and Robinson 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Vytal et al., 2013)</ref> and learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Grupe, 2017)</ref>.</p><p>The ability to learn efficiently to seek rewards and to avoid punishments is one of the core features of adaptive behavior. Extensive evidence suggests that humans and animals learn by trial and error using algorithms akin to reinforcement learning, so as to repeat actions that maximize the occurrence of rewards and to suppress actions that lead to punishments <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Rescorla and Wagner, 1972;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Sutton and Barto, 1998)</ref>. Given this pivotal role of reinforcement-learning in generating our behavior on the one hand, and the prevalence of anxiety in our daily lives on the other, a growing body of studies has investigated the impact of anxiety on learning in reward seeking and loss avoidance contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abraham and Hermann, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berghorst et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Browning et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cavanagh et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cavanagh, Frank, and Allen 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">DeVido et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Glienke, Wolf, and Bellebaum, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lighthall et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Mather and Lighthall 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Otto et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Petzold et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Schwabe and Wolf, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Treadway et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Voegler et al., 2019</ref>; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 1</ref> and Supplementary- <ref type="table">Table S10</ref>).</p><p>However, to date, there seems to be little consensus on the precise effect of anxiety on reinforcement learning, let alone its potential neurobiological underpinnings <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Cavanagh et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cavanagh et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Glienke et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Treadway et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Voegler et al., 2019)</ref>. While some studies suggest general positive effects of anxiety on learning mediated by increased sensitivity to reward <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Lighthall et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Mather and Lighthall, 2012)</ref>, other studies found a general detrimental effect of anxiety on learning, which reportedly impair learning flexibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Browning et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Otto et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Raio et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Schwabe and Wolf, 2009)</ref>. Likewise, it is not clear how the effects of anxiety on learning could depend on the valence of learning contexts (reward seeking vs loss avoidance). Again, although several studies have investigated this question, they have yielded somewhat contradictory results. For instance, <ref type="bibr">Berghorst and colleagues (2013)</ref> found that threat decreased the probability of approaching a learned reward, but increased avoidance of losses. However, using the same task, other teams reported opposite results <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Lighthall et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Mather and Lighthall, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Petzold et al., 2010)</ref>, with some authors concluding that stress, a source of anxiety, facilitates the sensitivity to positive feedback <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Lighthall et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Mather and Lighthall, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>To address these contradictory results more systematically, we conducted a targeted literature review of key studies <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figure 1</ref>, N = 13, see Supplementary Material for inclusion/exclusion criteria) that investigate the impact of induced anxiety, as well as trait anxiety on reinforcement learning. The results from this literature review confirm the lack of consensus on the direction of the effects of anxiety on learning performance <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figure 1</ref>). This puzzling observation points to a more complex role of anxiety in learning than initially thought .</p><p>To resolve the seemingly contradictory effects of anxiety reported in prior research, we identified three main experimental dimensions which regularly differ between studies, and whose investigation could <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 1</ref>. Overall effect of anxiety on learning and post-learning/transfer task. The stack bars summarized number of previous findings about the effect of anxiety on performance in learning task (middle-left panel), transfer tasks of approaching gains (middle-right panel) and transfer tasks of avoiding losses (right panel). In each pool of task, we separately reported numbers of articles showing decreases <ref type="bibr">(-)</ref>, no changes (0) or increases (+) of performance. The findings were categorized by both types of anxiety (green: state-anxiety; yellow: trait-anxiety) and sample size (brighter: N&lt;50; darker: N&gt;50). For instance, light green and and light yellow represents effect of state-anxiety and effect of trait-anxiety with sample size N&lt;50, respectively. illuminate some of the discrepancies in the effects of anxiety on learning observed previously. These three dimensions, detailed in the following sections, cover 1) the methods of anxiety induction, including the nature of the stressor, and the dynamics and intensity of the induced anxiety 2) the measures of learning performance, and 3) the manipulation of outcome valence.</p><p>Regarding the first factor, namely anxiety induction, a large variety of methods and protocols have been used in the literature. A significant proportion of studies investigating the impact of anxiety on learning have used paradigms such as the Cold Pressor Test <ref type="bibr">(CPT, Porcelli et al., 2012)</ref> and the Trier Social Stress Test (TSST: <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Jackson et al., 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Petzold et al., 2010</ref>, which suffer from significant drawbacks: these induction techniques operate before the learning task, making the actual emotion state less contingent with the task of interest and introducing uncertainty with respect to the dynamics of the emotion intensity and related endocrine reactions <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Hermans et al., 2014;</ref>.</p><p>Both self-reported anxiety and corticosterone (a glucocorticoid stress hormone) levels generally decrease over time after the initial stressor <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Hermans et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Jackson et al., 2006)</ref>, suggesting that the peak of cortisol release, which is typically the time point at which the task is conducted, correlates with a state of relaxation that follows a stressful event, rather than a state of anxiety <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Takahashi et al., 2005)</ref>. Moreover, these stressors are not unpredictable, which is a critical factor of anxiety <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Schmitz and Grillon, 2012)</ref>. A significant portion of the studies reviewed above might therefore not investigate the effects of prolonged anxiety, but instead complex post-stress recovery processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Hermans et al., 2014</ref>). In the current experiments, we addressed this issue by using the well-established Threat of Shock (ToS) procedure to reliably induce anxiety during the learning task <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Engelmann et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Grillon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Schmitz and Grillon, 2012)</ref>. ToS enables researchers to flexibly turn threat on and off (by contrasting periods during which electrical shocks are administered with periods of relative safety), which offers important advantages over other induction methods, including the ability to conduct experiments within subjects and measuring in real time the causal effects of anxiety on behavior.</p><p>Secondly, previous studies differ in what they refer to as learning. Two main experimental paradigms have been used to assess learning performance, which differ significantly in the aspect of learning they assess. More specifically, a first set of tasks ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 1</ref>, middle-left panel) primarily assesses the dynamic evolution of learning (learning tasks), while a second set of tasks ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 1</ref>, middle-right and right panel) mostly assesses post-learning preferences, much like extinction tests commonly employed in the animal learning literature (transfer tasks). Learning tasks directly assess the correct response rate during probabilistic instrumental-learning (see e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Pessiglione et al., 2006)</ref> and typically require participants to make repeated choices between fixed pairs of stimuli. Transfer tasks involve similar learning during an initial learning stage that provides feedback about the accuracy of participants' choices. However, learning performance is assessed after learning has already taken place in the form of an extinction test that involves novel pairings of the same stimuli and no longer includes feedback (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Frank et al., 2004)</ref>. Although these tasks seem very similar, those two ways of measuring learning performance have been shown to produce qualitatively different results, e.g. in the case of contextdependent learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Klein et al., 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">, Palminteri et al., 2015</ref>. Accordingly, using different paradigms to capture the effects of anxiety on learning might not lead to comparable results across studies. We address this here by including both types of tasks in our experiments and separating these in our smallscale literature review, enabling us to assess the impact of anxiety on both learning and post-learning preferences.</p><p>Finally, despite the suggestions that the impact of anxiety could be valence-dependent, few studies have explicitly manipulated the valence of outcomes (gains vs losses) to contrast reward seeking and loss avoidance under conditions of anxiety <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Berghorst et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cavanagh et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lighthall et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Petzold et al., 2010)</ref>. Instead, most studies have typically either limited their investigations and claims to one valence or re-framed low reward probabilities as an avoidance context <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Schwabe and Wolf, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Stevens et al., 2014)</ref>. Neither of these approaches is actually suitable to investigate potential valence-specific effects of anxiety on learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Palminteri and Pessiglione, 2017)</ref>. We address this here by including both rewards and punishments in our experiments. This enables us to assess the differential impact of anxiety on reward seeking and punishment avoidance.</p><p>In the present study, we designed two experiments investigating the impact of anxiety on reinforcement learning to systematically address the shortcomings identified above. First, we employed Threat-of-Shock (ToS) to reliably and flexibly induce anxiety throughout the learning task <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Engelmann et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Grillon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Schmitz and Grillon, 2012)</ref>. In two different implementations of the task, we varied the dynamics and intensity of the anxiety induction, by applying Threat-of-Shock to relatively shorter blocks consisting of three trials or to relatively longer periods consisting of the entire period of a learning session. In both experiments, shock intensity was calibrated for each individual. Second, we used a combination of tasks assessing both learning and transfer performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>. Finally, we explicitly manipulated the valence of outcomes (gains and losses) to assess potential valence-specific effects of anxiety on learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Pessiglione et al., 2006)</ref>.</p><p>Regarding the analytical strategy, we first analyzed our data using standard linear mixed models that assess learning in different contexts on a trial-by-trial basis. Moreover, to more specifically assess how anxiety impacts on the underlying computations during learning and to parsimoniously make sense of this high-dimensional behavioral data, we used a recently developed computational modelling framework built around the concept of context-dependent learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015</ref>. We aimed to identify the effects of anxiety on learning and its robustness across tasks and conditions: in other words, conditional on addressing what we identified as important caveats in previous studies (anxiety induction method based on ToS, explicit dissociation of learning and transfer performance, explicit gain and loss contexts), the anxiety effects should not be idiosyncratic to a specific experimental design, and should be comprehensively captured by computational modelling. We specifically hypothesized that anxiety would impact context-dependent learning and/or valencespecific learning conditioned by context-dependent-learning. Despite our rigorous, comprehensive and high-powered experimental and analytical approaches, we found no clear, specific effect of anxiety on learning. In line with the lack of apparent consensus observed in the literature, our results seem to indicate that the average effects of incidental anxiety on learning are at best elusive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Subjects</head><p>114 right-handed subjects were recruited from the subject-pool of the Center for Research in Experimental Economics and Political Decision Making (CREED, www.creedexperiment.nl), and 100 subjects were analyzed in the end <ref type="table">(Table 1</ref>; Total: 56 males, aged 19-32, mean±SD = 23.27±3.08). We excluded four and ten subjects from experiment 1 and experiment 2, respectively, either because of technical problems or average learning performance that was significantly lower than guessing level as identified via a binomial test assessing above chance performance (i.e., requiring a 50% performance at an alpha level of 0.01). All subjects were prescreened via a questionnaire. Inclusion criteria consisted of (1) no history of psychiatric and neurologic disorders, (2) not taking medicine for anxiety or depression, (3) no implanted electric devices in the body (that electric shocks might interfere with), and (4) right-handedness. All subjects gave their written informed consent before participation, after being given instructions about the task, the safety of electrical stimulation and their rights as participants. All procedures were executed in compliance with relevant institutional guidelines and were approved by the CREED Ethical committee at the University of Amsterdam.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Timeline of Procedure</head><p>We invited potential subjects from the CREED subject-pool, and asked them to complete a battery of questionnaires at least one-day before the main task for an initial endowment of 10EU. When subjects arrived at the lab, they were asked to thoroughly read the instructions and consent form and were allowed to ask questions to ensure understanding. We then orally explained the task if necessary.</p><p>Subjects' non-dominant hand (i.e., left hand) was then fitted with different electrodes meant to measure SCRs and deliver electric shocks. The successful setup was then followed by a calibration of shock intensity (see Anxiety induction), and a short training session (see behavioral task) while recording electrodermal activity. Subsequently the main task started and subjects completed two (four) sessions in experiment 1 (experiment 2). Halfway through the learning experiments (i.e. before the second session for experiment 1, and before the third session for experiment 2), an additional calibration session was performed to control for (de)sensitization to the electrical stimulation. After the last learning session (the second session for experiment 1, the third and fourth session for experiment 2), subjects completed the transfer task and an exit questionnaire. The total participant fee, including endowment amount and accumulated outcome from the learning task, was handed to subjects in cash after completion of the exit questionnaire. The whole experiment took around 90 min, including instructions, electrodes setup time, exit questionnaire and payment (average amount earned in experiment1: mean±SD = 21.54 ±4.21; experiment2: mean±SD = 26.96 ±6.4).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental Paradigm</head><p>All experimental paradigms were programmed and conducted with Matlab 2017b with the Cogent library (http://www.vislab.ucl.ac.uk/cogent.php).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Learning task</head><p>Subjects performed a probabilistic instrumental learning task adapted from previous imaging, developmental and clinical studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Palminteri et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Salvador et al., 2017)</ref>. They were instructed that the aim of the task was to maximize their payoff, by learning to choose the best cue out of cue pairs. They were explicitly told that seeking monetary rewards and avoiding monetary losses were equally important.</p><p>Each learning session contained four novel, fixed pairs of cues, implementing a 2 (outcome valence: Gain vs Loss) x 2 (anxiety: Safe vs Threat) within-subject design. In other words, each pair of cues indicated a specific condition ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2B</ref>; Safe/Gain, Safe/Loss, Threat/Gain, Threat/Loss). In the Gain conditions, possible outcomes were +0.5 or 0. Symmetrically, in the Loss conditions, possible outcomes were -0.5 and 0. The cue-outcome associations were determined by reciprocal but independent binomial probabilities, 75% or 25% ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2B</ref>). Therefore, successful learning entailed choosing the cue associated with the higher probability of reward in the gain domain, and choosing the cue associated with the lower probability of loss in the loss domain.</p><p>Each block in experiment 1 (resp. of each session in experiment 2) started with a 1000ms reminder cue indicating the anxiety condition for the upcoming trials (i.e., "SHOCK" or "SAFE" associated with a frame of a particular color that was counterbalanced across subjects -see <ref type="figure">Figure 2A</ref>) that was shown before the first trial. The reminder cues were followed by a fixation cross (1000-6000ms) and three trials. Each trial first featured a pair of cues (2500ms). During this cue display, subjects indicated their decision by pressing the left or right arrow key to choose the left or right cue, respectively. The position of the options was counterbalanced. After 2500ms, an arrow appeared under the chosen cue (500ms). If subjects did not respond in the allocated 2500ms, this phase was omitted and subjects would get the relatively worse outcome in the feedback phase (i.e., -0.5 in the loss domain; 0 in the gain domain). In contrast, if subjects successfully made decisions in time, the outcome associated with the chosen option was revealed (2500ms). Both trials and mini-blocks were separated by a jittered fixation cross (1000-5000ms).</p><p>In experiment 1, anxiety was induced through a ToS protocol used previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Engelmann et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Engelmann et al., , 2019</ref>. More specifically, in order to maintain the emotional state for a prolonged period of time, we used a blocked presentation of the ToS conditions, such that three consecutive trials of the learning task were presented either under threat, or under safety ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2D</ref>). Therefore, experiment 1 comprised two sessions, each including 96 trials (i.e. 32 blocks) and featuring a new, different set of eight cues. The ToS blocks were pseudorandomly interleaved to avoid repeating the same emotional treatment (Safe or Shock) more than two consecutive times. In experiment 2, we modified the experimental design and varied the ToS condition across separate sessions of 80 trials (with 20 repetitions of the four cue pairs; see <ref type="figure">Figure 2D</ref>). This was done in order to reduce the frequent switching of emotional states required by the relatively short blocks: the dynamics of emotion being notoriously slow <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">(Williams et al., 2004)</ref>, we wanted to exclude the possibility of spill-over effects of anxiety on Safe blocks. Consequently, only the valence of outcomes was manipulated within a session.</p><p>Each session still featured four cue pairs, probabilistically associated with gains or losses. Experiment 2 comprised four learning sessions (two implementing the Safe condition and two implementing the threat condition, interleaved, with the order counterbalanced across subjects).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2. Experimental paradigm</head><p>A. Threat-of-Shock learning task. Schematic representation illustrating the learning task under safe and threat conditions for both experiment 1 and experiment 2. B. Manipulations. In the two-by-two within-subject design, anxiety (i.e., absence and presence of threat of shock for safe and threat conditions, respectively) and outcome valence (i.e., gain and loss) were associated with specific pair of cues. C. Transfer task. 24 novel cue pairings were formed by pairing each learned with all other cues in the transfer task. These new and original pairs were repeated four times, resulting in 112 choices. D. Experimental design for each session in experiment 1 and experiment 2. E. Experimental design for both learning and transfer task. Top: Experiment 1: Full intermixed design. The transfer task took place right after second session and contained cues from all four conditions. Bottom: Experiment 2: Session manipulation. The transfer task took place after the third and fourth sessions. The cues used in the transfer task were drawn from two of four conditions, depending on the emotional state of the previous session.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Transfer task</head><p>After completing the learning task, subjects performed a transfer task <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>. The task was built around the eight cues used in the last session(s) of the learning task. Participants were asked to choose between pairs of cues and indicate which cue they preferred. Yet, contrary to the learning sessions where cue pairs were fixed, all possible pairs were built from pairing each cue with the other 7 cues, leading to 28 combinations. Each pair was repeated four times, resulting in 112 trials ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2C</ref>). Decisions were self-paced, and not followed by feedback about the decisions. Subjects were not informed about the post-learning task until they had completed the learning task, so as to avoid explicit memorization strategies.</p><p>In experiment 1, the transfer task was conducted after the second learning session, which contained cues from both threat and safe conditions <ref type="figure">(Figure 2E</ref>, top). In experiment 2, the transfer task was conducted after the third and fourth session, to elicit choices between cues from both threat and safe conditions ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2E</ref>, bottom).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Monetary compensation</head><p>In both experiments, all subjects received a payment that included an initial endowment of 10 Euros for filling in the questionnaire before the experiment, a performance-based bonus based on all trials from the learning task (including gain and loss trials) and a final bonus (0.5€ for each question, totally four questions) for correctly filling out the exit questionnaire.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Anxiety induction</head><p>The incidental anxiety was induced by the presence of unpredictable and mildly painful electric shocks in the Threat conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Engelmann et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Engelmann et al., , 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Grillon et al., 2004)</ref>. The shock stimulation was generated by a DS5 Isolated Bipolar Constant Current Stimulators (Digitimer Ltd.), and delivered through two electrodes. The electrodes were attached to the wrist of the non-dominant (left) hand throughout the experiment where they were taped with Velcro. Calibrations for the intensity of electric stimulation took place three times in both experiment 1 and 2. In experiment 1, calibration occurred before the first and second learning sessions, and before the transfer task. In experiment 2, which consisted of four learning sessions, the calibration took place before the first and third learning sessions, and after the last transfer task.</p><p>The DS5 stimulator generated stable electric shocks with a fixed maximum input of 5V, maximum output of 25mA and a stable duration of 50ms across subjects and studies. Only the intensity of shocks was individually customized for each learning session to match each subject's pain threshold. This was achieved using a staircase procedure asking subjects to evaluate the painfulness of delivered electric shocks on a visual analog scaling ranging from 0 (not painful at all) to 10 (Extremely painful) <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Engelmann et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Engelmann et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Story et al., 2013)</ref>. The shock intensity was initialized at 10% of the maximum output (i.e., 2.5mA) and was then iteratively increased or decreased by 10% based on the following rules. If two consecutive ratings for the same intensity were less than 7, the intensity in the third trial would be increased by 10%. On the other hand, the intensity would be decreased when the rating was above 9. The procedure terminated as soon as the shock intensity was rated between 7 and 9 three times in a row, and we used this value in the subsequent learning sessions.</p><p>During the calibration, the electric stimulations were self-triggered, i.e. subjects could deliver the electric pulses by pressing the Enter key themselves. In order to avoid sensitization or desensitization, the intensity of electric stimulation was calibrated before and after each learning session in the experiment 1, and was calibrated before and after every two learning sessions in the experiment 2.</p><p>During the learning sessions, subjects were not informed about the number of shocks and the precise time point of shock stimulation to maintain the unpredictability of electrical shocks. In Experiment 1, the number of shocks for each mini-block in the Threat Condition was randomly drawn from the predetermined set [1 1 3 3 3 3 5 5] without replacement. The timing of the shock was randomized within the period of a threat block with the constraint that two consecutive shocks should be spaced more than 0.2s apart. Subjects were explicitly notified that the shocks were unpredictable, uncontrollable and independent of their performance. Similar procedures were applied to Experiment 2 with the exception that three electric shocks were delivered at random intervals within in each Threat session.</p><p>An important advantage of the ToS anxiety induction procedure is that anxiety states can be switched on and off during the task. To make sure that subjects were subjected to this anxiety manipulation, mini-blocks (experiment 1) and sessions (experiment 2) started with a reminder (i.e. "SAFE" or "SHOCK") and a color frame (i.e. Green or Blue; independent of the valence factor, <ref type="figure">Figure 2A</ref>). The color frame was displayed until the end of the mini-block (experiment 1) or session (experiment 2).</p><p>The assignment of color frames to Safe and Threat conditions was counterbalanced across subjects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Screening Questionnaire</head><p>Data collected with the screening questionnaire was used to (1) pre-screen the subject by inclusion and exclusion criteria, and (2) assess a range of state and trait emotions. Exclusion criteria were examined first, and used to determine whether the subject qualified for the experiment (see Subjects). The screening questionnaire also included a basic demographic survey, Beck Depression Inventory (BDI: to index depression symptoms; <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Beck, Steer, and Carbin, 1988)</ref>, Beck Anxiety Inventory (BAI: to index clinical anxious symptoms; , State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI: to index stateand trait-anxiety; <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Spielberger et al., 1983)</ref> and Positive and Negative affect schedule (PANAS: to index currently positive and negative affect; <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Watson, Clark, and Tellegen, 1988)</ref>. Finally, in order to avoid attentional biases from novel cues, the cues used in the experiment were displayed in the end of questionnaire for 60s, so that subjects have chance to explore them before the main task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exit Questionnaire</head><p>The exit questionnaire required subjects to retrieve and report their emotional state on a 7-point scale and to explain the strategies they used in the task. For the self-reported emotions, subjects were asked to separately rate how often they felt seven emotional-states (i.e., Anxiety, Fear, Happiness, Sadness, Anger, Surprise and Disgust) during the threat condition (from 0 (never) to 7 (every time)). In experiment 2, a few additional questions were added, where subjects reported (1) the intensity of their emotional-state on the above emotions, and (2) their negative affect (from 0 to 7: positive to negative) and arousal level (from 0 to 7: arousal to calm) during both threat and safe conditions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Skin Conductance Responses (SCRs) SCR Acquisition</head><p>The SCRs were measured by Ag/AgCl electrodes filled with gel, and recorded via an amplifier and the software Vsrrp98 (version 7.29). After the instruction, two electrodes were attached on the ring and 3rd fingers of the left hand using medical tape. SCR data was collected at 1000Hz from the beginning to the end of the learning sessions (with the exception of 37 subjects in experiment 1 for which a sampling rate of 500Hz was used). SCR data was synchronized with task events based on markers that indexed block/session onsets, trial onsets and feedback onsets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SCR Analysis</head><p>Before statistical analyses, each participant's SCR data were preprocessed using the following steps: the data underwent (1) despiking by replacing outlier signals (defined as signals &gt;= 3 times the standard deviation), (2) down-sampling to 10Hz and (3) normalization by z-scoring the data. The SCRs were analyzed as phasic responses relative to the trial onset <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Bradley et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Clark et al., 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Specifically, we extracted SCRs for the time window covering 2-4 seconds post trial onset and averaged the SCR response. From this we subtracted the trial-specific baseline, which was the mean SCR covering the 1-second period preceding trial onset (i.e., mean SCR during Inter-trial Interval). To avoid potential confounds caused by the delivery of the electric shock, the trials including shocks were not included in the analysis. Averages for each condition were then entered into a two-way repeated measure ANOVA with outcome valence (gains vs. losses) and anxiety treatment (safe vs. threat) as within-subject factors. Note, that one (experiment 1) and five (experiment 2) subjects were excluded from the SCR analysis, because of the low quality of the recorded SCR signal.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Behavioral Analysis Learning task analysis</head><p>Correct choices from the learning task were extracted and served as a binary outcome variable (coded 1/ -respectively 0 -for a choice of the cue associated with the highest -respectively lowest -objective expected value). Averaged correct choice rates were computed per condition and per subject, and analyzed via a repeated-measures two-way ANOVA with (1) valence and (2) anxiety as factors, subject ID as a random effect, and a full interaction structure. To assess the effect of the differences in design between our two experiments on the different effects, we also added experiment number as betweensubjects factor in the original ANOVA. Paired t-test were used to evaluate post-hoc comparisons between specific conditions.</p><p>As a complementary -and presumably more powerful -analysis, we also analyzed trial-by-trial data using a generalized linear mixed-effect (GLME) model. GLME models included independent variables accounting for the trial number (computed per condition, i.e. Experiment 1: trial = 0:1:23; Experiment 2: trial = 0:1:19), feedback valence (gain= 1; loss = -1), anxiety (threat = 1; safe =-1) and their 2-and 3-way interaction terms (valences* affective* trial). These variables were used in both the fixed-effects and the random-effects structure. The random effects structure accounted for the differences in experimental setups (coded 1 or 2 for Experiment 1 and Experiment 2, respectively) and inter-individual variations (subject's ID), which is nested within experiments. In Wilkinson-Rogers notation, this GLME writes as follows: Given that the dependent variable was binary (the correctness of the choice) we used a logistic link function.</p><p>To directly assess the potential effects of the experimental designs on the manipulation effects, we also estimated the following GLMEs:</p><p>GLME2Learning: Correct ~ (Intercept) + Valence + Anxiety * Experiment * Trial + (1 + Valence + Anxiety * Experiment * Trial | Subject);</p><p>Transfer task analysis Similar to the learning task, the data from the transfer task was analyzed with both a repeated-measures ANOVA and GLME model. In order to impose similar data structures in Experiment 1 and in Experiment 2, we limited our analysis of Experiment 1 transfer pairs to trials where both cues were presented in the same Anxiety condition (i.e. both Safe or both Threat). Averaged choice rates for each cue were computed, and analyzed using a three-way repeated-measures ANOVA with (1) option valence, (2) quality (option expected value: coded 1 if cue was the best of its pair during learning, 0 otherwise) and (3) anxiety manipulation as within-subjects factors, subject ID as a random effect, and a full interaction structure. Again, we added experiment number as between-subjects factor to the original ANOVA to account for the potential effects of design differences between our two experiments.</p><p>Because the preference relationship between intermediate values (i.e. Gain 25% -referred to as G25and Loss 25% -referred to as L25) provide information about contextual learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>, we ran additional analyses that focused on those cues. We submitted the choice rate of cues G25 and L25 to a two-way ANOVA with (1) option valence and (2) emotion manipulation. Afterward, we separately analyzed them for each comparison using a one-sample t-test. Like for the learning task data, the transfer task data was further analyzed more comprehensively at the trial-by-trial level using a GLME approach. The model included independent variables accounting for differences between right and left cues, such as Diff_valence (difference in valence during learning) and Diff_quality (difference in the likelihood of avoiding a loss/attaining a gain during learning), and whether cues were learned in the context of threat (threat = 1; safe =0) and their interactions. These variables were entered into a logistic linear mixed model to predict binary choice based on the same structure of fixed-and random-effects, and also accounting for experiment (coded 1 or 2 for Experiment 1 and Experiment 2, respectively) and inter-individual variations (subject's ID), which is nested within experiment. In Wilkinson-Rogers notation, this GLME writes as follows: All statistical analyses were performed using Matlab R2015a. GLME models were estimated using the function fitglme.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational modelling</head><p>Step 1: identifying the best computational architecture</p><p>In a first modelling stage, we aimed to identify the general algorithm governing learning, regardless of the anxiety condition. Following a previous approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Rescorla and Wagner, 1972)</ref>, we first built a nested model-space (Model Space 1), including six increasingly complex RL models (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> A-B). The six models are referred to as ABS, REL, RELw, ABSa and RELa, and RELa,w, where REL and ABS respectively referred to ABSOLUTE and RELATIVE, 'a' to asymmetric, and 'w' to weighted counterfactual outcome. The ABSOLUTE and RELATIVE models were introduced in <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>In the ABSOLUTE model, at each trial t, the chosen option value (c) of the current context s is updated with the Rescorla-Wagner rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Rescorla and Wagner, 1972)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">"#$ ( , ) = " ( , ) + × "</formula><p>Equation <ref type="formula">1</ref>Where is the learning rate for the chosen option and " is the prediction error term calculated as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">" = " ( ) − " ( , )</formula><p>Equation <ref type="formula">2</ref>In the RELATIVE model, a choice context value ( ( )) is also learned and used as the reference point to which an outcome should be compared before updating option values.</p><p>Context value is also learned via a delta rule:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">"#$ ( ) = " ( ) + 4,"</formula><p>Equation <ref type="formula">3</ref>Where is the context value learning rate and 4 is a prediction error-term calculated as follows:</p><p>4," = ( " ( ) + ¬ " ( ))/2 − " ( ), Equation <ref type="formula">4</ref>¬ " ( ) indexes the outcome not received available in context s, and is computed as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">¬ " ( ) = ⎩ ⎨ ⎧ 0</formula><p>" ( ) = −0.5 or 0.5 0 " ( ) = 0 and " ( ) = 0 0.5 " ( ) = 0 and " ( ) &gt; 0 −0.5 " ( ) = 0 and " ( ) &lt; 0 Equation <ref type="formula">5</ref>Therefore ¬ " captures the fact that participants infer that the non-selected cue is associated with the complementary outcome to the one they actually received. The formulation of ¬ " depends on the context value " ( ) because context values have to be disambiguated (i.e. gain or loss context) before participants can infer the outcome that is complementary to 0. Note that this specification slightly differs from the original model proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>, which writes:</p><p>4," = ( " ( ) + " ( , ))/2 − " ( ), Equation <ref type="formula">6</ref>where " ( , ) is the Q-value of the unchosen option.</p><p>The proposed modifications to the RELATIVE model (Equations 4-5) are meant to account for the significant context dependency observed in our data, evidenced in the Transfer task data (See Results -Model-based analysis indicates that learning is asymmetric and context-dependent). In addition, this formulation provided a better fit of the data than the original one in a formal model-comparison.</p><p>In the asymmetric models (ABSa, RELa, RELa,w), we additionally introduced different learning rates after positive versus negative prediction errors. This follows from several studies showing that individuals tend to give more weights to positive, confirmatory feedback than to negative, disconfirmatory feedback <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Lefebvre et al., 2017</ref>.</p><p>In those models, Equation (1) therefore becomes H "#$ ( , ) = " ( , ) + # × " " &gt; 0 "#$ ( , ) = " ( , ) + I × " " &lt; 0 Equation <ref type="formula">7</ref>In the weighted models (RELw, RELa,w), the inference on the forgone outcome ¬ " ( ) was modulated by a weight as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">4," = ( " ( ) + (¬ " ( )))/2 − " ( ), Equation<label>(8)</label></formula><p>In all models, the probability of choosing option A over B was derived from a softmax function with temperature parameter β:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">( ℎ = ) = (1 + exp ( ( ( ) − ( )))) I$</formula><p>Equation <ref type="formula">9</ref>In the learning task at trial , we have, for an option of a context : ( ) = " ( , )</p><p>In the transfer task, we have, ( ) = XYZ ( , ), where XYZ ( , ) indicate the Q-values of option at the end of the learning session.</p><p>Step 2: Modelling the effects of anxiety</p><p>After having identified the general algorithm governing learning, we next investigated if and how incidental anxiety -as induced by threat of shocks -affects specific sub-processes of learning. We therefore defined a second model space (Model Space 2) by systematically allowing each parameter (the temperature parameter, each of the three learning-rates, and the weighting parameter) of the winning model (i.e., model RELa,w) to differ between the safe and the threat condition. This produced a 5-models model-space, to which was added a base model where all parameters were identical between the safe and the threat condition (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 8A</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Initialization</head><p>Option (Qs) and context (Vs) values were initialized at 0 in each condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Parameter optimization</head><p>For each model , and regardless of the criterion used for model comparison (see below), the parameters ] were optimized by minimizing the negative logarithm of the posterior probability (LPP) over the free parameters:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">LPP = − logb ( ] | , )e ∝ − logb ( | , ] )e − log ( ( ] | ))</formula><p>Here, ( | , ] ) is the likelihood of the data (i.e. the observed choice) given the considered model M and parameter values ] , and ( ] | ) is the prior probability of the parameters.</p><p>Following <ref type="bibr">(Daw et al., 2011)</ref>, the prior probability distributions were defined as a gamma distribution (gampdf(β,1.2,5)) for the choice temperature, and as beta distributions (betapdf(α,1.1,1.1)) for learning rates and weight.</p><p>This procedure was conducted using Matlab's fmincon function with different initialized starting points of the parameter space (i.e., 0&lt;β&lt;Infinite, 0&lt;α&lt;1) <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>. Note that both the learning and transfer task data were used for the parameter optimization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model comparison criteria</head><p>We computed three model comparison criteria, which measure the ability of each model to explain the experimental data, by trading-off their goodness-of-fit and complexity: the Bayesian Information Criteria (BIC), the Akaike's Information Criteria (AIC) and the Laplace approximation to the model evidence (LAME).</p><p>Defining g ] the model parameters identified in the optimization procedure, df the number of model parameters, and n the number of data-points (i.e. trials), AIC, BIC and LAME were computed as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">BIC = log k b l , g ] em − 2 log ( ) AIC = log k b l , g ] em − LAME = log k b l , g ] em + log k b g ] l em + 2 log(2 ) − 1 2 log| |</formula><p>Where | | is the determinant of the Hessian.</p><p>These three criteria were compared in their ability to correctly identify model simulations (see Model identifiability and parameter recovery section below). Because LAME gave the most satisfactory results, only model comparisons using this criterion are reported in the main text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bayesian Model Comparison</head><p>To identify the model most likely to have generated a certain data set, AIC, BIC and LAME were computed at the individual level for each model in the respective model-space, and fed to randomeffects Bayesian Model Comparison using the mbb-vb-toolbox (http://mbb-team.github.io/VBAtoolbox/; <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Daunizeau, Adam, and Rigoux, 2014)</ref>. This procedure estimates the expected frequencies (denoted PP) and the exceedance probability (denoted XP) for each model within a set of models,</p><p>given the data gathered from all subjects. XP quantifies the belief that the model is more likely than all the other models of the model-space. An XP &gt;95% for one model within a set is therefore typically considered as significant evidence in favor of this model being the most likely. Expected frequency (PP), on the other hand, quantifies the posterior probability, i.e., the probability that the model generated the data for any randomly selected subject.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model identifiability and parameter recovery</head><p>In order to assess the reliability of our modelling approach, we performed model identifiability and parameter recovery simulations (see Correa et al., 2018 for a similar approach). Choices from synthetic subjects were generated for each task and each model by running our computational models with model parameters sampled in their prior distribution: softmax temperature β were drawn from gamma distribution (random('Gamma',1.2,5)) and learning rates and weights were drawn from beta distributions (random('beta,1.1,1.1)), as outlined above. Option values Qs and context values Vs were initialized from 0 for four conditions. For each model, we ran 10 simulations including 50 synthetic subjects (N=500).</p><p>Model identifiability was assessed by running the Bayesian Model Comparison on the synthetic data.</p><p>Results are pictured as confusion matrices, where perfect recovery would result in matrices with diagonal elements equal to 1, and off-diagonal elements close to 0. Parameter recovery was assessed by evaluating the correspondence between the parameters used in the simulation, and the parameters recovered by the parameter optimization procedure (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 8</ref> and Supplementary Information). We used two main assessment criteria: first, we performed a linear regression analysis between the parameters used for simulations and the estimated parameters, using data from all simulations (n = 500). In this case, perfect recovery would result in intercepts close to 0 and slopes close to 1, and would be pictured as a 500 dots scatter plot aligned on the identity line. Then, we performed correlation analyses between the parameters used for simulations and the estimated parameters on individual simulations (each with n = 50 synthetic data). Correlation coefficients were averaged over the 10 simulations, and displayed as correlation matrices. In this case, perfect recovery would result in matrices with diagonal elements equal to 1, and off-diagonal elements close to 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Manipulation checks: successful induction of anxiety</head><p>In order to ensure that our anxiety manipulation was successful, we inspected self-reported emotion and physiological responses. In both experiments, self-reported anxiety during the threat condition was significantly higher than other (negative and high arousal) emotions, including sadness (Exp.1: t44 = 6.78, P &lt; .001, d = 1.01; Exp.2: t49 = 6.17, P &lt; .001, d = 0.87) and anger (Exp.1: t44 = 3.56, P &lt; .001, d</p><p>= 0.53; Exp.2: t49 = 4.98, P &lt; .001, d = 0.70), but was similar to fear (Exp.1: t44=1.57, P =.1235, d = 0.23; Exp.2: t44 = 0.67, P = .5024, d = 0.09). While self-reported anxiety levels were significantly greater than 0 in both experiments (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>), anxiety levels were significantly higher in experiment 1 compared to experiment 2 (t93= 4.28, P &lt; .001, d = 0.87). This indicates that blocking ToS, as done in experiment 1, induced greater levels of anxiety compared to the more prolonged ToS presentation in experiment 2.</p><p>The self-report results are paralleled by the SCR results, which showed significantly higher phasic responses during anxious compared to safe trials <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Figure 3</ref>). An ANOVA showed a main effect of  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model-free analysis: No effects of Valence and Anxiety on learning performance</head><p>To investigate the overall effects of our experimental manipulations (valence: gain vs. loss; anxiety: safe vs. threat) on learning performance, we first analyzed the probability of correct responses averaged per condition, using a two-way repeated-measures ANOVA. This analysis revealed no significant main effects of -nor significant interactions between -our experimental factors on learning performance (Exp.1: Ps' &gt; 0.12; Exp.2: Ps' &gt; 0.14; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4A</ref> and Table S1-S2). While the two variants of the ToS procedure had a marginally different impact on average learning performance (Exp.1 = 74.12%, Exp.2 = 71.60%; F1,99 = 2.66, P = .1057, v w = 0.02), they did not induce significantly different effects of anxiety on learning (F1,99 = 0.008, P = .9271, v w = 0.00). As subsequent analyses focus on identifying the effect of anxiety, we therefore combined the data from the two experiments (but we additionally continue to report individual experiment results for all main analyses).</p><p>Combining the two experiments in a single ANOVA, we replicate the absence of significant main and interaction effects on learning performance (All Ps' &gt; 0.12: see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4A</ref> and <ref type="table">Table S2</ref>), as reported above. Although the lack of valence effects replicates previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Fontanesi et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Lebreton et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>, the absence of significant effects of anxiety might seem surprising at first glance, as it contradicts several previous studies suggesting anxiety affects learning per se <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(DeVido et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Glienke et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Treadway et al., 2017)</ref>. However, our findings agree with our literature review of 13 studies on the effects of experimentally induced anxiety on instrumental learning, which also failed to identify a consensual, robust effect of anxiety on learning <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figure 1</ref> and Supplementary- <ref type="table">Table S10</ref>).</p><p>Because the absence of effects of anxiety contradicts our a priori hypothesis, we next turned to a more flexible statistical analysis framework using a generalized linear mixed-effect (GLME) model. This approach allows us to inspect our data trial-by-trial to capture learning effects and may be more powerful than ANOVAs in the presence of unbalanced or missing data <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Matuschek et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Pinheiro and Bates, 2000)</ref>. Although the GLME revealed a main effect of trial on performance, capturing the dynamics of learning ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4B</ref> and Supplementary- <ref type="table">Table S3</ref>), no other significant main effects and/or interaction with the experimental manipulations were detected. Confirming the ANOVAs results, this indicates that threat of shock might have a limited impact on learning processes.</p><p>Moreover, we also did not find an effect of experimental designs on learning (βexp = -0.00±0.03, t25276= -0.14, P = .8834; βexp*anxiety = 0.03±0.04, t25276= 0.82, P = .4082; see Supplementary -Robustness tests and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure S1A</ref>). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model-free analysis: non-specific effects of Anxiety on transfer task performance reflecting learned values</head><p>Participants' choices in the transfer task provide additional information about the value of the cues that they have learned throughout the learning task. We first computed the preference for each cue as the probability of choosing the cue over all other cues ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref>; and see <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Palminteri et al., 2015</ref> for a similar approach). Importantly, the three-way repeated-measures ANOVA (see <ref type="table">Table S4</ref> and Methods -Behavioral analysis) identified an interaction between cue quality and anxiety (interaction of anxiety and quality; F1,99 = 6.37, P = .0131, v w = 0.06). Post-hoc tests were performed to characterize the interaction between anxiety and quality. Results indicate that the interaction is driven by subjects choosing the better symbols (G75 and L25) over the worse symbols (G25 and L75) significantly more often in the threat compared to the safe condition (Better-Worse in threat &gt; Better-Worse in safe: t99 = 2.41, P = .0165, d = 0.17; see also <ref type="table">Supplementary Table S7</ref>). These results indicate that anxiety boosts participants' preference for higher quality cues.</p><p>Additional results from this ANOVA revealed that a cue is more likely to be preferred if it was associated with gains compared to losses (main effect of option valence; F1,99 = 212.85, P = 2.07 × 10 -26 , v w = 0.68), regardless of the anxiety condition (F1,99 = 0.31, P = .5756, v w = 0.00). A cue is also more likely to be preferred if it was the best cue (G75 and L25) of the pair during the learning task (main effects of Option quality; F1,99 = 241.60, P = 2.59×10 -28 , v w = 0.70). However, there were no valence-dependent effects of anxiety on preferences in the transfer task (F1,99 = 0.55, P = .4586, v w = 0.00), as well as no main and interaction effects of anxiety with the factor experiment (P's &gt; 0.19).</p><p>The latter result suggests that the two anxiety induction methods did not differentially impact preference in the transfer task. Taken together, anxiety during learning improved recognition of cue quality in the transfer task independent of valence.</p><p>Those results were confirmed in a more comprehensive GLME approach (see Methods -Behavioral analysis ), which modelled transfer task choices between two cues as a function of (1) the difference between the cues' valence (gains vs. losses), (2) the difference between the cues' quality (better option in learned pair vs. worse option in learned pair), and (3) whether cues were learned in the anxiety condition (safe vs shock). The GLME model also accounted for differences in experimental designs (experiment 1 vs. experiment 2) and subject ID, which was nested within each experiment (see Methods -Behavioral analysis). The results ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5B</ref> and <ref type="table">Table S5</ref>) showed that subjects' decisions were influenced by valence (T13592 = 8.90; P = 5.83× 10 -19 ), quality (T13592 = 6.53; P = 6.73× 10 -11 ) and the interaction between anxiety and quality (T13592 = 2.44; P = .0144). Comparable to the ANOVA results above, we did not find a main effect of experiment (βexp = -0.01±0.08, t13591 = -0.13, P = .8940)</p><p>nor an interaction between experiment and anxiety (βexp*anxiety = -0.03±0.12, t13591= -0.24, P = .8041; see Supplementary Robustness tests and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure S1B</ref>), indicating that the experimental design had little effect on the impact of anxiety on post-learning performance.</p><p>Post-hoc analyses showed that cue discrimination (G75+L25 &gt; G25+L75) was significantly improved in the threat compared to the safe condition (t99 = 2.41, P = .0165, d = 0.17). Note that this effect was The results indicate that anxiety might enhance subjects' ability to identify the higher quality symbol some time after learning, even though it does not affect average learning performance at the learning stage <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Figure 4</ref>).</p><p>Following previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015</ref> we conducted an additional analysis that focused on cues that were associated with intermediate values (i.e., G25 and L25) and tested if subject displayed rational preferences to choose cues based on expected value <ref type="table">(Table S6</ref>). The two-way ANOVA with valence and anxiety as factors showed a significant main effect of valence (F1,99 = 5.96, P = .0163, v w = 0.05), but no significant main effect of anxiety (F1,99 = 0.55, P = .4586, v w = 0.00) nor its interaction (F1,99 = 2.63, P = .1077, v w = 0.02).</p><p>Model-based analysis indicates that learning is asymmetric and context-dependent.</p><p>Our analysis of the general effects of anxiety in our factorial design (see previous sections) points toward non-specific, elusive effects of anxiety in reinforcement learning. Two concurrent hypotheses might explain this observation: on the one hand, it is possible that anxiety affects specific latent mechanisms of reinforcement-learning, that may be subtle and therefore difficult to identify via modelfree factorial design analyses; alternatively, it may be that anxiety indeed does not affect reinforcement-learning processes in a strong and idiosyncratic way.</p><p>To tease apart these competing explanations, we next turned to computational modelling. By explicitly modelling the computations giving rise to participants' behavior, computational modelling can efficiently combine data from both learning and transfer task <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref> and can identify latent operations that would be specifically impacted by anxiety <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bishop and Gagne, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Mkrtchian et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Treadway et al., 2017)</ref>. As a first step, we aimed at identifying a core architecture that would capture the learning behavior regardless of anxiety (i.e. in both safe and threat conditions).</p><p>Following decades of research on the modelling of similar tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Pessiglione et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Rescorla and Wagner, 1972;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Sutton and Barto, 1998)</ref>, we assumed that participants learned the value of available options using an algorithm akin to Q-learning.</p><p>Yet, several features of the observed behavioral pattern suggest that simple Q-learning would not be sufficient to comprehensively capture our participants' learning dynamics. First, the fact that subjects generally express higher preference for the L25 than for the G25 cue in the transfer task is a signature of context-dependent learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Klein, Ullsperger, and Jocham 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Lebreton et al., 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">, Palminteri et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">, 2017</ref>. Briefly, in addition to standard Q-learning computations, context-dependent learning explicitly computes a context-value, which approximates the average expected value from a specific context. Obtained outcomes are then reframed relatively to this context value, allowing e.g. minor losses encountered in a loss context to be experienced as relative gains and vice-versa. This explains why small losses (L25) are preferred to small gains (G25) post learning in the transfer task.</p><p>Second, the apparently higher variability of performance observed in the gain compared to the loss domain could be a signature of asymmetric learning. Briefly, if positive prediction errors are weighted more heavily than negative ones, individuals can quickly diverge in response rates <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Lefebvre et al., 2017)</ref>. Considering these two potential additional features of reinforcement learning models, we built a model space comprising six computational models presenting different combinations of those features (see Methods and <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> A-B). Using simulations, we verified that those models were identifiable, and that their parameters could be satisfactorily estimated <ref type="figure">(Figure 6 C-D)</ref>.</p><p>We then fitted those models to our data, and ran a full Bayesian model comparison (BMC) procedure, aiming at identifying the best and most parsimonious computational architecture. In line with the behavioral signatures identified in the beginning of this section, the BMC identified the RL model including both learning-rate asymmetry and context-dependency (RELa,w) as the best explanation of <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. Modelling approach (Step 1). A. depiction of the model architecture basis. B. Model Space. C. Model identifiability analysis. Data from 100 synthetic participants were simulated (50 with experiment 1 design, 50 with experiment 2 design) with each of our 6 models. Bayesian model selection was used to identify the most probable model generating the data, using the Laplace approximation to model evidence. This procedure was repeated 10 times. Left: average exceedance probability confusion matrix. Right: Best model selection confusion matrix. D. Parameter recovery analysis. The confusion matrices represent summary statistics of the correlations between parameters, estimated over 100-subjects simulations, and averaged over the 10 simulations. Diagonal: correlations between simulated and estimated parameters. Off diagonal: cross correlation between estimated parameters. Left: Pearson correlation (R). Right: explained variance (R 2 ).</p><p>our data (exceedance probability: 93%; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7A</ref>). Note that RELa,w also won the BMC procedure based on data restricted to experiment 1 and 2 (exceedance probability: 76% and 88%; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7A</ref>).</p><p>Average estimated parameter values were very similar to previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>, and were also very similar between experiment 1 and 2 ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7B</ref>). The modelling results notably replicate the learning asymmetry reported in previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Lefebvre et al., 2017;</ref>, with positive learning rates being significantly larger than negative learning rates (α + = 0.37±0.02; α -= 0.07±0.01; t99 = 10.26, P = 2.92´10 -17 , d = 1.06). Overall, this model provided a very good fit of both learning and transfer task data <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">(Figure 7 C-D)</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model-based analysis of the effects of anxiety on learning is inconclusive</head><p>To investigate the effects of anxiety on learning, we next built a second model space, where all models were derived from the RELa,w , but additionally allowed parameters to vary between the Safe and Threat conditions. Given that RELa,w possesses 5 parameters (the choice temperature, three learning rates, and the unchosen outcome weighting parameter), the second model space featured 6 models (see Methods). Similar to the first modelling step, we ran model identifiability and parameter recovery analyses ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 8B)</ref>. Results show that some models cannot be perfectly identified: models 4 and 6, which respectively feature differential learning rates for negative PE (α-) and differential weighting parameters (w) between anxiety and safe conditions both tended to be identified as the simplest model.</p><p>Despite those limitations, we still compared those models in their ability to account for the observed data (see Methods). The Bayesian Model Comparison with LAME failed to identify a clear best model ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 8C</ref>), indicating that allowing important model parameters to vary as a function of anxiety does not improve model fit. Step 2). A. Model Space. S and T represent safe and threat condition, respectively. S = T indicates safe and threat condition share the same parameter. B. Model identifiability analysis. Data from 100 synthetic participants were simulated (50 with experiment 1 design, 50 with experiment 2 design) with each of our 6 models. Bayesian model selection was used to identify the most probable model generating the data, using the Laplace approximation to model evidence. This procedure was repeated 10 times. Left: average exceedance probability confusion matrix. Right: Best model selection confusion matrix. C. Model comparison results. These panels depict the results of a Bayesian model comparison analysis on our participants data, for experiment 1 (yellow diamonds), experiment 2 (blue diamonds) and both experiments combined (black diamonds). Left: exceedance probability of each model. Right: expected frequencies of each model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Summary of design, results and contributions</head><p>In two experiments, we investigated the impact of incidental anxiety on both learning performance during a probabilistic instrumental task <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Pessiglione et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref> and on postlearning transfer preferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Frank et al., 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">, Palminteri et al., 2015</ref>, using a well-established Threat of Shock (ToS) paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Engelmann et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Engelmann et al., , 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Grillon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Schmitz and Grillon, 2012)</ref>. Two variants of the anxiety induction method were used during learning: threat and safety trials were either alternated in blocks of three trials (experiment 1), which induced relatively higher levels of anxiety, or in sessions of 80 trials (experiment 2), which induced relatively lower levels of anxiety.</p><p>Behavioral results from two experiments consistently showed that anxiety and outcome valence had little to no effect on learning performance per se. At first glance, these results may be somewhat surprising given that they seem to contradict several previous studies suggesting that anxiety alters learning performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(DeVido et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Schwabe and Wolf, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Stevens et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Treadway et al., 2017)</ref>. However, a small-scale literature review agrees with our main result as it also failed to identify consensual and robust main effects of anxiety on learning across 13 papers <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figure 1</ref> and Supplementary- <ref type="table">Table S10</ref>).</p><p>Importantly, our results nonetheless suggest that transfer preferences were significantly altered by the anxiety manipulation. Specifically, post-learning preferences indicate that participants were better able to identify the quality of cues when these cues were learned in a threatening compared to a safe context.</p><p>Note again that this effect was observed in the absence of any effects of anxiety on average learning performance and therefore is indicative of anxiety exhibiting somewhat delayed effects on postlearning preferences and recall (see also Discussion: transfer task). Similar improvements in the ability to identify cues during a post-learning transfer task have been observed in one other prior study <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Cavanagh et al., 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Considering the possibility that anxiety effects differ when individuals seek rewards vs. avoid punishments, our experiment did not reveal any valence-dependent effects during both learning and post-learning performance. These results agree with our targeted literature review, which also failed to identify a robust consensus on this question. Specifically, other studies have reported inconsistent valence dependent effects of stress or anxiety on post-learning performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abraham and Hermann, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berghorst et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cavanagh et al., 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cavanagh et al., , 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lighthall et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Petzold et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Voegler et al., 2019)</ref>: for learning performance in the domain of gains 6/8 studies reported a null effect, 1/8 reported improvements and 1/8 reported reduced performance. In the domain of losses, 4/8 studies reported improved performance, while 1/8 reported reduced performance in the domain of losses and 3/8 reported a null effect <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figure 1)</ref>. Jointly, the current and previous results indicate that anxiety likely does not have differential effects on learning to seek rewards and to learning to avoiding punishments.</p><p>A primary goal of the current experiments was to assess multiple experimental factors that could skew results from prior experiments in one experimental setup. To this end, our experiments were carefully designed to assess the differential effects of anxiety on learning and post-learning preferences, as well as on punishment and reward learning, while simultaneously reducing the effects of potential confounding factors using multiple methods. Firstly, by adapting a ToS paradigm to induce anxiety, each subject learned action-outcome associations separately under a threatening context and under safety. Moreover, the ToS procedure allowed us to customize the intensity of the negative event (i.e., electric shock) to each participant's pain threshold, and to successfully create significant threat levels for all subjects across two experiments (as assessed by SCR responses and self-reports). The ability to turn threat on and off at specific time points throughout the experiments allowed us to directly assess the effects of anxious states on learning in a within-subject design. This is important to assess the causal effects of anxiety on learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Engelmann et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Engelmann et al., , 2019</ref>, and addresses a major limitation of traditional emotion and stress induction techniques, the common delay between the induction time point and behavioral task. Secondly, we induced anxiety for two different periods including relatively short blocks of three trials (experiment 1) and relatively long periods lasting for a full session of 96 trials (experiment 2). This was done for two reasons; (1) it allowed us to assess potential biases induced by the repeated switching of emotional states and associated stimuli in experiment 1, and (2) it allowed us to assess the effect of different threat level intensities, with experiment 1 creating a relatively more intense emotional state compared to experiment 2. Thirdly, we assessed the effects of anxiety on learning over gains and losses by crossing the ToS manipulation with an outcome valence manipulation. This allowed us to directly assess the effects of anxiety on learning to seek gains and to avoid losses separately <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Palminteri and Pessiglione, 2017)</ref>. Finally, we differentiated the effects of anxiety on learning and post-learning performance by including both a learning stage and a postlearning task in the same study. Despite these methodological advances, we find only limited effects of anxiety on learning per se, but significant enhancements of the ability to identify better quality cues in a post learning transfer task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion: learning</head><p>We consider three explanations for the limited effects of incidental anxiety on learning, observed in the current two experiments. These include the hypotheses that (1) only trait, but not state anxiety may have an impact on learning;</p><p>(2) anxiety reduces the available cognitive resources and its effects can only be revealed in more difficult settings;</p><p>(3) anxiety causes an inflexibility in learning, which can only be revealed using more complex task designs that require planning and adaptation.</p><p>Firstly, a prominent hypothesis suggests that state and trait anxiety might impact different underlying learning mechanisms . Specifically, Robinson et al argue that state anxiety in response to unpredictable threat is "adaptive" as it prepares flexible physiological responses and behaviors to cope with negative events that may ensure survival . Elevated and prolonged levels of trait anxiety on the other hand can become "maladaptive" and interfere with normal day-to-day functioning . A number of previous studies showed behavioral effects of trait and pathological anxiety on learning that generally support this hypothesis ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 1</ref>, yellow bars; <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abraham and Hermann 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Browning et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">DeVido et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Robinson, Bond, and Roiser, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Stevens et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Voegler et al., 2019)</ref>. However, this idea has recently been challenged by research revealing more limited effects of both trait and state anxiety on learning performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Berghorst et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cavanagh et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lighthall et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Petzold et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Schwabe and Wolf, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Voegler et al., 2019)</ref>, even in more complicated settings (modelbased learning: <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Gillan et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">social learning: Safra et al., 2018)</ref>. To resolve this disagreement on the relative importance of state compared to trait anxiety, we assessed the effects of trait anxiety in our current data set by conducting additional analyses focusing on individual differences in BAI scores on learning and post-learning performance (see Supplementary-Robustness test, section 2 and <ref type="figure">Figure S2</ref>).</p><p>Note that our approach allows us to identify both main effects of state and trait anxiety, but also their interaction. Our results did not identify any main effects of BAI in the learning and post-learning task, indicating that high and low anxious subjects learned to seek gains and avoid losses equally well.</p><p>Moreover, we did not observe an interaction effect between state and trait anxiety during learning and post-learning. Our results, together with the inconsistent findings of prior research identified by our literature review, suggest that both trait and state anxiety have little main and interactive effects on learning and post-learning performance.</p><p>Secondly, according to attentional control theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Eysenck et al., 2007)</ref>, performance might be intact if cognitive demands of the task do not exceed cognitive resources. Therefore, if the probability of a positive or negative outcome differs substantially between the stimuli during the learning phase (i.e., 75% vs 25%), the task might be too easy to reveal the impact of anxiety given the experimental setup in the current study. Specifically, subjects might have sufficient cognitive resources to deal with such a relatively simple task, even when learning under conditions of anxiety. Although this explanation is partially rejected by previous studies that found no significant interactions between difficulty and anxiety manipulations, the tasks used in previous experiments might also not have sufficiently challenged participants <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abraham and Hermann, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berghorst et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cavanagh et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cavanagh et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lighthall et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Petzold et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Voegler et al., 2019)</ref>. To address this potential explanation, we inspected our data by focusing on a subset of participants that showed evidence for finding this task relatively difficult. We identified these subjects via cluster analysis (kmeans, Supplementary-Robustness test, section 3) and split our subject pool into two groups, one showing relatively lower average performance (57% accuracy) throughout the learning task and another with relatively higher average performance (76% accuracy). If the predictions from attentional control theory apply to our results, we should observe larger effects of anxiety on learning and postlearning performance in the subject group with lower average performance that likely found the task more difficult. Our results did not support this potential interpretation and were consistent with previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abraham and Hermann, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berghorst et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cavanagh et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cavanagh et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lighthall et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Petzold et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Voegler et al., 2019</ref>; see also . Specifically, while we found a significant main effect of performance group on predicting correct choice in the learning task, this effect was not modulated by anxiety (see Supplementary-Robustness test, section 3 and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure S3</ref>). The result in the transfer task also showed non-significant two-and three-way interactions of anxiety with performance group and quality. These results further support the notion that anxiety has limited effects on learning performance. Moreover, the effects we observe here are likely not modulated by task-dependent availability of cognitive resources (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Engelmann et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>In a similar vein, the anxiety condition might specifically increase cognitive task load. We inspected this possibility by analyzing reaction times across the two conditions, which is generally considered one of the hallmark measures of cognitive load <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Pashler, 1994)</ref>. We did not find slower reaction times under conditions of anxiety <ref type="table">(Table S8)</ref>, indicating that subjects did not face greater cognitive load in the threat condition.</p><p>Finally, the effects of anxiety have previously been associated with inflexibility in learning, which might be caused by either difficulty in switching between habit and goal-directed decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Browning et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Otto et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Raio et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Schwabe and Wolf, 2009)</ref> or intolerance for uncertainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Browning et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Christian and Florian, 2019)</ref>. Therefore, our one-stage reinforcement learning task with stable contingencies of action and outcome might not be able to detect these anxiety-related changes in behavior. Taken together, the impact of anxiety on learning might be varied and depend on the type of anxiety and the task's difficulty and their interactions. Yet, again, the robustness of the effects of anxiety on learning flexibility have been challenged by recent high-powered studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Gillan et al., 2019)</ref> and our small-scale review.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion: transfer task</head><p>The significant general improvement in the ability to identify better options during the transfer task when these were learned under anxiety is consistent with a growing literature showing that a threatening environment can significantly impact memory processes under specific conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bolton and Robinson, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Vytal et al., 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Vytal et al., , 2013</ref>. In light of this, the current results might indicate that anxiety enhances memory retrieval for the value of cues encoded under anxiety <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Mather and Lighthall, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Porcelli and Delgado, 2017)</ref>.</p><p>Note that the presence of anxiety effects observed in the transfer task in the absence of any effects of anxiety on average learning performance could also indicate that the transfer task is more sensitive to capture anxiety effects, whereas average learning effects dilute them. We tested this possibility, by analyzing separately the early and late phase of learning (see Supplementary-Robustness test, section 5). Our results suggest that the learning performance in the late learning stage, rather than early or overall performance, might be more susceptible to the effect of incidental anxiety -although these effects are still very marginal and would need to be replicated.</p><p>The absence of detectable valence-specific effects of anxiety on performance in the transfer task in the present study might at first glance contradict previous results on the effects of anxiety on learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Berghorst et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cavanagh et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lighthall et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">, Petzold et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Voegler et al., 2019)</ref>. However, our targeted literature review, suggests that prior results are rather inconsistent with no detectable trends in the domain of gains (null effect: 75%, improvement: 12.5%, decline:</p><p>12.5%) and suggest a slight improvement in average performance in the domain of losses (null effect: 37.5%, improvement: 50%, decline: 12.5%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion: Modelling</head><p>Besides model-free analyses, we also used computational modeling as a more formal tool to characterize the specific influence(s) of anxiety on the learning process. Our modelling approach, validated by simulation-based parameter recovery and model indentifiability procedures, identified a winning model that updates expected values using a context-dependent and asymmetric learning rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Wilson and Collins, 2019)</ref>. Context-dependency implies that option values are updated with respect to a reference point, which approximate the average expected value of a pair, and which is learned on a trial-by-trial basis with a specific contextual-learning rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Palminteri et al., 2015)</ref>. Factually, this allows to reframe small losses as rewards in a loss context and small rewards as losses in a gain context. Learning asymmetry was featured by different learning rates to update values after positive vs negative prediction errors. Similar to previous reports, we found that learning asymmetry captures a confirmation bias, with positive learning rate parameters taking values twice as big as negative learning rate parameters <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Lefebvre et al., 2017;</ref>.</p><p>These results have important implications: they suggest that human learning incorporates more features (context-dependency, learning asymmetry) than typically thought, even in simple, traditional instrumental learning tasks that have been used for years <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Frank et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Pessiglione et al., 2006)</ref>.</p><p>Because interpreting parameter fits from models that provide incomplete descriptions of behavior is problematic <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Nassar and Gold, 2013)</ref>, this suggests that some simple modelling approaches that omit those features could have converged on erroneous conclusions about the effects of experimental manipulations or neuro-psychiatric pathologies on learning parameters.</p><p>After having identified the model that best and most comprehensively accounts for the general learning behavior of our participants, we aimed to evaluate the impact of anxiety on its parameters. Yet, we found that models including extra parameters to capture the effect of anxiety cannot be robustly identified. This misidentification issue suggests that those parameters have such a subtle (i.e., small) effect on the general behavior observed in the learning and transfer tasks, that the current task design (with its conditions, number of sessions, and number of trials) is not powerful enough to detect them.</p><p>Given that our experimental design favorably compares to previous ones in terms of power (number of subjects, trials, etc.), this indicates that most designs (including ours) might not be powerful enough to allow the detection of the potential effects of anxiety, once all the complex features of learning that can be detected in human learning behavior (context dependency, learning asymmetry) are taken into account.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>The current study investigated the effects of anxiety on learning, while addressing several concerns about experimental designs and analytical choices that might have led to discrepancies in the identification of such effects in previous studies. Despite our relatively powerful approach that simultaneously assessed learning and post-learning performance, as well as reward and punishment learning in the context of a within-subject anxiety induction, and contrary to some previous studies, our experiments failed to reveal clear and specific effects of anxiety on learning per se. While surprising at first glance, our null results agree with findings from a small-scale review that shows little to no effects of anxiety on learning and post-learning performance on average and they add to recent results, which have started to challenge the role of anxiety in experience-based decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bishop and Gagne, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Gillan et al., 2019)</ref>.   respectively. B. Model identifiability analysis. Data from 100 synthetic participants were simulated (50 with experiment 1 design, 50 with experiment 2 design) with each of our 6 models. Bayesian model selection was used to identify the most probable model generating the data, using the Laplace approximation to model evidence. This procedure was repeated 10 times. Left: average exceedance probability confusion matrix. Right:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figures and Figure Legends</head><p>Best model selection confusion matrix. C. Model comparison results. These panels depict the results of a Bayesian model comparison analysis on our participants data, for experiment 1 (yellow diamonds), experiment 2 (blue diamonds) and both experiments combined (black diamonds). Left: exceedance probability of each model. Right: expected frequencies of each model.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>GLME1Learning: Correct ~ (Intercept) + Valence * Anxiety * Trial + (1 + Valence * Anxiety * Trial | Experiment/Subject);</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>GLME1Transfer: ChooseRight ~ (Intercept) + Diff_Valence * Diff_Quality * Anxiety + (1 + Diff_Valence * Diff_Quality * Anxiety | Experiment/Subject); Additional GLMEs added experiment number as fixed effect to assess its effect on experimental manipulation effects: GLME2Transfer: ChooseRight ~ (Intercept) + Diff_Valence + Diff_Quality * Anxiety* Experiment + (1 + Diff_Valence + Diff_Quality * Anxiety* Experiment | Subject);</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>anxiety (Exp.1: F1,47 = 130.35, P &lt; .0001, v w = 0.69; Exp.2: F1,44 = 4.28, P = .0444, v w = 0.08). This effect was not modulated by outcome valence (Exp.1: F1,47 = 0.08, P = .7719, v w = 0.02; Exp.2: F1,44 = 0.00, P = .9901, v w = 0.00). While SCR levels were significantly greater during threat compared to safe trials in both experiments (Exp.1: t48 = 10.44, P &lt; .0001, d = 1.49; Exp.2: t44 = 2.06, P = .0444, d = 0.30), arousal levels during threat (vs. safe) conditions were also significantly greater on average in experiment 1 compared to experiment 2 (Exp.1&gt; Exp.2: t92 = 6.94, P &lt; .0001, d = 0.35). Jointly, results from SCR and self-report indicate that ToS successfully induced anxiety in both experiments.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Electrophysiological results. Skin conductance responses (SCR) were significantly higher in the threat condition compared to the safe condition (Exp.1: t48 =10.44, P &lt; .0001, d = 1.49; Exp.2: t44 =2.06, P = .0444, d = 0.30). Moreover, this effect was more significant in Experiment 1 than Experiment 2 (Exp.1&gt; Exp.2: t92= 6.9499, P &lt; .0001, d = 0.35). ~ 0.05&lt;p&lt;0.1; * 0.01&lt; p&lt;0.05; ** 0.001&lt; p&lt; 0.01; *** p&lt; 0</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Learning performance and results from generalized linear mixed-effect model. A. Left and middle panels: learning curves representing the fraction of correct choices in the safe (left; filled dots) and the threat (middle; unfilled dots) conditions. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean (SEM), and shaded areas represent the mean ± SEM of GLME predictions. Right panels: average correct rate across four conditions. Each gray line indicates individual's choice patterns across the conditions. B. Generalized linear mixed-effect model (i.e., GLME1Learning) with choice accuracy as dependent variable. The y-axis represents the estimated standardized coefficient (t-value), and the x-axis represents each factor in the GLME model. Dot colors indicate results from different dataset. Tr.: Trial; Val.: outcome valence; Anx.: Anxiety manipulation</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Choice pattern in transfer task and corresponding results from generalized linear mixed effect model. (A) Averaged choice rate for each cue. Each gray line indicates individual's choice pattern. The filled dots represent cues learned under the safe condition, the unfilled dots indicate cues learned during the threat condition. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean (SEM), and shaded areas represent the mean ± SEM of the GLME predictions (B) Generalized linear mixed-effect model (i.e., GLME1Transfer) with cue selection as dependent variable. The y-axis represents the estimated standardized coefficient (t-value), and the x-axis represents each factor in the GLME model. Dot colors indicate results from different dataset. G75: 75% of gain; G25: 25% of gain; L25: 25% of loss; G75: 75% of loss; Val.: outcome valence; Qual.: Quality of cue (i.e. Higher expected value in its pair during learning); Anx.: Anxiety manipulation not significant in experiment 1 (t49 = 1.27, P = .2058, d = 0.12), but the direction was the same as observed in experiment 2 (t49 = 2.42, P = .0171, d = 0.24).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Modelling results for the general learning architecture (Step1). A. Model comparison results. These panels depict the results of a Bayesian model comparison analysis on our participants data, for experiment 1 (yellow diamonds), experiment 2 (blue diamonds) and both experiments combined (black diamonds). Left: exceedance probability of each model. Right: expected frequencies of each model. B. Model parameters of the winning model (RELa,w) for experiments 1 (yellow) and 2 (blue).Filled dots represent individual parameters while error bars represent population mean±SEM. C. Learning curves, representing the fraction of correct choices in the safe (left; filled dots) and the threat (middle; unfilled dots) conditions. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean (SEM), and shaded areas represent the mean ± SEM of the RELa,w predictions. D. Transfer choice rate for each cue. Each gray line indicates individual's choice pattern. The filled dots represent cues learned under the safe condition, the unfilled dots indicate cues learned during the threat condition. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean (SEM), and shaded areas represent the mean ± SEM of the RELa,w predictions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Modelling approach (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Overall effect of anxiety on learning and post-learning/transfer task. The stack bars summarized number of previous findings about the effect of anxiety on performance in learning task (middleleft panel), transfer tasks of approaching gains (middle-right panel) and transfer tasks of avoiding losses (right panel). In each pool of task, we separately reported numbers of articles showing decreases (-), no changes(0)or increases (+) of performance. The findings were categorized by both types of anxiety (green: state-anxiety; yellow: trait-anxiety) and sample size (brighter: N&lt;50; darker: N&gt;50). For instance, light green and and light yellow represents effect of state-anxiety and effect of trait-anxiety with sample size N&lt;50, respectively.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 3 .Figure 6 .</head><label>36</label><figDesc>Electrophysiological results. Skin conductance responses (SCR) were significantly higher in the threat condition compared to the safe condition (Exp.1: t48 =10.44, P &lt; .0001, d = 1.49; Exp.2: t44 =2.06, P = .0444, d = 0.30). Moreover, this effect was more significant in Experiment 1 than Experiment 2 (Exp.1&gt; Exp.2: t92= 6.9499, P &lt; .0001, d = 0.35).~ 0.05&lt;p&lt;0.1; * 0.01&lt; p &lt;0.05; ** 0.001&lt; p &lt; 0.01; *** p&lt; 0.001 and middle panels: learning curves, representing the fraction of correct choices in the safe (left; filled dots) and the threat (middle; unfilled dots) conditions. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean (SEM), and shaded areas represent the mean ± SEM of GLME predictions. Right panels: average correct rate across four conditions. B. Generalized linear mixed-effect model (i.e., GLME1Learning) with choice accuracy as dependent variable. The y-axis represents the estimated standardized coefficient (t-value), and x-axis represents each factor in the GLME model. Tr.: Trial; Val.: outcome valence; Anx.: Anxiety manipulation Modelling approach. Modelling approach. A. depiction of the model architecture basis. B. Model Space. C. Model identifiability analysis. Data from 100 synthetic participants were simulated (50 with experiment 1 design, 50 with experiment 2 design) with each of our 6 models. Bayesian model selection was used to identify the most probable model generating the data, using the Laplace approximation to model evidence. This procedure was repeated 10 times. Left: average exceedance probability confusion matrix. Right: Best model selection confusion matrix. D. Parameter recovery analysis. The confusion matrices represent summary statistics of the correlations between parameters, estimated over 100-subject simulations, and averaged over the 10 simulations. Diagonal: correlations between simulated and estimated parameters. Off diagonal: cross correlation between estimated parameters. Left: Pearson correlation (R). Right: explained variance (R 2).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 7 .Figure 8 .</head><label>78</label><figDesc>Modelling results -Step 1 Modelling results -Step2. A. Model Space. S and T represent safe and threat condition,</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biases in probabilistic category learning in relation to social anxiety</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abraham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01218</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01218" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxiety patients show reduced working memory Related dlPFC activation during safety and threat</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Balderston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Vytal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>O'connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Torrisi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Letkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ernst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/da.22518</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/da.22518" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Depression and Anxiety</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Threat-related attentional bias in anxious and nonanxious individuals: A metaanalytic study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bar-Haim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Pergamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bakermans-Kranenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Van Ijzendoorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-2909.133.1.1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.133.1.1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An inventory for measuring clinical anxiety: Psychometric properties</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Steer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037//0022-006X.56.6.893</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//0022-006X.56.6.893" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="893" to="897" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychometric properties of the Beck Depression Inventory: Twenty-five years of evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Steer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Carbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0272-7358(88)90050-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0272-7358(88)90050-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinical Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Acute stress selectively reduces reward sensitivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Berghorst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogdan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pizzagalli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnhum.2013.00133</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00133" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxiety, Depression, and Decision Making: A Computational Perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bishop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gagne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev-neuro-080317-062007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-neuro-080317-062007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="388" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of threat of shock-induced anxiety on memory encoding and retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/lm.045187.117</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/lm.045187.117" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Learning &amp; Memory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="532" to="542" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Covert and overt orienting of attention to emotional faces in anxiety</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bradley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mogg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Millar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02699930050156636</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02699930050156636" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition and Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="789" to="808" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxious individuals have difficulty learning the causal statistics of aversive environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Browning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Jocham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>O'reilly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bishop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.3961</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3961" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="590" to="596" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple dissociations between comorbid depression and anxiety on reward and punishment processing: Evidence from computationally informed EEG</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bismark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J B</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/cpsy_a_00024</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/cpsy_a_00024" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social stress reactivity alters reward and punishment learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J B</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/scan/nsq041</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/scan/nsq041" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="320" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhanced risk aversion, but not loss aversion, in unmedicated pathological anxiety</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Charpentier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Aylward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.biopsych.2016.12.010</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2016.12.010" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1014" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Threat disrupts reversal learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Christian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Florian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Prepint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mechanisms of attentional biases towards threat in anxiety disorders: An integrative review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cisler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H W</forename><surname>Koster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cpr.2009.11.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2009.11.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinical Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk-avoidant decision making increased by threat of electric shock: Risk avoidance under threat of shock</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rome</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fairchild</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R F</forename><surname>Aitken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1469-8986.2012.01454.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-8986.2012.01454.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1436" to="1443" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for Countercyclical Risk Aversion: An Experiment with Financial Professionals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Maréchal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1257/aer.20131314</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1257/aer.20131314" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="860" to="885" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How the Level of Reward Awareness Changes the Computational and Electrophysiological Signatures of Reinforcement Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M C</forename><surname>Correa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Noorman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Gaal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0457-18.2018</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0457-18.2018" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10338" to="10348" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">VBA: A Probabilistic Treatment of Nonlinear Models for Neurobiological and Behavioural Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Adam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Rigoux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003441</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003441" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stimulus-reinforcement-based decision making and anxiety: Impairment in generalized anxiety disorder (GAD) but not in generalized social phobia (GSP)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Devido</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Geraci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Hollon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J R</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Pine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S003329170800487X</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S003329170800487X" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">07</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1153</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anticipatory Anxiety Disrupts Neural Valuation during Risky Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2880-14.2015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2880-14.2015" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3085" to="3099" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural circuitry of affect-induced distortions of trust</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/sciadv.aau3413</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.aau3413" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxiety and cognitive performance: Attentional control theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Eysenck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Derakshan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Calvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/1528-3542.7.2.336</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/1528-3542.7.2.336" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="336" to="353" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decomposing the effects of context valence and feedback information on speed and accuracy during reinforcement learning: A metaanalytical approach using diffusion decision modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fontanesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13415-019-00723-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13415-019-00723-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="490" to="502" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">By Carrot or by Stick: Cognitive Reinforcement Learning in Parkinsonism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Seeberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Randall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">306</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1940" to="1943" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Experimentally-induced and real-world acute anxiety have no effect on goal-directed behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vaghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hezemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Van Ghesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dafflon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Brühl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Savulich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Robbins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/606145</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/606145" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of stress on feedback and error processing during behavioral adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Glienke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bellebaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2015.04.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2015.04.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="190" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models and mechanisms of anxiety: Evidence from startle studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s00213-007-1019-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00213-007-1019-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychopharmacology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">199</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="421" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxious responses to predictable and unpredictable aversive events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Baas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lissek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Milstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0735-7044.118.5.916</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0735-7044.118.5.916" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="916" to="924" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-Making in Anxiety and Its Disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Grupe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-0-12-805308-9.00026-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-805308-9.00026-9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Decision Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="338" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxiety and Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hartley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.biopsych.2011.12.027</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2011.12.027" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="118" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic adaptation of large-scale brain networks in response to acute stressors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hermans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J A G</forename><surname>Henckens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Joëls</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tins.2014.03.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2014.03.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Neurosciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="304" to="314" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress differentially modulates fear conditioning in healthy men and women</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Nadel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jacobs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.biopsych.2005.08.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2005.08.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="516" to="522" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning relative values in the striatum induces violations of normative decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ullsperger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Jocham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/ncomms16033</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms16033" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16033</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Contextual influence on confidence judgments in human reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bacily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">27</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioural and neural characterization of optimistic reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lefebvre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Meyniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bourgeois-Gironde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-017-0067</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-017-0067" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress modulates reinforcement learning in younger and older adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lighthall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gorlick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schoeke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0029823</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0029823" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology and Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxiety and the Allocation of Attention to Threat</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macleod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mathews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14640748808402292</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14640748808402292" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology Section A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="653" to="670" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk and Reward Are Processed Differently in Decisions Made Under Stress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lighthall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0963721411429452</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0963721411429452" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Balancing Type I error and power in linear mixed models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Matuschek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kliegl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vasishth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Baayen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jml.2017.01.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jml.2017.01.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Memory and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling Avoidance in Mood and Anxiety Disorders Using Reinforcement Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mkrtchian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Aylward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.01.017</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.01.017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="532" to="539" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Healthy Fear of the Unknown: Perspectives on the Interpretation of Parameter Fits from Computational Models in Neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Nassar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003015" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working-memory capacity protects model-based learning from stress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Otto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Raio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1312011110</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1312011110" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20941" to="20946" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual modulation of value signals in reward and punishment learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Khamassi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Joffily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Coricelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/ncomms9096</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms9096" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Computational Development of Reinforcement Learning during Adolescence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kilford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Coricelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-J</forename><surname>Blakemore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004953</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004953" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confirmation bias in human reinforcement learning: Evidence from counterfactual feedback processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lefebvre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kilford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-J</forename><surname>Blakemore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005684</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005684" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opponent Brain Systems for Reward and Punishment Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pessiglione</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-0-12-805308-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-805308-9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Decision Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The importance of falsification in computational cognitive modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Koechlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2017.03.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2017.03.011" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="425" to="433" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dual-task interference in simple tasks: Data and theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pashler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-2909.116.2.220</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.116.2.220" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="220" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine-dependent prediction errors underpin reward-seeking behaviour in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pessiglione</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Seymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Flandin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nature05051</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nature05051" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">442</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1042" to="1045" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress reduces use of negative feedback in a feedback-based learning task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Petzold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Plessow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Goschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kirschbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0018930</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0018930" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mixed-effects models in S and S-PLUS</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Pinheiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stress and decision making: Effects on valuation, learning, and risk-taking. Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Porcelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Delgado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cobeha.2016.11.015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cobeha.2016.11.015" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="39" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Acute stress influences neural circuits of reward processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Porcelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Delgado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnins.2012.00157</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2012.00157" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress attenuates the flexible updating of aversive value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Raio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hartley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Orederu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1702565114</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1702565114" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11241" to="11246" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Theory of Pavlovian Conditioning: Variations in the Effectiveness of Reinforcement and Nonreinforcement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rescorla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="99" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of stress on financial decisionmaking varies as a function of depression and anxiety symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7717/peerj.770</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.770" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PeerJ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress increases aversive prediction error signal in the ventral striatum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Overstreet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Charney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Vytal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1213923110</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1213923110" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4129" to="4133" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of anxiety upon cognition: Perspectives from human threat of shock studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Vytal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cornwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnhum.2013.00203</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00203" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social information impairs reward learning in depressive subjects: Behavioral and computational characterization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Safra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chevallier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/378281</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/378281" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Specific effect of a dopamine partial agonist on counterfactual learning: Evidence from Gilles de la Tourette syndrome</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Salvador</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Worbe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Delorme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Coricelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gaillard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Robbins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-017-06547-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-06547-8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing fear and anxiety in humans using the threat of predictable and unpredictable aversive events (the NPU-threat test)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schmitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nprot.2012.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2012.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Protocols</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="527" to="532" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress prompts habit behavior in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Schwabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0979-09.2009</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0979-09.2009" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7191" to="7198" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Manual for the state-trait anxiety inventory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Spielberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gorsuch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lushene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Vagg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Jacobs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<publisher>Consulting Psychologists</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Palo Alto, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhanced avoidance behavior in social anxiety: Evidence from a probabilistic learning task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abraham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jbtep.2013.07.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbtep.2013.07.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavior Therapy and Experimental Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dread and the Disvalue of Future Pain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Story</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Vlaev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Seymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Winston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Darzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003335</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003335" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reinforcement learning: An introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxiety, reactivity, and social stress-induced cortisol elevation in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Takahashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ikeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ishikawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kitamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tsukasaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nakama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kameda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuro Endocrinology Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stressful events as teaching signals for the brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Trapp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O'doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Schwabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2018.03.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2018.03.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="478" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Association between interleukin-6 and striatal prediction-error signals following acute stress in healthy female participants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Treadway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Admon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Arulpragasam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mehta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Douglas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Vitaliano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Olson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pizzagalli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.02.1183</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.02.1183" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="570" to="577" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modulation of feedback processing by social context in social anxiety disorder (SAD)-an event-related potentials (ERPs) study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Voegler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Peterburs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bellebaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Straube</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-019-41268-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-41268-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The complex interaction between anxiety and cognition: Insight from spatial and verbal working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Vytal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cornwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Letkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Arkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnhum.2013.00093</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00093" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development and validation of brief measures of positive and negative affect: The PANAS scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tellegen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.54.6.1063</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.54.6.1063" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1063" to="1070" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dynamics of cortico-amygdala and autonomic activity over the experimental time course of fear perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Boucsein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Sokolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Olivieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Peduto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogbrainres.2004.06.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogbrainres.2004.06.005" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Brain Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ten simple rules for the computational modeling of behavioral data. ELife, 8, e49547</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.49547</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.49547" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In the two-by-two within-subject design, anxiety (i.e., absent and present threat of shock for safe and threat condition, respectively) and outcome valence (i.e., Gain and loss) was associated with specific pair of cues. C. Transfer task. Each learned cue was paired with the other cues and form 24 new pairs in the post-learning task. These new and original pairs were repeated four times, resulting in 112 choices. D. Experimental design for each session in experiment 1 and experiment 2. E. Experimental design for both learning and transfer task</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A. Threat-of-Shock learning task. The illustration of learning task under safe and threat conditions for both experiment 1 and experiment 2. B. Manipulations</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Top: Experiment 1: Full intermixed design. The transfer task took place right after second session and contained cues from all four conditions. Bottom: Experiment 2: Session manipulation. The transfer task took place after third and fourth session. The cues used in the transfer task were drawn from two of four condition, depended on the emotional state of previous session</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Each gray line indicates individual&apos;s choice pattern. The filled dots represent cues learned under the safe condition, the unfilled dots indicate cues learned during the threat condition. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean (SEM), and shaded areas represent the mean ± SEM of the GLME predictions. B. Generalized linear mixed-effect model (i.e., GLME1Transfer) with cue selection as dependent variable. The y-axis represents the estimated standardized coefficient (t-value), and the x-axis represents each factor in the GLME model</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Choice pattern in transfer task and corresponding results from generalized linear mixed effect model. A</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Averaged choice rate for each cue. Dot colors indicate results from different dataset</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">G75: 75% of gain; G25: 25% of gain; L25: 25% of loss; G75: 75% of loss; Val.: outcome valence; Qual.: Quality of cue</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>i.e. Higher expected value in its pair during learning</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Filled dots represent individual parameters while error bars represent population mean±SEM. C. Learning curves, representing the fraction of correct choices in the safe (left; filled dots) and the threat (middle; unfilled dots) conditions. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean (SEM), and shaded areas represent the mean ± SEM of the RELa,w predictions. D. Transfer choice rate for each cue. Each gray line indicates individual&apos;s choice pattern. The filled dots represent cues learned under the safe condition, the unfilled dots indicate cues learned during the threat condition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Anx</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Anxiety manipulation A. Model comparison results for the general learning architecture</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>These panels depict the results of a Bayesian model comparison analysis on our participants data, for experiment 1 (yellow diamonds), experiment 2 (blue diamonds) and both experiments combined (black diamonds). Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean (SEM), and shaded areas represent the mean ± SEM of the RELa,w predictions</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
