<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Social Expected Utility: Indifference to Others Can Influence Risk Preferences</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2022-06">June 2022</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rumen</forename><surname>Iliev</surname></persName>
							<email>rumen.iliev@tri.global</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Totte</forename><surname>Harinen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Filipowicz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nayeli</forename><surname>Bravo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><forename type="middle">Sarah</forename><surname>Sumner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shabnam</forename><surname>Hakimi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kent</forename><surname>Lyons</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charlene</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Toyota Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Social Expected Utility: Indifference to Others Can Influence Risk Preferences</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2022-06">June 2022</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:58+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Many of the choices we make affect other people. While the social component of decision making is well-studied, a social dimension has not yet been incorporated into existing quantitative models of choice under uncertainty. In this paper we review previous proposals for how best to include a social component into existing models and then introduce a new approach: the Social Expected Utility model. Our approach combines social discounting and expected utility models, and accounts not only for previous findings, but also leads to novel, testable predictions, including a surprising preference reversal effect. We present the results from four empirical studies that compare our model with alternative theories and we conclude that social discounting should be included in our efforts towards more comprehensive choice models.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Virtually all of the decisions we make impact those around us. When parents buy a home, the local school district impacts their children's education. When a professor plans a course, the material impacts students' potential career choices.</p><p>When a congresswoman supports a certain bill, it impacts the lives of her constituents. While the social component of how we make choices has been an increasingly popular topic among behavioral researchers <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Larrick, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bruch and Feinberg, 2017)</ref>, it has not yet been incorporated into existing choice models.</p><p>Yet, adding a social component can lead to more generalizable and more accurate choice models. Indeed, previous research shows that the processes we use to make choices for others can deviate from how we make choices for ourselves.</p><p>When choosing between gains, we tend to be risk averse, preferring choices that have a higher probably success over choices with a lower probability of success (even if these low probability choices lead to higher average payouts). However, this risk aversion differs when we make choices that can affect others: two recent meta-analyses found that when choosing between potential gains, people are more likely to make risky choices when making choices for others than when making choices for themselves <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Polman and Wu, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Batteux et al., 2019)</ref>. When choices lead to a loss (as opposed to a gain), results were less conclusive: <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Polman and Wu (2020)</ref> found that risk seeking is negligibly increased when making choices for others, whereas <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Batteux et al. (2019)</ref> found greater risk seeking for self than for others. 1 Several theoretical explanations of this shift in risk preferences have been proposed, but to the best of our knowledge, they have not been directly linked to existing quantitative models of choice under uncertainty.</p><p>In this work, we explore how previous explanations of greater risk-seeking for others can be linked to risk preferences in utility-based models. We then propose a new model that manages to explain previous findings and leads to distinguishable and testable predictions. We note that because previous work has only found conclusive evidence for changes in risk seeking in the domain of gains, the current work will also focus primarily on gains. The rest of the paper is organized as follows: first we review the basic components of models of choice under uncertainty and speculate as to how they can be linked to previous theoretical explanations of self versus other risk preferences. We then propose a new model and contrast its predictions with those derived from alternative models. The predictions from our new model are then tested in a series of four studies. We conclude by discussing the theoretical implications of our results, as well as the limitations of the current work and some possible future directions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Utility-Based Models</head><p>Some of the earliest empirical research on choices under uncertainty find that people are generally risk averse <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bernoulli, 1738)</ref>: people tend to prefer a sure gain (e.g., 100% chance of receiving $10) than a probabilistic gain with a similar expected value (EV; e.g., 50% chance or receiving $20). This finding has been explained by the expected utility (EU) model, which has a long history in philosophy, economics and psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Briggs, 2019)</ref>. In its simple form, the expected utility model accounts for choices between lotteries such as: Lottery A: win $x 1 with probability p 1 and $0 with probability 1 -p 1 Lottery B: win $x 2 with probability p 2 and $0 with probability 1 -p 2</p><p>The EU model suggests that people prefer (or should prefer) the lottery with higher expected utility, which is defined as EU = u(x)p</p><p>(1)</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">u(x) = x α<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The α parameter captures the curvature of the utility function u(x). Typically, values of α range between 0 and 1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Rieger et al., 2017)</ref>, resulting in a concave shape. A concave utility function leads to risk aversion 2 , e.g. the utility of an outcome $x with a probability of 1 is larger than the utility of $2x with probability 0.5, even though both options have the same expected value.</p><p>Once the expected utility has been computed for both lotteries, the probability that either lottery will be chosen is computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P (x 1 , p 1 , x 2 , p 2 ) = 1 1 + e β(EU A −EU B )<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Equation 3 is often referred to as Luce's choice rule, which emphasizes the stochastic nature of human choice. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Luce, 1959;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Rieskamp, 2008)</ref> 3 . In stochastic models of value-based decisions the β parameter is typically interpreted as a measure of consistency of choice, where a greater β is associated with a greater consistency 4 Another interpretation of β, rooted in psychophysics research, is that it measures the sensitivity to the differences between the alternatives <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Huys et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gold and Shadlen, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Scheibehenne and Pachur, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Broomell and Bhatia, 2014)</ref>. When β is large, the decision maker is more sensitive to these differences and even a small relative advantage of one of the options might be enough to move the choice in that direction. When β is small, on the other hand, the same small relative advantage might not be enough to</p><p>2 For the binary outcomes used here we define risk as uncertainty, where by riskier we mean more uncertain. Defining risk, however, has been an active area of research, with multiple definitions available <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fischhoff et al., 1984;</ref><ref type="bibr">Weber et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Holton, 2004)</ref> 3 In cognitive science and reinforcement learning this equation is typically referred to as softmax function. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We thank to an anonymous reviewer to pointing out the different interpretations of beta.</p><p>5 move the decision maker from an indifference point. In this paper we will use the latter interpretation, treating beta as a measure of sensitivity to the differences between alternatives. In section 1.2.1 we will show how beta might be related to social distance, where increased social distance might lead to a lower sensitivity to differences in utility and therefore to a greater difficulty in distinguishing between close alternatives.</p><p>Another possible source of risk aversion is how people process the probabilities of the outcomes. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kahneman and Tversky (1979)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Tversky and Kahneman (1992)</ref> proposed that the expected utility is not directly multiplied by the given probability, but instead by a decision weight function π of the objective probability p.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">π(p) = p γ (p γ + (1 − p) γ ) 1/γ<label>(4)</label></formula><p>The parameter γ controls the shape of the function π and is typically estimated to be between 0 and 1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Rieger et al., 2017)</ref>, resulting in a convex shape in the range of medium and large probabilities and a concave shape in small probabilities. The convex part of the function contributes to risk aversion in the domain of gains since people underestimate medium and large probabilities, which increases the preferences for a more certain option (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>).</p><p>As such, the models above propose two potential mechanisms for risk aversion: concave expected utility functions (when values of α in eq. 2 &lt; 1), or probability distortions (e.g., γ in eq. 4). However, these models have been primarily validated in situations where participants are making choices for themselves.</p><p>We next explore how these models relate to observed increases in participant risk seeking when making choices for others.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2">Theoretical Explanations for Greater Risk Seeking for</head><p>Others <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Polman and Wu (2020)</ref> divide the theories explaining differences in risk preferences for self versus others into cognitive, emotional and socio-cultural theories.</p><p>Socio-cultural theories propose that risk preferences reflect societal values, and that people are more likely to make choices more aligned with societal expectations when choosing for others than for themselves. In cultures and contexts</p><p>where greater risk seeking is a norm, choosing for others will lead to riskier choices than choosing for oneself. However, these types of theories cannot be mapped directly to existing quantitative models relevant to risk preferences without deeper understanding of cultures and contexts, which is beyond the scope of the current article. Therefore, in this article we will only focus only on cognitive and emotional theories.</p><p>Cognitive theories suggest that people process information differently depending on who will receive the outcome. A prominent example of this approach is Construal Level Theory (CLT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Trope and Liberman, 2010)</ref>, which suggests that increase in psychological distance leads to greater consideration of desirability and lower consideration of feasibility. In monetary gambles such as the lotteries studies in economic decision making, desirability can be mapped to outcomes and feasibility to probabilities. As such, CLT suggests that when choosing for others we focus more on outcomes and less on probabilities, which can ultimately result in greater risk seeking for others <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Lu et al., 2013</ref> </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">P (x 1 , p 1 , x 2 , p 2 ) = 1 1 + e β(x A −x B )<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Or as equation 6 when the focus is only on probabilities:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">P (x 1 , p 1 , x 2 , p 2 ) = 1 1 + e β(p A −p B )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Mapping cognitive theories to quantitative models, however, is not entirely straightforward. What cognitive theories have in common is that they propose that people tend to focus more on one or another dimension of the alternative, but these theories are not explicit about how this focus should be represented in a choice model. For example, let us consider an attentional interpretation of CLT, where more attention is allocated to outcomes in other-choices but more attention is allocated to probabilities in self-choices. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Pachur et al. (2018)</ref> have shown that more attention to outcomes leads to less curvature of the utility function (higher α) which, as predicted by CLT, would lead to more risk seeking for others. Yet, the authors also show that more attention to probabilities results in less curvature of the decision weight function (higher γ) and therefore should also increase risk seeking in gains (for medium and high probabilities). CLT predicts that when choosing for self, participants pay more attention to probabilities, and given the results from Pachur et al. <ref type="formula">(2018) it</ref>should also predict that self-choices would lead to more risk seeking (for medium and high probabilities). This is a contradiction since CLT predicts (and finds) greater risk seeking for others. Attentional interpretation of CLT, therefore, is aligned with its qualitative statement for outcomes (the α parameter) but not for probabilities (the γ parameter)</p><p>Another possible interpretation of CLT is that self versus other choices are not captured by EU-type models, where both probabilities and outcomes are simultaneously taken into account for each option. Instead they might be driven by lexicographic rules similar to the ones proposed by Von Gunten and Scherer (2019). When choosing for others, for example, participants might be comparing only outcomes, while when choosing for themselves they might be comparing only probabilities. Such a pattern would again lead to greater risk seeking for others in a typical choice task where the riskier option has a better outcome. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: The three separate mechanisms through which choice models can account for risk preferences for positive lotteries. For illustrative purposes, let us assume that self-choices can be described by the following parameters: α = 0.5, β = 4 and γ = 0.5. Increasing α or γ, or decreasing β can all lead to greater preference for the riskier option. A. Increasing the α parameter from 0.5 to 0.7 will affect the greater outcome more compared to the smaller outcome. Since in a typical choice task the option with lower probabilities has higher outcomes, this leads to an increased preference for the riskier option. B. Reducing the β parameter from 4 to 2 moves the preferences closer to the indifference point.</p><p>Since riskier options are in general less preferred, changing the preference toward the middle results in a greater risk seeking. C. Increasing the γ parameter from 0.5 to 0.7 leads to less underestimation of the objective probabilities in the medium and high range, which results in increased preference for the uncertain option (except in low probabilities). 10 salient outcomes salient probabilities</p><p>Cognitive Theories Emotion Theories Social Expected Theory <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Relationship between the three theoretical accounts for increased risk seeking for others and how they can be explained by a choice model. The mapping for cognitive and emotional approaches is based on our interpretation of existing theoretical explanations since the original theories did not provide explicit quantitative models or formal rules.</p><p>In addition to cognitive theories, emotional theories have also been proposed to account for increased risk seeking in choices for others. Emotional theories propose that affective responses are stronger for self-choices than for otherchoices. Indeed, risk preferences have been linked to affect <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Loewenstein et al., 2001)</ref>, with lower affective response leading to greater risk-seeking on otherchoices. One possibility is that self versus other decisions result in different weighting of the objective probabilities. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Rottenstreich and Hsee (2001)</ref> suggested that lower affect can be captured by less curvature of the decision weighting function. As such, increased risk seeking for others (for medium and larger probabilities) can be directly modeled by an increase of the γ parameter in the weighting function.</p><p>The mapping between cognitive and emotional approaches and quantitative models is presented in Table 1. To summarise, the greater risk seeking often observed in choices for others can be predicted by a greater α parameter, greater γ parameter, increased prevalence of a lexicographic rule based on outcomes alone, or by a decreased prevalence of a lexicographic rule based on probabilities alone.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.1">The Social Expected Utility Model</head><p>We find the mapping between theoretical explanations and quantitative models described in the previous section useful, but it is important to keep in mind that these theories were not explicitly linked to existing models and their parameters.</p><p>In contrast, here we take a different approach. We start by combining two existing models into one model that attempts to both explain known findings and also derive novel, previously untested predictions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Jones and Rachlin (2006)</ref> proposed that the value of a particular outcome is a function of social distance. In their model, the value of $X is higher if the amount is received by the decision maker rather than by someone else.</p><p>The greater the social distance between the self and the other recipient, the greater the reduction in value. They capture this reduction in value using a social discounting model, which has a similar form to hyperbolic time and to probability discounting models:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">v = V 1 + sN (7)</formula><p>where v is the discounted value of a reward, V is the original value, N represents social distance and s is a discounting constant. When N = 0, the recipient is the self and the discounted value v is equal to the original value V . To apply this model to generic self-other distances, we can split it and assume that N for self is 0, and N for a generic other is 1 6 . Now we can define social expected utility (SEU) as an extension of the expected utility model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">SEU = 1 1 + sN px α (8) P (x 1 , p 1 , x 2 , p 2 , N ) = 1 1 + e β(SEU A −SEU B )<label>(9)</label></formula><p>This model is the same as the original EU model, except that now it introduces separate βs for self and for others, which we will refer to as β 0 and β 1 respectively.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">P (x 1 , p 1 , x 2 , p 2 , N ) =      1 1+e β 0 (EU A −EU B ) if N = 0 1 1+e β 1 (EU A −EU B ) if N &gt; 0 (10)</formula><p>The SEU model explains increased risk seeking for others as a decrease in the sensitivity parameter β. A lower β moves decisions closer to the indifference point (50/50), so if the probability of choosing a riskier option is 20% when choosing for self, it might increase to 30% when choosing for others, leading to a greater risk seeking for others. Unlike the previous explanations, the SEU model suggests that increasing risk seeking for others does not necessarily come from focusing on outcomes or focusing on probabilities alone, but it is related to decreased sensitivity to the differences between the alternatives. In other words, we propose that instead of considering two αs or two γs, we should consider two βs as a potential explanation of self-other differences. In the next section, we contrast the predictions from the SEU model to predictions from other theories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3">Model Comparison and Model Predictions</head><p>To test our proposed SEU model, we identify five key hypotheses that both validate it's ability to account for previous results, and test new predictions made by the SEU that help differentiate it from previous explanations: H1: In the domain of gains, people are more risk-seeking when making choices for others than for themselves. This hypothesis is a restatement of what has been already repeatedly observed in multiple studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Polman and Wu, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Batteux et al., 2019)</ref>. In its general form, this hypothesis can be predicted by all five approaches listed in the columns of <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. As we will see with H5, however, there are special cases in which this prediction does not hold.</p><p>H2. People are more sensitive to differences in outcomes when making choices for others than for themselves. This hypothesis is based on a possible lexicographic rule, where people choose the option with better outcome and ignore the information provided by the probabilities. It cannot be accounted for by EU-based models, since in those models outcomes and probabilities are used simultaneously and combined multiplicatively.</p><p>H3. People are more sensitive to differences in probabilities when making choices for themselves than for others. This hypothesis is similar to H2, but this time the salient dimension is probabilities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H4</head><p>. People are closer to indifference when choosing for others rather than for themselves. This hypothesis follows from the two β parameters in the SEU model. Since β 1 &lt; β 0 , the choices for others will be closer to an indifference point than choices for the self.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H5</head><p>. When a risky option is highly desirable, other-choices will be less risky than self-choices. This hypothesis is the central prediction stemming from our model, and it will require a more detailed explanation. In its generic form H1 can be predicted by all five approaches in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. However when considering the whole space of possibilities, we can find regions where different models predict different types of preference reversals. For example, the two γs model suggests that when the probabilities of the riskier option are sufficiently low, this will result in greater risk seeking in gains for self than for others. The reason for this potential preference reversal is that the γ parameter controls both the underestimation of medium and high probabilities and the overestimation of lower probabilities. Therefore changing it can lead to opposite change in risk preferences for different regions of the probability space. Although the two γs preference reversal is potentially interesting and deserves appropriate empirical consideration, in this paper we are more interested in a preference reversal that comes from the two βs parameters of the SEU model. Remember, that the key mechanism through which the two βs lead to higher risk seeking for others is through moving the choices closer to the indifference point. If a riskier option is chosen 20% of the time, moving the preference closer to the indifference point might result in raising the risky choices to 30%. However, we can also construct gambles where the riskier option is more desirable, and the majority of people would prefer it over the certain option. For example, if the preference to a riskier option is 80%, a lower β might move the preference toward the indifference point and change it to 70%, making choices for others seem more risky. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> depicts how this type of preference reversal is predicted by the two βs of the SEU, but not by the two αs or the two γs models. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Preference for the certain option as a function of the outcome of the riskier option. The y-axis is the probability to choose $10 for sure over 50% chance to win $X, where the different values of $X are presented on the x-axis. The dotted vertical line shows the X-value where the expected value of the two alternatives is equal (in this case X = $20). The self-line is the default choice for self, and it is estimated with parameters α = 0.5, β = 4 and γ =0.5. The three additional lines represent the shift in risk preferences if any of the three parameters is changed (α and γ increasing by 0.2 or β decreasing by 2). While all three models predict initial shift toward increased risk seeking for others compared to self, only the two βs of the SEU model predict preference shift, where for highly desirable riskier options choices for self will be more risk seeking than choices for others (after the indifference point where y=0.5 the self line is lower than the β-other line).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Study 1</head><p>The first study is designed as an initial test of H1. It will also provide a validation of our method of data collection and detecting self versus other differences in choices under uncertainty. In addition, while our paper is mainly focused on the domain of gains, in this first study we will also manipulate both gains and losses to explore if our method of data collection leads to any cross-domain differences salient outcomes salient probabilities H1: More risk seeking for others H2: Higher sensitivity to outcomes for others H3: Lower sensitivity to probabilities for others H4: Greater choice uncertainty for others H5: Preference Reversal in risk seeking for others <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Mapping between proposed explanations and their potential formalization into a choice model. Increased risk seeking in gains for others can be explained as higher α, higher γ, lower β, increased prevalence of salience to outcomes, or decreased prevalence of salience to probabilities. Our model predicts H1, H4 and H5, but does not predict H2 and H3.</p><p>aligned with <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Polman and Wu (2020)</ref> or <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Batteux et al. (2019)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>The series of studies reported in this paper received an "exempt" status from WCG IRB (www.wcgirb.com). For Study 1 we recruited 1224 participants from Amazon Mechanical Turk and we excluded from the analysis those who completed the survey in less than one minute 7 . The remaining sample of 1205 participants had a mean age = 41, 44% were females, 54% males, 2% non-conforming and other. The participants were paid $3.62. The task took 19 minutes on average. All participants provided informed consent before participating.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Procedure</head><p>We created 64 lottery choices 8 , where participants had to choose between two alternatives. The alternatives differed in outcomes, probability for winning, domain (losses versus gains) and recipient of the outcome (self versus other).</p><p>All participants saw each of the 64 choices in a random order. For each pair of choices, participants indicated the option they preferred. Half of the choices were between pairs of lotteries that would lead to gains and half of the choices were between losses. As part of the study, some of the questions gave participants the option to chose between an outcome for themselves or for another participant.</p><p>For the current study we only focus on 32 of the choices that presented identical self:self and other:other choices (i.e., no self:other choices) as these allow for a direct comparison between lotteries where the only difference is the recipient (see <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>). <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: Trial Sequence in Study 1. First participant saw a randomized sequence of self:self choices where the self was the only recipient. Next participants saw a randomized sequence of self:other and other:other choices. The analysis here is focused on otherwise identical self:self and other:other choices. (see the Supplementary Materials for more details).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>We conducted a mixed-effect logistic regression that predicted preference for uncertain choices, based on the recipient (self:self versus other:other) and domain (gains versus losses). Participants and questions were included as random intercepts. There was a significant main effect of domain (z = -48.15, n = 1205, p &lt; 2x10 −16 ) 9 , where the domain of losses was associated with more risk seeking choices than the domain of gains. This is a replication of the classical reflection effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Kahneman and Tversky, 1979)</ref>. There was also a main effect of the recipient (z = -2.45, n = 1205, p = .0142), where choices for others were more risk seeking than self choices in otherwise identical gambles. This effect was moderated by a significant domain X recipient interaction (z = -2.233, n = 1205, p = .0199), where the effect of recipient was stronger in gains than in losses (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>). <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>: Proportion of risky choices as a function of domain and recipient. In both domains choices for others were more risk seeking than choices for self, but the effect was stronger for gains. ** p &lt;0.01, *** p &lt;0.001</p><p>These results provide initial support for H1 in the domain of gains. However, it is important to note that the SEU cannot predict the pattern observed in the domain of losses. The SEU and the original EU models were developed to account for risk preferences in gains. If the main idea behind SEU of shifting toward an indifference point due to lowered sensitivity is extended to losses, we should expect that in the domain of losses, in contrast to the domain of gains, other-choices will be less risk seeking than self-choices. For example, if in the domain of losses 80% of choices are for the riskier option, if we shift towards the indifference point when making choices for others, we should expect 70% preference for the riskier option. Such a pattern, for example, was reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Zhang et al. (2017)</ref>, but it was not observed in our study. Based on these results, in Studies 2 to 4 we concentrate on the domain of gains only. We will return to this point in the discussion section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Study 2</head><p>This study is aimed at testing H2 and H3. In addition, the study design also serves as a preliminary test of H4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 1000 participants from Amazon Mechanical Turk and we excluded from the analysis those who completed the survey in less than one minute.</p><p>The remaining sample of 991 participants had a mean age = 42, 49% were females, 49% males, 2% non-conforming and other. The participants were paid $3.62. The task took 17 minutes on average.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Procedure</head><p>We created an initial list of 10 base choices between lotteries, similar to ones used in Study 1. All 10 lotteries were in the domain of gains and the expected values of the two alternatives were equal or very close (rounded to a whole dollar). We used the initial 10 choices to create another 40 choices, varying 2 factors: which alternative was better (1 or 2) and why it was better (better due to outcomes or better due to probabilities). Here is an example of how for each base question we created 4 questions with different expected values:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Q.1 Base choice:</head><p>A. 31% chance to win $8 B. 25% chance to win $10.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Q.11 A better due to outcome:</head><p>A. 31% chance to win $9 B. 25% chance to win $10.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Q.21 B better due to outcome:</head><p>A. 31% chance to win $8 B. 25% chance to win $11.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Q.31 A better due to probability:</head><p>A. 35% chance to win $8 B. 25% chance to win $10.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Q.41 B better due to probability:</head><p>A. 31% chance to win $8 B. 28% chance to win $10.</p><p>This design will allow us to check if changes in probabilities or changes in outcomes have different influences on choices for self and for others. For example, the lexicographic interpretation of CLT captured by H2 suggests that people will be more likely to choose option A in Q.11 relative to Q.21 when making choices for others, while the effect will be absent or weaker when making self-choices. Similarly, H3 predicts people will show a bigger difference between Q.31 and Q.41 when making choices for themselves compared to that for others. For each of the choices the recipient was randomly assigned to be the self or the recipient. In addition to the 50 choices described above, we also included four choices as an attention check where one of the alternatives dominated the other and we do not use these in the analysis 10 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>First we tested H2 and H3. We ran a mixed effect logistic regression model, predicting choice (option 1 or option 2) based on which option is objectively better based on EV (option 1 is better or option 2 is better), the lottery dimension on which the option is better (better due to probability or better due to outcome) and who the recipient is (self versus other). The only significant effect was the main effect of better option (z = -8.35, n = 989, p &lt; 2x10 −16 ).</p><p>Not surprisingly, when the expected value of one of the options was higher, the participants were more likely to choose that option. The results are presented in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: Choice preference as a function of difference in outcomes, difference in probabilities and recipient. Preferences for option 1 are on the y-axis. The x-axis represents which of the two options is objectively better and the facets represent why the option is better (due to differences in probability or differences in outcomes.) The different colors represent the recipient. Both changes in outcomes and changes in probabilities had the expected effect on preferences. However, those changes did not differ as a function of who the recipient was.</p><p>H2 would predict the difference between "Option 1 better due to outcome" and "Option 2 better due to outcome" would have been larger when making choices for others rather than for the self. Similarly, H3 would have predicted that the difference between "Option 1 better due to probability" and "Option 2 better due to probability" would have been larger when making choices for selves. The results, however, did not support either of these hypotheses (for both interactions, p-values &gt; .48).</p><p>The relatively large number of questions also allowed us to conduct a preliminary test of H4. For each of the 50 questions we computed how far the preference for choice A is from the indifference point 0.5 (distance = P roportion(A) − 0.5 ). For example, if the proportion of A choices for one question was .70, and for another question it was .30, for both questions the distance to the indifference point was .20. A paired t-test (t(49) = -2.05, p = .0461) revealed that preferences were closer to indifference for other-choices (m = 0.27, sd = 0.12) than for self-choices (m = 0.28, sd = 0.11). This result provides preliminary support for H4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Study 3</head><p>In this study we further explore H4. The previous study allowed us to test H4 on the level of questions only, since individual answers were binary. In this study we use a Likert scale rather than binary choices. The Likert scale will let us to compute distances to the indifference point for each individual answer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 1000 participants from Amazon Mechanical Turk, and we excluded from the analysis those who completed the survey in less than one minute.</p><p>The remaining sample of 995 participants had a mean age = 43, 53% were females, 45% males, 2% non-conforming and other. The participants were paid $3.62. The task took 19 minutes on average.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Procedure</head><p>The questions were identical to those used in Study 2, except that instead of binary choice, the participants indicated their answer on a 6-point Likert scale, ranging from 1 (Definitely prefer option A) to 6 (Definitely prefer option B).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>For each answer we took the distance to the indifference point of 3.5, and we used this distance as a dependent variable in a mixed-effects regression model. As in the previous analyses, questions and participants were entered as random intercepts. As predicted, there was a significant effect of recipient (t(4801) = 6.54, p &lt; 6.26x10 −11 ), where the distance to the indifference point was larger for self-choices (m = 1.78, sd = 0.78) than for other-choices (m = 1.74, sd = 0.78).</p><p>This result provides further support for H4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Study 4</head><p>H5 suggests that greater risk seeking for others can be reversed when the riskier option becomes more desirable. In this study we provide an empirical test of this prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 1000 participants from Amazon Mechanical Turk, and we excluded from the analysis those who completed the survey in less than one minute.</p><p>The remaining sample of 985 participants had a mean age = 41, 46% were females, 53% males, 1% non-conforming and other. The participants were paid $4.35. The task took 10 minutes on average.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Procedure</head><p>We created 15 choices where the riskier option had a lower EU than the less risky option, and another 15 choices for which the riskier option had a higher EU. The degree to which the riskier option was better or worse was controlled by an asymmetry factor af :</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">x 2 = x 1 af ( p 1 p 2 ) 2<label>(11)</label></formula><p>For the first 15 choices that asymmetry factor 11 was af =0.5 and for the second group of 15 choices the af = 1.5. Each question had a self-and otherversions, resulting in a total of 60 questions. Based on H5 we expected that for af = 0.5 we will observe the familiar increase in risk seeking for other-choice, but for af = 1.5 we expected the opposite. In addition, similarly to the previous two studies, there were 4 attention-check gambles, bringing the total number of questions to 64.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>We ran a mixed-effect logistic regression, predicting uncertain choices from the af and from the recipient. Similarly to the previous analyses, the participants and the questions were entered as random intercept effects. H5 predicts that the af can reverse the relationship between recipient and risk seeking, and this was confirmed by the results. There was a significant interaction between af and recipient (z = 3.45, n = 981, p = .0006) in the predicted direction:</p><p>choosing for others increased riskier choices when the expected values of the two were relatively close, but decreased risk seeking when the risky option was more desirable (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). This pattern supports H5. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>: Preference for the uncertain option as a function of recipient and the asymmetry factor. The well known relationship between recipient and risk preferences was reversed when the riskier option was much more desirable than the less risky option. This preference reversal is predicted in Hypothesis 5 and can be explained by the two βs in the SEU model. The asterisks indicate self/other statistically significant differences based on post-hoc mixed-effects model tests: * p &lt;.05,** p &lt;.01</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Parameter Fitting Across Studies</head><p>The five hypotheses tested in the studies above were based on qualitative predictions that were derived from the various parameters of utility-based choice models. It is possible, however, to directly fit a choice model and to test if the estimated parameters will differ in the direction predicted by different theories.</p><p>For example, if risk seeking for others is based on different shapes of the utility function, then we can expect that an estimate of the α parameter will be higher in other-choices than in self-choices. Similarly, if the greater risk seeking for others comes from our interpretation of probabilities, then we should expect higher estimates for the γ parameter in the other-choices than in the self-choices.</p><p>And last, if the SEU model is correct, we should expect higher β estimates in self-choices and in other-choices.</p><p>To test these predictions we fitted a choice model that included all three parameters (Equations 1 to 4) to the data from the four studies reported in this paper. We fitted a separate model for self-and other-choices for each of the four studies. We used grid search with a step of 0.02 and with a range of 0 to 1 for α and γ and a range of 0 to 5 for β. In addition, to estimate the degree to which the parameters in self-and other-choices were different we used a bootstrapping method. We generated 1000 bootstrapped samples for all self-choices and for all other choices for each of the four studies. For each of the bootstrapped samples we estimated the best-fitting value for the three parameters. The bootstrapping provides us with a distribution of values for each parameter, which can be used for significance-testing of self versus other differences for the different parameters.</p><p>The results are presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 7</ref>. Across the four studies, the α and the γ parameters differed in only one experiment between self-and other-choices at p&lt;.05 (one-tailed). However, the difference was in the opposite direction as would be predicted, with higher estimates for self-than for other-choices.</p><p>On the other hand, the β parameters differed in the predicted direction for all four studies. This difference was significant in one-tailed bootstrapped tests at p&lt;.001 for Studies 1, 3 and 4 and marginally significant for Study 2 (p = 0.07, one-tailed). These results converge with the hypotheses tests which we reported in the earlier sections and provide an additional support for the SEU model.</p><p>They suggest that people are less sensitive to differences between alternatives when making decisions for others. In addition, the results from the model fitting also found no support for different utility or decision weight functions for self and for other choices. Estimates from a choice model with three parameters. For each of the four studies we fitted a three parameter choice model, α, β, and γ. The model was fitted separately for self and for other choices. The statistical significance of the differences between self and other was based on bootstrapped estimates. The results provide strong support for two-βs, but no support for two-αs or two-γs. The error bars are based on the standard deviations of bootstrapped estimate. Significance levels: * p &lt;0.05, ** p &lt;0.01, *** p &lt;0.001.</p><p>While choice models have become more complex and account for an increasingly larger choice space <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Busemeyer and Townsend, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Erev et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Peterson et al., 2021)</ref>, they have largely ignored how these decisions are made when others are impacted, a central components of real world choices. In this paper we took a different path toward enlarging the choice space. Instead of making more complex choice problems by various combinations of outcomes and probabilities, we expanded a basic EU model by adding a social component based on the concept of social discounting <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Jones and Rachlin, 2006)</ref>. The resulting SEU model proposes a very different possible explanation for why people are more risk seeking for others than for themselves in the domain of gains. Previous explanations have suggested that we process either outcomes or probabilities differently when we make choice for ourselves versus for others. We proposed that these explanations could be mapped to different α parameters in the utility function u, different γ parameters in the decision weight function π, or to salient probability or salient outcome differences. In contrast, the SEU model suggests that the increased risk seeking for others is due to a decrease in the sensitivity parameter β rather than to outcome-specific or probability-specific processing.</p><p>Decreased sensitivity shifts the choices closer to an indifference point, and since in the domain of gains people tend to prefer more certain options, moving this preference towards indifference results in greater risk seeking for others by making people's choice more stochastic. The moving towards an indifference point when choosing for others was stated as H4 and was found both on the level of items (Study 2) and on the level of individual choices (Study 3). Instead of just being an alternative explanation to greater risk seeking for others, however, our model also made an additional prediction for a preference reversal. As stated in H5, when the riskier option is much more desirable than the safer option,  Summary of the empirical tests of the five hypotheses. H1, H4 and H5 are consistent with the SEU model, while H2 and H3 were competing explanations.</p><p>moving the preference towards indifference would result in less risky choices for others. As predicted by the model, this preference reversal was observed in Study 5. In contrast, no support was found for the existing explanations that focus on outcomes or probabilities alone (H2 and H3). The summary of those findings is presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3.</ref> It is important to note that while we found empirical support for our model, we see this work just as a step towards including additional dimensions to choice under uncertainty models. We do not suggest that EU-based models should be treated as descriptive models of choice under uncertainty. Neither do we emphasize on the null findings for H2 and H3. Despite the lack of support for the alternative models, it is still possible that both α and γ parameters, as well as salience of outcomes or salience of probabilities play a role in self versus other choices in different contexts or in other risk-preference tasks. What our results do demonstrate, however, is that sensitivity to differences is at least a part of the explanation of why we are more risk seeking when making choices for others. We also demonstrated how a simple extension of a basic choice model can account for a major finding in the field of social choice and can lead to novel, surprising, and testable predictions. A more distal goal of our line of work is to contribute toward building a generalized utility model, which incorporates all four dimensions of psychological distance proposed by CLT <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Fiedler, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Liberman and Trope, 2008)</ref>. Recently, there has been an increased attention on how these dimensions are related to each other in decision tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Trautmann and van de Kuilen, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Vanderveldt et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Raue et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Jin et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Luckman et al., 2018)</ref>, but these efforts have not yet resulted in a generalized quantitative model of choice. The framework we provide here could also easily be extended to include time, which we expect might behave similarly to social distance. Previous research has already found that in the domain of gains time distance leads to more risk seeking choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Vanderveldt et al., 2015)</ref>. This pattern has been attributed to a decreased role of probabilities in the decision making process, but similarly to what we observed with social distance, this shift in risk preference might be related to a lower sensitivity to the differences between the choice alternatives when temporal distance increases.</p><p>Even though our goal is to build more generalizable models of decision making, the current set of studies has a number of limitations. First, it is not clear how our model can be extended to the domain of losses. In Study 1 we observed weaker self-other differences in the loss domain, and this difference was not aligned with the predictions of the model nor with previously reported results <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Zhang et al., 2017)</ref>. It might be that losses are processed very differently in a social context as implied by the recent meta analyses <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Batteux et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Polman and Wu, 2020)</ref>. Based on the existing findings, it is not apparent how social distance should be incorporated in formal models that account for both gains and losses. Second, we used only one type of choice content. The lotteries in our studies are a very common method to elicit risk preferences and were well suited for testing our hypotheses, but they were focused on financial choices alone. There are well-documented differences on risk preferences in specific applied scenarios <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Beisswanger et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Stone et al., 2013)</ref>. For example, in situations involving physical safety, such as moving a heavy bookshelf alone, people tend to make risk averse decisions for others, but be more risk seeking themselves. Conversely, in social situations people tell others to take more risks whereas they would choose safer options for themselves (such as asking a stranger to dance). Future work will be needed to estimate to what extent our model can account for non-financial choices. Another limitation of the current model is that it does not account for many real-world decision-making scenarios.</p><p>Future work will also be needed to estimate the generalizability across populations. We used Amazon Mechanical Turk workers <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Mullinix et al., 2015)</ref> who are highly skilled in online surveys and even though we replicated some classical effects from decision making it is not clear to what extent our studies will have the same results if other populations are used.</p><p>Before we conclude, we also want to discuss one final point. The gist of the SEU model is that it shifts the focus from the well-studied α and γ parameters to the β parameter, which has received less theoretical attention. More recently however, there has been an increased attention towards how randomness or "noise" plays an important, albeit rarely measured role in learning and decisionmaking <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Drugowitsch et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Wyart and Koechlin, 2016)</ref>. The β parameter in our model can be conceptually related to noise, where lower β behaves as adding noise to the preference. When risk aversion is sub-optimal, for example, adding noise reduces risk aversion not by increasing preference for risk per se, but by increasing the random chance that risky options would be selected. As a result, noisier decisions could move otherwise risky-averse choices closer to more normative choice patterns. Moreover, this increase in noise has been proposed as a mechanism to reduce existing biases, particularly in uncertain and changing environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Findling and Wyart, 2021)</ref>. This bias reduction interpretation could fit well with previous work on biases in social contexts. Previous work on advice-giving, for example, has shown that taking a third-person perspective, or providing advice can mitigate some cognitive biases <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Perloff (1999)</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kray and Gonzalez (1999)</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Kray (2000)</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Danziger et al. (2012)</ref>. Thus, another possible future direction for the current work is to analyze the beneficial effect of thirdperson perspective or advice giving from the lenses of decreased sensitivity to alternatives and its relation to noise.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion</head><p>Quantitative descriptive models of decision making have become one of the pinnacles of cognitive psychology and behavioral economics <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Camerer, 2011)</ref>. They have led to highly accurate predictions of how people choose under uncertainty and have captured a number of surprising choice patterns. An open question, however, is how to increase the generalizability of those models <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Yarkoni, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>The main approach, so far, has been to extend the dimensionality of the stimulus space and to develop complex models that account for multiple decision "anomalies" simultaneously <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Roe et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Stott, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Erev et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Peterson et al., 2021)</ref>. Although this direction is certainly important, it is still mainly focused on outcomes and probabilities, and as such it is missing some important context of real world decisions, such as temporal, spatial and social relations. In this paper, we proposed an alternative direction: starting from simple models and then adding dimensions that go beyond outcomes and probabilities. Using this method we demonstrate how these models can be extended to account for social aspects of decision-making and provide testable, and sometimes surprising hypotheses that can be validated experimentally.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>36</head><p>• Funding: There was no external funding by private or public sponsors.</p><p>• Compliance with Ethical Standards: The studies reported in this paper were performed in accordance with the current ethical standards and were classified as an exempt by the ethics committee of Western IRB.</p><p>• Conflicts of Interest: The authors declare they have no conflict of interest.</p><p>• Informed Consent: All participants signed informed consent before participating.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Estimates from a choice model with three parameters. For each of the four studies we fitted a three parameter choice model, α, β, and γ. The model was fitted separately for self and for other choices. The statistical significance of the differences between self and other was based on bootstrapped estimates. The results provide strong support for two-βs, but no support for two-αs or two-γs. The error bars are based on the standard deviations of bootstrapped estimate. Significance levels: * p &lt;0.05, ** p &lt;0.01, *** p &lt;0.001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1"><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Atanasov (2015)</ref> conducted earlier meta analysis based on a smaller data set and found no effect in the domain of gains and a greater risk seeking for self in the domain of losses.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">It is worth noting that when the β parameter in Luce's choice rule approaches infinity, Luce's choice rule becomes a lexicographic rule.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">We do not argue that social distance per se should be represented as a binary variable, but for the current purposes a binary variable is a useful simplification.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">The conclusions in this and in the following studies do not change if we use more conservative exclusion thresholds, such as 5 minutes.8 For more information about the stimuli for all studies see the Supplementary Materials.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">All statistical tests are two-tailed unless otherwise stated.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">Across all four studies, participants answered correctly to an attention check about 90% of the time. In our analyses we do not exclude participants who did not answer correctly, but the conclusions do not change if we use the attention checks as an exclusion criteria.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">When af = 1 and α = 0.5 (commonly observed) the EU of the two alternatives is the same.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Risk preferences in choices for self and others: Meta analysis and research directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Atanasov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Working paper SSRN 1682569</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do our risk preferences change when we make decisions for others? a meta-analysis of self-other differences in decisions involving risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Batteux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tunney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">216566</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk taking in relationships: Differences in deciding for oneself versus for a friend</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Beisswanger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hupp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allgaier</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Commentarii Academiae Scientiarum Imperialis Petropolitanae, 5. Translated by Louise Somer and reprinted as</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bernoulli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="1738" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Exposition of a New Theory on the Measurement of Risk</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Normative theories of rational choice: Expected utility. Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Briggs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Parameter recovery for decision modeling using choice data. Decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Broomell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">252</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-making processes in social contexts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bruch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Feinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual review of sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision field theory: a dynamiccognitive approach to decision making in an uncertain environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">432</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chapter five. prospect theory in the wild: Evidence from the field</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in behavioral economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="148" to="161" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Idealistic advice and pragmatic choice: A psychological distance account</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Danziger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Montal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Barkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1105</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational precision of mental inference as critical source of human choice suboptimality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-D</forename><surname>Devauchelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Koechlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1398" to="1411" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From anomalies to forecasts: Toward a descriptive model of decisions under risk, under ambiguity, and from experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Plonsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">369</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Construal level theory as an integrative framework for behavioral decision-making research and consumer psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Fiedler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Computation noise in human learning and decision-making: origin, impact, function. Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Findling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="132" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defining risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fischhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hope</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Policy sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="139" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu. Rev. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="535" to="574" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Defining risk. Financial analysts journal</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Holton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping anhedonia onto reinforcement learning: a behavioural meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Huys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pizzagalli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogdan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biology of mood &amp; anxiety disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social discounting under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">392</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social discounting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Rachlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory: An analysis of decision under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="391" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differential weighting in choice versus advice: I&apos;ll do this, you do that</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gonzalez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Contingent weighting in self-other decision making. Organizational behavior and human decision processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="106" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The social context of decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Larrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual review of organizational psychology and organizational behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="441" to="467" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of transcending the here and now</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Liberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Trope</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">322</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5905</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1201" to="1205" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk as feelings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Welch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">267</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Desirability or feasibility: Self-other decisionmaking differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="144" to="155" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Individual choice behavior: A theoretical analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
			<publisher>John. Wiley and Sons</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can a single model account for both risky choices and inter-temporal choices? testing the assumptions underlying models of risky inter-temporal choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Luckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="785" to="792" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The generalizability of survey experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mullinix</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Leeper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Druckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freese</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pachur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schulte-Mecklenbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory reflects selective allocation of attention</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">147</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The third person effect: A critical review and synthesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Perloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Media psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="378" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using large-scale experiments and machine learning to discover theories of human decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bourgin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reichman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">372</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6547</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1209" to="1214" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision making for others involving risk: A review and meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Polman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102184</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How far does it feel? construal level and decisions under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Raue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Streicher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Lermer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Research in Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="264" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Estimating cumulative prospect theory parameters from an international survey. Theory and Decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Rieger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="567" to="596" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The probabilistic nature of preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1446</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative decision field theory: A dynamic connectionst model of decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Roe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">370</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Money, kisses, and electric shocks: On the affective psychology of risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Rottenstreich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="190" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using bayesian hierarchical parameter estimation to assess the generalizability of cognitive models of choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Scheibehenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pachur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I can take the risk, but you should be safe: Self-other differences in situations involving physical safety</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yoonsun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bruine De Bruin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cumulative prospect theory&apos;s functional menagerie</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Stott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory or construal level theory?: Diminishing sensitivity vs. psychological distance in risky decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Trautmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Van De Kuilen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="254" to="260" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Construal-level theory of psychological distance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Trope</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Liberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">440</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advances in prospect theory: Cumulative representation of uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discounting of monetary rewards that are both delayed and probabilistic: delay and probability combine multiplicatively, not additively</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vanderveldt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Myerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">148</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-other differences in multiattribute decision making: Compensatory versus noncompensatory decision strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Von Gunten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Scherer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">430</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Psychological review</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice variability and suboptimality in uncertain environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Koechlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The generalizability crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Yarkoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions for others are less risk-averse in the gain frame and less risk-seeking in the loss frame than decisions for the self</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Shang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1601</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
