<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Dissociable behavioural signatures of co-existing impulsivity and apathy in decision-making</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Petitet</surname></persName>
							<email>pierre.petitet@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>OX1 3PH</postCode>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Centre de Recherche en Neurosciences de Lyon</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">UMR-S 1028</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Équipe Trajectoires</addrLine>
									<country>Inserm</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">UMR 5292</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université Lyon 1</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Bron</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sijia</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>OX1 3PH</postCode>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Drew</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>OX3 9DU</postCode>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjay</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Manohar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>OX1 3PH</postCode>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>OX3 9DU</postCode>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masud</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>OX1 3PH</postCode>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>OX3 9DU</postCode>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Dissociable behavioural signatures of co-existing impulsivity and apathy in decision-making</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:01+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Apathy and impulsivity are expressed in a wide range of neuropsychiatric disorders, and, to a less severe extent, in healthy people too. Although traditionally considered to be opposite extremes of a single motivational spectrum, recent epidemiological questionnaire-based data suggest that both traits can in fact co-exist within the same individual. Here, we sought to investigate the relationship between these constructs in healthy people within a controlled task environment that examines the ability to make a decision under temporal uncertainty and measures the vigour of the response. Sixty participants performed a new version of the Traffic Light Task (TLT) and completed self-report questionnaire measures of apathy and impulsivity. Although the two traits were positively correlated in questionnaire assessments, they were associated with distinct behavioural signatures on the task. Impulsivity was expressed as an inflexible tendency to generate rapid anticipatory responses, regardless of task context. Apathy, on the other hand, was associated with a blunted effect of reward on response vigour. These findings reveal how apathy and impulsivity are related to distinct dimensions of goal-directed behaviour, explaining how these traits might co-exist in the same individuals.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>A major goal of modern neuroscience is to understand the mechanisms underlying motivated behaviour, and their implementation in the brain. Disorders of motivation, such as apathy and impulsivity, offer a valuable opportunity to study such mechanisms when they become dysfunctional in clinical populations. The core defining features of these syndromes are the diminution of self-generated purposeful actions 1 (apathy) and the tendency to decide/act quickly with little deliberation or forethought 2 (impulsivity). These traits are observed across a wide range of neuropsychiatric disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> and, to a certain extent, in all individuals <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> . Although more precise definitions of these syndromes distinguish between various possible domains of expression <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> , it is broadly agreed that their genesis involves the disruption of key decision-making processes underlying motivated behaviour <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11</ref> . A perplexing finding across several recent reports is the positive correlation of apathy and impulsivity traits in both healthy individuals <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12</ref> and patient <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> groups. How can someone be both apathetic and impulsive?</p><p>Because they influence motivated behaviour in opposite directions (i.e., insufficient vs. excessive actions), apathy and impulsivity have often naturally been considered to be polar opposites. The best example of such framework is the motivational spectrum hypothesis, which posits that apathetic and impulsive behaviour may originate from opposite dysregulations of the same neural networks involved in motivated behaviour <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref> . According to this view, motivated behaviour results from multiple cognitive processes (e.g., information seeking, option generation, option selection, cost-benefit decisions, action initiation, learning from outcome) that can each be directionally regulated to meet the specific constraints of the task environment. Ventral striatal dopamine is proposed to be the biological substrate that calibrates an individual's behaviour along these multiple cognitive axes, with a net directional effect towards apathy or impulsivity depending on whether there is too little or too much dopamine <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11</ref> . Support for this model comes mostly from the literature on Parkinson's disease, which contains descriptions of patients behaving apathetically or impulsively depending on whether they are in a hypo-or hyper-dopaminergic state, respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref> .</p><p>Implicit in the motivational spectrum hypothesis is the notion that, at any given time, an individual may behave either apathetically or impulsively, but crucially not both since these two states exist at opposite extremes of the same spectrum. A growing set of observations, however, appears to contradict this. Instances of co-occurrence of apathy and impulsivity have indeed been reported in patients suffering from Parkinson's disease <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref> , but also in frontotemporal lobar degeneration syndromes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">30</ref> , Alzheimer's disease <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">31</ref> , attention deficit hyperactivity disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32</ref> , and schizophrenia <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">33</ref> . In fact, even in individuals free from any neuropsychiatric diagnosis, the pattern of responses on self-report questionnaires reveals a certain degree of co-variation between the severity of apathetic and impulsive traits, especially within the goal-directed behavioural dimension <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12</ref> .</p><p>By challenging the motivational spectrum hypothesis, these observations open a range of new questions regarding the inter-relationship of apathy and impulsivity, the extent to which their respective mechanisms may overlap, and the ways in which they could be co-expressed. Can individuals act both impulsively and apathetically simultaneously, or do they instead fluctuate between these two behavioural states in response to environmental triggers (or lack thereof)? To our knowledge, the relationship between apathy and impulsivity has solely been explored in subjective self-report or clinician assessments (e.g. questionnaires or diagnostic criteria), and not in behavioural tasks. Even though both traits can be observed in isolation in dedicated tasks (e.g., apathy: Effort-Based Decision-Making task <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">34</ref> , Option Generation task <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35</ref> ; impulsivity: Balloon Analogue Risk-Taking task <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">36</ref> , Cued Go No-Go task <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">37</ref> ), there is, to our knowledge, no experimental paradigm allowing for their potential co-expression.</p><p>In the present work, we aimed to investigate the mechanisms underlying the co-expression of apathy and impulsivity in healthy individuals within a single behavioural paradigm. To do so, we used a new version of the Traffic Light Task <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> (TLT)a task known to encourage impulsive behaviour -in order to incorporate potential opportunities for a co-expression with apathy.</p><p>In the TLT, it is financially advantageous to take risks and behave in an anticipatory manner <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38</ref> . On each trial, a light successively turns red, amber then green, and participants are instructed to make a response as quickly as possible after the onset of the green "go" signal. Responses recorded prior to green onset incur a small monetary penalty, while those recorded after green onset are remunerated according to a reward function that declines at a rapid rate, so that within a few tens of milliseconds the reward that can be obtained is very low. Due to sensorimotor delays, standard human reaction times are typically slower than this <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">41</ref> so it is impossible to collect the highest reward by merely reacting to the "go" signal. Instead, and because the temporal sequence of lights on TLT trials is sufficiently predictable though not fixed, participants can decide to initiate their response during the amber foreperiod in order to generate a response closer to the exact green onset. But in so doing they take a risk that their movement will actually be initiated before the light turns green, and thereby incur a small penalty. On the TLT, such anticipatory responses are still nevertheless advantageous in the long run because small penalties are worth incurring if many of the responses actually fall shortly after green onset, when the reward to be obtained is large.</p><p>To meet our study goals, the TLT was modified in three ways. First, the magnitude and decay rate of the reward function were manipulated to create different task environments in which it was more or less advantageous to anticipate. This allowed us to measure participants' responsiveness to changes in the cost-benefit structure of the task environment, and determine whether such contextual adjustments could account for the apparent co-expression of apathy and impulsivity in self-report questionnaire data. For example, individuals who score high on both traits with standard assessments might in fact be particularly responsive to the environmental context, and thereby fluctuate to a greater extent between an apathetic and impulsive behavioural state in response to environmental triggers. Second, instead of an eye movement <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40</ref> or a button press 38 , a hand-held dynamometer was used to record responses, such that they became physically effortful. This introduced an effort-based decision-making dimension to the task, a process known to be implicated robustly in apathy <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[42]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[43]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[44]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[45]</ref> . Lastly, the subjective perception of fatigue, which is also known to be associated with apathy <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[46]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[47]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[48]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[49]</ref> , offers an alternative route to explain an apparent co-expression between apathy and impulsivity. It might indeed be the case that impulsive individuals tend to build up more fatigue, which may secondarily promote apathy. To measure how fatigue developed in the TLT, subjective ratings of fatigue were collected at various times throughout the experiment.</p><p>Consistent with previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> , total apathy and impulsivity questionnaire scores were positively correlated in the healthy participants tested here (n = 60). Nevertheless, when partialed out, the two constructs showed unique associations with distinct features of the modified TLT. Impulsivity was associated with a rigid urge to respond early, which was insensitive to changes in specific task constraints. Apathy, on the other hand, was associated with a blunted effect of reward on the energization of response vigour and on the prevention of fatigue. Finally, we found no evidence of an apathy-impulsivity axis on the TLT since the two traits appear to operate along distinct decision process components. Taken together, our results explain the possible co-expression of apathy and impulsivity in self-report questionnaire data: the two traits are in fact related to distinct dimensions of decision-making, which accounts for why they can be expressed in parallel in the same individual. . Self-report measures of apathy and impulsivity are positively correlated. a. Pairwise correlation plot of the total scores of the four questionnaires. The strongest positive associations were observed between the two questionnaires assessing the same construct (Apathy: AES vs. AMI; Impulsivity: BIS-11 vs. UPPS-P; both p &lt; 0.0001). In addition, significant cross-construct correlations were observed between the AES and impulsivity measures (BIS-11 &amp; UPPS-P; both p &lt; 0.004).</p><p>Pearson correlation coefficients are shown in the top left corner of each scatter plot (asterisks indicate significant relationships, p &lt; 0.05). The sample distribution of each questionnaire total score is shown on top. b. PCAs were performed on apathy (AES &amp; AMI total score) and impulsivity (BIS-11 &amp; UPPS-P total scores) measures in order to capture, in a single score, most of the variance of the construct's questionnaires. These two scores were positively correlated (r (58) = 0.33, p = 0.0096).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Self-report measures of apathy and impulsivity are positively correlated</head><p>On the day of the experimental session, participants (n = 60; 30 females; mean age: 24.97 years, s.d.: 4.85) filled out two validated self-report questionnaire measures of impulsivity (Barratt Impulsiveness Scale, BIS-11 <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8</ref> Urgency, Premeditation (lack of), Perseverance (lack of), Sensation Seeking, Positive Urgency, Impulsive Behavior Scale, UPPS-P 9 ) and two measures of apathy (Apathy Evaluation Scale, AES <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7</ref> ; Apathy Motivation Index 10 ). Consistent with previous observations in healthy individuals using these same measures <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> , positive correlations were observed within and across the two constructs assessed by these questionnaires <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1a)</ref>. For each construct, a Principal Component Analysis (PCA) was performed to derive a global index (PCA score) quantifying its severity across the two self-report questionnaires used to assess it (Apathy score: PCA of AES &amp; AMI total scores; Impulsivity score: PCA of BIS-11 &amp; UPPS-P total scores; see Methods). As expected, these two scores positively correlated with one another (r (58) = 0.33, p = 0.0096; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1b</ref>) such that individuals who reported being overall more impulsive also reported being more apathetic. In order to identify behavioural markers uniquely associated with apathy and/or impulsivity, all subsequent questionnaire-based analyses systematically included both these PCA scores within the same regression model (partial regressions).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental paradigm</head><p>The present study used a new version of an established measure of rapid decision-making for reward, the Traffic Light Task <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> (TLT). In our paradigm, a visual display successively turned red (800 ms), amber (700 ms on 15% of trials, 1000 ms on 70% of trials, 1300 ms on 15% of trials) then green (800 ms), and participants had to gently squeeze a hand-held dynamometer (above 15% of their Maximum Voluntary Contraction, MVC) after the green onset in order to receive time-sensitive monetary reward ( <ref type="figure">Fig. 2a)</ref>. Anticipatory responses (i.e., supra-threshold squeezes recorded before the green onset) led to a small penalty (£0.05).</p><p>Conversely, responses recorded after the green onset were rewarded according to the following rapid exponential discounting function ( <ref type="figure">Fig. 2c</ref>):</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">       R(RT ) = R 0 × e −λ ×RT if RT ≥ 0 R(RT ) = −0.05 if RT &lt; 0 (1)</formula><p>where R is the reward obtained as a function of the reaction time relative to the green onset, RT. Both the reward available <ref type="table">(R 0 )</ref> and decay rate after green onset (λ ) were manipulated in a two-by-two design <ref type="figure">(Fig. 2b</ref>). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reward (£)</head><p>Amber light Green light <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Overview of the Traffic Light Task. a. A picture of a coin (£1, £0.20) and an animal (turtle, hare) indicated the reward magnitude and decay rate for the upcoming trial. Pressing the space bar initiated the sequence of red, amber, green background colours. The duration of the amber light was either 700 ms (15.38% of trials), 1000 ms (69.23% of trials) or 1300 ms (15.38% of trials). Participants won monetary reward by squeezing a hand-held dynamometer above 15% of the Maximum Voluntary Contraction (MVC) as quickly as they could after the background turned green. b. Both the intercept (R 0 ) and decay rate (λ ) of the exponential reward function were experimentally manipulated in a two-by-two design (104 trials per condition in total, uniformly spread across eight experimental blocks). c. Visual representation of the reward function of the four experimental conditions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Anticipation but not vigour leads to larger earning</head><p>Similar to previous versions of the task, it was functionally advantageous to respond early, as participants who made more penalised anticipatory responses nevertheless accumulated more reward overall (β = 0.73, 95%CI = [0.57, 0.90], t (57) = 8.70, p &lt; 0.001, controlling for mean vigour; LMM S1; <ref type="table">Table S1</ref> -Model 1; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. S1</ref>). By contrast, and by design, the vigour of the response (i.e., maximum contraction generated during the response, expressed as a percentage of the MVC) showed no . The use of a hand-held dynamometer therefore introduced a physical effort dimension to the task that was not directly rewarded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Impulsivity but not apathy is advantageous on the TLT</head><p>Given that our version of the TLT provided a task environment in which it was financially advantageous to respond early ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. S1</ref>), we hypothesised that individuals who are naturally more impulsive may have a functional advantage. That is, the questionnaire-derived impulsivity score might positively correlate with total earnings. Similarly, if apathy operates along the same decision-making axis but has an opposite influence (motivational spectrum hypothesis), then it may be negatively associated with earnings (i.e., more apathetic people might win less reward overall).</p><p>To test these hypotheses, a single linear mixed-effect model (LMM) was built with both questionnaire-derived scores as predictors of total earning (LMM S3), controlling for age (fixed effect) and gender (random effect). The results showed that individuals with higher impulsivity scores indeed accumulated more reward overall on the task (β = 0. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Impulsivity is associated with a rigid all-encompassing urge to respond early</head><p>Next, we set out to characterise the specific means by which impulsivity conferred a functional advantage on the TLT. Were the most impulsive individuals merely faster to respond overall and/or did they strategically tailor their fast responses to the specific conditions that would yield highest reward? In order to answer this question, we first needed to establish which experimental factors influenced the speed of the response on our modified TLT. Five experimental factors were considered:</p><p>• the amber light duration of the current trial, a n ;</p><p>• the amber light duration of the previous trial, a n−1 ;</p><p>• task practice, captured as the block index;</p><p>• the reward available, R 0 (£0.20 or £1);</p><p>• the decay rate of reward, λ (fast or slow).</p><p>The main effect of these five factors was assessed using a single LMM with conditional average RT (relative to green onset)</p><p>as the dependent variable and participant as a random effect (LMM S4; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 3</ref>). Block index was log-transformed as this proved to yield a better fit to the data (∆BIC = −241.62).</p><p>The amber light duration of both the current and previous trials significantly influenced mean RT (Main effect of a n on  <ref type="table">Table S2</ref> -Model 1). Participants responded faster when the current amber light lasted longer than usual, and slower when it lasted shorter than usual <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3</ref>). By contrast, they responded faster when the previous amber light lasted shorter than usual, and slower when the previous amber light lasted shorter than usual <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3</ref>).</p><p>These two effects illustrate two sides of the same process: the fact that participants built an internal estimate of the duration of the amber light, which they used to anticipate the green light onset (sensitivity to a n ), and updated on a trial-by-trial basis (sensitivity to a n−1 ). These effects were also observed in previous versions of the task <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> , and are regarded as key features of the TLT.</p><p>Participants improved markedly (i.e., they learnt to respond earlier) with task practice. This was expressed as a negative  <ref type="table">Table   S2</ref> -Model 1; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 3</ref>). Follow-up pairwise t-test comparisons of block averaged RTs showed that performance reached an asymptotic level in the fifth block as blocks 1 to 4 significantly differed from all others (all p &lt; 0.001, Bonferroni-corrected) but it was no longer the case from the fifth block onwards. This learning effect appeared to result from a shift in strategyfrom reaction to anticipation -rather than mere predictive learning based on the statistical properties of the task. The latterassessed with a separate "Predictive" control task interleaved between TLT blocks (see Methods) -behaved very differently, plateauing much earlier during the experimental session (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Supplementary Results; Fig. S3</ref>).   <ref type="table">Table S2</ref> -Model 2). Coloured bars show significant effects (p &lt; 0.05) and white bars non significant effects with 95% confidence interval. Five experimental factors influenced the speed of the response: duration of the amber light of the current (a n ) and previous (a n−1 ) trial, block index (log-transformed), magnitude (R 0 ) and decay rate (λ ) of the reward. Impulsivity had a significant negative main effect and interaction with a n . This behavioural signature reflects a rigid tendency to respond early, regardless of the experimental condition. b-c. For visualisation purposes, the average reaction time (pm s.e.m.) is plotted as a function of the five experimental factors of interest, with a group median split on the impulsivity score (b.) or apathy score (c.). Individual data are plotted as separate lines of the corresponding colour. Importantly, both the reward available (R 0 ) and the rate of its decay after green onset (λ ) influenced the average RT.  <ref type="table">Table S2</ref> -Model 1; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 3f</ref>). Thus, individuals were incentivised to respond earlier both to harvest larger amounts of reward, and to avoid losing too much of it. There was no significant interaction between the two factors (β = −0.01, 95%CI = [−0.02, 0.00], t (9294) = −1.68, p = 0.09; <ref type="table">Table S2</ref> -Model 1).</p><p>Having established that the average speed of the response on the TLT was influenced by task statistics (a n , a n−1 ), learning (block), and cost-benefit environment (R 0 , λ ), the key question was to determine whether the functional advantage enjoyed by impulsive individuals involved any of these factors. To answer this, we added the apathy and impulsivity scores and their interactions with experimental factors to the LMM reported above, while controlling for age (fixed effect) and gender (random effect; LMM S5). This revealed that more impulsive individuals responded generally earlier, regardless of the specific task Taken together, these results are consistent with the functional advantage of impulsivity on the TLT deriving from an urge to respond earlier rather than any strategic adjustment to specific task constraints. Follow-up parcellation of this result into the individual sub-scales of the UPPS-P questionnaire revealed that it was driven significantly by positive urgency (Negative main effect of UPPS-P "Positive Urgency" on mean RT: β = −0.13, 95%CI = [−0.25, −0.01], t (9281) = −2.06, p = 0.039;</p><p>Interaction UPPS-P "Positive Urgency" × a n : β = −0.06, 95%CI = [−0.12, −0.00], t (9281) = −2.05, p = 0.041; <ref type="table">Table S3</ref>).</p><p>Furthermore, Supplementary Results provide a computational parameterisation of this finding within a variant of a two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> able to reproduce the full RT distribution (Figs. S4-S8). The main conclusion of this alternative analysis is that more impulsive individuals showed a greater baseline probability to activate the anticipatory process in the task. This is consistent with the results of the simpler analysis reported in the main text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Apathetic individuals are less energized by reward</head><p>The use of a hand-held dynamometer in our modified TLT enabled us to measure not only the speed of the response but also its vigour (i.e. peak force exerted within each trial). This metric has been proposed to offer an indirect read-out of utility <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">50</ref> , i.e., the subjective value individuals attribute to particular actions/stimuli. The force requirements to trigger a response were voluntarily chosen to be low (15% of the MVC) to avoid exhaustion, and leave room for potential overshoot. On average, participants overshot this threshold by 39.71% (s.d.: 19.30%).</p><p>The same analysis strategy as the previous section was adopted, with the difference that the LMM additionally controlled for mean RT to orthogonalise vigour and RT (LMM S6). Before investigating interactions with apathy and impulsivity, we first established which of the five experimental factors (a n , a n−1 , block index, R 0 , λ ) influenced the vigour of the response. The duration of amber light of the current but not previous trial had an influence on the vigour of the response (Main effect of a n on mean vigour: β = −0.10, 95%CI = [−0.12, −0.07], t (9293) = −7.48, p &lt; 0.001; Main effect of a n−1 on mean vigour: β = 0.00, 95%CI = [−0.01, 0.01], t (9293) = −0.17, p = 0.87; <ref type="table">Table S4</ref> -Model 1). Thus, the surprise induced by a exceptionally short amber light duration was reflected in a harder squeeze than usual, while the opposite was true for a longer amber foreperiod.</p><p>This surprise effect, however, led to no force adjustment from one trial to the next (no significant effect of a n−1 ). As the   <ref type="table">Table S4</ref> -Model 2). Coloured bars show significant effects (p &lt; 0.05) and white bars non significant effects with 95% confidence interval. Three experimental factors influenced the speed of the response: duration of the amber light of the current trial (a n ), block index (log-transformed), and magnitude of the reward available (R 0 ). Apathy negatively interacted with the latter effect. b-c. For visualisation purposes, the average vigour (± s.e.m.) is plotted as a function of the three experimental factors of interest that significantly influenced it, with a group median split on the impulsivity score (b.) or apathy score (c.). Individual data are plotted as separate lines of the corresponding colour. The force requirement to trigger a response (15%MVC) is shown as a horizontal dotted black line. 95%CI = [−0.04, 0.00], t (9287) = −2.48, p = 0.013; <ref type="table">Table S5</ref>). No other interaction with experimental factors was significant for neither impulsivity nor apathy <ref type="table">(Table S4</ref> -Model 2; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 3a</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Although it may seem counter-intuitive, a growing evidence base suggests that apathy and impulsivity can co-occur in psychiatric and neurological patients <ref type="bibr">13-16, 25, 28-30</ref> and in the general population <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12</ref> . The present study aimed to use behavioural tools to uncover some of the mechanisms allowing for this co-occurrence to exist. Using a new version of the TLT <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> , we found that although apathy and impulsivity positively correlated in self-report questionnaires, these two motivational disorders were associated with unique, distinct behavioural signatures on the task. On the one hand, impulsivity was associated with an urge to respond faster, regardless of task constraints <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3)</ref>. On the other hand, apathy was characterised by reduced response invigoration with higher reward <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig. 4)</ref> as well as decoupling of reward and fatigue (the latter result is presented and discussed in <ref type="figure">Supplementary Information; Fig. S9</ref>). Crucially, we found no instance in which apathy significantly influenced behaviour in the opposite direction as impulsivity. That is, there was no support for the motivational spectrum hypothesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref> .</p><p>The finding that impulsivity was associated with faster responding on the TLT is consistent with previous observations <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38</ref> , and with a broader literature that used various tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">52</ref> (in particular go-no go or stop-signal tasks). Because it leads to larger reward on the TLT, this mode of responding had previously been assumed to capture a form of "functional" impulsivity, that is the tendency to act rapidly when this response style is optimal <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">53</ref> . By manipulating the cost-benefit structure of the TLT (R 0 and λ ; <ref type="figure">Fig 2b)</ref>, the present experiment tested directly whether people responded to task environment. The results revealed that the TLT was indeed able to capture a behavioural manifestation of "functional" impulsivity since participants were incentivised to respond earlier when greater reward was available and when it was set to decay faster after the green onset <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3</ref>). This is in line with previous studies demonstrating a motivational role of both reward (R 0 ) and punishment (λ ) in motor decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[54]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[55]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[56]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[57]</ref> .</p><p>The cost-benefit structure of our TLT was such that it was actually always financially advantageous to anticipate the green onset, regardless of the current R 0 -λ combination. What varied across experimental conditions was the financial benefit associated with doing do. Thus, a truly rational agent performing this new version of the TLT should have invariantly aimed to respond at green onset with as little variance as possible since this strategy maximised return. The notion of Expected Value of Control 58-60 offers a theoretical framework for understanding why human participants may have deviated from this strategy to instead adjust their response speed to R 0 and λ . According to this framework, exerting control (to generate the response that harvests most reward) comes at a cost that is weighted against expected reward to determine the optimal amount of control to invest in the ongoing task. If accurately anticipating the green onset comes at an extra cost -potentially due to more precise temporal estimation and greater attentional resources -then it may become optimal to invest these additional resources only when the associated pay-off is high enough (large reward available and/or large cost of generating late responses). Within the two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> developed in Supplementary Information <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figs. S4-S5</ref>), R 0 and λ were indeed found to increase the accumulation rate of the anticipatory decision process, thereby allowing the model to generate responses that fell closer to the green onset and were less variable <ref type="figure">(Fig. S8</ref>). Our results are therefore consistent with the idea that reward (R 0 ) and punishment (λ ) exerted their motivational influence on the TLT through the optimisation of the anticipatory process, which in itself may have come at an intrinsic cost. Apathy and impulsivity were not found to interact with this process in the current study.</p><p>Although all individuals strategically tailored their response speed to the cost-benefit structure, the psychometric trait measure of impulsivity derived from the BIS-11 and UPPS-P questionnaires was instead related to a rigid readiness to respond earlier on the TLT, irrespective of experimental condition <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3</ref>). This can be seen as a form of "dysfunctional" impulsivity which incidentally happened to be beneficial on the TLT. Within the modeling framework developed in Supplementary Information, this behaviour was conceptualised as a bias towards engaging the anticipatory process in the task at baseline prior to any exposure. Consistent with this idea, the greatest contributor of the relationship between impulsivity score and RT on the TLT was "Positive Urgency", a subscale of the UPPS-P that has previously been linked to a difficulty inhibiting prepotent motor responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">61,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">62</ref> . We therefore propose that inhibitory control deficit may be a dimension of impulsivity that sits outside the dopamine-mediated motivational spectrum. In agreement with this interpretation is the report of inhibitory control deficits in both impulsive and apathetic patients with rather specific neuroanatomical <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">63,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">64</ref> (ventral prefrontal cortex) and neurochemical <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">[65]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[66]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[67]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> (serotoninergic and noradrenergic deficiency) signatures.</p><p>The use of a hand-held dynamometer allowed us to measure response vigour in addition to speed in our version of the TLT. As expected <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">50</ref> , this offered an indirect read out of wanting 69 as participants were found to squeeze harder when the reward available increased <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig. 4</ref>). It is worth noting the absence of effect of decay rate (λ ) on vigour, suggesting this behavioural metric was related to the reward available presented on the screen (R 0 ) as opposed to expected outcome.</p><p>Reward sensitivity is one of the pillar candidate mechanism of the motivational spectrum hypothesis 11 since it involves dopaminergic frontostriatal circuits that can be up-or down-regulated in disease and pharmacologically, and it shares conceptual links to both apathy and impulsivity depending on the direction of the impairment (too little: apathy; too much: impulsivity).</p><p>Although the role of altered reward sensitivity in the genesis of apathy is well established <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[42]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[43]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[44]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[70]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">[71]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[72]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">[73]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[74]</ref> , its contribution to impulsivity is more debated, with many authors arguing for a distinction between these two concepts -so called "reward (hyper)sensitivity" vs. "rash impulsiveness" <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">[75]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">[76]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">[77]</ref> . The psychometric measure of impulsivity used in our study seemed to be more specific to rash impulsiveness given its relationship to RT on the TLT <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3</ref>). On the other hand, the apathy score derived from the AES and AMI questionnaires was associated with blunted reward sensitivity on the TLT, i.e. lower invigoration of the manual response by monetary incentives. Thus, apathy seems to be more specifically a disorder of the valuation system, compared to impulsivity. Note that this finding does not invalidate the existence of a potential motivational spectrum for reward sensitivity. For example, it might be the case that reward hypersensitivity only leads to impulsive behaviour in the presence of a conjoint inhibitory control deficit <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">77</ref> .</p><p>Overall, the findings presented here suggest that impulsivity may have a direct effect on action initiation/inhibition, whereas apathy appears to be more specifically related to the valuation system. These distinct mechanisms may contribute to the possible co-expression of both apathy and impulsivity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Sixty young healthy adults (30 females, mean age: 24.97 years, s.d.: 4.85) took part in the study. They were recruited via the Oxford Psychology Research participant recruitment scheme website (https://opr.sona-systems.com) and online study advertisement. Volunteers who reported a personal history of neurological or psychiatric condition or undertaking psycho-active medication were excluded from participation. The study was approved by the University of Oxford ethics committee, and all participants provided written informed consent at the beginning of the experimental session. Data collection took place in person between October and February 2020.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>External measures</head><p>Participants completed two well-established self-report questionnaire measures of apathy (Apathy Evaluation Scale, AES 7 ;</p><p>Apathy Motivation Index 10 ) and impulsivity (Barratt Impulsiveness Scale, BIS-11 <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8</ref> ; Urgency, Premeditation (lack of), Perseverance (lack of), Sensation Seeking, Positive Urgency, Impulsive Behavior Scale, UPPS-P 9 ). The use of two questionnaires per construct provided a more reliable measure of apathy and impulsivity (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref> for cross-questionnaire correlations).</p><p>Details about the four questionnaires are provided below:</p><p>• Apathy Evaluation Scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Maximum Voluntary Contraction (MVC)</head><p>At the beginning of the experimental session, participants were asked to squeeze the hand-held dynamometer as hard as they possibly could on three consecutive occasions (5 seconds per squeeze). The strongest force recorded during this procedure was defined as the Maximum Voluntary Contraction (MVC), and used for task calibration purposes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Modified Traffic Light Task</head><p>The Traffic Light Task (TLT) is a well-established test of rapid, opportunistic decision-making under temporal uncertainty in pursuit of risky, time-sensitive reward <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> . The current version of the task departed from the one used in previous studies in two important ways <ref type="figure">(Fig. 2)</ref>. First, a hand-held dynamometer was used to record the response, as opposed to an eye movement <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40</ref> or a button press 38 . This provided a measure of vigour as an indirect index of subjective utility <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">50</ref> , as well as introduced a fatigue-inducing physical effort dimension to the task. Second, both the starting point (R 0 ) and decay constant (λ ) of the reward function (Eq. 2) were manipulated in a two-by-two design in order to investigate the influence of cost-benefit structure on performance.</p><p>At the beginning of each trial, participants were presented with a picture of a coin (20p or £1) and an animal (turtle or hare) that informed them of the cost-benefit features of the trial (R 0 -λ combination). They subsequently had to press the space bar with their non-dominant hand to self-initiate each trial. Upon release of the space key, the screen background turned red, then amber, then green. The red and green colours both stayed on the screen for 800 ms. The duration of the amber light, however, could take one of three values. It was 1000 ms in most cases (69.2% of all trials, i.e., 72 trials per condition in total), but departed from this time by ± 300 ms in the remaining cases (30.8% of all trials., i.e., 16 trials per condition and per deviation in total). Experimental blocks included 13 repetitions of each of the four possible R 0 -λ combinations (52 trials per block in total). Nine of these trials had the most common amber light duration (1000 ms), while two had a shorter one (700 ms), and two had a longer one (1300 ms). The order of trials was random such that rarer amber light durations occurred unexpectedly. Note, however, that rare trials (700 ms or 1300 ms amber duration) were always followed by a common trial (1000 ms amber light duration).</p><p>The task statistics allowed participants to form an internal representation of the most common amber light duration (see Predictive control task), and use this knowledge to anticipate the green onset if they wished. Thus, on a trial-by-trial basis, people had to rapidly decide whether to wait for the green light to appear before generating a (reactive) response, or whether to respond based on their knowledge of task statistics but risk incurring a penalty (anticipatory response).</p><p>Participants were instructed that they could win hypothetical money by "catching the animal" as quickly as they could once the screen turned green. To catch the animal, they had to squeeze the hand-held dynamometer with a force of at least 15% of their MVC. They were explicitly informed that stronger squeezes did not yield higher reward. A vertical progress bar provided visual feedback on the current (sub-threshold) force exerted. Upon crossing the response force threshold (15% MVC), an outline appeared around the picture of the animal to indicate that the response had been recorded. It was red if the response occurred before the green onset (penalised anticipatory response), and black otherwise (rewarded response). The trial outcome was subsequently presented for 2 seconds. Reward was calculated according to the following inverse exponential temporal discount function ( <ref type="figure">Fig. 2c)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">       R(RT ) = R 0 × e −λ ×RT if RT ≥ 0 R(RT ) = −0.05 if RT &lt; 0 (2)</formula><p>where R 0 refers to the magnitude of the reward available (£1 or £0.20), λ refers to the rate of its decay after green onset (λ f ast = 0.0125 £.ms -1 and λ slow = 0.0033 £.ms <ref type="bibr">-1</ref> , which correspond to a half-life of 55 ms and 208 ms, respectively), and RT refers to the time elapsed between the green onset and the crossing of the 15%MVC threshold. The outcome of each trial was added to the amount in the "bank", displayed at the top of the screen. In-between blocks, a score board showed to amount earned in each block, ranked from highest to lowest. To keep participants motivated, they were encouraged to beat their own score from one block to the next. The amount in the bank was reset to zero at the beginning of each task block.</p><p>Participants underwent eight blocks of 52 trials each (mean block duration </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fatigue Ratings</head><p>Because of the physical effort component of this version of the TLT, participants were asked to rate their level of subjective fatigue throughout the experimental session. When doing so, a vertical visual analogue scale (VAS) appeared in the middle of the screen with the words "Not at all" and "Extremely" displayed at its lowest and highest extremes, and the question "How TIRED do you feel?" at the top <ref type="figure">(Fig. S2d)</ref>. Individuals then placed a cursor at the level that best reflected their current fatigue by touching the screen, and pressed the space bar to validate their rating. The percentage corresponding to the level selected was displayed on the side of the cursor. Within a task, the initial position of the cursor was set to the value of the preceding rating.</p><p>The reactive control task included four fatigue ratings in total (one every 40 trials), the TLT task four fatigue ratings per block (one every 13 trials), and the temporal duration discrimination task four fatigue ratings in total (one every trials).</p><p>Analysis and discussion of fatigue data is provided in Supplementary Information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical analysis</head><p>Data handling and statistical analysis were done in MATLAB (The Math-Works Inc., version 2020a). On the TLT, were excluded from the analysis trials in which: (1) no response was recorded (0.88% of the data); (2) a response was recorded earlier than 1000 ms before the green onset (0.10% of the data); (3) a response was recorded later than 1000 ms after the green onset (0.10% of the data). The behavioural measure of interest were: (1) Earnings (i.e. the amount of reward obtained); <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref> Anticipation (i.e. the percentage of trials in which participants responded before the green onset); (3) Reaction Time (RT) relative to the green onset; (4) Vigour (i.e. peak force exerted within a trial, expressed as a percentage of the MVC).</p><p>Statistical analysis used general linear mixed-effect models (LMM). When analysing the relationship between apathy and a behavioural variable, the other motivation disorder (impulsivity) was also included in the model (partial correlation). Similarly, when analysing the relationship between impulsivity and a behavioural variable, the model systematically controlled for apathy.</p><p>All statistical tests were two-sided. All LMM equations are provided in Supplementary Information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reactive Control Task</head><p>Before undergoing the TLT, participants performed a short control task (mean duration: 5.77 min, s.d.: 0.49) aimed at measuring their responsiveness to unpredictable changes in screen background colour <ref type="figure">(Fig. S2a)</ref>. A secondary objective of this task was to familiarise participants with the visual display and mode of responding of the TLT. The background was grey and turned green for 800 ms every 800 to 2800 ms according to a pseudo-uniform distribution. Participants were instructed to squeeze the hand-held dynamometer as quickly as they could in response to the green light. When reaching 15% of the MVC, the progress bar filled up, and a black outline appeared around a grey rectangle indicating that a response had been recorded. This short control task included three blocks of 40 trials each, separated by a fatigue rating.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predictive Control Task</head><p>Anticipatory behaviour on the TLT may in part reflect statistical learning. That is, in order to respond at green onset, individuals need to build an accurate internal representation of the distribution of amber light durations. In order to track how this ability developed over the course of the TLT, a predictive response task was interleaved at the end of each TLT block <ref type="figure">(Fig. S2b</ref>). In this short task (10 trials per block; mean block duration: 1.13 min, s.d.: 0.22), the background turned red for 800 ms, then amber, but did not turn green. Instead, participants were instructed to respond when they thought the background should turn green (i.e., after 1000 ms on average). On each trial, after the response was recorded, a visual representation of the most frequent timeline (red/amber/green: 800/1000/800 ms) was presented on the screen and participants had to report whether they thought they had responded too early, on time, or too late by positioning an arrow at the time of their response. This rating provided a measure of metacognitive accuracy, i.e., the precision of ones' perception of their own performance. No performance feedback was provided on the predictive control task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Temporal Duration Discrimination Task</head><p>In order to investigate the extent to which performance on the TLT was influenced by inter-individual differences in time perception, participants performed a two-alternative forced choice temporal duration discrimination task at the end of the experimental session ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Fig. S2c; 64</ref> trials; mean duration: 7.38 min, s.d.: 0.51). The task was adapted from Bueti et al.</p><p>(2008) <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">79</ref> , task B, and was similar to the one used by Burnett et al. (2012) <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38</ref> . The screen turned amber twice in a row with a grey interval of 800 ms in-between. On each trial, one of the two amber durations was 1000 ms (the "reference" duration), equivalent the mean and most frequent duration on the TLT <ref type="figure">(Fig. S2a)</ref>. The other amber duration (the "test" duration) was either 700 ms (short amber light duration on the TLT), 850 ms, 1150 ms or 1300 ms (long amber light duration on the TLT). The order of reference and test durations was fully randomised across trials (16 repetitions per test duration).</p><p>Participants pressed the left or right arrow keys with the index and middle fingers of their dominant hand to indicate whether the first or second flash lasted longer. On half of the trials, the left arrow key corresponded to the first flash, while on the other half it corresponded to the second flash. The key-response matching was explicitly displayed on the screen, and reversed only once halfway through the task. No performance feedback was provided on the temporal duration discrimination task. Mean RT ∼ 1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R 0 + λ + Imp + a : Imp + a n−1 : Imp + ln(Block) : Imp + R 0 : Imp + λ : Imp + Ap + a : Ap + a n−1 : Ap + ln(Block) : Ap + R 0 : Ap + λ : Ap + Age + (1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R 0 + λ + Imp + a : Imp + a n−1 : Imp + ln(Block) : Imp + R 0 : Imp + λ : Imp + Ap + a : Ap + a n−1 : Ap + ln(Block) : Ap + R 0 : Ap + λ : Ap + Age | Gender)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mixed-effect model equations</head><formula xml:id="formula_2">+ (1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R 0 + λ + R 0 : λ | Participant) (S5)</formula><p>Mean Vigour ∼ 1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R 0 + λ + R 0 : λ + Mean RT + (1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block)</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">+ R 0 + λ + R 0 : λ + Mean RT | Participant) (S6)</formula><p>Mean Vigour ∼ 1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R 0 + λ + Mean RT + Imp + a : Imp + a n−1 : Imp + ln(Block) : Imp + R 0 : Imp + λ : Imp + Ap + a : Ap + a n−1 : Ap + ln(Block) : Ap + R 0 : Ap + λ : Ap + Age + (1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R + λ + Mean RT + Imp + a : Imp + a n−1 : Imp + ln(Block) : Imp + R 0 : Imp + λ : Imp + Ap + a : Ap + a n−1 : Ap + ln(Block) : Ap + R 0 : Ap + λ : Ap + Age | Gender)</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">+ (1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R 0 + λ + R 0 : λ + Mean RT | Participant) (S7)</formula><p>For the following two analyses, fatigue ratings, vigour and reward obtained were block-averaged. Time-on-task corresponded to the cumulative time reached at the end of each of the eight experimental blocks (starting from zero at the beginning of the first block). Baseline fatigue was the average fatigue rating before the start of the TLT. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational model of reaction time distributions</head><p>On the TLT, the distribution of reaction times (RT) relative to the green onset is characterised by the presence of two distinct peaks -corresponding to anticipatory/predictive and reactive responses -whose relative magnitude is influenced by the duration of the amber light <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref>  <ref type="figure">(Figs. S6-S8</ref>). Trials in which the amber light lasts longer than usual typically lead to more anticipatory (early) responses, while trials in which the amber light is shorter are characterised by predominantly reactive (late) responses. This data feature is well reproduced by a two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model in which processes compete (or "race") towards a threshold in order to generate a response <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> . According to this two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model, the probability that a response has occurred by time t following amber light onset (i.e., the cumulative probability distribution) is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">Pr(T ≤ t|n) = Ψ(t, µ A , σ 2 A ) + Ψ(t − a n , µ R , σ 2 R ) − Ψ(t, µ A , σ 2 A ) × Ψ(t − a n , µ R , σ 2 R ) (S10)</formula><p>where Ψ is the cumulative recinormal distributions <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">80</ref> , and a n is the amber light duration of the n-th trial (i.e., either 700, 1000, or 1300 ms). The cumulative recinormal distribution is defined for t &gt; 0 as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Ψ(t, µ, σ 2 ) = 1 − Φ 1/t − µ σ (S11)</formula><p>where µ and σ 2 are the mean and variance of the standard cumulative normal distribution Φ. Thus, within the two-horse linear rise-to-threshold modeling framework, each process (anticipatory and reactive) is parameterised in terms of the mean and variance of its rate-of-rise. The anticipatory process is assumed to start rising (with mean rate-of-rise µ A and variance σ 2 A ) from amber onset onwards, thereby crossing the response threshold around the average green onset. The reactive process, on the other hand, is automatically triggered by the actual onset of the green light, and rises more sharply (with mean rate-of-rise µ R and variance σ 2 R ).</p><p>By design, this formulation (Eq. S10) is solely capable of capturing how the duration of the amber light of a given trial (a n )</p><p>impacts the relative contribution of the anticipatory and reactive processes to the RT distribution. However, a simple analysis of mean reaction times using a LMM demonstrated that at least three other factors also had an impact on the average speed of the response <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3)</ref>, namely:</p><p>• Amber light duration of the previous trial, a n−1 ;</p><p>• Task practice, indexed by the trial number, n;</p><p>• The cost-benefit structure of the trial (R 0 and τ).</p><p>The goal of incorporating these effects within a computational model (two-horse model) was to gain further mechanistic insight by considering the full RT distribution (as opposed to mere mean RT). In other words, the question asked was: what is the putative mechanism by which any of these experimental factors influence reaction time? For simplification purposes, the two experimental variables defining the cost-benefit structure of the trial (R 0 &amp; λ ) were assumed to both affect the same compartment of the model. For each factor (a n−1 , n, R 0 &amp; λ ), we tested three candidate computational mechanisms by which the factor could exert its influence ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Fig. S4</ref>):</p><p>• By advancing/postponing the time at which the anticipatory process starts rising towards the response threshold, t 0 (Fig <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">.   S4b</ref>);</p><p>• By increasing/decreasing the mean rise of the anticipatory process, µ A <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig. S4c)</ref>;</p><p>• By increasing/decreasing the probability of the anticipatory process to be active on a given trial, w n <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig. S4d</ref>).</p><p>Incorporating these candidate mechanisms into the two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model required extending Eq. S10 as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">Pr(T ≤ t|n) =w(n) × [Ψ(t − δ (n), µ A (n), σ 2 A ) + Ψ(t − a n , µ R , σ 2 R ) − Ψ(t − δ (n), µ A (n), σ 2 A ) × Ψ(t − a n , µ R , σ R )] + (1 − w(n)) × Ψ(t − a n , µ R , σ 2 R ) (S12)</formula><p>where w(n) is the probability of the anticipatory process to be active on the n-th trial (0 ≤ w(n) ≤ 1), δ (n) is the shift in starting time of the anticipatory process relative to the amber onset on the n-th trial, and µ A (n) is the mean rate-of-rise of the anticipatory process on the n-th trial.</p><p>As illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure S4</ref>, each of these alternative mechanisms (manipulating δ (n), µ A (n) or w(n)) has a unique, distinct, signature on the RT distribution. This mathematical property made it possible to determine, for each experimental factor (a n−1 , n, [R 0 &amp; λ ]), the candidate computational mechanism (δ (n), µ A (n) or w(n)) that best explained its impact on human performance.</p><p>δ (n) and µ A (n) were assumed to be a linear combination of the experimental factors influencing them, that is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">δ (n) = Xβ δ (n) = Xβ (S13)</formula><p>where X is in a design matrix containing the experimental factors of interest and β is a vector of parameter estimates capturing the magnitude of these effects. Because w(n) was bounded between 0 and 1, it was assumed to have instead a logistic relationship to the experimental factors of interest, that is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">w(n) = 1 1 + e −Xβ (<label>S14)</label></formula><p>Note that the experimental factors included in a given design matrix were z-scored at the individual level to facilitate model fitting.</p><p>By considering all possible combinations of experimental factor (a n−1 , n, [R 0 &amp; λ ]) vs. computational mechanism (δ (n), µ A (n) or w(n)), twenty-seven models were created (3 3 = 27 combinations; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Fig. S5a</ref>). In addition to these 27 models, we also tested the original two-horse linear-to-arise model described in Equation S10 <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">39</ref> (Reference model 1) as well as its simple upgrade (Reference model 2) that included a subject-specific probability of anticipating w that was fixed across trials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Control tasks</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reactive Control Task</head><p>The Reactive Control Task was used to measure participants' ability to respond to unpredictable changes in screen background colour. Since no anticipation was possible, RT was thought to primarily reflect delay due to visuomotor processing. To investigate the relationship of apathy and impulsivity with this process, a LMM was built with the two questionnaire-derived scores as predictors of mean RT, controlling for age (fixed effect) and gender (random effect). Trials for which a response occurred within the 800 ms preceding a change in background colour were excluded from the analysis (0.67% of the data excluded).</p><p>Mean RT on the Reactive Control Task showed no relationship to neither apathy (β = 0.00, 95%CI = [−0.01, 0.01], t (56) = 0.30, p = 0.77; <ref type="table">Table S8</ref>) nor impulsivity (β = 0.01, 95%CI = [−0.01, 0.02], t (56) = 0.89, p = 0.38; <ref type="table">Table S8</ref>). This null result reinforces the idea that faster responses of more impulsive individuals on the TLT is due not to shorter visuomotor delays but rather to a greater tendency to anticipate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predictive Control Task</head><p>At the end of every TLT block, participants underwent a short Predictive Control Task in which they were explicitly instructed to respond based on their internal estimate of the green onset (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Methods)</ref>. The reaction time (RT) was expressed in relation to the most common green onset (i.e., 1000 ms after the amber onset). Trials for which the RT was further than three scaled median absolute deviations (MAD) away from the median of the participant were excluded from the analysis  <ref type="table">Table   S2</ref>). Follow-up pairwise t-test comparisons of block averaged RTs showed that performance reached an asymptotic level as early as the second block since only the first block significantly differed from all others (p &lt; 0.001, not Bonferroni-corrected).</p><p>Furthermore, participants responded earlier on average on the Predictive Control Task compared to the TLT in the first and second blocks (paired t-tests: both p &lt; 0.01).</p><p>Performance on the Predictive Control Task therefore indicates that, when instructed to do so, participants were well able to anticipate the green light onset. Nevertheless, the strategy adopted by participants on the TLT task led to slower mean RT, especially in the first two experimental blocks <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. S3a)</ref>. This is consistent with the idea that the learning effect observed on the TLT only marginally reflects predictive learning but instead seem to derive from a shift in strategy from reaction to anticipation.</p><p>To investigate the relationship of apathy and impulsivity with predictive learning, the two questionnaire-derived scores were added to the LMM while controlling for age (fixed effect) and gender (random effect). Although impulsivity did not significantly the two questionnaire-derived scores to the LMM while controlling for age (fixed effect) and gender (random effect) showed no interaction of these traits with metacognition (both p &gt; 0.19).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Temporal Duration Discrimination Task</head><p>The Temporal Duration Discrimination Task was used to measure inter-individual differences in time perception. The effect of test duration on the response was analysed using the following logistic mixed-effect model:</p><p>Responded "Test duration is longer" ∼ 1 + Test duration</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">+ (1 + Test duration | Participant)<label>(S15)</label></formula><p>Overall, participants' responses were accurate (slope: β = 1.64, 95%CI = [1.47, 1.80], t (3838) = 19.23, p &lt; 0.001; <ref type="table">Table   S10</ref> -Model 1). Adding questionnaire-derived scores to the logistic regression showed no significant interaction of apathy and impulsivity with the accuracy of time discrimination (Apathy score × accuracy: β = −0.07, 95%CI = [−0.21, 0.07], t (3834) = −0.95, p = 0.34; Impulsivity score × accuracy: β = 0.00, 95%CI = [−0.13, 0.14], t (3834) = 0.07, p = 0.94; <ref type="table">Table   S10</ref> -Model 2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A computational model of RT</head><p>The goal of this supplementary analysis of TLT data was to take advantage of the greater information carried by the full distribution of RT to characterise the impact of impulsivity on the putative cognitive mechanisms involved. It is well established that RT on the TLT follows a bimodal (double recinormal) distribution with an early "anticipatory" and a late "reactive" peak whose relative magnitude depends on the duration of the amber light <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> . This data feature is well reproduced by a two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model, which posits the existence of two competing decision processes -an anticipatory and a reactive one -racing towards a fixed response threshold. The anticipatory process is thought to capture an urge to respond that starts building up from amber onset onwards and culminates at the green onset. This can be seen as a direct manifestation of functional impulsivity on the TLT. By contrast, the reactive process captures to the response to the onset of the green light.</p><p>Visual inspection of the RT distribution in our modified TLT confirmed the presence of distinct anticipatory and reactive peaks, which were more or less ample depending on the duration of the amber light <ref type="figure">(Figs. S6-S8</ref>). When the amber light duration was shorter than usual, the RT distribution was dominated by the late reactive peak, whereas when the amber light lasted longer than usual, the RT distribution was dominated by the early anticipatory peak. Crucially, the other experimental factors considered in the main text (a n−1 , block index, R 0 , λ ) appeared to have distinctive signatures on the RT distribution. In order to capture such effects, we extended the two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model to allow for three candidate mechanisms by which the factors may influence the model (see Supplementary Methods):</p><p>• by shifting the time at which the anticipatory process starts rising, t 0 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig.S4b)</ref>;</p><p>• by changing in the rate at which the anticipatory process rises toward the response threshold, µ A <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig.S4c)</ref>;</p><p>• by changing the probability of the anticipatory process to be active on a given trial, w <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig.S4d)</ref> As illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Fig.S4b-d</ref>, each of these three candidate computational mechanisms was associated with a unique, distinct signature on the RT distribution, making it possible, through model fitting and comparison, to determine the mechanism that best explained the effect of each experimental factor. Variants of the two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model were created by testing potential candidate mechanisms for each experimental factor. To reduce the number of models to test, costbenefit parameters (R 0 &amp; λ ) were assumed to operate through the same computational mechanism (see Supplementary Methods).</p><p>All combinations of three potential mechanisms (effect on t 0 , µ A , w) to explain three experimental factors (a n−1 , trial index, cost-benefit structure) led to 27 (i.e., 3 3 ) candidate models. Two additional models were tested for reference. They did not include a sensitivity to any of the three experimental factors, and merely differed in terms of their architecture: (1) two-horse model with an anticipatory process that was always active (i.e., w = 1; Reference model 1, equivalent to the model used in previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref> ); (2) a "weighted" version of the same model in which the anticipatory process had a fixed probability w (0 ≤ w ≤ 1) to be activated. Models were fitted to individual datasets separately, using a ∆BIC = −213.74; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Fig. S5a</ref>) accounted for these effects in the following ways:</p><p>• The amber duration of the previous trial influences the mean rate-of-rise of the anticipatory process (faster/slower µ A when the previous amber light was shorter/longer than usual);</p><p>• The probability of the anticipatory process to be active (w) grows logarithmically with task practice (trial index);</p><p>• The cost-benefit structure of the trial influences mean rate-of-rise of the anticipatory process (faster/slower µ A when more/less reward is available and when the reward decays faster/shorter after the green onset). RT distributions. Note that, in this model, learning is parameterised as an increase in the probability of the anticipatory process to be active (purple curve in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Fig. S5b</ref>). In that respect, individuals can differ in term of the baseline w (intercept), as well as the speed at which w rises across successive trials.</p><p>In order to determine which features of the model conferred a functional advantage on the TLT, we investigated the relationship between parameter estimates and total earnings. These correlations were run separately for each of the nine model parameters with Spearman correlation after outlier removal (exclusion of parameter estimates further than three scaled median absolute deviations away from the median of the group), and controlled for Age and Gender (partial correlation). The mean rate-of-rise of both the anticipatory (ρ (55) = 0.78, p &lt; 0.001) and reactive (ρ (57) = 0.35, p = 0.0078) process were positively associated with total earnings. In addition, the baseline probability of the anticipatory process to be active (ρ (50) = 0.72, p &lt; 0.001), as well as the speed at which this probability rose over successive trials (ρ (49) = 0.52, p &lt; 0.001) were both positively correlated to total earnings. None of the other five model parameters (σ A , σ R , effect of a n−1 on t 0 , effect of R 0 on µ A , effect of λ on µ A ) showed any significant relationship to total earnings. Thus, two features of the model were particularly rewarded: (1) maximising the speed of evidence accumulation in favour of a manual response (for both the anticipatory and reactive process), and (2) maximising the probability of the anticipatory process to be active.</p><p>Finally, we used the model developed above to investigate the mechanism through which impulsivity led to a functional advantage on the TLT. This was done by computing the Spearman correlation between Impulsivity Score and the four functional model parameter estimates (outliers removed as above), while controlling for Age, Gender, and Apathy Score. The only significant correlation was observed between Impulsivity Score and the baseline probability of the anticipatory process to be active (ρ (50) = 0.24, p = 0.045, one-tail). Note that this is a less sensitive analysis compared to the LMM reported in the main text due to the non-normal distribution of model parameter estimates that obliged us to exclude a large number of data points (n = 8 participants excluded from this analysis). Nevertheless, the results were consistent in that they indicated that the functional advantage impulsive individuals benefited from was related to a pre-existing tendency to produce an early anticipatory response before any exposure to the task, rather than any form of learning or sensitivity to the task environment.</p><p>Further support for this interpretation was provided by the relationship to questionnaire sub-scales. The only impulsivity sub-scale that showed a significant relationship to the baseline w was the UPPS-P "Lack of Premeditation" (ρ (50) = 0.30, p = 0.019, one-tail).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Apathy is expressed as a decoupling of reward and fatigue</head><p>Lower motivation has been proposed to be a central feature of both apathy and fatigue <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">49,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">81</ref> . More specifically, both constructs have been associated with distorted effort-based decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">82</ref> , and appear to implicate similar neural circuits involved in valuation and reward processing <ref type="bibr" target="#b83">[83]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">[84]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[85]</ref> . In the present study, fatigue ratings were collected in order to track the development of fatigue throughout the experiment. Participants were asked to rate, on a visual analogue scale (VAS), how tired they felt four times per TLT block (i.e., every 13 trials, see Methods).</p><p>There  <ref type="table">Table S6</ref>). This finding is consistent with a protective effect of reward on fatigue -as observed in dedicated tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b86">86,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">87</ref> and naturalistic work environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b88">88,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b89">89</ref> . However, the correlational nature of the data did not allow us to conclude on the directionality of the relationship observed. An alternative interpretation is that lower momentary fatigue might have led to better performance and therefore higher reward. Future work should disentangle between these two alternative interpretations.</p><p>Finally, adding the two questionnaire-derived scores to the LMM (while controlling for Age and Gender; LMM S9)</p><p>suggested that apathy weakened the association between earning and fatigue (Interaction Apathy × Block reward: β = 0.06, 95%CI = [0.00, 0.14], t (466) = 1.92, p = 0.055; <ref type="table">Table S6</ref> -Model 2). That is, in more motivated individuals reward appeared to be negatively associated with fatigue, while in more apathetic participants this effect was much weaker <ref type="figure">(Fig. S9c)</ref>. Although this result was not statistically significant, it was considered of interest because it was consistent with apathy promoting of form of fatigue accumulation through a lack of reward sensitivity, a mechanism that is in line with current neurocomputational models <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">49</ref> .</p><p>Follow-up parcellation of this result into the individual sub-scales of the AMI questionnaire revealed that it was driven mostly by behavioural apathy (Interaction AMI-behavioural × Block reward: β = 0.07, 95%CI = [0.00, 0.13], t (466) = 2.03, p = 0.043; <ref type="table">Table S7</ref>). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary figures 10 30</head><p>Percentage of (penalized) anticipatory trials (%)</p><p>Total earnings (£)  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>. Anticipatory but not strong responses are functionally advantageous. A multiple linear regression showed that total earnings were best predicted by the number of (penalised) anticipatory trials, than the average force exerted during the response (Tables S1 -Model 1). d. <ref type="figure">Figure S2</ref>. Control tasks. a. On the Reactive Control Task, participants were instructed to respond to unpredictable changes in background colour from grey to green. This task was performed before the Traffic Light Task (TLT), and also served as a training to the use of the dynamometer. b. On the Predictive Control Task, the background turned red then amber, and participants were instructed the respond when they thought the background should turn green (based on their experience of the TLT). After their response, a visual representation of the normal time line was displayed, and patient had to indicate (by touching the screen to position an arrow) when they thought they had responded in relation to this time line. This control task was interleaved with the TLT (10 trials at the enf of each TLT block). c. On the Temporal Duration Discrimination Task, the back ground turned amber twice in a row, and participants had to indicate which of these two flashes (the first or the second) lasted the longest. This control task was performed last, after the TLT. d. At various points throughout the experimental session, participants were asked to rate how tired they felt. When doing so, a vertical scale appeared in the middle of the screen, and participants could place a cursor at the appropriate level. A number between 0 (no fatigue at all) and 100 (extremely tired) was displayed on the side of the cursor based on its position on the scale.    <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure S4</ref>. Visual illustration of the two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model of reaction time in TLT. a. Group and individual reaction time data were fit to a two-horse linear rise-to-threshold model. RT distributions arise probabilistically from one of two linear rise-to-threshold processes: (1) an anticipatory decision process, triggered by the onset of the amber light, with mean rate of rise mu A and SD rate of rise sigma A . The background in the box shows the duration of red, amber and green lights. The dashed vertical line marks the onset of the green light. This process has a small mean rate of rise and large variance, and therefore results in a wide but early RT distribution (the orange distribution above the top box), of which some are elicited prior to the onset of the green light. (2) A reactive decision process, triggered by the onset of the green light, with mean rate of rise mu R and SD rate of rise sigma R . This process has a high mean rate of rise and small variance, and therefore results in a narrow but late RT distribution with median shortly after green onset (the green distribution above the bottom box). The first process to reach the threshold (the top horizontal edge of each box) on a given trial will trigger a response. This results in a two-peak RT distribution observed in TLT, as illustrated in blue on the right box. The anticipatory process can be affected in three mechanisms: b. the starting point of the anticipatory process t 0 ; c. the mean rise of the anticipatory process µ A , and d. the probability of activating the anticipatory process w. The box grid shows the model architecture. Reference models 1 and 2 were a two-horse and weighted two-horse model, respectively. Models 1-27 were constructed by varying the computational mechanisms (effect on t 0 , µ A or w) by which each experimental factor (a n−1 , n, R0/λ ) had an effect. For each of the three columns, a black box on the left/middle/right means an effect on t 0 /µ A /w, respectively. The best model (lowest BIC) included an effect of a n−1 and cost-benefit structure (R 0 , λ ) on µ A , and an effect of trial number on w. b. These effects are plotted here. Bars and error bars indicate group mean ± s.e.m. (outliers removed). Individual participants are shown as individual lines. a n−1 : duration of the amber light in the previous trial; n: trial index; R 0 : intercept of the reward function; λ : time constant of the reward function; µ A : mean rate-of-rise of the anticipatory process; w: probability of the anticipatory process to be active. -900 -600 -300 300 900 -900 -600 -300 0 300 600 900 -900 -600 -300 0 300 600 900</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>&gt;15% MVC</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>a.</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Traffic Light Task Predictive Control Task</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean reaction time (ms)</head><p>Relative to green onset</p><p>x 10 -3 ms ms ms a n-1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Raw Data</head><p>Model fit <ref type="figure">Figure S6</ref>. Observed and modeled reaction time distributions, partitioned by amber duration of the current and previous trial. From left to right, each column shows the RT distribution (relative to green onset) pooled across participants for the short (700 ms), average (1000 ms) and long (1300 ms) amber duration. The top row shows the raw data (smoothed with a normal kernel function and estimated every 10 ms), and the bottom one shows the fit of the winning model (model 4). The line colour represents the duration of the amber light in the previous trial (a n−1 ). Note that, by design, an extreme amber duration was always followed by an average one. This explains why the a n−1 partitioning is only effective for a current amber duration of 1000 ms. The best account of the influence of a n−1 on the RT distribution implicated an effect on the mean rate-of-rise of the anticipatory process (µ A ; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Fig. S5</ref>). -900 -600 -300 0 300 600 900 -900 -600 -300 0 300 600 900 -900 -600 -300 0 300 600 900</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean reaction time (ms)</head><p>Relative to green onset</p><p>x <ref type="bibr">10 -3</ref> Task Block</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Raw Data</head><p>Model fit <ref type="figure">Figure S7</ref>. Observed and modeled reaction time distributions, partitioned by amber duration and block index. From left to right, each column shows the RT distribution (relative to green onset) pooled across participants for the short (700 ms), average (1000 ms) and long (1300 ms) amber duration. The top row shows the raw data (smoothed with a normal kernel function and estimated every 10 ms), and the bottom one shows the fit of the winning model (model 4). The line colour represents the task block number. The best account of this learning effect implicated an effect of trial index on the probability of the anticipatory process to be active (w; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Fig. S5</ref>). -900 -600 -300 0 300 600 900 -900 -600 -300 0 300 600 900 -900 -600 -300 0 300 600 900</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean reaction time (ms)</head><p>Relative to green onset  <ref type="figure">Figure S8</ref>. Observed and modeled reaction time distributions, partitioned by amber duration and cost-benefit information. From left to right, each column shows the RT distribution (relative to green onset) pooled across participants for the short (700 ms), average (1000 ms) and long (1300 ms) amber duration. The top row shows the raw data (smoothed with a normal kernel function and estimated every 10 ms), and the bottom one shows the fit of the winning model (model 4). The line colour represents the amount of reward available (pink: R 0 = £1; black: R 0 = £0.20). Solid lines represent trials in which the reward decayed quickly after green onset (λ = 0.0125 ms -1 ), and dotted lines represent trials in which it decayed more slowly (λ = 0.0033 ms <ref type="bibr">-1</ref> ). The best account of the effect of the cost-benefit structure implicated an effect of R 0 and λ on the mean rate-of-rise of the anticipatory process (µ A ; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Fig. S5</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>b.</head><p>c. a.  <ref type="figure">Figure S9</ref>. Apathy reduces the protective effect of reward on fatigue accumulation. a. As participants progressed through the task, the vigour of their response decreased (left graph) while the average reward obtained per trial increased (middle graph). Simultaneously, fatigue ratings showed a marked monotonic increase (right graph). For each TLT block, Points and error bars show group mean with boot-strapped 95% confidence intervals. Individual participants are shown as thin lines. b. Parameter estimates of the linear mixed-effect model of fatigue (see also <ref type="table">Table S6</ref> -Model 2). Longer time-on-task and higher force exertion were associated with higher fatigue ratings. By contrast, higher average reward was linked to lower fatigue. The latter was counteracted by apathy. Asterisks indicate significance (p &lt; 0.05). c. Graphical representation of the proposed interpretation of the finding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary tables</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Self-report measures of apathy and impulsivity are positively correlated. a. Pairwise correlation plot of the total scores of the four questionnaires. The strongest positive associations were observed between the two questionnaires assessing the same construct (Apathy: AES vs. AMI; Impulsivity: BIS-11 vs. UPPS-P; both p &lt; 0.0001). In addition, significant cross-construct correlations were observed between the AES and impulsivity measures (BIS-11 &amp; UPPS-P; both p &lt; 0.004). Pearson correlation coefficients are shown in the top left corner of each scatter plot (asterisks indicate significant relationships, p &lt; 0.05). The sample distribution of each questionnaire total score is shown on top. b. PCAs were performed on apathy (AES &amp; AMI total score) and impulsivity (BIS-11 &amp; UPPS-P total scores) measures in order to capture, in a single score, most of the variance of the construct's questionnaires. These two scores were positively correlated (r (58) = 0.33, p = 0.0096).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>instrumental relationship to earnings (β = 0.13, 95%CI = [−0.34, 0.30], t (57) = 1.55, p = 0.13, controlling for percentage of anticipatory responses; contrast anticipatory responses vs. mean force: F (1) = 22.90, p &lt; 0.001). A within-participant trialwise analyse of the determinants of the reward obtained (LMM S2) also demonstrated that although trials in which individuals responded faster led to greater outcomes (β = −0.08, 95%CI = [−0.11, −0.05], t (24685) = −5.52, p &lt; 0.001), the amount of force exerted on the dynamometer was not associated with the reward obtained (β = 0.01, 95%CI = [−0.01, 0.02], t (24685) = 0.27, p − 0.27)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>effect of block index (log-transformed) on mean RT (β = −0.23, 95%CI = [−0.27, −0.19], t (9294) = −12.06, p &lt; 0.001;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Impulsivity is associated with an all-encompassing pre-emptiveness to respond. a. Parameter estimates of the linear mixed-effect model of mean RT (model controlling for Age and Gender; see</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Participants responded faster on average when more reward was available (Main effect of R 0 on mean RT: β = −0.06, 95%CI = [−0.08, −0.04], t (9294) = −6.12, p &lt; 0.001; Table S2 -Model 1; Fig. 3e), and when reward decayed faster after the green onset (Main effect of λ on mean RT: β = −0.04, 95%CI = [−0.05, −0.02], t (9294) = −3.82, p &lt; 0.001;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>constraints (Negative main effect of impulsivity score on mean RT: β = −0.10, 95%CI = [−0.18, −0.01], t (9282) = −2.28, p = 0.023; Table S2 -Model 2; Fig. 3a-b). In addition, their average RT was more influenced by the duration of the amber light of the current trial (Interaction Impulsivity score × a n : β = −0.05, 95%CI = [−0.09, −0.01], t (9282) = −2.46, p = 0.014;Table S2-Model 2;Fig. 3a-b). This suggests that more impulsive individuals were faster not because of shorter sensorimotor delays (see alsoSupplementary Resultsfor an absence of relationship between impulsivity and simple reaction time) but instead because of a greater tendency to anticipate the green onset. None of the other interactions with experimental factors were significant for neither impulsivity nor apathy(Table S2-Model 2;Fig. 3a).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>task progressed, the vigour of the response diminished (Main effect of log-transformed block on mean vigour: β = −0.19, 95%CI = [−0.24, −0.13], t (9293) = −6.24, p &lt; 0.001; Table S4 -Model 1), likely due to a fatigue effect and/or a better estimation of force threshold required to trigger a response. Finally, and crucially, participants were energized to squeeze harder when more reward (£1 vs. £0.20) was available (Main effect of R 0 on mean vigour: β = 0.09, 95%CI = [0.07, 0.11], t (9293) = 8.68, p &lt; 0.001; Table S4 -Model 1), an effect we interpreted as a marker of reward sensitivity. By contrast, the decay rate of reward or the interaction between these two factors had no significant influence on the vigour of the response (Main effect of λ on mean vigour: β = −0.01, 95%CI = [−0.03, 0.01], t (9293) = −0.61, p = 0.54; Interaction R 0 × λ : β = 0.00, 95%CI = [−0.01, 0.01], t (9293) = 0.20, p = 0.84; Table S4 -Model 1). Thus, in summary, the vigour of the response was influenced by: (1) surprising amber foreperiod duration, (2) task-practice, and (3) the magnitude of reward available(Fig. 4).Next, we asked whether apathy or impulsivity interacted with any of these three effects. Adding the questionnaire-derivedscores to the LMM (LMM S7) revealed that the severity of apathy was associated with a weaker energization by reward (Interaction Apathy score × R 0 : β = −0.02, 95%CI = [−0.03, 0.00], t (9287) = −2.01, p = 0.044; Table S4 -Model 2; Fig. 4a). In other words, more apathetic individuals showed less evidence of increased subjective utility when the magnitude of the objective reward available increased. Follow-up parcellation of this result into the individual sub-scales of the AMI questionnaire revealed that it was predominantly driven by emotional apathy (Interaction AMI-emotional × R 0 : β = −0.02, Most impulsive participants (n = 30) Least impulsive participants (n = 30) Most apathetic participants (n = 30) Least apathetic participants (n = 30)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Apathy is associated with blunted valuation of reward. a. Parameter estimates of the linear mixed-effect model of mean Vigour (model controlling for Age and Gender; see</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(AES): 18-item questionnaire scored on a 4-point Likert scale (total scores ranging from 18 to 72), subdivided into 4 sub-scales (emotional apathy, behavioural apathy, cognitive apahty, other); • Apathy Motivation Index 10 (AMI): 18-item questionnaire scored on a 5-point Likert scale (total scores ranging from 0 to 4), sub-divided into 3 sub-scales (emotional apathy, behavioural apathy, social apathy); • Urgency, Premeditation (lack of), Perseverance (lack of), Sensation Seeking, Positive Urgency, Impulsive Behavior Scale 9 (UPPS-P): 59-item questionnaire scored on a 4-point Likert scale (total scores ranging from 59 to 236), sub-divided into the 5 sub-scales (negative urgency, lack of premeditation, lack of perseverance, sensation seeking, positive urgency); • Barratt Impulsiveness Scale 8 (BIS-11): 30-item questionnaire, scored on a 4-point Likert scale (total scores ranging from 30 to 120), sub-divided into 3 sub-scales (attentional impulsiveness, motor impulsiveness, non-planning impulsiveness). Apparatus Behavioural testing took place in a quiet room with only the participant and the experimenter present. All tasks were presented on a 17-inch touchscreen PC using MATLAB version 2018 (MathWorks; https://uk.mathworks.com) and Psychtoolbox 78 (version 3). Force responses were recorded using a dynamometer (SS25LA, BIOPAC Systems) held in the dominant hand.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>: 4.87 min, s.d.: 0.34 min). To limit the cognitive load, the reward decay rate (animal) was held constant for the first and second half of each block, and changed only once, half-way through the block (after 26 trials). It alternated in a "AB-BA" fashion over a two-block period with half of the participants (15 females, 15 males) starting with the quick decay condition (FS-SF-FS-SF-FS-SF-FS-SF), and the other half starting with the slow decay condition (SF-FS-SF-FS-SF-FS-SF-FS). The amount of reward available (£1 or £0.20), by contrast, varied randomly on a trial-by-trial basis. All blocks included the same number of each trial type although in different order. Control tasks for (1) simple RT, (2) anticipatory abilities, and (3) time discrimination are described and analysed in Supplementary Information.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Total earnings ∼ 1 +</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Percentage Anticipation +Vigour + (1 + Percentage Anticipation +Vigour | Gender) (S1) Trial earning ∼ 1 + RT +Vigour + R 0 + λ + a n + (1 + RT +Vigour + R 0 + λ + a n | Block) +(1 + RT +Vigour + R 0 + λ + a n | Participant) (S2) Total earnings ∼ 1 + Apathy Score + Impulsivity Score + Age + (1 + Apathy Score + Impulsivity Score + Age | Gender) (S3) Mean RT ∼ 1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R 0 + λ + R 0 : λ + (1 + a + a n−1 + ln(Block) + R 0 + λ + R 0 : λ | Participant) (S4)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Mean f atigue rating ∼ 1 +</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Baseline f atigue + Time-on-task +Vigour + Reward + (1 + Baseline f atigue + Time-on-task +Vigour + Reward | Participant) (S8) Mean f atigue rating ∼ 1 + Baseline f atigue + Time-on-task +Vigour + Reward + Age + Ap + Time-on-task : Ap +Vigour : Ap + Reward : Ap + Imp + Time-on-task : Imp +Vigour : Imp + Reward : Imp + (1 + Baseline f atigue + Time-on-task +Vigour + Reward + Age + Ap + Time-on-task : Ap +Vigour : Ap + Reward : Ap + Imp + Time-on-task : Imp +Vigour : Imp + Reward : Imp | Gender) + (1 + Time-on-task +Vigour + Reward | Participant) (S9)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>( 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>27% of the data excluded). The variation of average RT over successive blocks was used as a measure of predictive learning. A linear mixed-effect model (LMM) showed that the average RT improved over successive blocks (Main effect of log-transformed Block on block-averaged RT: β = −0.10, 95%CI = [−0.16, −0.03], t (478) = −2.87, p = 0.0042; Table S9 -Model 1; Fig. S3). Note that this constitutes a much less pronounced reduction in RT compared to the one observed in the TLT (β = −0.23, 95%CI = [−0.27, −0.19];</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>interact with predictive learning (Interaction Impulsivity score × log-transformed Block on block-averaged RT: β = 0.02, 95%CI = [−0.06, 0.11], t (472) = 0.55, p = 0.58; Table S9 -Model 2), apathy did (Interaction Apathy score × log-transformed Block on block-averaged RT: β = −0.12, 95%CI = [−0.18, −0.06], t (472) = −3.82, p &lt; 0.001; Table S9 -Model 2). That is, greater Apathy scores were associated with faster reduction of mean RT over successive blocks in the Predictive Control Task. After squeezing the dynamometer, participants indicated when they thought they responded in comparison to when they should have responded. The position of the cursor they placed allowed us to calculate an "estimated RT" in relation to the theoretical green onset. The relationship between the estimated and actual RT gave us an measure of metacognitive abilities, i.e. how well individuals could perceive/report their own performance. On average, there was a good agreement between actual and estimated RT (both RT and estimated RT z-scored withinindividuals; slope: β = 0.49, 95%CI = [0.38, 0.52], t (4545) = 12.41, p &lt; 0.001), indicating accurate metacognition. Adding</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>maximum likelihood procedure with a gradient-based method fminsearch implemented in MATLAB (The MathWorks inc., version 2020a). Model comparison was carried out with Bayesian Information Criterion (BIC), summed across all individual datasets. This model selection method was chosen for its stringent penalisation of model complexity. The introduction of a probabilistic activation of the anticipatory process induced a large explanatory gain compared to the original two-horse model (Reference model 2 vs. Reference model 1: ∆BIC = −1, 117.03; Fig. S5a). Further, compared to simpler, context-insensitive reference models, incorporating a sensitivity to task statistics, practice and cost-benefit structure provided a better account of the data (lower BIC in Models 1-27 relative to Reference models 1-2; Fig. S5a). Overall, the winning model (lowest BIC score; Model 4 vs. Reference Model 1: ∆BIC = −7, 076.87; Model 4 vs. Model 17:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>Fig.</head><label></label><figDesc>S5b provides a visual illustration of the best model's architecture, and Figs. S6 to S8 show model fit of the pooled group</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>was a clear monotonic increase in block-averaged ratings as a function of task progression (Main effect of block on block-averaged fatigue rating: β = 0.28, 95%CI = [0.20, 0.38], t (478) = 6.17, p &lt; 0.001; Fig. S9a). Concurrently, and as reported in the main text, the average vigour of the response gradually diminished (Main effect of log-transformed block on block-averaged vigour: β = −0.19, 95%CI = [−0.25, −0.12], t (478) = −5.61, p &lt; 0.001), while participants learnt to harvest more reward per trial (Main effect of log-transformed block on block-averaged earnings: β = 0.39, 95%CI = [0.32, 0.46], t (478) = 10.72, p &lt; 0.001; Fig. S9a). A LMM was used to investigate the extent to which block-averaged fatigue ratings co-varied with time-on-task, force exerted (block-averaged vigour), and reward obtained (block-averaged), while controlling for baseline (pre-TLT) fatigue (LMM S8). Higher fatigue was associated with longer time-on-task (Main effect of time-on-task on fatigue ratings: β = 0.34, 95%CI = [0.23, 0.45], t (475) = 6.02, p &lt; 0.001; Table S6; Fig. S9) and greater force exertion (Main effect of block vigour on fatigue ratings: β = 0.08, 95%CI = [0.01, 0.15], t (475) = 2.33, p = 0.020; Table S6; Fig. S9). By contrast, fatigue showed a negative association with reward (Main effect of block earnings on fatigue ratings: β = −0.07, 95%CI = [−0.12, −0.02], t (475) = −2.68, p = 0.0076;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. S9cillustrates our proposed interpretation of the findings. Apathy is thought to be manifested as a weakening of the protective effect of reward on fatigue accumulation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head>14 F ( 1 )</head><label>141</label><figDesc>= 21.76, p &lt; 10 -4    </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>Figure S3 .</head><label>S3</label><figDesc>Performance on control tasks. a. Mean reaction time as a function of experimental block on the Traffic Light Task (dotted black line) and the Predictive Control Task (full orange line). Mean reaction time on the Reactive Control task is plotted for reference in green. Error bars represent s.e.m. b. Probability of responding that the test duration lasted longer than the reference duration as a function of test duration. Error bars represent s.e.m. Lines represent individual participants.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Figure S5 .</head><label>S5</label><figDesc>Model comparison and winning model. a. The Bayesian Information Criterion (BIC) summed across all participants is plotted for every model tested.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank all members of the Cognitive Neurology Research Group for their assistance as experimental confederates. This work was supported by the Wellcome Trust (206330/Z/17/Z). P.P., S.Z., D.D. and M.H. were funded by the Wellcome Trust (206330/Z/17/Z). S.G.M. was funded by an MRC Clinician Scientist Fellowship (MR/P00878/X). The funders had no role in study design, data collection and analysis, decision to publish or preparation of the manuscript.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability statement</head><p>Anonymised data and code for replicating the main results in the manuscript have been deposited on the Open Science Framework platform: https://osf.io/6y54r/?view_only=c4d38174393d4568948e6287f498db88.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing interests</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.  <ref type="table">Table S1</ref>. Fixed effects of the analysis of total earnings. Models were specified as follows. Model 1: Earnings ∼ 1 + Anticipation + Vigour + (1 + Anticipation + Vigour | Gender); Model 2: Earnings ∼ 1 + Apathy Score + Impulsivity Score + Age + (1 + Apathy Score + Impulsivity Score + Age | Gender). 46 p = 0.014 a n−1 :Apathy Score β = −0.0175 SE = 0.00989 t 9282 = −1.77 p = 0.08 a n−1 :Impulsivity Score β = +0.0147 SE = 0.0089 t 9282 = +1.65 p = 0.10 Apathy Score β = +0.0308 SE = 0.0921 t 9282 = +0.33 p = 0.74 Apathy Score:R 0 β = +0.0106 SE = 0.0088 t 9282 = +1.20 p = 0.23 Apathy Score:λ β = −0.0147 SE = 0.00888 t 9282 = −1.65 p = 0.10 Apathy Score:log(Block) β = +0.00739 SE = 0.0239 t 9282 = +0.31 p = 0.76 Impulsivity Score β = −0.0987 SE = 0.0433 t 9282 = −2.28 p = 0.023 Impulsivity Score:R 0 β = −0.00285 SE = 0.00888 t 9282 = −0.32 p = 0.75 Impulsivity Score:λ β = +0.00429 SE = 0.00737 t 9282 = +0.58 p = 0.56 Impulsivity Score:log(Block) β = −0.00238 SE = 0.0195 t 9282 = −0.12 p = 0.90  <ref type="table">Table S2</ref>. Fixed effects of the analysis of mean reaction time. Models were specified as follows. Model 1: Mean RT ∼ 1 + a n−1 + a n + log(Block) + λ *R 0 + (1 + a n−1 + a n + log(Block) + λ *R 0 | participant); Model 2: Mean RT ∼ 1 + Age + a n−1 *Apathy Score + a n *Apathy Score + a n−1 *Impulsivity Score + a n *Impulsivity Score + Apathy Score*λ + Impulsivity Score*λ + Apathy Score*R 0 + Impulsivity Score*R 0 + Apathy Score*log(Block) + Impulsivity Score*log(Block) + (1 + Age + a n−1 *Apathy Score + a n *Apathy Score + a n−1 *Impulsivity Score + a n *Impulsivity Score + Apathy Score*λ + Impulsivity Score*λ + Apathy Score*R 0 + Impulsivity Score*R 0 + Apathy Score*log(Block) + Impulsivity Score*log(Block) | Gender) + (1 + a n−1 + a n + λ + R 0 + log(Block) | participant).  <ref type="table">Table S3</ref>. Fixed effects of the analysis of the relationship between questionnaire sub-scales and mean reaction time. Models were specified as follows. Model 1: Mean RT ∼ 1 + a n−1 + log(Block) + Age + a n *Impulsivity Score + λ *R 0 + a n *UPPS-P Persev + a n *UPPS-P Premed + a n *UPPS-P negU + a n *UPPS-P posU + a n *UPPS-P SS + (1 + a n−1 + log(Block) + Age + a n *Impulsivity Score + λ *R 0 + a n *UPPS-P Persev + a n *UPPS-P Premed + a n *UPPS-P negU + a n *UPPS-P posU + a n *UPPS-P SS |  <ref type="table">Table S4</ref>. Fixed effects of the analysis of mean Vigour. Models were specified as follows. Model 1: vigour ∼ 1 + a n−1 + a n + Mean RT + log(Block) + λ *R 0 + (1 + a n−1 + a n + Mean RT + log(Block) + λ *R 0 | participant); Model 2: vigour ∼ 1 + Mean RT + Age + a n *Apathy Score + a n *Impulsivity Score + Apathy Score*R 0 + Impulsivity Score*R 0 + Apathy Score*log(Block) + Impulsivity Score*log(Block) + (1 + Mean RT + Age + a n *Apathy Score + a n *Impulsivity Score + Apathy Score*R 0 + Impulsivity Score*R 0 + Apathy Score*log(Block) + Impulsivity Score*log(Block) | Gender) + (1 + a n + Mean RT + R 0 + log(Block) | participant).  <ref type="table">Table S5</ref>. Fixed effects of the analysis of the relationship between questionnaire sub-scales and mean Vigour. Models were specified as follows. Model 1: vigour ∼ 1 + a n + Mean RT + log(Block) + Age + Impulsivity Score*R 0 + R 0 *AMI beh + R 0 *AMI emo + R 0 *AMI soc + (1 + a n + Mean RT + log(Block) + Age + Impulsivity Score*R 0 + R 0 *AMI beh + R 0 *AMI emo + R 0 *AMI soc | Gender) + (1 + a n + Mean RT + R 0 + log(Block) | participant); Model 2: vigour ∼ 1 + a n + Mean RT + log(Block) + Age + Impulsivity Score*R 0 + R 0 *AES beh + R 0 *AES emo + R 0 *AES cog + R 0 *AES other + (1 + a n + Mean RT + log(Block) + Age + Impulsivity Score*R 0 + R 0 *AES beh + R 0 *AES emo + R 0 *AES cog + R 0 *AES other | Gender) + (1 + a n + Mean RT + R 0 + log(Block) | participant).  <ref type="table">Table S6</ref>. Fixed effects of the analysis of fatigue ratings. Models were specified as follows. Model 1: fatigue ∼ 1 + Block Reward + Block Vigour + Baseline Fatigue + Time-on-task + (1 + Block Reward + Block Vigour + Time-on-task | participant); Model 2: fatigue ∼ 1 + age + Baseline Fatigue + Block Reward*Apathy Score + Block Vigour*Apathy Score + Block Reward*Impulsivity Score + Block Vigour*Impulsivity Score + Apathy Score*Time-on-task + Impulsivity Score*Time-on-task + (1 + age + Baseline Fatigue + Block Reward*Apathy Score + Block Vigour*Apathy Score + Block Reward*Impulsivity Score + Block Vigour*Impulsivity Score + Apathy Score*Time-on-task + Impulsivity Score*Time-on-task | female) + (1 + Block Reward + Block Vigour + Time-on-task | participant).   <ref type="table">Table S8</ref>. Fixed effects of the analysis of mean reaction time on the Reactive Control Task. The model was specified as follows: RT ∼ 1 + Age + Apathy Score + Impulsivity Score + (1 + Age + Apathy Score + Impulsivity Score | Gender).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Information</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy and the Functional Anatomy of the Prefrontal Cortex-Basal Ganglia Circuits</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Dubois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/cercor/bhj043</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cereb. Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="916" to="928" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The five factor model and impulsivity: using a structural model of personality to understand impulsivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Whiteside</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lynam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0191-8869(00)00064-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0191-8869(00" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pers. Individ. Differ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fractionating impulsivity: neuropsychiatric implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Dalley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Robbins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/nrn.2017.8</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="158" to="171" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuroscience of apathy and anhedonia: A transdiagnostic approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/s41583-018-0029-9</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="484" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neuroimaging basis of apathy: Empirical findings and conceptual challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Starkstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brockman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2018.01.042</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2018.01.042" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The contribution of neuropsychological and neuroimaging research to the definition of the neurocognitive correlates of apathy</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="48" to="53" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relationship between apathy and impulsivity in large population samples</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Petitet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/s41598-021-84364-w</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reliability and validity of the Apathy Evaluation Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Marin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Biedrzycki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Firinciogullari</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factor structure of Barratt impulsiveness scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Patton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stanford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Barratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Clin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="768" to="774" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The UPPS-P: Assessing five personality pathways to impulsive behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lynam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Whiteside</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cyders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<publisher>Purdue Univ</publisher>
			<pubPlace>West Lafayette, IN</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinct subtypes of apathy revealed by the apathy motivation index</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Lockwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Apps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Muhammed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1371/journal.pone.0169938</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impulsivity and apathy in Parkinson&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sinha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Manohar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1111/jnp.12013</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Neuropsychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="283" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy and executive functioning among non-demented community-dwelling elderly individuals in an everyday environment: the mediating effect of impulsivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cuvillier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bayard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/psyg.12725</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/psyg.12725" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychogeriatrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="636" to="649" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neuroanatomical and neurochemical basis of apathy and impulsivity in frontotemporal lobar degeneration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Passamonti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lansdall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1016/j.cobeha.2017.12.015</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Behav. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Co-occurrence of apathy and impulse control disorders in parkinson disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1212/WNL.0000000000010965</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2769" to="2780" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Co-occurrence of apathy and impulsivity in progressive supranuclear palsy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Kok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Murley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Rittman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Passamonti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1101/2021.02.26.21252350</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy and impulsiveness in parkinson disease: Two faces of the same coin?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Palmeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1097/MD.0000000000029766</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuropsychiatric effects of subthalamic neurostimulation in parkinson disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Volkmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Daniels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Witt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/nrneurol.2010.111</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Neurol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="487" to="498" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine agonists and risk: impulse control disorders in Parkinson&apos;s; disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Voon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/awr080</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1438" to="1446" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine overdose hypothesis: Evidence and clinical implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Vaillancourt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schonfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kwak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Bohnen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Seidler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1002/mds.25687</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mov. Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1920" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy and impulse control disorders: Yin &amp; yang of dopamine dependent behaviors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sierra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.3233/JPD-150535</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Park. Dis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="636" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">From apathy to addiction: Insights from neurology and psychiatry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kirschner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rabinowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dagher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Prog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2020.109926</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnpbp.2020.109926" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuro-Psychopharmacology Biol. Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">109926</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-motor dopamine withdrawal syndrome after surgery for Parkinson&apos;s disease: Predictors and underlying mesolimbic denervation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Thobois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/awq032</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1111" to="1127" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine Agonist Withdrawal Syndrome in Parkinson Disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rabinak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Nirenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1001/archneurol.2009.294</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Arch. Neurol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impulse Control Disorders in Parkinson Disease: A Cross-Sectional Study of 3090 Patients</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Weintraub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1001/archneurol.2010.65</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Arch. Neurol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="589" to="595" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An exploration of apathy and impulsivity in Parkinson disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ahearn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Barraclough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Leroi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1155/2012/390701</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Gerontol. Geriatr. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clinical features of dopamine agonist withdrawal syndrome in a movement disorders clinic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pondal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1136/jnnp-2012-302684</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relationship between self-reported apathy and executive dysfunction in nondemented patients with parkinson disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zgaljardic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Behav. Neurol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impulse control disorders in parkinson disease and rbd</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Baig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1212/WNL.0000000000007942</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="675" to="687" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine and reward hypersensitivity in Parkinson&apos;s disease with impulse control disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Drew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/awaa198</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">143</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2502" to="2518" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy and impulsivity in frontotemporal lobar degeneration syndromes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lansdall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/awx101</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">140</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1792" to="1807" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy and disinhibition related to neuropathology in amnestic versus behavioral dementias</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Borges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Rademaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bigio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-M</forename><surname>Mesulam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Weintraub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1177/1533317519853466</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. J. Alzheimer&apos;s Dis. &amp; Other Dementias</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="343" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not always hyperactive?: Elevated apathy scores in adolescents and adults with adhd</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Torrente</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1177/1087054709359887</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Atten. Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="556" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontal systems behavior scale in schizophrenia: relationships with psychiatric symptomatology, cognition and adaptive function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Velligan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ritch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dicocco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Huntzinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0165-1781(02)00264-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0165-1781(02)00264-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual Differences in Premotor Brain Systems Underlie Behavioral Apathy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Bonnelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Manohar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/cercor/bhv247</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cereb. Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="807" to="819" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine modulates option generation for behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y.-S</forename><surname>Ang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cub.2018.03.069</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2018.03.069" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1561" to="1569" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of a behavioral measure of risk taking: the balloon analogue risk task (bart)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lejuez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/1076-898X.8.2.75</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/1076-898X.8.2.75" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Psychol. Appl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Drug abuse as a problem of impaired control: Current approaches and findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1177/1534582303257007</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Cogn. Neurosci. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="197" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impulsivity and rapid decision-making for reward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Burnett Heyes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00153</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rapid decision-making under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Adam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bays</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1080/17588928.2011.613988</idno>
		<idno>DOI: 10.1080/ 17588928.2011</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">613988</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine reverses reward insensitivity in apathy following globus pallidus lesions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Adam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cortex.2012.04.013</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2012.04.013" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1303" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Foreperiod and simple reaction time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Niemi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Näätänen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">133</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinct effects of apathy and dopamine on effort-based decision-making in parkinson&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Le Heron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">141</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1455" to="1469" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dysfunctional effort-based decision-making underlies apathy in genetic cerebral small vessel disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Le Heron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">141</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3193" to="3210" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy in small vessel cerebrovascular disease is associated with deficits in effort-based decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Saleh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/awab013</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">144</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1247" to="1262" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heightened effort discounting is a common feature of both apathy and fatigue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jurgelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/s41598-021-01287-2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">22283</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The association of apathy with central fatigue perception in patients with parkinson&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sáez-Francas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hernández-Vara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Corominas Roso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Alegre Martín</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Casas Brugué</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0031531</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0031531" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy in untreated early-stage parkinson disease: Relationship with other non-motor symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Dujardin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/mds.26058</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.26058" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mov. Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1796" to="1801" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The association between fatigue and apathy in patients with either parkinson&apos;s disease or multiple sclerosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cochrane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2015.07.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.parkreldis.2015.07.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Park. &amp; Relat. Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1093" to="1095" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivational fatigue: A neurocognitive framework for the impact of effortful exertion on subsequent motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Apps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2018.04.030</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2018.04.030" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Cognitive Effort</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Movement vigor as a reflection of subjective economic utility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shadmehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Reppert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Summerside</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Yoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tins.2019.02.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2019.02.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="336" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Dalley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Everitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Robbins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Impulsivity</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.01.020</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.01.020" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">compulsivity, and top-down cognitive control</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="680" to="694" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rapid-response impulsivity: definitions, measurement issues, and clinical implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pers. Disord. Theory, Res. Treat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">168</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impulsivity and speed-accuracy tradeoffs in information processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. personality social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">274</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical decision theory and the selection of rapid, goal-directed movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1364/JOSAA.20.001419</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Opt. Soc. Am. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1419" to="1433" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining a Role for Ventromedial Prefrontal Cortex in Encoding Action-Based Value Signals During Reward-Related Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gläscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Hampton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/cercor/bhn098</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cereb. Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="483" to="495" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Go and no-go learning in reward and punishment: Interactions between affect and effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Guitart-Masip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2012.04.024</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2012.04.024" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="166" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of visual error and reward feedback in learning to aim to an optimal movement endpoint</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Leblanc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Neyedli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Psychol. Hum. Percept. Perform</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1001</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The expected value of control: An integrative theory of anterior cingulate cortex function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="240" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward Pays the Cost of Noise Reduction in Motor and Cognitive Control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Manohar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1016/j.cub.2015.05.038</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1707" to="1716" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cognitive Control as Cost-Benefit Decision Making, chap</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kool</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="189" />
			<pubPlace>Ltd</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relationship between self-report and lab task conceptualizations of impulsivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cyders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Coskunpinar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Res. Pers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Positive urgency is related to difficulty inhibiting prepotent responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tharp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Peckham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Sanchez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">750</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apathy and disinhibition in frontotemporal dementia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zamboni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Huey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Krueger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Nichelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Grafman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1212/01.wnl.0000324920.96835.95</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="736" to="742" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuroanatomy of apathy and disinhibition in frontotemporal lobar degeneration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Massimo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1159/000194658</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dementia Geriatr. Cogn. Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="104" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Selective serotonin reuptake inhibition modulates response inhibition in Parkinson&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/awu032</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1145" to="1155" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving response inhibition systems in frontotemporal dementia with citalopram</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Rittman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Regenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Robbins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/awv133</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving response inhibition in parkinson&apos;s disease with atomoxetine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1016/j.biopsych.2014.01.024</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biol. Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="740" to="748" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Atomoxetine restores the response inhibition network in Parkinson&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/aww138</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2235" to="2248" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissecting components of reward: &apos;liking&apos;, &apos;wanting&apos;, and learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Berridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Aldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.coph.2008.12.014</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coph.2008.12.014" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Pharmacol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Neurosciences</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Poor reward sensitivity and apathy after stroke</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Rochat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1212/01.wnl.0000435290.49598.1d</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1674" to="1680" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Characterization of reward and effort mechanisms in apathy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Bonnelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1016/j.jphysparis.2014.04.002</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Physiol. Paris</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reduced pupillary reward sensitivity in parkinson&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Manohar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/npjparkd.2015.26</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>npj Park. Dis. 1, 15026</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward sensitivity deficits modulated by dopamine are associated with apathy in Parkinson&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Muhammed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/brain/aww188</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2706" to="2721" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward sensitivity and action in Parkinson&apos;s disease patients with and without apathy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Muhammed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ben Yehuda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Drew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Manohar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/braincomms/fcab022</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of impulsivity in the development of substance use and eating disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dawe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Loxton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2004.03.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2004.03.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Festschrift in Honour of Jeffrey Gray -Issue</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>Anxiety and Neuroticism</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Neurosci. &amp; Biobehav. Rev.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gray&apos;s impulsivity dimension: A distinction between reward sensitivity versus rash impulsiveness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Franken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Muris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.paid.2005.11.016</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.paid.2005.11.016" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pers. Individ. Differ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1337" to="1347" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating the relationship between reward sensitivity, impulsivity, and food addiction: A systematic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Maxwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gardiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Loxton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/erv.2732</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/erv.2732" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Eat. Disord. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="368" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What&apos;s new in psychtoolbox-3?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kleiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Brainard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sensory and association cortex in time perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bueti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1162/jocn.2008.20060</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Cogn. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1054" to="1062" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of urgency on decision time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Reddi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/77739</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="827" to="830" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of cognitive fatigue: Cortico-striatal circuitry and effort-reward imbalance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dobryakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Deluca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Genova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wylie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1017/S1355617713000684</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Int. Neuropsychol. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="849" to="853" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heightened effort discounting is a common feature of both apathy and fatigue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jurgelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/s41598-021-01287-2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">22283</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causal role of lateral prefrontal cortex in mental effort and fatigue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Soutschek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tobler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/hbm.25146</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.25146" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Hum. Brain Mapp</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4630" to="4640" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural mechanisms underlying the effects of physical fatigue on effort-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Hogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Teh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Chib</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/s41467-020-17855-5</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural and computational mechanisms of momentary fatigue and persistence in effort-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Klein-Flügge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Manohar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Apps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/s41467-021-24927-7</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fronto-striatal network activation leads to less fatigue in multiple sclerosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dobryakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1177/1352458517717087</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Multiple Scler. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1174" to="1182" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward presentation reduces on-task fatigue in traumatic brain injury</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dobryakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cortex.2020.01.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2020.01.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">126</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Voluntary or involuntary? control over overtime and rewards for overtime in relation to fatigue and work satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Beckers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1080/02678370801984927</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Work. &amp; Stress</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why does work cause fatigue? A real-time investigation of fatigue, and determinants of fatigue in nurses working 12-hour shifts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/abm/kay065</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals Behav. Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="562" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
