<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Full title: The effects of base rate neglect on sequential belief updating and real-world beliefs Short title: How and why base rate neglect biases beliefs over time</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brandon</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ashinoff</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychiatry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">New York State Psychiatric Institute (NYSPI</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Buck</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychiatry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">New York State Psychiatric Institute (NYSPI</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guillermo</forename><surname>Horga</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychiatry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">New York State Psychiatric Institute (NYSPI</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Full title: The effects of base rate neglect on sequential belief updating and real-world beliefs Short title: How and why base rate neglect biases beliefs over time</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Base-rate neglect is a pervasive bias in judgment that is conceptualized as underweighting of prior information and can have serious consequences in real-world scenarios. This bias is thought to reflect variability in inferential processes but empirical support for a cohesive theory of baserate neglect with sufficient explanatory power to account for longer-term and real-world beliefs is lacking. A Bayesian formalization of base-rate neglect in the context of sequential belief updating predicts that belief trajectories should exhibit dynamic patterns of dependence on the order in which evidence is presented and its consistency with prior beliefs. To test this, we developed a novel &apos;urn-and-beads&apos; task that systematically manipulated the order of colored bead sequences and elicited beliefs via an incentive-compatible procedure. Our results in two independent online studies confirmed the predictions of the sequential base-rate neglect model: people exhibited beliefs that are more influenced by recent evidence and by evidence inconsistent with prior beliefs. We further found support for a noisy-sampling inference model whereby base-rate neglect results from rational discounting of noisy internal representations of prior beliefs. Finally, we found that model-derived indices of base-rate neglect-including noisier prior representationcorrelated with propensity for unusual beliefs outside the laboratory. Our work supports the relevance of Bayesian accounts of sequential base-rate neglect to real-world beliefs and hints at strategies to minimize deleterious consequences of this pervasive bias.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Accurate judgments in the face of equivocal-even nearly unequivocal-evidence depend critically upon incorporating prior knowledge about the probability of different scenarios, often referred to as their base rate. Consider a doctor deciding whether a patient has a rare disease <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">72</ref> (i.e., one with a very low base rate). She orders a diagnostic test that is 99% accurate, and it 73 comes back positive. Intuitively, you may reason it is likely that the patient has the disease. <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">74</ref> However, in this case a positive test result is actually associated with a very low probability of 75 the disease. In this scenario, neglecting to account for the base rate may lead to a misdiagnosis <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">76</ref> and serious negative outcomes. This example illustrates the pervasive bias known as base-rate 77 neglect <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> and its potential real-world consequences. Far from merely being a hypothetical example, studies have shown that diagnosticians tend to discount known disease rates <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> and relevant medical history <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref> . Research into base-rate neglect in other areas further highlights its broad societal relevance: for example, base-rate neglect leads to an overestimation of success 81 in environmentally relevant pursuits <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10</ref> , inaccurate judgments about job candidates <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11</ref> , and errors in legal decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref> . However, despite its importance, the mechanisms governing baserate neglect and its longer-term effects on human belief updating are poorly understood.</p><p>Starting with foundational work on base-rate neglect <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> , previous theoretical <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref> work has formalized base-rate neglect in a Bayesian framework as an underweighting of prior beliefs, or beliefs summarizing previously observed information into the a priori probability of a state or event without additional information-mathematically equivalent to its base rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> . This Bayesian framework extends to belief updating in sequential contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> that encompass and go beyond classically studied 'one-shot' scenarios, and which arguably have more ecological validity <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18</ref> . Crucially, in the context of sequential belief updating, under a Bayesian model where underweighted prior beliefs are iteratively updated upon observation of new evidence samples, theoretical work indicates that base-rate neglect should impact belief-updating dynamics in a lawful manner, simultaneously producing two main effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> . First, base-rate neglect in this context, henceforth referred to as 'sequential base-rate neglect', should result in more reliance on newer information to form beliefs-a recency bias. Second, it should result in a specific form of prior-dependent belief updating-with smaller updates to prior-consistent evidence-that imposes a lower boundary on belief certainty over the long run. These two model predictions imply that the beliefs of a sequential base-rate neglecter, unlike those of an unbiased observer, <ref type="bibr" target="#b99">99</ref> should critically depend on the order in which evidence is presented and reach different levels of 100 certainty even when presented with the same amount of evidence. Importantly, these theoretical 101</p><p>predictions have not been jointly or systematically tested in empirical studies. 102</p><p>Previous empirical work is broadly consistent with the notion that base-rate neglect <ref type="bibr" target="#b104">103</ref> coexists with a recency bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31]</ref> . However, whether the degree of base-rate neglect that individuals exhibit is commensurate with both the recency bias and the prior-dependent belief updating in a way that aligns with the abovementioned theoretical predictions remains unknown. Testing these predictions would ideally require a sequential belief-updating paradigm that incentivizes true beliefs, has sufficient evidence samples, is conducive to quantitative analysis, and systematically manipulates evidence order. In contrast, previous work on base-rate neglect 109 has often used single <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32</ref> or short series of evidence samples <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref> , non-incentivized paradigms <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref> , or qualitative designs <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23</ref> . These concerns raise the possibility of various confounds <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36</ref> and further limit the ability of previous paradigms to characterize critical belief-112 updating dynamics predicted under sequential base-rate neglect. 113</p><p>To address this gap in the literature, we developed and validated a novel probabilityestimation task ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1)</ref> adopting an "urn-and-beads" design <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref> , which we combined with computational modeling to test the predictions of the abovementioned weighted Bayesian framework of sequential base-rate neglect ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>). Critically, our task systematically and selectively manipulated the evidence order of relatively long (8-sample) sequences and used an incentive-compatible belief-elicitation procedure <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[37]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref> .</p><p>Another outstanding issue in this literature relates to the underlying explanation for baserate neglect and its (sub)optimality. While base-rate neglect can lead to adverse outcomes in one-shot scenarios <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref> , whether it can generally be considered suboptimal depends upon the theoretical framing. Early views framed base-rate neglect as a consequence of qualitative differences in the assessed representativeness <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">40</ref> or relevance <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> of prior information relative to new evidence samples that are more immediately significant and thus disproportionately influential. An implication of these and related views <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[44]</ref> is that base-rage neglect results from a suboptimal heuristic strategy. In contrast, recent explanatory (functional or mechanistic) theories of belief updating <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46</ref> suggest that sequential base-rate neglect may represent an optimal response to perceived volatility in the environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46</ref> or to internal capacity limitations in the precision of information processing <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> . We thus evaluated these alternative accounts in order to advance a functional explanatory model of base-rate neglect <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41</ref> .</p><p>Our results in two independent online studies confirm the joint predictions of the weighted Bayesian model on the dynamic hallmarks of sequential base-rate neglect. We additionally show that interindividual variability in sequential base-rate neglect measures derived from task behavior correlates with a tendency to hold odd beliefs outside the laboratory, further supporting the real-world relevance of sequential base-rate neglect. Finally, we provide initial support for a capacity-limited noisy-sampling model of sequential base-rate neglect that predicts the interindividual relationships with response variability observed in the data, supporting a framing of base-rate neglect as a rational response to imprecise prior representation. boxes, a 'green box' mostly filled with green beads and a 'blue box' mostly filled with blue beads. The ratio of blue to green beads (bead ratio) is shown. Participants are instructed that one of these two boxes, referred to as the "hidden box", is selected at random, and that their task is to estimate which box is the hidden box based on beads drawn from it. Next, they are shown an obscured representation of the hidden box, but no bead is drawn. Participants then make a first probability estimate using a slider to indicate their perceived probability that the hidden box is either the blue or green box. White circles on top of the screen are used as placeholders to illustrate the remaining samples that will be drawn during the trial. After this first estimate, participants see the hidden box again but this time a bead rises out of the box. Participants are then asked to report a second probability estimate after seeing the first bead. The drawn bead replaces the leftmost available placeholder, starting a sequential visual record of beads drawn during a trial. This process of drawing and estimating repeats until participants have observed 8 samples and reported 9 estimates per trial. At the end of the trial, participants make a binary choice of the box they believe is the hidden box. After this choice, a new trial begins. (b) Task variable space showing bead-ratio conditions on the y-axis (each shown in a different shade of blue) and an evidence-order metric (evidence asymmetry) on the x-axis, with negative values indicating front-loading of majority beads (more majority beads, beads consistent with the identity of the hidden box, in the first half of the 8-bead sequence) and positive values indicating back-loading (more majority beads in the second half). The absolute value of the x axis corresponds to more extreme front-or back-loading (the most extreme being a sequence where 5 majority beads are all in the front or all in the back, respectively, and the least extreme being sequences where beads are evenly distributed around the middle). Larger circles reflect sequences with more majority beads. Sequences are organized in mirror-opposite pairs, with two example pairs shown on the right. Note that the examples illustrate majority beads as black and minority beads as white (albeit in the task majority beads were green or blue consistent with the identity of the hidden box in a given trial). Trials were selected to span the full range of the evidence asymmetry space while avoiding confounds with the bead-ratio condition ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b</ref>  our prior work with a similar beads task <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> . (a) Simulated sequential probability estimates for two mirror-opposite sequences for a base-rate neglecting agent (blue) and the ideal Bayesian observer (grey). Majority beads are shown as black and minority beads as white for illustrative purposes. Belief trajectories for front-loaded sequences show a gradient from dark to light and those for the back-loaded sequences transition from light to dark (b) Simulation of the recency bias, defined as the difference between the final probability estimate after 8 beads between mirror-opposite pairs, as a function of the absolute evidence asymmetry of the pairs. As in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, larger circles reflect sequences with more majority beads. The fit line shows the fixed effect of absolute evidence asymmetry on the final estimate difference. The simulated base-rate neglecter shows higher estimates for back-loaded sequences (compared to their front-loaded mirror opposites), particularly for sequence pairs with more evidence asymmetry. This effect varies with evidence strength and is strongest in the 90:10 condition ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1a</ref>). See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1e</ref> for a simulation of an agent that overweights the prior. The lower-case delta shows the example from (a). (c) Simulation of the magnitude of logitbelief updates as a function of the prior with respect to the color of the current evidence. For illustrative purposes, the x-axis has been discretized into bins equivalent to 0.1 increments of prior beliefs in probability space. The y-axis represents the mean magnitude of the logit belief updates (the difference in the log-odds of the prior and the posterior belief). The Bayesian ideal observer has constant logit belief-updates. In contrast, the simulated base-rate neglecter shows logit-belief updates that depend upon the prior belief, with relatively larger updates for prior-inconsistent evidence (left of the vertical dashed line) and smaller for prior-consistent evidence (right) (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1b</ref> for a condition-wise simulation). The fit line reflects the fixed effect of logit-prior on the logit-belief update, which we refer to as prior-dependent belief updating. The model predicts main effects of logit-prior and bead-ratio condition, but no interaction ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1b</ref>). See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1d</ref> for a simulation illustrating the distinct scaling effects of 2 and S1f for a simulation of an agent that overweights the prior. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>In each trial of the probability-estimates beads task <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1a</ref> and Methods), participants had to estimate the probability of and eventually determine the identity of a "hidden" box, either a 'blue box' mostly filled with blue beads or a 'green box' mostly filled with green beads-with the bead ratios of blue to green beads being reciprocal and explicitly shown. The hidden box was randomly selected on each trial and remained the same for the duration of the trial. Participants were shown beads drawn from the hidden box one at a time. After each bead sample, and once before seeing any samples, participants had to report an estimate of the probability that the hidden box was the blue or the green box using a slider. At the end of a trial, after seeing 8 bead samples and reporting 9 estimates, participants made a binary choice about the hidden box. Critically, the task included various novel manipulations at the trial level to allow testing the predictions of the weighted Bayesian model of sequential base-rate neglect ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>): we systematically manipulated evidence strength (majority-to-minority ratio of bead colors in the hidden box, or 'bead ratios') and crucially the evidence order and symmetry of the 8-bead sequences, which we arranged as mirror-opposite sequence pairs presented in pseudorandom order <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1b</ref>).</p><p>In the context of this task, sequential base-rate neglect is mathematically equivalent to underweighting of prior beliefs in a recursive weighted Bayesian model <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> (Methods) of the form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">( ) = 1 • ( ) + 2 • ( ℎ )</formula><p>, where d is a given draw of an evidence (bead) sample, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">( ) = ( ) −1 .</formula><p>In short, this model forms a posterior belief about the hidden box after a new sample is drawn (at d) by integrating a weighted prior probability of the hidden box (the belief before observing the new sample) and a weighted likelihood determined by the color of the new bead sample at draw d and the bead ratio for the trial. While the likelihood weight 2 multiplicatively equally scales all evidence samples for a given bead ratio, the prior weight prior weight 1 affects the evidence samples differentially as a function of the draw number d. In particular, prior underweighting ( 1 &lt; 1) or sequential base-rate neglect, implies exponential discounting of older evidence samples as a function of number of draws into the past (i.e., the older the information, the more it is neglected or discounted). Theoretical predictions under this model suggest that sequential base-rate neglect should manifest as two main dynamic effects commensurate with the degree of baserate neglect <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> : a recency bias ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2b</ref>) and prior dependence in belief updating ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure   2c</ref>).</p><p>Using this paradigm, we conducted two online studies which produced high-quality data consistent with in-person studies based on extensive quality checks (see Online Data Quality in Methods).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>After exclusions (Methods), data for 151 participants were analyzed for Study 1.</p><p>Manipulation check. We first checked whether the draw-by-draw probability estimates for the hidden box reported by participants indicated that they generally engaged in the task as we expected. Indeed, averaging across all sequences and participants, probability estimates showed a gradual increase towards higher probabilities for the true hidden box as the number of observed beads increased, and the rate of this increase was higher for bead-ratio conditions denoting stronger evidence ( <ref type="bibr">[90:10]</ref>  <ref type="bibr">-60</ref> , linear mixed-effects model; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3a</ref> and <ref type="table">Table S4</ref>), suggesting that participants' beliefs tracked the cumulative evidence strength of observed samples over a trial. This effect was also obvious in most individual participants and in an analysis restricted to a subset of 16 identical sequences (see Methods) across 60:40 and 90:10 bead-ratio conditions ([90:10] &gt; <ref type="bibr">[60:40]</ref>; interaction of bead draw [0-8] by bead-ratio condition: t 182.96 =11.81, p=2.79x10 <ref type="bibr">-24</ref> , linear mixed-effects model; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3a</ref> inset and <ref type="table">Table S5</ref>). The first estimates before seeing any bead were generally unbiased ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref>) and no systematic between-trial effects were apparent.</p><p>Behavioral signatures of sequential base-rate neglect. As mentioned above, the weighted Bayesian model predicts that base-rate neglecters ( 1 &lt; 1) should have a recency bias. In the sequential context relevant here, the recency bias should manifest at the end of a sequence as higher final probability estimates for the true hidden box when more majority beads (beads whose color is consistent with the true identity of the hidden box) are presented towards the end versus the beginning of the sequence ("back-loaded" versus "front-loaded" sequences, respectively). This would directly show that more recent samples, closer to the end of the sequence, have a stronger influence on the final estimate relative to older samples closer to the beginning <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2a</ref>). Furthermore, model simulations showed that this effect should be more apparent when comparing pairs of sequences with more extreme front-loading and back-loading ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2b</ref>), which we quantified based on a linear weighted sum of majority beads in the sequence based on their order (1 st to 8 th position) and which we refer to as 'evidence asymmetry' (with respect to the middle of the sequence). In contrast to a base-rate neglecter (prior weight 1 &lt; 1), the Bayesian ideal observer exhibits path-or evidence-orderindependence in its final beliefs, as do observers with different likelihood weighting ( 2 ≠ 1; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>).</p><p>Our task design included a systematic sequence-level manipulation of evidence order and asymmetry ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b</ref>) to allow for a direct demonstration of recency bias. Per the above explanation, a simple test for this bias consisted of comparing the final probability estimate between mirror-opposite sequence pairs that had the same number of majority beads and bead ratio but in which majority beads were either front-loaded or back-loaded <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2a)</ref>. Critically, the data showed evidence-order-dependence in the form of a recency bias consistent with sequential base-rate neglect: pair-wise differences in final probability estimates were higher for back-loaded versus front-loaded sequences (mean final estimate difference &gt; 0, p=1.66x10 <ref type="bibr">-8</ref> ; sign-rank test) and this positive difference increased with evidence asymmetry (evidence asymmetry slope &gt; 0, p=2.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3b</ref> and <ref type="table">Table S6</ref>). All three findings conformed with the predictions of the sequential base-rate-neglect model.</p><p>A further prediction of the weighted Bayesian model is that sequential base-rate neglect induces a form of prior-dependent belief updating whereby, as the prior increases in favor of one option, the magnitude of logit belief updates to prior-consistent evidence decreases, and it increases to prior-inconsistent evidence <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2c</ref>). This impedes reaching full certainty in beliefs over the long run, resulting in more "moderate" beliefs <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17</ref> . In contrast, the ideal observer would predict belief updates of constant magnitude in logit space. In line with sequential baserate neglect and our model predictions, we observed that mean logit belief updates in response to prior-consistent evidence tended to decrease as prior certainty increased (logit-prior main effect: t 150.30 = -2.643, p = 0.009; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3c</ref>), an effect which was independent of the bead-ratio condition (logit-prior x bead-ratio interaction: t 143.13 = 0.903, p = 0.368; linear mixed-effects model; <ref type="table">Table S7</ref>). Thus, these model-agnostic results show evidence-order dependence and priordependent updating that are generally consistent with the predictions of sequential base-rate neglect under the weighted Bayesian model <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17</ref> and satisfactorily captured by this model based on posterior predictive checks (shaded regions in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3a</ref>-c).</p><p>Relationship between model-agnostic and model-based measures of sequential base-rate neglect. We carried out a group-level model comparison of variants of Bayesian-inference models, including the (unweighted) Bayesian ideal-observer model, as previously (see Methods). As in this previous work, the winning model ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3d</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S8</ref>) was the weighted Bayesian model with a prior-weight parameter ( 1 ) and one likelihood-weight parameter per condition ( ( ) , where ( ) is one of the three bead-ratio conditions). Examining the fitted priorweight 1 parameter values across participants revealed substantial interindividual variability and a general tendency for underweighting of prior beliefs ( 1 &lt; 1: p=2.27x10 <ref type="bibr">-4</ref> , sign-rank test), consistent with sequential base-rate neglect. Critically, and consistent with the model predictions <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2d</ref> and 2e), participants exhibiting lower 1 values tended to exhibit stronger recency biases and stronger modulation with increasing evidence asymmetry in their final probability estimates (mean final estimate difference: ρ = −0.60, p &lt; 2.22 x 10 −308 ; evidence asymmetry slope: ρ = −0.64, p &lt; 2.22 x 10 −308 ; Spearman correlation; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3e</ref> and 3f). The evidence asymmetry slope and the mean final estimate difference also correlated strongly with each other (ρ = 0.63, p &lt; 2.22 x 10 −308 ). Note that the model-predicted relationship between the prior weight 1 and these model-agnostic measures of recency bias <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2d</ref> and 2e) is nonmonotonic for very low values of 1 but monotonic for the range of 1 values roughly over 0.75, where the majority of our data are (92.72%); results held when analyses were restricted to this monotonic range (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3 caption</ref>). Furthermore, prior-dependent updating-the slope of the logit belief update in the direction of the evidence as a function of the logit prior-across all bead-ratio conditions positively correlated with 1 (ρ = 0.71, p &lt; 2.22 x 10 −308 ), and negatively correlated with the evidence-asymmetry effect (ρ = −0.50, p = 1.32 x 10 −10 ) and the mean final estimate difference (ρ = −0.49, p = 2.57 x 10 −10 ). These model-predicted relationships all held when controlling for the three 2 ( ) parameters, and the model root-mean-squared error (RMSE <ref type="table">;   Table S9</ref>) and were robust to exclusion of potential outliers (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>caption).</head><p>This indicates consistency across model-based and model-agnostic analyses and highlights the specificity of the relationship between 1 and the predicted behavioral signatures of sequential base-rate neglect. Furthermore, measures of general cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">47</ref> and psychopathology <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">48</ref> did not show a specific relationship with 1 , suggesting that variability in 1 is unlikely to reflect domain-general factors (despite sufficient variability in both; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S3</ref> and Tables S10-13).</p><p>Relationship between laboratory indices of sequential base-rate neglect and odd realworld beliefs. Individuals with more extreme sequential base-rate neglect may tend to hold peculiar beliefs due to excessive susceptibility to new evidence (i.e., recency bias) combined with an inability to resolve belief uncertainty 2 (per prior-dependent belief updating). To examine the relevance of interindividual variability in the task-based measures of sequential base-rate neglect to real-world beliefs, we collected a self-report questionnaire that measures proclivity to various odd or unusual beliefs (Peters Delusions Inventory [PDI] 49 ; Methods). We did not observe significant relationships between the relevant measures of sequential base-rate neglect and PDI scores <ref type="table">(Table S9</ref>). However, very few participants had high PDI scores based on previously published cutoffs <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">50,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">51</ref> (only 1-15 participants or ~1-10% of the sample), thus limiting our power to detect relationships with PDI. To address this, we conducted a second study that used pre-screening to ensure an adequate range of PDI scores. visual clarity, the confidence intervals for the raw data overlap substantially with the model fits. For visualization only, we excluded extreme outlier or noisy data points (logit belief updates &gt; 2, individual median values based on less than 3 data points for a given bin, group median values based on less than 25% of individuals) for a total exclusion of 6.96% of the data. Consistent with model predictions <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2c</ref>), the data shows prior-dependent belief-updating with less updating for prior-consistent evidence (right of the vertical dashed line; i.e. an overall negative slope). Note that at the group level this effect appears to be non-monotonic (with slightly positive slope towards the rightmost end) due to aggregation of data across individuals with different 1 values, since individuals with 1 &gt; 1 are predicted to have and exhibit more updating to prior-consistent evidence (i.e., positive slopes; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref>). (d) Formal model comparison for data from study 1. We compared 10 different models <ref type="table">(Table S27</ref>) as in our previous work . Each model is defined by its free parameters, which are reflected on the x-axis. See <ref type="table">Table S27</ref> for details. The winning model was defined as the model with the highest protected exceedance probability, which was the same as in our previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref>  were robust to the exclusion of outliers with an 1 more than 3 scaled median absolute deviations <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">52</ref> from the median ( 1 &lt; 0.75; 11 outliers): after their removal, the correlation between 1 and the evidence asymmetry slope was still significant (ρ = -0.58, p &lt; 10 -307 ), as was the correlation between 1 and the mean final estimate difference (ρ = -0.53, p = 2.32 x 10 -12 ). Posterior predictive checks further recapitulate the range of values in the data (Figure S10 -S12).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>Pre-screening, exclusions, and retained sample. To ensure a wide range of PDI scores and sufficient high PDI participants with odd beliefs, Study 2 used a pre-screening procedure following prior work <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[53]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[54]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[55]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[56]</ref> (Methods). The study consisted of two parts: (i) a pre-screening based on the PDI (and, secondarily, on the Paranoia Checklist; Methods), and (ii) a separate experimental session involving administration of a second PDI and the task discussed above (separated on average by 3.5 days). Critically, the pre-screening used unbiased PDI-score cutoffs derived from previously published norms <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">49</ref> (under 34.9 for low PDI and over 82.9 for high PDI; Methods). After exclusions (Methods), 116 participants were retained of whom 91 comprised the main sample: 34 in the high PDI group and 57 in the low PDI group <ref type="table">(Table S1</ref>; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4a</ref>-b inset). Attesting to the effectiveness of (and need for) the pre-screening, note that only 2 participants from study 1 would have been classified as high PDI based on study 2's prescreening cutoffs.</p><p>Direct replication of results from study 1. As further validation of our task and model, we replicated the critical results from study 1 in the main sample of study 2 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">(Figure 4</ref> and Supplemental results), including the winning model ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure S5</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S8</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Group differences in sequential base-rate neglect reflect variability in real-world odd beliefs.</head><p>Having ensured enough variability in odd beliefs (i.e., PDI scores), we tested whether the high and low PDI groups differed on the relevant measures of sequential base-rate neglect. Both groups separately showed recency biases (mean final estimate difference and evidence asymmetry slope; all p&lt;0.009), but only the high PDI group showed the prior-dependent beliefupdating effect (low PDI: p=0.41; high PDI: p=0.02; sign-rank tests). There were no group differences for the recency bias measures (mean final estimate difference or evidence asymmetry slope; all p&gt;0.48) or for the prior-dependent belief-updating effect, although the latter trended towards significance (p=0.083, rank-sum test; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5a</ref>). Crucially, the modelbased measure of sequential base-rate neglect did differ between the groups, with more sequential base-rate neglect (lower 1 ) in the high PDI compared to the low PDI group (p=0.018; rank-sum test; effect-size Cliff's delta δ=0.30). No group differences were observed in the other model parameters ( 2 ( ) : all 0.43&gt;p&gt;0.09; rank-sum tests; -0.10&gt;δ&gt;-0.21; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5a</ref> and <ref type="table">Table S22</ref>).  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref>, after excluding outliers <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">52</ref> ( 1 &lt; 0.82; 11 outliers), the correlation between 1 and the evidence asymmetry slope was still significant (ρ = -0.37, p = 1.08 x 10 -4 ), as was the correlation between 1 and the mean final estimate difference (ρ = -0.47, p = 7.32 x 10 -7 ).</p><p>Consistent with the observed group differences, an exploratory dimensional analysis (including 25 participants with PDI scores in an intermediate range between the high and low cutoffs in addition to the 91 comprising our primary groups per the pre-screening protocol; n=116) showed that individuals with more unusual beliefs tended to exhibit lower 1 (ρ = −0.25, p = 0.007) and a trend towards stronger prior-dependent belief-updating (i.e., a more negative slope; ρ = −0.17, p = 0.065). The relationship with 1 held after controlling for all three  <ref type="table">(Table S22)</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>Functional explanations for sequential base-rate neglect. Thus far, we have shown evidence that human behavior in a sequential belief-updating task generally conforms to the predictions of a weighted Bayesian model of sequential base-rate neglect. Specifically, this model jointly predicts a recency bias and a pattern of prior-dependent updating as well as interindividual relationships with prior underweighting that we observed empirically. Further, interindividual variability in sequential base-rate neglect correlates with real-world belief oddity. However, this descriptive model does not provide a normative explanation as to why sequential base-rate neglect is such a predominant feature or why it varies across individuals. It also does not address whether prior underweighting may or may not be an optimal strategy under realistic constraints.</p><p>Study 3 thus aimed to address these outstanding mechanistic questions of why people exhibit base-rate neglect and whether it could reflect an optimal strategy. To do so, we considered models that explain variation in prior weighting as a rational response to external or internal factors. We specifically considered a first class of functional models that explains sequential base-rate neglect and its variability as a consequence of perceived variability in the environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46</ref> and a second class that explains it as a rational adjustment to a noisy internal sampling process <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> . In the first, in a volatile environment where the underlying evidencegenerating process can change abruptly, the relevance of evidence before an inferred change point should be proportional to the certainty that a change point occurred. Thus, an optimal agent that perceives the environment as volatile will tend to decrease the prior weight around potential change points, therefore exhibiting sequential base-rate neglect. This class of model should be less applicable to the stable environment in the current task, but we reasoned that participants could still assume some degree of volatility despite explicit instructions to the contrary. The second class of models prescribes the optimal behavior for an agent with limited cognitive resources <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">57</ref> . Under the noisy-sampling model <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> within this class, the agent can only access an imprecise, noisy representation of prior beliefs through random sampling of its internal representation (i.e., the distribution of the logit prior resulting from additive noise); it is possible to increase precision of the prior representation by increasing samples at the cost of allocating more internal cognitive resources, but the optimal strategy balances this cost against that of prediction inaccuracy <ref type="figure">(Figure 6a</ref>). Given this, the optimal strategy in this capacity-limited agent consists of decreasing the prior weight more in response to greater noise in the prior representation <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> . Because more noise in the prior representation should lead to more variable responses, even after accounting for structured variability due to sequential effects the noisysampling model predicts a correlation between the degree of sequential base-rate neglect and (unstructured) response variance. In contrast, the alternative volatility-based model we considered here does not predict this correlation in the context of our task ( <ref type="figure">Figure S6</ref>).</p><p>We thus assessed the interindividual correlation between prior-weight 1 and response variance across all 267 participants from studies 1 and 2. A clear correlation was observed with 1 when using the unexplained variance by the weighted Bayesian model (the model RMSE) as an index of unstructured response variability (ρ = −0.40, p = 8.9 x 10 −12 , Spearman correlation; <ref type="figure">Figure 6a</ref>). This relationship was also present in each independent sample <ref type="table">(Table S24</ref>). To circumvent potential artifacts of modeling, we also derived a model-agnostic measure of response variance focused on the unstructured variability of responses under identical circumstances-specifically, the aggregate response variance of logit probability estimates for repeated, identical sequence fragments matched on bead color and bead ratio (Methods), which we refer to as the response variance for simplicity and which captures variability that cannot be attributed to sequential evidence-order effects. Using this measure, we again found a correlation with 1 in the expected direction (ρ = −0.46, p &lt; 2.22 x 10 −308 ; <ref type="figure">Figure 6b</ref>). Again, this relationship was also present in each independent sample <ref type="table">(Table S24)</ref>. Although this result does not rule out the broader class of volatility models, it is more consistent with the noisysampling model; we thus further explored the ability of the latter model to capture our data.</p><p>The noisy-sampling model captures belief-updating behaviors described by the weighted Bayesian model. The noisy-sampling model posits that the prior and likelihood weights of the weighted Bayesian model ( 1 and 2( ) ) scale negatively with the respective noise in the representation of the prior and likelihood, captured respectively by parameters <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> and <ref type="table">Table S25</ref>). The noisy-sampling model also includes parameters <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> and</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">ℎ ( ) 2 (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">ℎ ( ) 2</formula><p>that reflect the uncertainty in the distribution of logit priors and logit likelihoods that the agent might encounter (here held constant for model fitting to avoid parameter tradeoff; Methods). Perhaps unsurprisingly given that the structure of the noisy-sampling model reduces to the weighted Bayesian model, when fitted to our data (Methods) the noisy-sampling model captured comparable variance (correlation of explained R 2 between models: ρ = 0.93) and the 2 noise parameters closely correlated with the corresponding weights of the weighted Bayesian model (mean Spearman correlation ρ = − 0.92; <ref type="figure">Figure 6c</ref> and S7) in the full sample combining studies 1 and 2 (n=267). Under the noisy-sampling model, behavioral variability is partly due to noise in the internal representation of variables such as the prior. If this is true and it explains the observed correlation between 1 and response variance, prior noise should correlate with response variance. Consistent with this, the fitted parameter correlated with response variance (ρ = 0.35, p = 5.06 x −9 ; <ref type="figure">Figure 6d</ref> and <ref type="table">Table S24</ref>). Control analyses evaluating contributions of <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> suggested that this parameter had no meaningful contribution to response variance or base-rate neglect ( <ref type="figure">Figure S8</ref> and Methods).</p><p>Alternative explanations to noisy sampling. A possible alternative explanation of the observed correlation between prior weight 1 and response variance may be that individuals respond more inconsistently not because of noisy internal representations but due to other lower-level factors such as distraction or late motor noise. In other words, some inattentive participants could in principle tend to respond randomly. Although this is unlikely based on control analyses ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures S9 and S10)</ref>, if this were the case, perhaps data from these individuals was better fitted with lower 1 values due to modeling artifacts. To evaluate this possibility, we assessed robustness of parameter recovery for the weighted Bayesian model and the noisy-sampling model in the presence of levels of late noise that could capture random responding during the task (Methods). These analyses showed that parameter recovery of the relevant parameters ( 1 and 2 ) had no appreciable biases at levels of late noise matching the observed behavioral variability in the data <ref type="figure">(Figures 6e-f</ref>), suggesting that variability in their fitted values is unlikely to stem from lower-level factors irrelevant to the noisy-sampling model. Moreover, an explanation of prior underweighting in terms of inattentiveness may predict modulations of response times by 1 that were not present in the data <ref type="table">(Table S27)</ref>. Altogether, these results speak against an explanation in terms of inattention or random responding and support noisy representation of prior beliefs as a more tenable explanation for sequential baserate neglect. Relationship between prior noise and real-world odd beliefs. Because belief oddity correlated with sequential base-rate neglect (lower 1 ) in study 2, and the previous results imply that prior noise ( 2 ) could explain sequential base-rate neglect, we next asked whether prior noise could account for belief oddity. In the main sample from study 2, the high PDI group showed higher 2 than the low PDI group (p=0.007, rank-sum test; δ = -0.34; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Figure 7a</ref>). No group differences were observed in the other model parameters (  <ref type="table">Table S26</ref>). These results suggest that high PDI may be specifically associated with increased prior noise.</p><p>An exploratory dimensional analysis (using the same sample as in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5b</ref>-c) further showed a correlation between prior noise <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> and more unusual beliefs (ρ = 0.29, p = 0.002; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Figure 7b</ref>), even after controlling for all three ℎ ( ) 2 parameters and the noisy sampling model RMSE (ρ = 0.265, p = 0.0048; <ref type="table">Table S24</ref>). Altogether, these results suggest that noisy prior representations may explain sequential base-rate neglect and interindividual variability in odd beliefs outside the laboratory. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In this study, we leveraged computational modeling and a novel task developed to test the joint predictions of a weighted Bayesian model of sequential base-rate neglect. People tended to exhibit base-rate neglect-defined as prior underweighting based on long-standing <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> and recent theories 1,2 -which in a sequential context manifested in two ways consistent with model predictions 1,2,17 : a recency bias, apparent in the raw differences in final probability estimates between mirror-opposite sequences, and a form of prior-dependent updating, apparent in the changes of probability estimates. Crucially, interindividual variability in the magnitude of these effects was commensurate with the degree of sequential base-rate neglect exhibited by individuals. We also considered functional explanatory models of base-rate neglect, and found initial support for a noisy-sampling model <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> whereby sequential base-rate neglect represents an optimal response to noisy representation of prior beliefs-in contrast to classical theories that frame base-rate neglect as a suboptimal heuristic strategy <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> . The noisy-sampling model predicted correlations between sequential base-rate neglect and unstructured response variance that we corroborated in the data. Finally, both model-derived measures of sequential base-rate neglect and prior noise from our laboratory task correlated with the endorsement of odd beliefs outside the laboratory, suggesting the relevance of these computationally characterized processes to the development and maintenance of real-world beliefs. Our study goes beyond previous studies showing evidence-order effects in sequential belief updating <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31]</ref> in several ways. First, our study used explicit quantitative information from a single evidence stream as the basis for both prior beliefs and the likelihood of evidence samples. This allowed us to rule out meaningful baseline biases ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref>) as each of two alternative states was confirmed to be considered equally likely before any evidence was presented. It also equalized the relevance and representativeness of the prior and likelihood information, making interpretations of base-rate neglect in terms of qualitative differences between observed evidence and base-rate information <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> less tenable. Second, we used a validated belief-elicitation procedure that financially incentivized participants to report their true beliefs <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref> . Third, we used computational modeling to parse the role of prior weighting during sequential belief updating. Combined with longer sequences and a novel manipulation of evidence order, this allowed us to systematically characterize evidence-order effects and empirically confirm the theoretical prediction 1,2,4,32 that sequential base-rate neglect expresses itself as a combination of recency bias and prior-dependent belief updating imposing a ceiling on belief certainty. And fourth, past studies have found an association between cognitive biases and odd beliefs <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[58]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[59]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[60]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[61]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[62]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[63]</ref> in the general population. However, their primary findings center on correlations between odd beliefs and broadly defined or composite measures of reasoning or cognitive biases-rather than more narrowly defined and more interpretable cognitive constructs defined via computational modeling. These broader measures have yielded mixed results, possibly due to the qualitative nature of the reasoning tasks or other limitations such as a small number of trials. In contrast, the current study identified a specific relationship between a precisely defined computational measure of sequential base-rate neglect from a well-controlled paradigm and a subjective report of odd beliefs in the general population.</p><p>A unifying theory for why people exhibit sequential base-rate neglect has been lacking <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41</ref> . A classic influential view of base-rate neglect framed it as a heuristic strategy <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[44]</ref> , although this notion lacked clear support and a fully developed explanatory framework. Here, we provide empirical support for an alternative functional (mechanistic) model <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> that explains sequential base-rate neglect as an efficient response to noise in the internal representation of prior beliefs. Individuals are assumed to have a certain trait-like degree of prior noise, or imprecision, and they can adapt to it by modulating its influence or weight on belief updating. Given limited internal resources (e.g., cognitive or metabolic), individuals must balance the internal costs of precision against the cost of incorrect predictions <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">[64]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[65]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">[66]</ref> . And given the limited precision with which prior information can be represented, the optimal strategy is to discount prior information (i.e., to neglect the base rate) in proportion to the degree of prior imprecision. We also considered alternative explanations to the noisy-sampling model, including lower-level factors such as inattention, ultimately deeming an explanation in terms of a response to internal prior noise to be more tenable. Partly supporting this conclusion, we found empirical support for a key prediction of the noisy-sampling model that the degree of prior noise should relate to the amount of unstructured variability reflected in response variance (beyond structured variability related to evidence-order effects). This conclusion is also in line with the finding that the degree of baserate neglect depends on the perceived trustworthiness of prior information <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">67</ref> . Our results may also be reconciled with the observation that recency bias is more prevalent upon sequential belief elicitation (as in our paradigm) versus end-of-sequence single-shot belief elicitation <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> , at least if we assume that belief updates only occur upon each elicitation <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> , since more elicitations should lead to more prior discounting with each belief update. Generally speaking, our results thus align with an emergent literature supporting the relevance and biological plausibility of sampling-based inference models <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[68]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[69]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[70]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[71]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">[72]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[73]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">[74]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[75]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">[76]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">[77]</ref> . While here we focused on a specific model of inference under internal capacity constraints, our main results are broadly consistent with this model family-including a learning-to-infer model where prior underweighting and sequential biases arise through learning of contextual information <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">78</ref> -and thus support further examination of these models in future work.</p><p>Finally, we extended previous field work linking sequential base-rate neglect to realworld judgments by demonstrating that individuals with more sequential base-rate neglect and noisier prior beliefs tend to endorse more odd beliefs in their daily lives <ref type="bibr" target="#b78">79</ref> -beliefs that are likely to influence how they function in society <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">[80]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">[81]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">[82]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b82">[83]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">53,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">[84]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">[85]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[86]</ref> . Notably, this has implications for psychiatric disorders involving delusions <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> or odd unsupported beliefs. Previous literature has emphasized a "jumping to conclusions <ref type="bibr" target="#b86">[87]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">[88]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b88">[89]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b89">[90]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b90">[91]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b91">[92]</ref> bias in schizophrenia, although interpretations of this bias in terms of altered belief updating in relation to delusions remains questionable <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b92">[93]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b93">[94]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">[95]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b95">[96]</ref> . Using a similar approach to the current paper, we previously showed that variability in sequential prior weighting correlated with the clinical delusion severity in schizophrenia <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> , suggesting a role for sequential base-rate neglect in belief psychopathology. Our finding that sequential base-rate neglect drives evidence order effects implies that different sequences of information may lead to inconsistent differences in certainty (and by extension information sampling) in schizophrenia <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17</ref> , which could explain mixed results in this literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b92">[93]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b93">[94]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">[95]</ref> . Systematic manipulations of evidence order such as the ones we introduced here may thus be helpful in clarifying the computational mechanisms underlying delusions. Further, our results also emphasize that alterations in noisy-sampling (and other limited-capacity) inference processes should be evaluated as candidate explanations for maladaptive or pathological beliefs, particularly given increasing support for their role in adaptive behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">97,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b97">98</ref> .</p><p>Our results indicate that sequential base-rate neglect makes human observers rely disproportionately on recent evidence. They also hint at a potential strategy that could be used to avoid or minimize potentially harmful consequences of sequential base-rate neglect. By manipulating the magnitude of evidence asymmetry, we showed that recency biases tend to disappear in sequences with balanced information (i.e., they approach zero as evidence asymmetry approaches zero; e.g., as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3b</ref>). This suggests that sequential information curated to maximize evidence symmetry may facilitate the development of unbiased beliefs. This principle could apply to real-world situations where unbiased, objective judgments are vital, like a clinician making a diagnosis or a jury rendering a verdict. In the former case, previous work has shown that the order of information affects diagnostic accuracy <ref type="bibr">8,20 99</ref> , so ensuring a balanced sequence of information-e.g., via medical decision-making scripts <ref type="bibr" target="#b100">100</ref> could plausibly minimize biases and improve diagnostic accuracy. More generally, our results suggest that symmetrically interleaving opposing pieces of evidence may yield a more balanced synthesis of the information at hand.</p><p>In summary, we have showed that base-rate neglect manifests sequentially as a combination of recency bias and prior dependence in belief updating, that this process may result from a noisy representation of prior beliefs, and that it likely contributes to the formation of odd beliefs in the real world. Altogether, our findings suggest that sequential base-rate neglect is not just a mathematical quirk or an artifact of laboratory methods but a robust feature of human belief formation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods Incentive-Compatible Probability-Estimates Beads Task</head><p>Task Aim. We developed a modified beads task building from previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> where participants had to infer the identity of a hidden state (blue or green box) based on multiple samples of evidence (colored beads). We elicited probability estimates about the identity of the hidden state after each sample of evidence, allowing us to track the development of beliefs over time. We manipulated both the strength of the evidence (bead ratio in the hidden box) and, critically, the order in which the evidence samples were presented. The same task was used in studies 1, 2, and 3.</p><p>Trial Structure. Trials started with a 3-s presentation of two boxes with the same majority-to-minority bead ratio and different majority bead color (i.e., the blue box and the green box). To enhance clarity, the border of each box indicated the color of the majority bead color in the box and the contents of each box were displayed in text above each box (e.g., "60 blue, 40 green"; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a)</ref>. One box was presented on the left side of the screen and the other on the right side of the screen. Next, participants were shown a white box with a black border and a question mark, which represented the hidden box. The first time it was displayed in a trial, participants just saw this hidden box for 1.5 s. On subsequent presentations of the hidden box, an animated green or blue bead rose up out of the box with this animation lasting 1.5 s. Participants then reported a probability estimate about how likely they thought the hidden box was the blue box or the green box. The top half of the screen showed a visual record of all beads shown so far within the trial, so as to minimize the working-memory burden and associated interindividual variability. The lower half of the screen displayed a black slider bar used to submit the probability estimate. Percentage values above each extreme of the slider indicated the complementary probability estimates for each box. The slider tick did not appear until a participant moved the mouse, and its starting point was randomized after each bead draw to minimize anchoring. Probability-estimate responses were self-paced and the response window was unlimited. After 8 samples were drawn and 9 probability estimates submitted, a binary choice for the hidden box was prompted. On this choice screen, the boxes were labeled "Left" and "Right" and participants had to respond with a corresponding (left or right) button press within an unlimited response window. When a response was submitted, the border of the selected box changed to yellow for 0.25 s to provide feedback that the selection was recorded. A blank screen was then presented for 0.5 s before the next trial began.</p><p>Task Structure. Participants completed 55 trials of the probability estimates task. At the beginning the experiment, participants were instructed that one of two boxes was randomly selected and hidden with equal probability: one containing mostly blue beads (blue box) or one containing mostly green beads (green box). One box was presented on the left side of the screen and the other on the right. The location of each box was determined at random on each trial. For a given trial, the bead ratio could be 51:49, 60:40, or 90:10, with each box displaying reciprocal ratios of bead colors. The participants' task was to identify which box was selected and accurately estimate its probability. During each trial, 8 bead samples were presented, one at a time, and probability estimates were prompted before the first bead and after each of the beads about the probability that the hidden box was the blue or the green one. Participants were told that the individual beads were drawn randomly with replacement. To endow the estimates with instrumental value, after seeing 8 beads participants made a binary choice about the identity of the hidden box.</p><p>Incentive Compatibility. During the instructions, to incentivize responses that accurately reflected true beliefs and preferences, participants were informed they would be given an endowment of $10 that they could keep in its entirety (losing $0 or $5) based on their performance. After they completed all blocks of the experiment, $0 or $5 were subtracted from the endowment based on their performance on one randomly selected response. This could be a probability estimate (out of the 9 per trial over all trials) or a binary box choice (1 per trial). To determine the payoff, we instituted a binarized scoring rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39</ref> that is more robust to risk preferences and produces more accurate estimates than other commonly used methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39</ref> , particularly when combined with potential loss from an endowment as in our implementation and in previous work leveraging endowment effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b102">101,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b103">102</ref> to maximize task engagement and accuracy. If a probability estimate was chosen to determine the payoff, the probability of losing $5 was a function of the squared error of the reported probability estimate relative to the objective probability <ref type="bibr" target="#b104">103</ref> . Specifically, a random value k from 0 to 1 was selected and participants lost $5 if the squared error of their chosen estimate was larger than k or $0 otherwise. The binarized scoring rule thus implies a quadratic loss function where the probability of losing $0 or $5, rather than the loss magnitude, depends on the precision of reported probability estimates. This leads to a U-shaped relationship between the expected value of a response and the posterior probability ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S13</ref>). We also applied the binarized scoring rule to box choices, which in this case reduced to losing $5 when the choice was incorrect or $0 otherwise.</p><p>At the end of the task, participants were shown the selected response and the payout realization as explained above. To make the underlying principle of the scoring rule clear, an accessible explanation without excessive mathematical detail and several examples were presented to participants during the instructions (Movie S1). To ensure comprehension, four of the miscomprehension quiz questions <ref type="table">(Table S30</ref>, Questions 1, 3, 4, and 9) specifically probed participants' understanding of the scoring rule.</p><p>Instructions, practice, and comprehension checks. To ensure participants completed the task within a reasonable time frame and in one session, they were required to complete the entire experiment within 4 hours ( <ref type="figure">Figure S9</ref>). The MTurk advertisement indicated that the task could take up to 2 hours to incentivize participants to minimize breaks. To minimize the incentive to rush through the task, participants were required to perform task trials for at least 40 minutes (and received additional trials if they completed the actual experimental trials earlier). To ensure task comprehension, participants were given comprehensive and detailed instructions for ~15-20 minutes. After the instructions, participants were required to complete a miscomprehension quiz ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S30</ref>). They were required to achieve 100% accuracy on the quiz or retake it until they did, consistent with prior work <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">48</ref> . After the quiz, participants completed 3 practice trials, one with each possible bead ratio, and could repeat the practice if they wished. The practice-trial sequences were not used in the main experiment. A video demonstrating the instructions, quiz, and practice trials is available (Movie S1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sequences of Evidence.</head><p>Bead sequences were defined by the specific order of majorityto-minority beads. The color (blue or green) of the majority beads in the hidden box, which determined its identity, was randomly determined on each trial. Each bead-ratio condition comprised a different set of pre-determined fixed sequences; these were chosen from a broader set of all possible sequences of beads drawn randomly with replacement, in line with the instructions. Out of the 55 trials, there were 26 unique sequences of evidence order <ref type="table">(Table   S29</ref>). Of those, 16 sequences were identical across the 60:40 and 90:10 conditions ("matched trials"). Sequences were presented in blocks of 11 trials, organized by the bead-ratio condition. The order of blocks was the same for each participant: 60:40, 90:10, 51:49, 60:40, 90:10. Within each block, sequences were selected at random without replacement from the sequence set. We selected sets of sequences for which the distribution of majority beads over trials for a given bead ratio matched the distribution of expected sequences of that ratio. To achieve this, 4 sequences were unique to the 51:49 condition, 6 sequences to the 60:40 condition, and none to the 90:10 condition.</p><p>Critically, we constructed mirror-opposite sequence pairs to facilitate isolation of sequence-order effects. Further, we aimed to vary sequences in their degree of evidence asymmetry, or how extremely front-or back-loaded the majority beads were in a sequence. Here, and throughout the manuscript, sequences are presented such that 1 (or black) represents the majority bead color, and 0 (or white) the minority color. We quantified evidence asymmetry as a linear weighted sum of a binary sequence, for instance [1 1 0 1 1 1 1 0], with each element in the sequence vector weighted as a function of their linear distance from the middle (weights: [-3.5, -2.5, -1.5, -0.5, 0.5, 1.5, 2.5, 3.5]). The result of the weighted sum (in this example, -2) thus indicated that majority beads were presented mostly towards the beginning of the sequence (front-loaded) with negative values. Positive values would indicate that majority beads were presented mostly towards the end of the sequence (back-loaded). Greater absolute values indicate more extreme back-or front-loading. Mirror-opposite sequence pairs had identical bead-ratio, number of majority beads, and absolute evidence asymmetry such that their comparison would isolate sequence-order effects. In particular, recency biases should manifest as more certain beliefs (favoring the true hidden box) for back-loaded (compared to front-loaded) sequences, particularly in sequences with greater evidence asymmetry.</p><p>Overall, we selected trials to span a range of evidence asymmetry, bead-ratio conditions, and total number of majority beads <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1b)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Questionnaires Study 1</head><p>Before completing the probability estimates beads task, participants completed a demographic survey <ref type="table">(Table S1</ref>) and the PDI <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22</ref> (see table S28 for the complete set of items). The PDI is a 21-item questionnaire that measures odd, delusion-like ideas in the general population. The experiences interrogated a range of more common experiences such as "do you ever feel as if some people are not what they seem to be?" or "are you worried that your partner may be unfaithful?" to more unusual ones, like "do you ever feel as if you are a robot or zombie without a will of your own?" or "do you feel as if things in magazines or on TV were written especially for you?" For each experience, the participant can endorse the belief with a Yes or No response. If they report No, then the global item score is 0. If they report Yes, they must then report on a scale of 1 to 5 how distressing the belief is (1 = not distressing at all, to 5 = very distressing), how often they think about it (1 = hardly ever, to 5 = all the time), and their conviction about it (1 = don't believe it's true, to 5 = believe it is absolutely true). The global item score is the sum of these three responses plus the "Yes" endorsement. The global PDI score (with a possible range of 0 to 336) is the sum of all the global item scores (each between 0 and 16).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>Participants completed the PDI and the Paranoia Checklist <ref type="bibr" target="#b106">104</ref> . Although our primary measure was PDI, we included the Paranoia Checklist for exploratory purposes to assess the generalizability of the results and to confirm that recency bias was generally related to odd beliefs and not to paranoid beliefs specifically. The Paranoia Checklist is a 18-item measure of paranoid beliefs in the general population.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>All participants provided informed consent. This study was approved by the Institutional Review Board at the New York State Psychiatric Institute (Protocol #6916).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants, Exclusions, and Retained Samples Study 1</head><p>Participants were recruited through Amazon MTurk, and the experiment was run on gorilla.sc . They were paid $10 plus a performance bonus of $5 or $10. Using MTurk filters, we only invited participants who had already successfully completed at least 50 tasks with a 90% approval rate, who were under 55 years old, located in the US, and had an MTurk Masters Qualification (given to workers who "demonstrate a high degree of success in performing a wide range of [tasks] across a large number of requesters").</p><p>The experiment comprised multiple components, including the task itself and questionnaires. Several participants began the study, completing the questionnaires but not the task. These non-completers were excluded from all analyses. Importantly, at least for those who completed the questionnaires <ref type="table">(Table S1</ref> and S2) we did not find differences in belief oddity (p = 0.484) or evidence for selection biases in completers on most relevant measures.</p><p>We also implemented exclusion criteria based on performance. First, to avoid "bots", we assessed if average responses were above a minimum of 350 ms (the approximate time needed to shift endogenous attention <ref type="bibr" target="#b108">106 )</ref>. No participants were excluded by this criterion. Second, we limited our analysis to participants who identified the "correct" box at the end of the bead sequence with accuracy above 68% for 60:40 and 90:10 bead-ratio conditions based on the binomial chance level (15 correct trials out of 22; accuracy criterion). Third, to assess engagement in the task, we used a linear regression analysis predicting participants' subjective probability estimates based on the random starting point of the cursor on the sliding scale (see task details below) and the optimal Bayesian estimate (i.e., the objective probability). Participants were excluded if the random cursor start position significantly predicted their subjective estimates and the Bayesian estimate did not. If both conditions were satisfied (random-estimates criterion), we reasoned that the participant was likely trying to the task as fast as possible with no regard for accuracy. If the optimal Bayesian estimate also predicted subjective estimates, we reasoned that the participant may have been engaged in the task but was anchoring to the random cursor-start location, which was insufficient for exclusion. A total of 213 participants began this study. 43 were non-completers, and 8 were excluded for meeting either the accuracy or the random-estimates criterion.</p><p>To further determine if participants were correctly engaging the task, we developed 2 heuristic models reflecting strategies that participants may have used and which would not reflect belief updating. The first heuristic model (no-prior model; equivalent to 1 = 0) reflects a strategy where participants report fixed belief certainty in favor of the most recent evidence sample. For example, for a blue bead they would report 0.8 in favor of the blue box and for a green bead 0.8 in favor of the green box. The second heuristic model (observed-proportion) reflects a similar strategy with the difference that the favored box is based on whichever color has been drawn more often. For instance, after observing 3 blue beads and 1 green bead the participant could report 0.8 in favor of the blue box and only change their estimate to 0.8 in favor of the green box after observing more green than blue beads. The heuristic models, along with all the belief updating models <ref type="table">(Table S27)</ref>, were fit to the data for the 60:40 and 90:10 conditions. The 51:49 condition was not used here because the low evidence strength in this condition makes it harder to determine whether estimates are consistent with heuristic strategies. We excluded any participant whose 60:40 and 90:10 data was fit best by one of the heuristic models in a formal model comparison using the BIC 107 at the individual level. Based on this criterion, 5 participants were excluded for being best fit by the no-prior model, and 6 participants by the observed-proportion model. There were no significant differences in demographic characteristics between participants who were included in the study and those who were excluded based on performance criteria or non-completers <ref type="table">(Table S2)</ref>.</p><p>In sum, 237 participants were recruited from Amazon MTurk, of whom 170 completed the task. Of these, 8 were excluded for poor accuracy or random responding and 11 because their data was best fit by a heuristic model which suggested they did not engage the task as intended. After exclusions, 151 participants were retained and included in the primary analysis. <ref type="table">Table S1</ref> shows the demographic information of all 151 completers who were included in the analysis for study 1. Quality checks indicated the data was of comparable quality than similar inperson studies <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figures S9 and S10</ref>; Online Data Quality).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>Participants were recruited through Amazon MTurk, and the experiment was run on gorilla.sc . We implemented the same MTurk filtering criteria as in study 1, with the exception that we did not limit participants to MTurk Masters so as to increase participation. We also excluded anyone who already participated in study 1. Study 2 consisted of two parts. For part 1, participants were paid $2 to complete 2 questionnaires. 547 participants started part 1, and 512 completed it (93.6%). Participants were invited back for part 2 based on their questionnaire scores from part 1. 241 participants were invited to participate in part 2. For part 2, completed 1 questionnaire and the probability estimates beads task. The task and incentive structure was identical to study 1. 213 participants started part 2, and 143 participants completed it (67.14%). We applied the same performance and model-based exclusion criteria as in study 1. Using these criteria, 10 participants were excluded based on their performance (accuracy and random-estimates criteria) and 17 due to evidence (BIC) favoring heuristic models. There were no significant differences in demographic characteristics between participants included in the study and those excluded based on poor performance <ref type="table">(Table S3</ref>). For study 2, we analyzed the data for 116 participants <ref type="table">(Table S1</ref>). Across all 116 retained participants, PDI scores were stable between the pre-screening and experimental sessions (ρ = 0.97) and both correlated strongly with the secondary measure of odd beliefs, the Paranoia Checklist (all ρ &gt; 0.79). Quality checks again suggested comparable quality to similar in-person studies ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures S9 and   S10)</ref>.</p><p>Pre-Screening and PDI Classification. To ensure a wide enough range of odd beliefs and sufficient sampling of meaningfully high levels <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">54</ref> , study 2 pre-screened participants based on the PDI <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22</ref> . Participants with high or low belief oddity based on their PDI scores were invited for the experimental session, with the cutoffs based on reported norms for PDI global scores <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">47</ref> (mean of 58.9 and standard deviation of 48.0 in healthy individuals): mean plus 0.5 standard deviation (&gt;82.9) for the high PDI group and mean minus 0.5 standard deviation (&lt;34.9) for the low PDI group. For secondary analyses, we also invited participants with high (&gt;17.15) or low (&lt;6.65) frequency scores on reported norms for the Paranoia Checklist <ref type="bibr" target="#b91">92</ref> . Participants who were invited solely based on the Paranoia Checklist scores were only included in exploratory dimensional analyses. Participants in the high and low PDI groups were genderand age-matched (within 2 years). Those who completed the experimental session completed the PDI a second time (typically within 1-2 days of the pre-screening) and the mean PDI across both sessions was used for dimensional analyses.</p><p>Data from these participants was again high quality ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures S9 and S10</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>Study 3 re-analyzes combined data from studies (n = 151) and (n = 116) in 267 participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Online Data Quality</head><p>In line with best practices for online studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b110">[108]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b112">[109]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b113">[110]</ref> , we limited recruitment (in study 1) to those with a high reputation and a record of active engagement with tasks, we implemented strict exclusion criteria to ensure retention of participants who were most likely to have been actively and honestly engaged in our task <ref type="table">(Table S1)</ref>, and we assessed and found evidence against selection bias <ref type="table">(Tables S2 and S3</ref>). Attrition was consistent with previous work in online samples and unlikely to compromise validity based on previous analyses <ref type="bibr" target="#b116">113</ref> . We further confirmed that participant behavior was well captured by our model and that participants completed the task within a reasonable time frame, both consistent with our previous data from a related in-person study <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> ( <ref type="figure">Figure S9a</ref>) and S9c). The precision of probability estimates was also consistent with previous in-person work, providing evidence that our incentive-compatible scoring method was effective ( <ref type="figure">Figure S9b</ref> and S9c). We also show that our parameter estimates were reliable and consistent within participants across the full duration of the task ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S10</ref>). Finally, we conducted a noise-corrupted parameter recovery analysis showing that our results were unlikely to be driven by general low-level factors such as inattention or disengagement <ref type="figure">(Figures 6e and 6f)</ref>. In line with previous online work <ref type="bibr" target="#b107">105,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b117">114,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b118">115</ref> , these analysis support that our data was valid, reliable, and high-quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model-agnostic Measure of Response Variance</head><p>In keeping with the noisy-sampling model and previous work 2, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17</ref> , we calculated the main measure of behavioral response variance in logit space as the variance of the log-odds of probability estimates for identical sequence fragments. The prediction of the noisy sampling model is that under identical circumstances, participants with a noisier prior representation will have greater variability in their posterior beliefs that will result in more response variability across instantiations. To isolate this variability, we determined the unique sets of sequence fragments, defined as subsequences of beads starting at the first bead that were identical in terms of bead-ratio condition and exact bead order (including bead color). For robustness, we only analyzed subsequences presented a minimum of 3 times (after excluding sequences with an incorrect final choice). (Note that the specific sequence fragments were identical in the order of the majority versus minority beads but differed in color across individuals, as the majority bead color of the hidden box was determined randomly for each subject.) For each given sequence fragment, we then calculated the variance of the logit estimates across different instantiations. We then calculated the median of variances across sequence fragments for a given bead-ratio condition, and calculated the mean of the medians across conditions to obtain the summary measure of response variance. We focus on this summary measure but our results hold separately for response variance measured separately by bead-ratio condition 1000 ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S11</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1001">1002</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical Analysis</head><p>To analyze the probability estimates from the task, we employed parametric linear mixed-effects models, with random intercepts and slopes to account for within subject variance (Wilkinson Notation for all regressions is provided in the supplement). To minimize type errors all linear mixed-effects models used the Satterthwaite correction for degrees of freedom . To minimize disproportionate contributions of repeat sequences on results, the probability estimates for the only sequence that was repeated multiple times (i.e., the 8-majority bead sequence in the 90:10 bead-ratio condition) were averaged across for each participant and analyzed as a single sequence.</p><p>To analyze the relationship between model-agnostic summary measures (mean final estimate difference, the evidence asymmetry slope, prior-dependent updating slope, and response variance) and model-derived parameter values (see modeling below), we employed non-parametric tests because these variables were generally not normally distributed across participants based on Lilliefors tests at p&lt;0.05. For group analyses of medians, we thus used sign-rank within-group tests and rank-sum between-group tests. Cliff's delta (δ) was used as a non-parametric measure of effect size 117 . For dimensional analyses, we used Spearman correlations and partial Spearman correlations to control for potential confounding variables. All tests were considered statistically significant at p&lt;0.05.</p><p>All analyses, including model-agnostic and model-based analyses, excluded trials with incorrect final choices, since these were unlikely to reflect inferential processes of interest and more likely to instead reflect model-unrelated lower-level factors such as inattention or task disengagement. The weighted Bayesian model predicts incorrect choices (due to evidenceorder effects) at extreme levels of ω 1 . However, most of the errors we observed in our data were not predicted by this model based on fitted estimates ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S17</ref>), suggesting that most errors were driven by lower-level factors like inattention. On average, this resulted in the exclusion of 1.5% trials per participant ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S17a</ref>). Less critically, the model goodness-of-fit was marginally improved after excluding trials with incorrect final choices ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S17b</ref>). Nonetheless the results of analyses including these trials were virtually unchanged.</p><p>Further, for all model-agnostic analyses involving the conversion of probability estimates to logit space, subjective probability estimates of 1 and 0 were excluded to avoid infinity values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational modeling Weighted Bayesian Belief-Updating Model and Variants</head><p>We fit several weighted Bayesian belief updating models to the draw-by-draw probability estimates for each participant individually and extracted best-fitting parameters for each model. All models in the model comparison were variants of a weighted belief-updating model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">( ) = 1 • ( ) + 2 • ( ℎ ).</formula><p>In this model, ( ) represents the log-odds of the prior probability or belief on the current draw before integrating the likelihood, and it is equivalent to the posterior probability after the previous draw.</p><p>( ℎ ) represents the log-odds of the likelihood (or the loglikelihood ratio), which is the strength of the sensory evidence given by the bead-ratio for a specific bead draw with respect to the correct box. ( ) represents the updated logposterior ratio about the probability that the beads are coming from the green or blue box after combining the prior and the likelihood terms. The prior-weight 1 is a free parameter that acts as a multiplicative weight on the prior belief; it affects how much older evidence is incorporated into the updated beliefs, controlling a primacy-recency bias. Prior underweighting ( 1 &lt; 1) captures sequential base-rate neglect, limiting belief certainty <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2c</ref>) and inducing a recency bias <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2d and 2e)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17</ref> . The likelihood-weight 2 is a free parameter that scales the likelihood term multiplicatively and equally for older and newer samples of evidence, producing distinct effects from the prior-weight 1 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure S1d)</ref>.</p><p>Model fitting was performed for each subject using the Matlab function fmincon 118 in order to minimize the root mean squared error (RMSE) between the model-estimated probabilities and the probability estimates reported by the participant. Only estimates after bead draws were used for fitting, and the participant's first estimate before the first bead draw defined the starting prior belief for a given trial. Data for sequences associated with an incorrect final decision were excluded from analyses. For robustness, participants' data were each fit 100 times to each model, using random starting points between 0 and 20 for each free parameter. Bounds were set to 0 and 20. The parameters associated with the iteration yielding the lowest RMSE were taken as the best-fitting parameters for the participant and model. Formal model comparison (for the same 10 models used for comparison in our previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> ) was conducted based on the Schwarz Bayesian Information Criterion (BIC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b109">107</ref> :</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">= • ln(∑ 2 ⁄ ) + ( ) • ln( ),</formula><p>where n is the total number of fitted probability estimates (per participant), error is the difference between the actual probability estimates and the simulated probability estimates, and is the number of parameters in the model. BIC values were used to calculate the protected exceedance probability (using the Variational Bayes Toolbox <ref type="bibr" target="#b122">119</ref> ; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure   3d</ref> and S5) for group-level Bayesian model selection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Noisy-Sampling Model</head><p>Azeredo da Silveira and Woodford <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> described a noisy-sampling model of belief updating where agents do not have access to the full prior distribution and instead represent prior beliefs imprecisely via noisy internal samples. Under this model, a rational response to imprecision in prior beliefs given the costs of precision and prediction inaccuracy is to underweight prior beliefs. This model thus provides a functional account for sequential base-rate neglect: lower prior-weight results from, and is inversely proportional to, noise in prior beliefs.</p><p>Here, we specify this model in the context of sequential belief-updating in our task. The noisy log-odds of the prior with respect to the true underlying state of the hidden box is: = log� ⁄ � + , ℎ ~�0, 2 �. reflects the noisy internal representation of the prior.</p><p>reflects the prior probability in favor of the true underlying state of the hidden box.</p><p>reflects the prior probability in favor of the incorrect state of the hidden box, where + = 1. reflects the Gaussian noise (in logit space) of the internal representation of the prior, which is centered around 0 and has a variance of 2 . Similarly, the noisy log-odds of the likelihood with respect to the true underlying state of the hidden box is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">ℎ = log � � + , ℎ ~�0, ℎ 2 �.</formula><p>ℎ reflects the noisy internal representation of the likelihood.</p><p>reflects the likelihood in probability space in favor of the correct state of the hidden box, and. reflects the likelihood in favor of the incorrect state, where + = 1. reflects the Gaussian noise (in logit space) of the internal representation of the likelihood. The Gaussian noise is centered around zero and its variance may vary per bead-ratio condition, where ℎ can take on values 2 , 2 , or depending on the condition. To calculate an optimal estimate of a participants' beliefs in response to new evidence, we must also define a probability distribution over the possible true underlying states; that is, we must define the prior distributions from which the values { , } may have been drawn. Here we define these distributions as centered around their corresponding probability ratio, log� ⁄ � or log� ⁄ �, where the variance of the distribution is given by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref>  . From this, the implied probability that the true state of the hidden box is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">= ∫ � 1+ � � � � , where � � �</formula><p>is the density function of the conditional distribution. In order to compute this quantity as a function of the 2 and 2 parameters, we use an analytical approximation 120 of this integral:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">( ) = γ prior •</formula><p>, where = �1 + � 3 � • Σ prior 2 &gt; 1. is a correction owing to the fact that the posterior distribution is not concentrated entirely at its mean. Then, we can substitute in the formula for prior to get:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">( ) = • log� ⁄ � + , where ~�0, � γ prior • prior � 2 �</formula><p>. Here, we show the calculation for the prior, but the calculation of the likelihoods follows the same logic and can be obtained by substituting the corresponding 2 and 2 parameters. To calculate the posterior after each bead draw, we simply add or subtract the likelihood from the prior depending on if the bead is in favor of or against the true underlying state of the hidden box. If the signal is in favor of the true underlying state of the hidden box, the posterior would be: parameters, we conducted a 4-dimensional grid search of 2 values from 0 to 1.4 in steps of 0.2, fitting the 4 2 parameters to each participant's data for a given set of 2 parameter values. To do this we used the Matlab function fmincon <ref type="bibr" target="#b121">118</ref> in order to minimize the RMSE between the model-estimated probabilities and the probability estimates reported by the participant. We then calculated the group-level BIC (based on RMSE across all trials and participants) and selected the 2 parameter values from the model with the lowest value; these were: 2 = 0.2, 51 2 = 0.2, 60 2 = 0.2, and 90 2 = 0.6. Fitted 2 parameter values from the noisy-sampling model with these fixed 2 values were taken as bestfitting values and used in our main analyses. Since increased <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> and 2 parameter values could both lead to decreased prior weighting and response variance under this model ( <ref type="figure">Figure S8</ref>), we empirically assessed the possibility that <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> , and not 2 , could drive interindividual variability in base-rate neglect and response variance. Instead of using fixed 2 parameter values, we took the best-fitting values for each individual. Critically, these individually best-fitting <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> values were uncorrelated with the prior-weight 1 from the weighted Bayesian model and our measure of response variance ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S12</ref>). Furthermore, comparisons of <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> parameter values fitted for relevant subgroups (median-split groups based on 1 or response variance) were inconsistent with an alternative explanation of baserate neglect in terms of variability in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Parameter Recovery Analysis</head><p>To generate simulated agents for parameter recovery, we sampled agent model parameters from the range of fitted parameters values found in the real data. Specifically, we randomly sampled parameters uniformly from the 10 th to 90 th percentile of values to limit the influence of extreme values. Responses were then simulated on the experimental trials that participants observed. Simulated observers started each trial with unbiased prior beliefs about the hidden box and posterior beliefs after each draw were updated in logit space according to the model. To evaluate the robustness of model fitting procedures to late (e.g., motor) noise, varying magnitudes of zero-mean Gaussian noise were added to the logit posterior beliefs after updating. This late noise was unrelated to the inference process, and thus only affected the agents' reported noisy estimates and did not propagate to subsequent prior beliefs. To simulate realistic levels of late Gaussian noise, we estimated the variance that matched the variability observed in the data. First, we determined the 95% confidence interval of the median response variance at the group level in the actual data via bootstrapping. Next, we simulated ten sets of random agents (n = 267 per set, as in the combined dataset for study 3) across a range of latenoise variance levels. For each level, we calculated the median response variance at the group level and the mean of the medians across the sets. We determined the estimated noise range of the actual data to correspond to noise levels where this mean of medians overlapped with the 95% confidence interval of the median response variance in the actual data.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Task schematic. (a) Trial structure of the probability-estimates beads task. Participants are first shown two</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>) and cumulative evidence (Figure S1).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Model predictions for sequential base-rate neglect under the weighted Bayesian model. An agent with sequential base-rate neglect ( 1 &lt; 1.00; for these simulations: = 0.88), in blue, is compared with a Bayesian ideal observer ( 1 = 1), in grey, on the 60:40 bead-ratio condition. Values of 2(60:40) are 0.51 (or between 0.31 and 0.66 in the shaded regions in panels d-e) consistent with observed mean values (and 25 th to 75 th percentile range) in</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(d) Simulation demonstrating the predicted relationship between 1 and the evidence asymmetry slope (blue fit line from b). (e) Simulation of the predicted relationship between 1 and mean final estimate difference (average of blue data points in b). (d,e) The blue and grey dots show the values for the base-rate neglecting and Bayesian ideal observers simulatedin (a,b,c).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Study participants show behavioral signatures of sequential base-rate neglect which scale with model-derived prior underweighting. (a) Group mean of average probability estimates over bead draws for each bead-ratio condition. Participants updated beliefs progressively toward the correct hidden box with steeper slopes for stronger evidence. The inset shows the same data limited to matched (identical) sequences for the 60:40 and 90:10 conditions. Solid lines and shaded regions reflect the mean and standard error of the mean (SEM) of the weighted Bayesian model fits across participants. (b) Group mean of final estimate difference as a function of evidence asymmetry. Each data point shows the difference in the probability estimate after 8 beads for a back-loaded and a front-loaded sequence comprising a mirror-opposite pair, with positive values indicating higher estimates for backloaded sequences consistent with recency bias. Solid lines and shaded regions reflect the mean and SEM of the weighted Bayesian model fits. Consistent with model predictions (Figure 2b), the data shows a recency bias scaling with evidence asymmetry. (c) Group median of individual medians for the magnitude of logit-belief updates as a function of the logit prior with respect to the color of the current bead sample, divided by bead-ratio condition. The xaxis is discretized into bins equivalent to 0.1 increments of the prior belief in probability space (with a lower limit of 0.01 and an upper limit of 0.99; data only binned for visualization). The y-axis represents the magnitude of the logitbelief updates (the difference in the log-odds of the prior and posterior beliefs). Solid lines and shaded regions reflect medians and 95% bootstrapped confidence intervals of the weighted Bayesian model fits. Although not displayed for</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>and in study 2 (</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure S5). (e) The evidence asymmetry slope (equivalent to a single line fitted across all conditions in panel b) is plotted against the prior-weight 1 , showing a negative correlation. This correlation closely follows model predictions indicated by the black line (as inFigure 2dbut with shaded regions including variability in likelihoodweight 2 parameters between the 25 th and 75 th percentile range of observed values in our previous work<ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> ).Marginal violin plots show group medians and interquartile ranges. (f) The mean final estimate difference is shown against 1 , again showing a correlation that follows the model prediction (black line as inFigure 2e). Marginal violin plots show group medians and interquartile ranges. (e, f) Asterisks indicate a significant sign-rank tests of group medians against the corresponding reference values indicated by the dashed lines. Note that results in (e) and (f)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Replication in study of results from study 1. (a, b) Mean final estimate difference as a function of evidence asymmetry for the low and high PDI groups independently(Table S18 andS19). Solid lines and shaded regions reflect the mean and SEM of the weighted Bayesian model fits. The center inset shows the exponential fit of the distribution of PDI global scores from study 1 (grey line) and study 2 (black line), indicating the cutoffs for high and low PDI by vertical dashed lines. (c, d) Logit-belief updates as a function of logit prior by bead ratio for the low (c; Table S20) and high (d; Table S21) PDI groups. Group medians of individual medians for logit-belief updates are shown and other conventions follow Figure 3c. Solid lines and shaded regions reflect medians and 95% bootstrapped confidence intervals of the weighted Bayesian model fits. (e) Evidence asymmetry slopes are plotted against 1 by group. Other conventions as in Figure 3e. Marginal violin plots show the group medians and interquartile ranges. The asterisk indicates a significant rank-sum test comparing group medians of 1 . (f) Mean final estimate differences are plotted against 1 . The marginal violin plot shows the group medians and interquartile ranges. (e, f) The solid black line shows model predictions as in Figures 2e-f. As in</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Prior underweighting relates to belief oddity outside the laboratory. (a) Summary of group-level differences</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>for model-based and model-agnostic measures between the low (n = 57) and high (n = 34) PDI groups. Bar plots are effect size (Cliff's delta, δ) and 95% confidence intervals. (b) Scatterplot showing a negative correlation between ranked mean PDI scores and 1 (n = 116). Values are adjusted by 2 ( ) parameter values and the model fit (RMSE) for specificity as in the partial Spearman correlation analysis. Boxplots show medians (blue lines) and 25 th and 75 th percentiles (bottom and top edges, respectively). The solid black line reflects the leastsquares linear fit to the data points. Mean PDI is the average of the global PDI scores across the pre-screening and the experimental sessions for each participant.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 6 . 2 , 2 . 2 , 2 �. 2 ( 3 )</head><label>6222223</label><figDesc>Relationship between prior underweighting, prior noise, and response variance. (a) Visual Schematic of Noisy Sampling Model. The noisy-sampling model captures an iterative sequential belief updating process where the internal representation of prior (and likelihood information) is noisy (see Methods). This is based on an agents' uncertainty about the true values of the prior and likelihood, given recent evidence, with variances 2 and ℎ and their assumed distributions of priors and likelihoods, with variances 2 and ℎ Note that variables are in logit space and noise consists of an additive zero-mean Gaussian distribution. Critical to the model are a noisy representation of the prior and likelihood where the noise is given by the functions � 2 , More noise (e.g., due to higher 2 ) leads to more random variability in responses reflecting the posterior belief (even for repetitions of identical sequence fragments, as captured by the model-agnostic measure of response variance). Optimal inference results from adjusting weighting commensurate with the degree of noise, with optimal weights given by the functions � 2 , 2 � and � ℎ Finally, the optimal posterior is a weighted sum of the noisy prior and noisy likelihood in logit space. Model fitting used 4 free parameters, (Methods). (b) Scatterplot of ranked response variance rank and 1 showing a negative relationship indicating that individuals with more sequential base-rate neglect have more variability in their probability estimates for identical sequence fragments (Methods). (c) Scatterplot of ranked response variance and prior noise 2 showing a positive relationship indicating that the model-agnostic measure of response variability scales with the model-derived measure of prior noise. (b, c) Boxplots reflect median (blue) and 25 th and 75 th percentiles (bottom and top edges, respectively). Black lines show the least-squares linear fit of the data points. (e, f) Noise-corrupted parameter recovery analysis for the weighted Bayesian model (e) and the noisy-sampling model (f). The y-axis shows the percent deviation in the recovered versus the original parameter values. The x-axis shows the magnitude of the late Gaussian noise added at the response level in the model simulations in standard deviation. Each grey line depicts a single agent defined by a set of parameter values across a range of noise levels. The red shaded area indicates the estimated range of response variance found in the actual data as a 95% confidence interval based on the median response variance (see methods). On average (black line), the critical parameters are adequately recovered, without systematic biases in their estimation for meaningful levels of late Gaussian noise (particularly for the weighted Bayesian model), indicating that low-level factors such as general inattention or random responding are unlikely to explain variability in 1 values.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>all 0.40&gt;p&gt;0.12, rank sum tests; 0.18&gt;δ&gt;-0.53) or in response variance (p =0.12, rank-sum test; δ = -0.20;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Prior noise relates to belief oddity outside the laboratory. (a) Summary of group-level differences for noisy-sampling model-based and model-agnostic measures between the low (n = 57) and high (n = 34) PDI groups. Bar plots are effect size (Cliff's delta, δ) and 95% confidence intervals. (b) Scatterplot showing a positive correlation between ranked mean PDI scores and 2 (n = 116). Values are adjusted by ( ) parameter values and the model fit (RMSE) for specificity as in the partial Spearman correlation analysis. Boxplots show medians (blue lines) and 25 th and 75 th percentiles (bottom and top edges, respectively). The solid black line reflects the least-squares linear fit to the data points. Mean PDI is the average of the global PDI scores across the pre-screening and the experimental sessions for each participant.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>2 ,</head><label>2</label><figDesc>If the signal is against the true underlying state of the hidden box, the posterior would be:The 1 and 2( ) parameters in the weighted Bayesian model correspond respectively to the weights (γ ) ⁄and (γℎ ℎ ) ⁄in the noisy-sampling model and are thus inversely proportional to the noise parameters, and ℎ respectively. They are also inversely proportional to the parameters<ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> and ℎ 2representing the assumed uncertainty in the underlying logit prior and likelihood distributions. In visual schematic of the model inFigure 6, the prior weight is framed as the function � 2 , 2 � = γ prior , the likelihood weight as the function � model, consistent with previous work<ref type="bibr" target="#b124">121</ref> we assumed that participants would adapt to the context of the task, acquiring a realistic estimate of the uncertainty underlying logit prior and likelihood distributions. Under this assumption 2 and ℎ 2 should be relatively constant across participants, and the primary source of interindividual variability should be reflected in the<ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> and ℎ 2 parameters. To avoid the possibility of parameter trade-off, our primary analysis fixed the 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>may similarly take on different values<ref type="bibr" target="#b50">51</ref> , 60 2 or 90 2 per condition. The complete generative model over true possible situations and the participants' noisy internal representations is specified by eight parameters: 2 Conditional on the prior (before the observation of a new bead draw), we can determine what optimal Bayesian inference of the true underlying state of the hidden box would be. The equations described above imply that the true log-odds (based on previously available</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>or</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>ℎ</cell><cell>. Further,</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>, 51 2 , 60 2 ,</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">90 2 , 2 , 51 2 , 60 2 , and 90 2 .</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>information),</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">≡ log�</cell><cell>⁄</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">�, and the prior have a joint, bivariate, Gaussian</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">distribution. Consequently, the distribution of</cell><cell cols="2">conditional on the noisy representation of</cell></row><row><cell>the prior,</cell><cell cols="6">, will also be a Gaussian distribution:</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>�</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">~ �γ prior •</cell><cell>, Σ prior 2</cell><cell>�,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">where γ prior ≡</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2 + 2</cell><cell>and Σ prior 2</cell><cell>≡</cell><cell>2 2</cell><cell>• 2 + 2</cell></row></table><note>ℎ</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">( ) parameters and the model RMSE (ρ = −0.22, p = 0.021;Figure 5candTable S23). The relationship with 1 also held after controlling for demographic variables including age, biological sex, race, education, handedness, smoking and drug use status, and previous hospitalizations for psychiatric and neurological conditions ( = −0.24, = 0.021), and none of these variables related to PDI scores. Our secondary measure of odd beliefs, the Paranoia Checklist, also correlated with 1 (ρ = −0.23, p = 0.014) and the prior-dependent belief-updating (ρ = −0.12, p = 0.039). Overall, the results of study 2 suggest that a laboratory measure of sequential base-rate neglect relates specifically to odd beliefs outside the laboratory.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Errors in probabilistic reasoning and judgment biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Behavioral Economics: Applications and Foundations</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Base-Rate Neglect: Foundations and Implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bodoh-Creed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the psychology of prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="251" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes Rule as a Descriptive Model: The Representativeness Heuristic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Grether</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Q. J. Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="537" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The base-rate fallacy in probability judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bar-Hillel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychol. (Amst.)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="233" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive bias in clinical medicine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>O'sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schofield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. R. Coll. Physicians Edinb</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="232" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The paradox of precision medicine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kimmelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Tannock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Clin. Oncol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="342" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clinical reasoning about new symptoms despite preexisting disease: sources of error and order effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bergus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gjerde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Elstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fam. Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="314" to="320" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Physicians neglect base rates, and it matters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hamm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Brain Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrate instead of ignoring: Base rate neglect as a common fallacy of petroleum explorers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Milkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AAPG Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1905" to="1916" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Neglect of Base Rate Data by Human Resources Managers in Employee Selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Whyte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sue-Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Can. J. Adm. Sci. Rev. Can. Sci. Adm</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Neglect the Base Rate: It&apos;s the Law!</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.2192423</idno>
		<ptr target="https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=2192423" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Law Doesn&apos;t Say Much About Base Rates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schweizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.2329387</idno>
		<ptr target="https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=2329387" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring information use in children&apos;s decision-making: Base-rate neglect and trust in testimony</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gualtieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Buchsbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Denison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Psychol. Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1527</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019-12-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Three Models of Sequential Belief Updating on Uncertain Evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hawthorne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Philos. Log</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noisy Memory and Over-Reaction to News</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Azeredo</forename><surname>Da Silveira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AEA Pap. Proc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="557" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking delusions: A selective review of delusion research through a computational lens</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ashinoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Singletary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Horga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.schres.2021.01.023</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr. Res. S0920996421000657</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Keep it real: rethinking the primacy of experimental control in cognitive neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nastase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Goldstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Hasson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">222</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">117254</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Law and order effects: on cognitive dissonance and belief perseverance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Maegherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ask</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Horselenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Koppen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry Psychol. Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clinical Diagnosis and the Order of Information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bergus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Ely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Oppliger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Med. Decis. Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="412" to="417" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisited: The Importance of Chronology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Favere-Marchesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Audit. J. Pract</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Order Effects</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supporting Better Decisions: How Order Effects Influence Decision Support System Alignment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Marquardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grimes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interact. Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="469" to="479" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing Information Order Effects in a Long Series of Evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C I K</forename><surname>Keltz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Adelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eng. Manag. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Order effects in belief updating: The belief-adjustment model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hogarth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Einhorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognit. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Order effects in belief updating with consistent and inconsistent evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tubbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gaeth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A V</forename><surname>Osdol</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Behav. Decis. Mak</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="269" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human Belief Revision and the Order Effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Annu. Meet. Cogn. Sci. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The order effect in human abductive reasoning: an empirical and computational study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Theor. Artif. Intell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Comparison of the Belief-Adjustment Model and the Quantum Inference Model as Explanations of Order Effects in Human Inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Quantum Probability Account of Order Effects in Inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1518" to="1552" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential effects in response time reveal learning mechanisms and event representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Curran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mozer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wilder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="628" to="666" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A distinct inferential mechanism for delusions in schizophrenia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Konova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Horga</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">142</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1797" to="1812" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Enke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Cognitive</forename><surname>Graeber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Uncertainty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.3489380</idno>
		<ptr target="https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=3489380" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Order effects in sequentially judged options due to the direction of comparison</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bruine De Bruin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Keren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Behav. Hum. Decis. Process</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The primacy order effect in complex decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Le Goff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Abadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Courrieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s00426-019-01178-2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing bayes rule and the representativeness heuristic: Some experimental evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Grether</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econ. Behav. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rules for Experimenting in Psychology and Economics, and Why They Differ. in Understanding Strategic Interaction: Essays in</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Albers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Güth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hammerstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Moldovanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Van Damme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-642-60495-9_25</idno>
		<editor>Honor of Reinhard Selten</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="327" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Belief Elicitation in the Laboratory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schotter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Trevino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu. Rev. Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating replicability of laboratory experiments in economics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">351</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1433" to="1436" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The binarized scoring rule</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Okui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Econ. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="984" to="1001" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective probability: A judgment of representativeness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognit. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="430" to="454" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Base-Rate Neglect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Cognitive Illusions: Intriguing Phenomena in Judgement, Thinking and Memory</title>
		<editor>ed. Pohl, R. F.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who uses base rates andP(D/∼H)? An analysis of individual differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stanovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mem. Cognit</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="179" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual differences in reasoning: Implications for the rationality debate?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stanovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Brain Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="665" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Base rates: Both neglected and intuitive</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Trippas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Handley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Psychol. Learn. Mem. Cogn</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="544" to="554" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Normative evidence accumulation in unpredictable environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Glaze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">8825</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A bias-variance trade-off governs individual differences in on-line learning in an unpredictable environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Glaze</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">14</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of Abbreviated Nine-item Forms of the Raven&apos;s Standard Progressive Matrices Test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bilker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="354" to="369" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Characterizing a psychiatric symptom dimension related to deficits in goal-directed control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kosinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Whelan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11305</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Delusional Ideation: The 21-Item Peters et al. Delusions Inventory (PDI)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Day</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Garety</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1005" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jumping to conclusions and the continuum of delusional beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Warman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lysaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Haudenschield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Res. Ther</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1255" to="1269" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reasoning biases in delusion-prone individuals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Linney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ayton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br. J. Clin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="302" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting outliers: Do not use standard deviation around the mean, use absolute deviation around the median</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Leys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bernard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Licata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="764" to="766" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inflexible social inference in individuals with subclinical persecutory delusional tendencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Wellstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">215</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="344" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Validity and utility of Hierarchical Taxonomy of Psychopathology (HiTOP): II. Externalizing superspectrum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Krueger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prediction of psychopathology and functional impairment by positive and negative schizotypy in the Chapmans&apos; ten-year longitudinal study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kwapil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silvia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Barrantes-Vidal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Abnorm. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="807" to="815" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Putatively psychosis-prone subjects 10 years later</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kwapil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eckblad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Zinser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Abnorm. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">171</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994-09-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bounded Rationality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Eatwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milgate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-349-20568-4_5</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Utility and Probability</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Palgrave Macmillan UK</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Individual differences in epistemically suspect beliefs: The role of susceptibility to cognitive biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Šrol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/4jcf7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://osf.io/4jcf7" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Paranormal Beliefs and Cognitive Processes Underlying the Formation of Delusions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Dagnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Drinkwater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paranormal belief and reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Dagnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Munley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personal. Individ. Differ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1406" to="1415" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probability misjudgment, cognitive ability, and belief in the paranormal</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Musch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ehrenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br. J. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="177" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the reception and detection of pseudo-profound bullshit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cheyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Barr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fugelsang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Koehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgm. Decis. Mak</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why should we try to think like scientists? Scientific reasoning and susceptibility to epistemically suspect beliefs and cognitive biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Čavojová</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Šrol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jurkovič</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Cogn. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="95" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biases and Variability from Costly Bayesian Inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Prat-Carrabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Meyniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tsodyks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Azeredo Da Silveira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entropy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">603</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Afrouzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Kwon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Landier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Thesmar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Working</forename><surname>Overreaction</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Memory</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3386/w27947</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.nber.org/papers/w27947.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Optimally Imprecise Memory and Biased Forecasts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Da Silveira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Sung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3386/w28075</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.nber.org/papers/w28075.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Seeing is believing: Priors, trust, and base rate neglect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Welsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Behav. Hum. Decis. Process</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Imprecise neural computations as a source of adaptive behaviour in volatile environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Findling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chopin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Koechlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-020-00971-z</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient sampling and noisy decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Heng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polania</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">54962</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational noise in rewardguided learning drives behavioral variability in volatile environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Findling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Skvortsova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dromnelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2066" to="2077" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Perceptual decisions result from the continuous accumulation of memory and sensory evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bornstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/186817</idno>
		<idno>doi:10.1101/186817</idno>
		<ptr target="http://biorxiv.org/lookup/doi/10.1101/186817" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceptual Decision-Making as Probabilistic Inference by Neural Sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Haefner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Berkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="649" to="660" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision Making and Sequential Sampling from Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="927" to="939" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational Precision of Mental Inference as Critical Source of Human Choice Suboptimality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-D</forename><surname>Devauchelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Koechlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1398" to="1411" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural Variability and Sampling-Based Probabilistic Representations in the Visual Cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Orbán</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Berkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lengyel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="530" to="543" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistically optimal perception and learning: from behavior to neural representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Berkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Orbán</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lengyel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpreting Neural Response Variability as Monte Carlo Sampling of the Posterior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Hoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hyvärinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<editor>Becker, S., Thrun, S. &amp; Obermayer, K.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="300" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of learning to infer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Dasgupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="412" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Delusion Proneness is Linked to a Reduced Usage of Prior Beliefs in Perceptual Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stuke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Weilnhammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sterzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schmack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Religion and delusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mckay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="166" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overly Strong Priors for Socially Meaningful Visual Signals Are Linked to Psychosis Proneness in Healthy Individuals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stuke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kress</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Weilnhammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sterzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schmack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1083</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dogmatism manifests in lowered information search under uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rollwage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31527" to="31534" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical Bayesian models of social inference for probing persecutory delusional ideation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Diaconescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Wellstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kasper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mathys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stephan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Abnorm. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="556" to="569" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conspiracy beliefs in the general population: The importance of psychopathology, cognitive style and educational attainment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Georgiou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Delfabbro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Balzan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personal. Individ. Differ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">151</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">109521</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social functioning impairments in schizotypy when social cognition and neurocognition are not impaired</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Aghvinian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sergi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr. Res. Cogn</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Associations of psychotic-like experiences, related symptoms, and working memory with functioning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Chun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ellman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. Psychiatry J. Assoc. Eur. Psychiatr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jumping to conclusions, a lack of belief flexibility and delusional conviction in psychosis: A longitudinal investigation of the structure, frequency, and relatedness of reasoning biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Abnorm. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">129</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jumping to conclusions and perceptions in early psychosis: Relationship with delusional beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Colbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Garety</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognit. Neuropsychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="422" to="440" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Specificity of the jump-toconclusions bias in deluded patients</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Thornton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Siksou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Linney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Maccabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br. J. Clin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reasoning in Deluded Schizophrenic and Paranoid Patients: Biases in Performance on a Probabilistic Inference Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A M P</forename><surname>Garety</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R P D</forename><surname>Hemsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M R C P</forename><surname>Wessely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Nerv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">179</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="194" to="201" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Normal and abnormal reasoning in people with delusions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E J</forename><surname>Dudley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Over</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br. J. Clin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="258" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic judgements in deluded and non-deluded subjects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Huq</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Garety</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hemsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Q. J. Exp. Psychol. Sect. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="801" to="812" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Association of the Jumping to Conclusions and Evidence Integration Biases With Delusions in Psychosis: A Detailed Meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mclean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mattiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Balzan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="344" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Delusions and the &quot;Jumping to Conclusions&quot; Reasoning Bias: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dudley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wickham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Psychosis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="652" to="665" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jumping to Conclusions About the Beads Task? A Meta-analysis of Delusional Ideation and Data-Gathering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mckay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Coltheart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Langdon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1183" to="1191" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">And Psychosis Liability: Findings From The Multi-Centre EU-GEI Case-Control Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tripoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/634352</idno>
		<idno>doi:10.1101/634352</idno>
		<ptr target="http://biorxiv.org/lookup/doi/10.1101/634352" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">General Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Jumping To Conclusions</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computation noise in human learning and decision-making: origin, impact, function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Findling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Behav. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Computation noise promotes cognitive resilience to adverse conditions during decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Findling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>. 2020.06.10.145300</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/2020.06.10.145300v1</idno>
		<idno>doi:10.1101/2020.06.10.145300</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.06.10.145300v1" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information order effects in clinical psychological diagnoses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Cwik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Margraf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clin. Psychol. Psychother</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1142" to="1154" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b100">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Medical Decision Scripts: Combining Cognitive Scripts and Judgment Strategies to</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hamm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b101">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Account Fully for Medical Decision</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/047001332X.ch15</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Thinking: Psychological Perspectives on Reasoning</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Ltd</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="315" to="345" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b102">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why the sun will not set on the endowment effect: the endowment effect after loss aversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b103">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a positive theory of consumer choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Econ. Behav. Organ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b104">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strictly Proper Scoring Rules, Prediction, and Estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gneiting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Stat</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b105">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Assoc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="359" to="378" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b106">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological investigation of the structure of paranoia in a non-clinical population</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br. J. Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">186</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="435" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b107">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gorilla in our midst: An online behavioral experiment builder</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Anwyl-Irvine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Massonnié</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Flitton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kirkham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Evershed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Res. Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b108">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bullet trains and steam engines: Exogenous attention zips but endogenous attention chugs along</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Chakravarthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Vanrullen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Vis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b109">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating the Dimension of a Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Stat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="464" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b110">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Aguinis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Villamor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ramani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Research</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review and Recommendations. J</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b111">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="823" to="837" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b112">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hosting and Recruiting: A Brief Introduction to Running Behavioral Experiments Online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sauter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Draschkow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Mack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Building</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">251</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b113">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How to Run Behavioural Experiments Online: Best Practice Suggestions for Cognitive Psychology and Neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Gagné</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Franzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/nt67j</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/nt67j" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Preprint at</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b114">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reputation as a sufficient condition for data quality on Amazon Mechanical Turk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Peer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vosgerau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acquisti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Res. Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1023" to="1031" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b115">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An assessment of exclusion methods and interactive experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Clifford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Validity</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Turk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="197" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b116">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conducting interactive experiments online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Arechar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gächter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Molleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Exp. Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b117">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Running Experiments on Amazon Mechanical Turk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Paolacci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chandler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ipeirotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b118">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating Variation in Replicability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="152" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b119">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating significance in linear mixed-effects models in R</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Luke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Res. Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1494" to="1502" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b120">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computation of measures of effect size for neuroscience data sets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hentschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Stüttgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. J. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1887" to="1894" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b121">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Matlab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b122">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">VBA: A Probabilistic Treatment of Nonlinear Models for Neurobiological and Behavioural Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Adam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Rigoux</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Comput. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1003441</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b123">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Semi-analytical approximations to statistical moments of sigmoid and softmax mappings of normal variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b124">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cognitive Imprecision and Small-Stakes Risk Aversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Khaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Rev</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b125">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econ. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
