<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Shiny App for Teachers to Track Daily Student Wellbeing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Avery</forename><surname>Chahl</surname></persName>
							<email>averychahl@psu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Human Development and Family Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Pennsylvania State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>16802</postCode>
									<settlement>University Park</settlement>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Shiny App for Teachers to Track Daily Student Wellbeing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>RShiny</term>
					<term>application</term>
					<term>dashboard</term>
					<term>research translation</term>
					<term>education</term>
					<term>teachers</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>This article describes an R Shiny application to plot and track student coping skills use, as well as stress, and feelings about school and friends. The application is built to process daily data and produce simple visualizations, as manual tracking of student wellbeing is demanding on school personnel. This paper illustrates the use of this application. Such data-driven decision making may have long term implications for improving student academic and social emotional outcomes.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Research translation is a critical yet undervalued area. Data driven decision making can have major impacts on communities and society as a whole. Education particularly can benefit from a wholistic data driven approach to facilitating the learning and development of youth. Social emotional competency is one way to develop adults who are happy and productive members of society. One key factor in creating a classroom climate promotive of social and emotional growth is teacher's awareness of students emotional states <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Jennings &amp; Greenberg, 2009)</ref>. If applicable, knowledge of student coping and regulation techniques is also important. Many school-based interventions have attempted to do this <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Goldberg et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Kuypers, 2011)</ref>. The goal of the present application is to track student data and produce simple visualizations in a user-friendly application.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implementation</head><p>Here a Shiny application is introduced, it is a dashboard that tracks student emotions, feelings about friends and school, and usage of emotional regulation techniques, each of which has its own tab in the application. The following shows a sample dashboard using example data. The dashboard is designed to use daily surveys taken by students in each classroom. That data would then be fed into the application. Each teacher would get their own Shiny application, potentially launched via shiny.io where they can access a link with their individualized classroom dashboard.</p><p>The first page of the dashboard shows a waffle plot displaying a macro level view of student stress (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> below). This displays class-wide stress levels at a glance. Below is page two which displays student-level coping skill use across the school year (see <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>). This will demonstrate which coping skills are most popular for each student and may inform which skills teachers want to prompt when students display emotional dysregulation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2. Coping Skill (SEL Technique) Use by Student Across the Semester</head><p>• The bars each indicate a different coping skill and a count of how many times the skill has been used this semester by the student. • The plot includes a dropdown menu to look at different students' use of the various coping skills taught in the classroom.</p><p>The next page of the dashboard shows each student's feelings about their peers (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>). This can inform the teacher which children are not feeling good about their peers, which may be an indicator of peer problems and can prompt the teacher to learn more. The orange line indicates the class average, which is a quick way to draw the eye to which students are reporting worse feelings about peers than their classmates. Next is a bar chart showing each student's feelings about school (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4)</ref>. This gives the teacher information about how each student is feeling about school in general. If the student is indicating they don't feel good about school, the teacher may investigate further and determine if something is wrong. The average line can draw the teacher's attention to which students are feeling worse about school than their peers. This page shows student-level stress across the school year (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5</ref>). This line chart shows how high the students' average stress level is for the month. The plot is created using the plotly package in R Shiny which has more options for plot interactivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Sievert, 2020)</ref>. The following figure <ref type="figure">(Figure 6a)</ref> shows an additional capability of the stress plot referenced above ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5)</ref>. When you double click on a specific student's line, you are able to get a closer look at their stress trajectory. You can double click a second student's line and view both at the same time to compare them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 6a. Closer Look at One Student's Stress</head><p>• After double clicking on a single student's line, or their name on the right-hand side, you can view that student's line in isolation. The axes will auto scale for a closer look.</p><p>This <ref type="figure">figure (Figure 6b</ref>) is another capability of the aforementioned stress plot tab. This demonstrates the cursor hover capabilities. By hovering over a line, the popover will display line information including the student's name. This is especially useful in areas of the plot where many lines overlap, and it is challenging to discern which line belongs to which child.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 6b. Hover Capabilities on Student Stress Plot</head><p>• When you mouse over a student's line, a popover appears giving student-specific information.</p><p>Lastly, the final dashboard tab shows a subset of the Shiny App code for the curious user. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Student Wellness Dashboard Home Page • Each box of the waffle plot indicates one student. The colors indicate high (red), medium (yellow), and low average stress (green) for the month. • At the bottom of every tab is a laymen's interpretation of the plot to guide understanding.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Feelings About Peers• Each bar represents a student, and the height of the bar indicates how they are feeling about their friends.Higher numbers indicate better feelings about friends. • The orange line indicates the classroom average.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Feelings About School • Each bar represents a student, and the height of the bar indicates how they are feeling about school. Higher numbers indicate better feelings about school. • The orange line indicates the classroom average.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Stress Across the Semester• Each line indicates a singular student's stress across the semester. Higher scores indicate more stress.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Subset of Shiny App Code• Subset of the app's code.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>First and foremost, I would like to acknowledge Gregory M. Fosco as the originial creator of this dashboard idea, without his orignial conceptualization, I would not have been inspried to implment and expand upon it.</p><p>I would like to thank Ellen Chen, website co-developer and undergraduate research assistant. Ellen provided a substantial amount of novel code for this project. She is an exceptional research assistant, who has also provided consultation on app components and data visualization.</p><p>I would also like to thank Mengyun Chen, graduate research assistant, who harnessing her clinical knowledge provided critical early consultation on app use and data visualization.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusions</head><p>This paper illustrates a Shiny application, which is a dashboard for facilitating teacher knowledge of student emotions, feelings about school and peers, and emotion regulation skills use. This application aims to promote teacher knowledge of individual student states as well as ease the cognitive burden of committing each student's status to memory. It intends to promote scaffolding of student emotional regulation by giving the teachers the information needed to detect if students can benefit from prompts to engage in emotional regulation techniques. Powerful tools like this that combine modern technological capabilities to better understand youth are critical in forwarding the field of education. Future directions include widespread improvement and implementation of such tools.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effectiveness of interventions adopting a whole school approach to enhancing social and emotional development: a meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sklad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Elfrink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M G</forename><surname>Schreurs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bohlmeijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10212-018-0406-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10212-018-0406-9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Psychology of Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="755" to="782" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Prosocial Classroom: Teacher Social and Emotional Competence in Relation to Student and Classroom Outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Jennings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3102/0034654308325693</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654308325693" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of Educational Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="491" to="525" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The zones of regulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kuypers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>Think Social Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>San Jose</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Interactive Web-Based Data Visualization with R, plotly, and shiny</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sievert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://plotly-r.com" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
