<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Public communication alters private confidence</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Einar</forename><surname>Andreassen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Birkbeck</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute of Philosophy</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Advanced Study</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Wellcome Centre for Human Neuroimaging</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Yon</surname></persName>
							<email>d.yon@bbk.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Birkbeck</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Advanced Study</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Public communication alters private confidence</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">Submitted as a preprint to PsyArXiv on 21st December 2024.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:36+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We use our private feelings of confidence to coordinate our public, social lives. For example, when making joint decisions we can share our uncertainty honestly to reach an accurate consensus, or exaggerate our confidence to exaggerate our influence on the group. Some theories in cognitive neuroscience suggest that we can strategically distort the confidence we express to others while leaving our private feelings unchanged. But other theories suppose that our interactions with others may be a key source of beliefs about uncertainty in our own minds. If the latter is true, communicating about confidence with others could alter introspection on ourselves. We tested this idea in a novel decision-making task, where participants made perceptual choices and gave confidence ratings alone, together with a partner and then alone again. Across studies, participants showed &apos;confidence matching&apos;, with the confidence they expressed gravitating towards the confidence of their partners. Most importantly, these shifts in reported confidence persisted even after the interaction terminated, and participants made decisions alone again. These effects can be captured by a new predictive learning model, which assumes that agents use the confidence expressed by themselves and others to predict the confidence they ought to feel. These results reveal how the dynamics of social interaction can shape our sense of confidence and point to a mechanism that explains how communication with others can change our private states of mind.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Our private feelings of confidence allows us to regulate and control our behaviour in a range of sophisticated ways -like allowing us to slow down or look again when we are uncertain <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> . But confidence plays a key role in regulating our social lives too <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> . For instance, when making decisions together we give more weight to opinions that are expressed with the most certainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7</ref> and when we give advice to others, we can adjust the confidence we communicate to exaggerate our influence or protect our reputation <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8</ref> . Some models in cognitive neuroscience suggest that we can strategically distort the confidence we express to others while keeping our private feelings unchanged -with separate brain regions encoding public and private confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9</ref> . However, recently we have hypothesised that changes in the way we communicate confidence to other people could also alter our own private metacognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10</ref> . In our theory, we assume that agents form beliefs about 'precision' of their own cognitive systems by integrating past expressions of confidence and uncertainty. Under this account, communicating about confidence with others could alter the inputs this learning mechanism receives -and thus in altering how represent ourselves to others, we may also alter how we represent ourselves to ourselves.</p><p>Here we investigated this possibility in the context of 'confidence matching' <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11</ref> . Previous work has found that when we make decisions with others, the confidence we express gravitates towards that of our partners: we begin to exaggerate the confidence we express when working more confident partners, and begin to downplay our confidence when collaborating with people who are more uncertain.</p><p>If our minds and brains can completely separate the confidence we communicate from the confidence we feel, we may expect that exaggerating or downplaying to others would have little effect on the confidence we feel in private. However, if we learn about the uncertainty in our own minds through social interaction with others, biases in how we communicate our uncertainty in public could also reflect a reshaping of the confidence representations we are left with when introspecting on our own (see <ref type="figure">Fig 1a)</ref>.</p><p>We compared these hypotheses in a novel perceptual metacognition task, where perceivers progress through making decisions alone, together with a partner and then alone again. To pre-empt our results, we found robust confidence matching in the joint decision making together phase -with participant confidence reports gravitating towards the confidence of their partner. Critically, we also find that these interaction-induced biases in confidence persisted even when participants were alone again, and had strong incentives to report their confidence honestly. Computational modelling revealed that these effects can be captured by a learning and inference model which uses metacognitive prediction errors from ourselves and others to form beliefs about uncertainty in our own mind. In sum, these results reveal how public communication with others can alter our private metacognitive states of mind.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Making decisions alone and together</head><p>Across two experiments, participants (N = 204) completed a perceptual decision-making task. On each trial they judged whether a brief cloud of dots moved left or right, giving a combined decision and confidence rating by placing a marker on a sliding scale (see <ref type="figure">Fig 1b)</ref>. Participants earned more points for expressing higher confidence in correct choices, but likewise lost more points for expressing higher confidence in errors.</p><p>Participants completed the task over three consecutive phases alone, together and alone again. The alone and alone again phases were identical and involved participants observing stimuli and making choices on their own. However, in the together phase participants were led to believe they made judgements with another observer, completing the task at the same time as them. After making their choices, participants observed the decision (and confidence rating) made by their 'partner' as an additional marker on the rating scale (see <ref type="figure">Fig 1c)</ref>. On any given trial, the most confident decision reported by either agent was recorded as the 'joint' choice, and this choice was used to determine the participant's wins or losses on that trial.</p><p>Despite the cover story, decisions from the 'partner' in the together phase were in fact generated by an algorithm programmed to make generally confident or generally uncertain decisions with the same overall accuracy as the real participant. Participants were randomly assigned to complete the task with the confident or uncertain partner, allowing us to assess whether participant confidence gravitates towards the partner in the together phase (i.e., 'confidence matching' <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11</ref> ) and whether this induces lasting changes in confidence when the participant returns to introspecting alone.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1: Hypothesis and experimental task: a)</head><p>Prior work suggests that we may exaggerate the confidence we express to 'match' the confidence of others. In this way, somebody who (e.g.) feels privately uncertain (left) may exaggerate their confidence to match the certitude of a more confident partner (middle). Our key hypothesis, though, is that these changes in confidence in social situations may have a lasting impact on how confidence is constructed even once the social interaction is over (right). b) We tested this prediction by having participants complete a perceptual decision making task (judging moving dot clouds) alone, together with a partner and alone again. c) In the together phase of the experiment, participants made their own choice and confidence rating (yellow) before seeing the choice and confidence of their partner (blue). Participants were randomly assigned to conditions where the partner was either programmed to respond with generally high or generally low confidence. With both decisions registered, the computer selected the decision expressed with the highest confidence as the group choice (e.g., in this case, the partner's choice 'left' is selected as it was expressed with higher confidence than the participant's own choice of 'right'). (NB: labels for 'your decision' and 'partner decision' are for illustration purposes only, and did not appear to participants during the task)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Confidence 'matches' and matching persists</head><p>In both experiments we found robust confidence matching (Exp 1: F1,78 = 6.834, p = .011; Exp 2: F1,122 = 18.017, p &lt; .001, see <ref type="figure">Fig 2a)</ref>. This reflected the fact that participants began to express more confidence when interacting with the confident partner compared to the uncertain partner in the together phase (Exp 1: t78= -2.253, p = .027; Exp 2: t122 = -4.569, p &lt; .001; see <ref type="figure">Fig 2a)</ref>. At an individual subject level, these shifts occurred because individual confidence reports gravitated towards the confidence of the decision partner in the together phase (Exp 1: t79 = 3.141, p = .002; Exp 2: t123 = 4.668, p &lt; .001; see <ref type="figure">Fig 2b )</ref>. This concords well with previous reports of confidence matching in joint decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11</ref> .</p><p>More intriguingly though, we also found that differences in decision confidence persisted into the alone again phase. Rather than returning back to baseline, participants continued to express higher confidence after interacting with the confident partner compared to the uncertain partner (Exp 1: t78= 2.582, p = .012; Exp 2: t122 = -3.086, p = .003; see <ref type="figure">Fig. 2a</ref>). This suggests that confidence matching does not simply reflect a strategic shift in how uncertainty is communicated during social interaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9</ref> ; but a lasting change in metacognition brought about by interacting with others 5,10 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2: Confidence 'matches' and matching persists: a)</head><p>In both experiments, we find that at the group level participant confidence is exaggerated when interacting with more confident partners and attenuated when interacting with uncertain ones -and this bias remains when participants are alone again. b) At an individual level, this effect arises because participant confidence becomes more similar to the partner's confidence level during interaction (i.e., any dot over the dashed line reports confidence that 'gravitates' towards the partner, any dot below becomes more dissimilar).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Modelling metacognitive learning from self and others</head><p>We used computational modelling to investigate how making decisions with others could lead to these metacognitive biases. We start from the premise that agents can form beliefs about the confidence they will feel in different settings, and these prior beliefs can be integrated into metacognition to affect the confidence that we feel <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13</ref> . For instance, we have shown previously that agents can learn to have more confidence in their senses when perception has been reliable in the past, and these learned expectations bias subjective confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12</ref> . Here we extend this idea, assuming that agents form prior beliefs about confidence by tracking their own (past) confidence and the confidence expressed by other people. These expectations -shaped in part by others -then percolate into the subjective confidence that is felt. We constructed a model of metacognitive learning and inference, where agents form estimates of perceptual confidence by combining incoming sensory data with prior beliefs about the confidence they expect to feel -learned by tracking themselves and others. As a first step, we begin by estimating how observers map objective sensory signals on a given trial into subjective feelings of confidence at 'baseline' -that is, in the first alone phase of the experiment before they have interacted with a partner. This is achieved by fitting a cumulative gaussian function to data from this phase -parametrised by a slope ( ) and bias ( ) value -which maps sensory evidence in the moving dot clouds into 'confidence evidence' that is used to create subjective feelings of confidence (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Material)</ref>. This follows recent theoretical developments in metacognition research that cast subjective confidence as a noisy read out of evidence in low-level circuits 14 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">= 1 2 [1 + ( − √2 )] (Eq. 1)</formula><p>In subsequent steps, our model combines this mapping function with algorithms that learn the level of confidence agents ought to expect based on past experiences. These expectations are combined with the metacognitive evidence generated by the stimulus on each trial. This means that confidence ratings are determined by a mixture of the ambiguity in the current stimulus and the expectations that participants have formed about the confidence they will feel. In particular, on each trial the participant's felt confidence is generated by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">= • + • (Eq. 2)</formula><p>Where:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">= 1 − (Eq. 3)</formula><p>Here the ConfEvidence is created by passing the current stimulus through the mapping function estimated in the first step (Eq 1). This captures the 'unadulterated' confidence this participant would be expected to feel when faced with this stimulus, without the influence of any prior beliefs. However, this evidence is then combined with ConfPrior, which captures the prior belief that agents hold about the confidence they are likely to feel. The parameter Wprior controls the extent to which agents rely on incoming evidence over this prior belies when constructing feelings of confidence. In effect, higher values of Wprior have a 'smoothing' quality on confidence ratings, such that confidence is more closely connected to confidence felt in the past rather than the properties of the current stimulus.</p><p>Our model assumes that agents arrive at this metacognitive prior in the first place by integrating the confidence they have already experienced across the experiment, computing trial-by-trial prediction errors to update their metacognitive beliefs. One prediction error that participant can experience during the task is the self prediction error ( ), which captures the difference between the confidence participants reported on the current trial and their initial expectation (see <ref type="figure">Fig 3a,</ref> yellow):</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">= − (Eq. 4)</formula><p>We also assume that agents can experience other prediction errors ( ℎ ), which capture the difference between the confidence ratings given by the partner on the current trial and that same initial expectation (see <ref type="figure">Fig 3a,</ref> blue):</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">ℎ = − (Eq. 5)</formula><p>These self and other prediction errors are combined into a composite prediction error , where the weighting towards self or other learning signals is controlled by the parameter wself: Participants with high values of wself form metacognitive priors that are more strongly informed by fluctuations in their own confidence, while participants with lower values of wself form metacognitive expectations that are more strongly influenced by the partner's confidence.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">= • + ℎ • ℎ (Eq. 6) = 1 − ℎ (Eq. 7)</formula><p>Our model then finally assumes the metacognitive prior belief for the next trial is updated using the Rescorla-Wagner 'delta rule' <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16</ref> . The magnitude of the belief update is controlled by the learning rate alpha (α).</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">+1 = + • (Eq. 8)</formula><p>This updated prior belief is then combined with the stimulus on the next trial (as per Eq. 2) to determine how confident the agent feels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Simulating confidence matching when together and alone</head><p>In this learning and inference model there are five free parameters -σ, μ, α, wprior, wself. To establish whether this model could explain the confidence matching results seen in our experiments, we fit the model to our data and simulated behaviour from the best-fitting parameter values.</p><p>First, we found a close correspondence between simulated and empirical confidence ratings across the experiment -r204 = .970, p&lt;.001 (see <ref type="figure">Fig 3c)</ref>. Critically, analysing simulated behaviour in the same way as our empirical data also revealed the same effects: in the together phase participants working with the confident rather than uncertain partner showed higher confidence ratings -t202 = 6.709, p&lt;.001 -and this shift in confidence persisted into the alone again phase when the partner was removed -t202 = 5.281, p&lt;.001 (see <ref type="figure">Fig 3d)</ref>. Likewise, individual 'confidence matching' scores simulated from the model -capturing how the participant and partner confidence becomes more similar in the together relative to the alone phase -also showed a strong matching effect -t203 = 11.982, p&lt;.001. There was additionally a close correspondence between the empirical confidence matching effect found for each participant and the effect simulated by the model -r204 = .877, p&lt;.001 (see <ref type="figure">Fig 3e)</ref>. This suggests that our model can successfully reproduce the key empirical patterns we see in our real subjects.</p><p>We conducted further analyses to investigate which parameters in the model contribute to the success of these simulations. To achieve this, we performed a multiple linear regression analysis where individual parameter values for each participant -of σ, μ, α, wprior, wself. -were used as predictors of each subject's individual confidence matching effect simulated from the model. This analysis found that confidence matching effects in the model were significantly influenced by the subject's parameter values for wprior -t = 3.946, p&lt;.001 -and wself -t = -2.696, p=.008. This entails that more confidence matching was seen in participants who relied more on prior beliefs when constructing confidence reports (higher wprior) and who attended relatively more to other rather than self prediction errors during metacognitive learning (lower wself ). Variability in other parameters (σ, μ, α) did not consistently connect to the magnitude of these confidence biases (all p&gt;.469).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3:</head><p>Modelling metacognitive learning from self and others: a) Our model assumes that agents form and update beliefs about the confidence they expect to feel using prediction errors generated by themselves and others. Often these prediction errors can diverge. For instance, in this sketch an agent could find that they felt less confidence than they expected to (i.e., a negative prediction error compared to their prior belief) but their partner has expressed higher confidence than they had expected (i.e., a positive prediction error compared to metacognitive expectations). Whether this agent would adjust their expected confidence on the next trial upwards or downwards would depend on how these different prediction error signals are weighted during learning (controlled by the parameter wself . b) In our model, these prior beliefs are combined with incoming evidence to construct a subject's feeling of confidence on each trial. This allows us to simulate how confidence begins to change when participants interact with confident or uncertain partners, and how these changes may persist. c) Analysing simulated confidence from the model reproduces the same group-level effects as found in our empirical data. Moreover, the model is also successful in capturing individual variation in overall confidence (d) and individual variability in how much 'confidence matching' each participant displays (e).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Psychologists and neuroscientists have known for some time that the communication of confidence plays a key role in coordinating our social lives <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> . But to date it's remained unclear whether our interactions with others can also alter our private metacognitive states of mind.</p><p>Here we show for the first time that biases in how we communicate our confidence to others can also percolate into our own private representations of uncertainty. Both Experiments 1 and 2 reveal that participants exaggerate or downplay their confidence to match the uncertainty expressed by others, and these shifts in confidence remain when they return to making choices alone.</p><p>Our computational modelling suggests that the contagious nature of confidence can be well-explained by a model that assumes we learn about our own uncertainty by tracking the confidence of ourselves and others. Indeed, our analyses suggest that the magnitude of these socially-induced confidence biases is controlled by how much we rely on prediction errors from ourselves and other people when forming expectations about uncertainty (wself ) and how much in turn we rely on these expectations when introspecting on ourselves (wprior).</p><p>These results are consistent with Bayesian models of metacognition, which suppose that we construct feelings of confidence by forming and updating models of the confidence we expect to feel <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17</ref> . Here we this extend existing work by showing that these metacognitive beliefs are formed not only by tracking our own confidence (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19</ref> ) but also by tracking the confidence shared by others. Indeed, in Bayesian terms one could imagine that the wself parameter in our model reflects the 'precision' or weight assigned to self and other as we learn about uncertainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20</ref> while wprior corresponds to (implicit) beliefs that agents hold about the 'precision' or reliability of their prior beliefs <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10</ref> . Understanding the mechanisms setting these 'precision weights' could be important for understanding why some of us are more susceptible than others to this form of metacognitive social influence than others.</p><p>Indeed, these results raise important questions about the kinds of cognitive representations agents deploy when learning about confidence from other people. One could imagine that learning about confidence from another agent involves using mentalising processes to construct relatively rich representation of another agent's mind and the confidence they feel. However, it is worth noting that in our experiments confidence biases did not differ among participants who felt confident they interacting with another person and those who had doubts (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Material)</ref>. This pattern could suggest that these effects don't depend on rich mentalising processes that are only deployed when representing the minds of other people -and could instead arise from simpler, possibly domaingeneral processes that allow us to learn about our own minds by interacting with others <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">21</ref> .</p><p>In either case, our results dovetail well with recent theories which suggest that social and cultural processes play a key role in constructing our private metacognitive states <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22</ref> . For example, existing evidence suggests that sociocultural groups differ in the confidence they feel -with men reporting more confidence than women <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23</ref> , politicians reporting more confidence than scientists <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> , or people working in finance reporting higher confidence than the population at large <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25</ref> . Our results are consistent with the possibility that these differences in confidence arise at least in part due to different norms of communication among these groups -with biases to exaggerate or downplay confidence in the presence of overconfident or underconfident group members percolating into the private feelings of confidence individuals then privately feel.</p><p>However, our findings leave open important questions about how far our own metacognition can be shaped by interactions with others. For example, here we show that it may be possible to inherit the metacognitive biases of those we interact with, but it remains unclear whether such effects could generalise to other aspects of introspective ability -like metacognitive sensitivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26</ref> . In our experiments, we do not see changes in the quality of metacognitive insight after participants interact with confident or uncertain partners (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Material)</ref>, but the 'partners' in these studies are not programmed to have particularly high or low metacognitive sensitivity (see Methods). Future work could target this question directly, asking whether making decisions with 'wiser', better-calibrated metacognitive partners could yield comparable changes in the sensitivity of confidence -analogous to the changes in confidence bias we see here.</p><p>Our findings also leave open questions about when this kind of social influence on private metacognition will and won't take place. For instance, in our experiments our participants collaborate to make accurate joint choices, but comparable 'social shifts' in confidence can be seen in adversarial 'advice-giving' contexts -where competing agents exaggerate their confidence to gain more influence when they are being ignored <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8</ref> . It is unclear whether these kinds of confidence shifts would also percolate into private metacognition once the interaction context is removed. Indeed, one possibility is that the mergence of 'self' and 'other' confidence we see in our experiments only occurs because agents have common goals and shared experiences -as these factors moderate how far other predictive learning signals in the brain are attuned to the self or the other <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> . But this remains to be tested too.</p><p>In conclusion, we generally think of metacognitive feelings like confidence as fundamentally private affair. Though we are beginning to understand how the communication of confidence coordinates interacting groups, our results suggest that the social life of confidence may run even deeper. In communicating confidence with others, we begin to learn about the uncertainty in our own minds. In this way, the picture we see when we introspect on ourselves may be importantly calibrated by our interactions with others. Experimental task: Participants completed an online perceptual decision making and metacognition task programmed in PsychoPy <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28</ref> . On each trial, a fixation cross was displayed (1500 ms) followed by a cloud of moving (300 ms), then a blank screen (700 ms). Some of the dots were programmed to move coherently left or right, while the remainder of the dots moved in random directions. The difficulty of the perceptual decision was varied by altering the coherence of the dot cloud across trials (i.e. easy = 20% coherent, medium = 12% coherent, hard = 4% coherent, with each difficulty appearing with equal probability.</p><p>After each trial, participants made a combined decision and confidence report, using their mouse to adjust marker on a slider to report their choice (left or right) and their level of confidence. The response scale was structured to incentivise honest and accurate reporting of confidence, such that participants symmetrically earned more points for expressing high confidence in correct answers but also lost an equivalent number of points for expressing high confidence in errors. For example, if participants expressed maximal confidence in a correct decision, they would earn +10 points, but maximal confidence in an incorrect choice would lose the participant -10 points. Participants were aware that points accumulated during the task were translated into an additional bonus payment.</p><p>The task was completed in three consecutive phases: alone, together and alone again. The alone and alone again phases were identical, and participants viewed stimuli and made decisions as described above. However, in the together phase participants believed they made their choices with a 'partner' who was viewing the same stimuli and making decisions at the same time. In reality, the 'partner' was a computer algorithm whose decisions and confidence reports were programmed trial-by-trial. Participants saw the decision and confidence ratings of their 'partner' after they have submitted their own choice. Each phase comprised a block of 90 trials.</p><p>Half of participants were allocated to the confident partner condition and half to the uncertain partner condition. Each partner was programmed to have the same objective accuracy as the real participant (i.e., the same p(correct choice), estimated as the mean accuracy from the first alone phase), but the confident and uncertain partner gave generally high or low confidence ratings, respectively, drawn from a Gaussian distribution. In Exp 1, the confident ratings were drawn from a distribution of mean = 75%, SD = 10, and the uncertain ratings drawn from a distribution of mean = 25%, SD =10; while in Exp 2 the confident and uncertain distributions were mean = 85%, SD = 10 and mean = 25%, SD = 10, respectively. The nature of this manipulation means that the partners are not programmed to have any particular level of metacognitive sensitivity and may express relatively high confidence in errors or relatively low confidence in correct choices on different trials throughout the task. Despite this, we still see robust learning about confidence from these partners in each experiment (see Results)</p><p>Manipulating and measuring beliefs about social partner: Though decision 'partners' in our experiments were computer algorithms, participants were led to believe that these decisions arose from another participant completing the task at the same time as them. They were told this explicitly on opening instruction pages and were exposed to screens which waited for 'both participants' before proceeding to the next block. The partner was programmed 'wait' for up to eight second before being displayed as 'ready'. The partner's 'reaction time' to begin each block was independent of when the participant indicated their readiness to continue (i.e., the partner could appear as 'ready' before or after the participant had indicated they were ready to proceed). At the end of the task, and before debriefing participants about the true nature of the experiment, participants completed a forced choice question about the nature of the partner, where they could respond that they were confident they were making decisions with another player, they doubted another player was present, or they were unsure either way. Supplementary analyses revealed that beliefs about the social cover story did not interact with any of the effects seen in the experimental task (see Supplementary Material).</p><p>Statistical analyses: We primarily tested our hypotheses by comparing confidence levels between participants who interacted with confident and uncertain partners in different phases of the experiment (alone, together and alone again) using 2 x 3 mixed analysis of variance (ANOVA) and follow-up independent t-tests. These statistical tests are appropriate because, if participants 'confidence match' and confidence matching persists, we would generally expect participants to be more confident after interacting with the confident partner in the together and alone again phases. However, these statistical comparisons could be complicated by baseline differences in the confidence of different participants. For this reason (and because this analysis choice was pre-registered for Experiment 2, see below) we conducted these analyses on confidence ratings which were 'corrected' to the participant's confidence ratings in the initial alone phase (i.e., a participant with a mean confidence rating of 0.5 in the alone phase and 0.7 in the together phase would have corrected confidence ratings of 0 and 0.2, while a participant with a mean confidence rating of 0.7 in the alone phase and 0.6 in the together phase would have corrected confidence ratings of 0 and -0.1). This correction means that any variance in confidence between conditions cannot be due to baseline differences in confidence between groups, but it is worth noting that no data patterns (nor their statistical significance) are altered if uncorrected confidence ratings are used instead.</p><p>In addition to these primary analyses, we also calculated individual 'confidence matching' effects for each individual participant. This was achieved by computing the absolute difference between the participant's confidence and their partner's confidence before interaction (alone) and during joint decision making (together). If participants 'match' their confidence to their partners, the difference between participant confidence and partner confidence should be smaller when interacting (together) than beforehand (alone). We assessed this using paired t-tests to compare the absolute participantpartner confidence differences between alone and together phases. It is worth noting that by working in absolute (unsigned) differences this analysis makes it possible to measure confidence matching independently of partner group membership.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sample sizes, preregistration and inclusion criteria:</head><p>The sample size for Experiment 1 was based on a smaller pilot experiment and provided 80% power to detect an effect at least as large as d = .63. Experiment 2 was a pre-registered replication of Experiment 1, and the sample size was powered to detect the effect of 'partner' on confidence ratings identified in Experiment 1. Experiment 2 was preregistered on AsPredicted (https://aspredicted.org/V4M_D8C).</p><p>Participants were excluded from the sample and replaced with a new participant if objective task accuracy (i.e. left vs right motion decisions) was below 50% in any phase of the experiment (alone, together or alone again), as this could have reflected misunderstanding of or failure to follow task instructions. Seven participants were excluded based on this metric in Experiment 1, and 16 were excluded in Experiment 2, where this criterion was pre-registered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Confidence matching effects do not depend on beliefs about the decision partner</head><p>In both experiments, there was no interaction found between the effect of partner confidence (confident partner vs uncertain partner) and a participant's professed belief about the nature of the partner at the end of the experiment (i.e., confident partner was real, doubted partner was real, or unsure) -Exp 1: F(2,74) = 1.385, p = .257; Exp 2: F(2,118) = .797, p = .453.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>No effects of partner confidence on metacognitive sensitivity</head><p>We investigated whether changes in confidence bias seen between confident and uncertain partner groups across the task were accompanied by any changes in metacognitive sensitivity. To achieve this, we constructed Type II ROC curves for confidence ratings in each condition -breaking the continuous confidence scale into 50 cumulative bins for analysis (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26</ref> for details). Once constructed, the area under these ROC curves (AUROC) reflects a non-parametric measure of metacognitive sensitivity -akin to meta-d -with higher values indicating more accurate subjective insight into the correctness of a choice.</p><p>In Experiment 1, analysing these AUROC values found no effect of experiment phase -F(2,156) = 1.808, p=.167 -not effect of partner group -F(1,78) = 1.167, p=.283 -and no interaction -F(2,156) = .042, p=.959. In Experiment 2, there was likewise no effect of partner group -F(1,122) = .268, p=.606 -and no interaction -F(2,244) = 1.751, p=.176 -though this analysis did reveal a main effect of experiment phase -F(2,244) = 9.604, p&lt;.001. This reflected the fact that metacognitive sensitivity increased from the alone -mean (sd) = .560 (.06) -to the together phase -mean (sd) = .578 (.05)and remained stable into the alone again phase -mean (sd) = .580 (.06). Such a finding could reflect that fact that agents' metacognitive sensitivity improves after receiving several trials of feedback about the accuracy of their decisions and confidence reports, and/or the possibility that confidence is reported more accurately in the presence of others than when we are making decisions alone.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary modelling details</head><p>We constructed a new computational model to describe how agents form metacognitive estimates of uncertainty from noisy perceptual signals, and how these inferences can be shaped by past uncertainty in our own experiences and the uncertainty shared by others (see main text, Modelling metacognitive learning from self and others).</p><p>The first element of this model is a mapping function that estimates the inputs accessible to a putative metacognitive circuit -confidence evidence that reflects an internal estimate of the quality of incoming sensory signals <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14</ref> . Though we assume that the interpretation of this evidence can be biased by prior beliefs and social information, we need to begin by constructing an estimate of how agents generate this kind of confidence evidence 'at baseline'.</p><p>To achieve this, we took data only from the first alone phase of the experiment, and used this to estimate how observers map perceptual information to feelings of confidence before they have had the chance to interact with the partner. For each trial, we estimated of the signal strength of the moving dot stimulus, taking the averaged cosine of the programmed angles of each dot in the moving dot cloud. This calculation creates a measure of signal strength bounded between 0 (completely random) to 1 (all dots move one coherent direction). Importantly, this calculation is specific to the stimulus displayed on each trial, and while generally higher coherence clouds will generally contain stronger signals, two clouds programmed to have equal coherence can nonetheless have differing signal strengths (i.e., depending on whether the noncoherent dots move in similar or dissimilar direction to the coherent motion path). We then fit a cumulative gaussian function that captured the mapping between objective sensory signal strength and subjective confidence rating (also bounded between 0-1) -effectively a 'metacognitive reverse correlation' analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14</ref> . The parameters of this function (σ and μ) capture an observer's sensitivity and bias in translating sensory signals into feelings of confidence, and crucially the same mapping function can be used to simulate the confidence rating a participant would give for a different stimulus. This is similar to the approach taken by Bang et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9</ref> , where participant behaviour is used to estimate the confidence participants would be likely to feel separately of any biases in confidence induced e.g., by communicating with other people or observing the confidence of others.</p><p>With this perception-to-confidence mapping function in hand, the second element of our model involved estimating how participants form metacognitive inferences by combining this kind of confidence evidence (i.e., a transformation of the incoming perceptual signal on each trial) with prior expectations about confidence, and how participants learn to form these prior expectations from what they experience trial-by-trial (see main text). Here we made use of all the stimuli and confidence ratings on all trials of the experiment. We set the initial value of the observer's confidence prior to the participant's mean level confidence in the alone phase, which assumes that agents have metacognitive expectations which are roughly calibrated to reality at the outset of the task. The learning and decision dynamics of the model create a simulated trajectory of confidence ratings for each trial in the experiment, and find best-fitting parameters for each participant by identifying the combination that minimises the mean squared error between this simulated confidence trajectory and the empirical confidence ratings made the participant on each trial using a bounded variant of Matlab's fminsearch. In particular, the parameters α, wprior and wself are bounded to values between 0 and 1.</p><p>Finally, while we estimated the value of wself parameter to control how self-confidence and partnerconfidence are weighted when updating of confidence priors, this parameter is only relevant in the together phase where social information is available. As such, in the alone and alone again phases of the experiment the teaching signal used for belief updating is always simply the self prediction error itself. This means that for the purposes of Eqs 6 and 8 = , or equivalently in the absence of any social information wself = 1.</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Material</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Confidence ratings track objective difficulty throughout task phases</head><p>We conducted additional analyses to ensure that participants continued to report their confidence sensitively throughout the different phases of the experimental task -in alone, together and alone again phases. As expected, in all three phases of the experiment, confidence was higher in the easier than moderate than difficult trials (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Figure S1</ref>). The main effect of task difficulty was also significant in all three phases in both experiments (Exp 1: Alone -F(2,156)=27.260, p &lt;.001 -Together -F <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2,</ref><ref type="bibr">156)</ref>  <ref type="figure">&lt;.001)</ref>. This indicates that the participants generally reported their confidence sensitively throughout the experiment, even though confidence was biased by interaction with the social partner. <ref type="figure">Supplementary Figure S1</ref>: Confidence-difficulty coupling across each phase in each experiment.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective Confidence Predicts Information Seeking in Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Desender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Boldt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797617744771</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797617744771" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="761" to="778" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognition: computation, biology and function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2012.0021</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2012.0021" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1280" to="1286" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognition in human decision-making: confidence and error monitoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Summerfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2011.0416</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2011.0416" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1310" to="1321" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence controls perceptual evidence accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Balsdon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mamassian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-020-15561-w</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-15561-w" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1753" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of metacognition in human social interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2012.0123</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2012.0123" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2213" to="2223" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supra-personal cognitive control and metacognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Shea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Boldt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Heyes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2014.01.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2014.01.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="186" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimally Interacting Minds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Olsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Latham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Roepstorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1185718</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1185718" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">329</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1081" to="1085" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural computations underpinning the strategic management of influence in advice giving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Hertz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brunetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Olesen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-017-02314-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-017-02314-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Private-public mappings in human prefrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ershadmanesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nili</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.56477</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.56477" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Precision and the Bayesian brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Yon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cub.2021.07.044</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2021.07.044" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1026" to="1032" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence matching in group decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Aitchison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Herce Castanon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rafiee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mahmoodi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y F</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Latham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Summerfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-017-0117</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-017-0117" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Hum Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Expectations about precision bias metacognition and awareness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Olawole-Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yon</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xge0001371</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0001371" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Exp Psychol Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">152</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2177" to="2189" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manipulating Prior Beliefs Causally Induces Under-and Overconfidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Van Marcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Denmat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Verguts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Desender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/09567976241231572</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/09567976241231572" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">9567976241231572</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reverse engineering of metacognition. eLife 11, e75420</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Guggenmos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.75420</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.75420" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A theory of Pavlovian conditioning : Variations in the effectiveness of reinforcement and nonreinforcement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Rescorla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational modelling of social cognition and behaviour-a reinforcement learning primer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lockwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Klein-Flügge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/scan/nsaa040</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/scan/nsaa040" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc Cogn Affect Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="761" to="771" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-evaluation of decision-making: A general Bayesian framework for metacognitive computation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000045</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000045" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forming global estimates of self-performance from local confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rouault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-019-09075-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-09075-3" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1141" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Formation of global self-beliefs in the human brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rouault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2003094117</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2003094117" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27268" to="27276" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is There a &apos;Social&apos; Brain? Implementations and Algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lockwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Apps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W C</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2020.06.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2020.06.011" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="802" to="813" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social learning in models and minds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Yon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Heyes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11229-024-04632-w</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11229-024-04632-w" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthese</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">203</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="0199" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowing ourselves together: The cultural origins of metacognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Heyes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Shea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="362" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender and Competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Niederle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Vesterlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="601" to="630" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grand Stage&quot;: the metadata and linguistic choices in a scientific advisory groups&apos; meeting minutes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Concannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Meller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Millington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1057/s41599-022-01403-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-022-01403-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Humanit Soc Sci Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>COVID-19 and science advice on the</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overconfidence, risk perception and the risk-taking behavior of finance professionals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Broihanne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Merli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Roger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.frl.2013.11.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.frl.2013.11.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Finance Research Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to measure metacognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnhum.2014.00443</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2014.00443" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front Hum Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social training reconfigures prediction errors to shape Self-Other boundaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Story</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Kurth-Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-020-16856-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-16856-8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PsychoPy2: Experiments in behavior made easy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Peirce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Macaskill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Höchenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sogo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kastman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Lindeløv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-018-01193-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-018-01193-y" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav Res Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="203" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
