<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Herrick</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
							<email>herrickfung@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Medha</forename><surname>Shekhar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Rausch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Rhine-Waal University of Applied Sciences</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Catholic University of Eichstätt-Ingolstadt</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dobromir</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology Georgia Institute of Technology 654 Cherry Str NW Atlanta</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>30332</postCode>
									<region>GA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:40+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>metacognition</term>
					<term>confidence</term>
					<term>perceptual decision-making</term>
					<term>folded-X pattern</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Visual stimuli can vary in multiple dimensions that affect accuracy and confidence in a perceptual decision-making task. However, previous studies have typically included just one or at most two manipulations, leaving it unclear how a wider set of manipulations may relate to each other. Here, we examine the similarities and differences between five different stimulus manipulations across two experiments. Subjects indicated whether a tilted Gabor patch was oriented clockwise or counterclockwise from 45°. In Experiment 1, we independently manipulated the size, duration, noise level, and tilt offset of the stimuli. In Experiment 2, we employed a 2x2x2x2 design jointly manipulating size, spatial frequency, noise level, and tilt offset of the stimuli. We found that manipulations of size, duration, noise level, and spatial frequency had remarkably similar effects on accuracy and confidence. In contrast, the tilt offset manipulation stood out by affecting accuracy more strongly than confidence. In addition, tilt offset exhibited supraadditive interaction with all other manipulations for both accuracy and confidence, whereas the remaining manipulations exhibited either no interactions or subadditive interactions with each other. Furthermore, tilt offset was also the only manipulation for which confidence in incorrect trials decreased with increasing difficulty, while all other manipulations exhibited the opposite trend. Overall, our results reveal a startling similarity between the effects of four very different stimulus manipulations and a prominent difference with a fifth manipulation. These results open the door for a priori predictions of how novel manipulations would affect accuracy and confidence.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Confidence is the subjective sense of how likely our decisions are to be correct <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Pouget et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sanders et al., 2016)</ref>. In the laboratory, confidence is often studied by asking observers to report their confidence after making a perceptual decision. These experiments typically entail manipulating stimuli, such as lowering contrast <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Shekhar &amp; Rahnev, 2021b)</ref>, infusing noise <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bang et al., 2019)</ref>, and masking the stimulus <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Lau &amp; Passingham, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Rausch et al., 2018)</ref>. Such manipulations produce varying levels of perceptual performance, enabling us to investigate how confidence fluctuates with performance. Intuitively, confidence should align with performance. For instance, recognizing a blurry face should decrease both confidence and performance as the level of blurriness increases. Many papers have explored how confidence tracks performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Busey et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Yeung &amp; Summerfield, 2012)</ref>. Numerous factors that affect visual confidence have been identified (for review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Rahnev &amp; Denison, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Shekhar &amp; Rahnev, 2021a)</ref>. Many computational models of confidence have been developed to explain different behavioral effects related to confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Boundy-Singer et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Fleming &amp; Daw, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hellmann et al., 2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hellmann et al., , 2024</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Maniscalco &amp; Lau, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Shekhar &amp; Rahnev, 2021b</ref>).</p><p>However, despite the variety of ways in which visual stimuli can be manipulated, most existing studies on visual confidence manipulated a single stimulus feature, which overlooks the potential differences between various manipulations. While it is true that all manipulations can effectively vary perceptual performance, it is unclear whether different manipulations would have equivalent effects on accuracy and confidence. In fact, several studies have hinted that different manipulations may sometimes have different effects. For instance, in an ensemble averaging task, stimuli can be made easier by increasing the sampling mean or decreasing the variance of the ensemble. Studies have shown that manipulating variance, as compared to manipulating the mean, has a stronger effect on confidence than accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Boldt et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Spence et al., 2016)</ref>. However, this is not always the case <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Zylberberg et al., 2014)</ref> and the effect may be subject to individual differences <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Gardelle &amp; Mamassian, 2015)</ref>. A more recent study using an orientation discrimination task also found that increasing the contrast of a Gabor stimulus increases confidence more than accuracy, whereas manipulating the tilt offset of the Gabor stimulus boosts accuracy but not confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Xue et al., 2024)</ref>. Despite the inconsistencies in findings, all these studies suggest that different manipulations produce different confidence-accuracy relationships. Therefore, a comprehensive understanding of the underlying computations of confidence requires examining how confidence responds to multiple stimulus manipulations within a single experiment.</p><p>Having multiple stimulus manipulations within a single experiment would also enable investigation into potential interactions among them for confidence and accuracy¾an area being largely unexplored due to the limited number of stimulus manipulations in most existing studies in the field. To date, only one study has investigated such interactions for confidence, reporting no significant interaction effect between manipulating the mean and manipulating the variance in a color ensemble judgement task <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Boldt et al., 2017)</ref>. Therefore, it remains largely unknown how different stimulus manipulations interact with each other and whether these interactions are the same or different for confidence and accuracy.</p><p>Further, emerging evidence suggests that different stimulus manipulations may produce different patterns of how confidence for correct and error trials changes with difficulty. It is generally thought that easier trials tend to increase confidence for correct trials but decrease it for error trials <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hangya et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sanders et al., 2016)</ref>. This pattern, known as the folded-X pattern <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Kepecs &amp; Mainen, 2012)</ref>, has been proposed as a framework for understanding how different stimulus features interact with the confidence generation process <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Hellmann et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Rausch et al., 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Rausch et al., , 2021</ref>. It has even been argued that whenever the folded-X pattern is detected in another psychological, neural, or physiological variable, that variable should be considered a correlate of confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Kepecs et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sanders et al., 2016)</ref>. Consequently, some studies have used the folded-X pattern to detect correlates of confidence empirically <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Braun et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Rolls et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Urai et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Voodla et al., 2025)</ref>. Despite being frequently observed across studies involving various manipulations, including contrast , tilt offset, and motion direction offset <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Xue et al., 2024)</ref>, other studies exists where the canonical folded-X pattern is violated and instead confidence for both correct and error trials increases for easier conditions. This alternative pattern, known as the double-increase pattern <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Rausch &amp; Zehetleitner, 2019)</ref>, has also been observed across various stimulus manipulations, including stimulus-onset asynchrony <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Hellmann et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Rausch et al., 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Rausch et al., , 2021</ref>, contrast <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Xue et al., 2024)</ref>, and motion coherence <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Kiani et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Xue et al., 2024)</ref>. However, no study to date has investigated how multiple stimulus manipulations or stimulus-specific factors might produce distinct confidence patterns or whether these patterns are taskspecific.</p><p>Here we conduct two experiments to explore the similarities and differences in the effects of various manipulations on confidence and accuracy. Both experiments featured four distinct manipulations within a single experiment. In Experiment 1, we independently manipulated size, duration, noise, and tilt offset in an orientation discrimination task. In Experiment 2, we employed a full-factorial design and manipulated size, spatial frequency, noise, and tilt offset. We found that the manipulations of size, duration, spatial frequency, and noise have remarkably similar effects on confidence and accuracy. Equally notably, the tilt offset manipulation differed from all other manipulations in having a larger effect on accuracy than confidence. In addition, tilt offset was the only manipulation that exhibited supraadditive interaction with any other manipulation and also the only manipulation that yielded a canonical folded-X pattern. Altogether, these results demonstrate remarkable similarities in four different stimulus manipulations and a prominent difference in the fifth manipulation, thus opening the door for predicting how novel manipulations would affect accuracy and confidence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Subjects</head><p>Sixty-two subjects participated in the two experiments for monetary compensation ($10/hour). Subjects were recruited using Prolific (https://www.prolific.com/), an online crowdsourcing platform. Experiment 1 had 30 subjects (6 females) aged between 19-38 (M = 26.6, SD = 5.47). Experiment 2 had 32 subjects (9 females) aged between 18-37 (M = 27.0, SD = 5.39). None of the subjects participated in both experiments. Based on previous studies from our lab <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Haddara &amp; Rahnev, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Rafiei et al., 2024)</ref>, we excluded subjects with an overall accuracy less than 55% or greater than 95% or overall average confidence above 3.7, which led to the exclusion of two subjects from Experiment 1 and three subjects from Experiment 2. All subjects were naïve to the purpose of the study, reported normal or corrected-to-normal vision, and provided informed consent. Ethical approval for the study was obtained from the Georgia Tech Institutional Review Board.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Task</head><p>Each trial began with a fixation for 1 second and was followed by a Gabor patch stimulus <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1a</ref>). After a 100ms interstimulus interval (ISI) with a blank screen, subjects first indicated whether the Gabor patch was tilted left (counterclockwise) or right (clockwise) relative to a 45° tilt. On the perceptual response screen, a red (#FF0000) line was drawn on a circle of the same size as the Gabor patch to indicate a 45° tilt reference. Subjects were instructed to press the left and right arrow on the keyboard with their right hand to indicate left and right tilt, respectively. Subjects subsequently rated their confidence on a 4-point scale, where 1 corresponds to low confidence and 4 corresponds to high confidence. They were encouraged to use the whole confidence scale. Subjects provided the confidence response using the keyboard with their left hand. Both the perceptual and confidence responses were untimed, and the next trial began after both responses were made. The experiment was programmed in JavaScript with the jsPsych library 7.3.3 (de Leeuw, 2015).</p><p>The virtual chinrest method was used to control differences in viewing distance, display size, and stimulus size. Specifically, subjects were first asked to resize the stimuli on the screen to match the size of a credit card, adjusting for discrepancies in display size. Then, subjects fixated on a central point and tracked the lateral movement of the target in their periphery, pressing the spacebar when the target disappeared. The procedure was repeated three times to estimate there viewing distance, assuming the blind spot is located at 13.5° of the visual angle <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Li et al., 2020)</ref>. Each trial began with a fixation for 1 second and was followed by a Gabor patch stimulus. After a 100ms interstimulus interval (ISI) with a blank screen, subjects first indicated whether the Gabor patch was tilted left (counterclockwise) or right (clockwise) relative to a 45° tilt and subsequently rated their confidence on a 4-point scale. Both responses were untimed, and the next trial began after both responses were made. (b) Stimulus parameters and experimental design of Experiment 1. Four stimulus features (size, duration, noise, and tilt offset) were manipulated with three levels of difficulty. "T" indicates the threshold estimated in a staircase procedure. The upper panel presents the exact stimulus parameters for each stimulus manipulation. The lower panel depicts the design of 9 experimental conditions. The number of asterisks (*) denotes the level of difficulty. (c) Stimulus parameters for Experiment 2. Experiment 2 had the same manipulations except that we used spatial frequency instead of duration. Unlike Experiment 1, here we used a full factorial design with a total of 16 conditions with each condition featuring a different combination of the four manipulations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Stimuli and design</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.1">Experiment 1</head><p>In Experiment 1, we independently manipulated 4 stimulus features: the size, duration, noise, and tilt offset of the Gabor patches <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1b)</ref>. For each feature, we sampled 3 levels of difficulty based on a pilot study. For the size manipulation, the three levels of difficulty were 2.5° (hard), 5° (medium), and 7.5° (easy) of visual angle. The three levels of duration were 33ms (hard), 100ms (medium), and 500ms (easy). Noise was manipulated by blending (computing the weighted sum of two images) the Gabor patch with a background of random noise. A 90% noise manipulation would indicate 10% weighting of the Gabor patch and 90% weighting of the noisy background. Three levels of difficulty for the noise manipulation were 90% (hard), 75% (medium), and 10% (easy). Finally, tilt refers to the degree of offset from 45° and was manipulated based on an individualized threshold (T) obtained by a staircase procedure as described below. The three levels of tilt included 0.5T (hard), T (medium), and 2T (easy). Other stimulus parameters of the Gabor patches were kept constant (Spatial frequency = 8 cycles; phase = 0). To manipulate these stimulus features independently, we first created a baseline condition that included the medium level for all four stimulus features. Other conditions were created by altering only the feature of interest while keeping other features at their baseline levels.</p><p>For instance, the size-hard condition was created by changing the size-medium parameter from the baseline condition to the size-hard parameter while keeping other features unchanged. This approach creates eight additional conditions, derived from the four stimulus features each having and easy and difficult levels. Including the baseline condition, we had a total of nine experimental conditions ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b</ref>). Each condition was tested for 72 trials, except for the baseline condition, which was tested for 144 trials, resulting in a total of 720 trials. All experimental conditions were randomly interleaved throughout the experiment.</p><p>Subjects completed the 720 experimental trials in the form of 5 runs, each containing 6 blocks of 24 trials. Subjects were advised to take short breaks after each run and block. Before the start of the main experiment, subjects received 3 practice blocks and 2 staircase blocks. In all these blocks, the stimulus parameters for size, duration, and noise were set at medium difficulty. The first practice block contained 15 trials with a tilt offset of 10°. Then, subjects completed 40 trials with the tilt offset decreasing for every 10 trials (tilt offset = 5°, 3°, 2°, and 1°). Feedback on perceptual performance was given for the first two practice blocks. In the third practice block, subjects completed 20 trials without feedback with tilt offsets of 4°, 2°, and 1° randomly interleaved. Subjects then performed 2 staircase blocks to obtain the individualized threshold (T). The average individualized threshold was 3.39 ± 0.90°. The staircase procedure was a three-down-one-up staircase with an asymmetric step size. The initial tilt offset was 2° and the step size was 0.2° implemented with a down/up factor of 0.7393 (Garcıá-Pérez, 1998). The staircase procedure terminates whenever the number of reversals exceeds 14 or the number of trials exceeds 60. The threshold was then obtained by averaging all reversal values except for the first reversal. The final threshold was obtained by averaging the threshold result from the 2 staircase blocks. Subjects were not prompted to provide confidence responses during the staircase procedure. The whole experimental procedure took about 60 minutes to complete.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2">Experiment 2</head><p>Experiment 2 employed a full-factorial design on four stimulus features: size, spatial frequency, noise, and tilt offset of the Gabor patches with 2 levels of difficulty for each feature <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1c</ref>). Stimulus duration was kept constant at 200ms. This 2x2x2x2 factorial design resulted in a total of 16 experimental conditions. Each condition was tested for 100 trials, for a total of 1600 trials. All conditions were randomly interleaved throughout the experiment.</p><p>We collected data from each subject over two different days. On each day, subjects completed 800 trials in the form of 5 runs, each containing 5 blocks of 32 trials. On the first day, subjects received the same 3 practice and 2 staircase blocks as in Experiment 1 before the main experiment to familiarize them with the task and obtain the individualized threshold. The average individualized threshold was 3.35 ± 0.90°. On the second day, we only included two recall blocks. The first recall block contained 10 trials with a tilt offset of 10° and perceptual feedback. Then, subjects completed a block of 24 trials in their individualized threshold without receiving feedback. In all these blocks, only the tilt offset was manipulated, other stimulus parameters were set as follows: size = 5°, spatial frequency = 8 cycles, and noise = 75%. Each day of experimental session took about 60 minutes to complete.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Analyses</head><p>We first computed subjects' performance (d') and mean confidence for each stimulus manipulations. d' was calculated using the following formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">! = "# (ℎ ) − "# ( )</formula><p>where "# is the inverse of the cumulative standard normal distribution that transforms hit rate and false alarm rate into z scores. Note that since Experiment 2 employed a full-factorial design, we computed the d' and mean confidence for each stimulus manipulation by combining trials that shared the same level of difficulty on the manipulation of interest (8 different experimental conditions for each level of difficulty). This allowed us to investigate the main effect of each stimulus manipulation.</p><p>We performed two different analyses to quantify the dissociable relationship between confidence and d' for all four manipulations in both experiments. For each manipulation, we first plotted confidence against d' and fit a linear regression. We then computed the slope ( ) of the linear regression, which shows the change in confidence for each unit increase in d'. A larger slope denotes a bigger change in confidence for each unit increase in d' (relatively larger impact on confidence than accuracy), whereas a lower slope denotes a smaller change in confidence for each unit increase in d' (relatively smaller effect on confidence than accuracy). Slopes from different manipulations were then compared using paired sample ttests. We also performed Bayes Factor analyses to assess the strength of evidence for our hypotheses. All statistical analyses were performed in Python3.9 with the Pingouin package (https://pingouin-stats.org/build/html/index.html). We used the default Cauchy scale factor ( = √2/2) for all Bayes factor analyses. Two subjects from each experiment were excluded in this specific analysis because they exhibited slightly higher accuracy for one of the hard compared to the corresponding each condition, which makes the slope estimation unreliable. In addition, 8 more subjects in Experiment 1 showed such reversals specifically for the duration manipulation (which also generally produced a very small d' difference between the hard and easy settings). To avoid excluding an excessive number of subjects, we instead removed the duration manipulation from this specific analysis.</p><p>In addition, we employed another method for quantifying the relative effects of each manipulation on d' and confidence. Specifically, we computed the differences in d' and confidence between the easy and hard conditions for each manipulation and compared these differences between pairs of manipulations using paired sample t-tests. To further compare these differences in d' and confidence among different stimulus manipulations, we first zscored the differences in d' and confidence to bring them onto the same scale and compute the difference between d' and confidence: (Δ ! ) − (Δ ). The resulting metric indicates the relative effect on accuracy versus confidence, where a positive value corresponds to a larger effect on accuracy than confidence, while a negative value corresponds to a larger effect on confidence than accuracy. We then compared this z-scored difference to zero using one-sided t-tests to test for the significance between d' and confidence difference for each manipulation and compared these z-scored differences between pairs of manipulations using paired sample t-tests.</p><p>Apart from examining the relationship between confidence and d', we also examined how confidence in correct and error trials changes with stimulus discriminability. Prior studies coined the term "folded-X pattern" to describe a pattern of results where easy conditions lead to confidence increase for correct trials but confidence decrease for error trials <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hangya et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sanders et al., 2016)</ref>. To quantify the folded-X pattern, we fitted linear regressions to predict confidence by stimulus difficulty separately for correct and error trials in each stimulus manipulations. We then computed the slope ( ) of the linear regression, in which a positive indicates a confidence increase with stimulus discriminability, whereas a negative indicates a confidence decrease with stimulus discriminability. The folded-X pattern corresponds to a positive for correct trials and a negative for error trials. The obtained values were compared to zero using one-sided t-tests.</p><p>In Experiment 2, we also investigated the two-way interaction effects among the four stimulus manipulations. We investigated the interaction effects separately for d' and confidence by conducting two-way repeated-measures analyses of variance (ANOVAs).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Data and code availability</head><p>All data and codes are available at https://github.com/herrickfung/4m_data_code.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>We explored the similarities and differences in the effects of five different manipulations on confidence and accuracy. Subjects indicated whether a Gabor patch was tilted left or right relative to a 45° tilt and provided confidence on a 4-point scale. In Experiment 1, we independently manipulated the size, duration, noise, and the tilt offset of the Gabor patch, while in Experiment 2, we jointly manipulated the size, spatial frequency, noise, and the tilt offset. We then performed extensive analysis to investigate the behavioral effects of these manipulations on confidence and performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Effects of each manipulation on average confidence and accuracy</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">Experiment 1</head><p>We first examined how each of the four manipulations in Experiment 1 affected average confidence and average performance. To do so, we plotted confidence against performance (d') ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2a</ref>). Qualitatively, confidence increased with d' for all four manipulations.</p><p>Critically, the relationship between confidence and d' appeared to be almost identical for the size, duration, and noise manipulations, but very different for the tilt offset manipulation.</p><p>We examine this qualitative impression in two different ways below.</p><p>First, to quantitatively examine the relative effects of each manipulation on d' and confidence, we computed the slope ( ) of the linear regression which shows the change in confidence for each unit increase in d' <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 2b)</ref>. We excluded the duration manipulation from this analysis because its effects on both confidence and accuracy were too small, leading to very noisy slope estimates (see Methods). The results for the size, noise, and tilt offset manipulations confirmed the qualitative impressions from <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2a</ref>. Specifically, the size and noise manipulations exhibited very similar, large slopes (Size: = 0.76, Noise: = 0.81; t(27) = 0.328, p = 0.745, BF 01 = 4.59). In contrast, the tilt offset manipulation exhibited substantially smaller slope ( = 0.22) compared to both size (t(25) = 5.87, p = 3.99 x 10 -6 , BF 10 = 4.99 x 10 3 ) and noise (t(25) = 3.94, p = 5.83 x 10 -4 , BF 10 = 55.3). These findings demonstrate that the size and noise manipulations have similar, large effects on confidence compared to their effects on d', whereas the tilt offset manipulation has a substantially smaller effect on confidence compared to its effect on d'. . The relationship between confidence and d' appeared to be very similar for the size, duration, and noise manipulations but was very different for the tilt offset manipulation. (b) The slope of the linear regression line plotting confidence against d' for the size, noise, and tilt offset manipulations. Larger slopes denote a larger increase in confidence for each unit increase in d'. We found a similarly large slope for both the size and noise manipulations. Both of which were significantly larger than the slope of the tilt offset manipulation. (c) Differences in d' and confidence between each stimulus manipulation's easy and hard conditions. The tilt offset manipulation produced a significantly larger d' difference, as compared to the size and noise manipulation, but yielded a smaller confidence difference. Note that the figure only highlights comparisons that change direction for d' vs. confidence. (d) z-score differences between d' and confidence for each stimulus manipulation. A positive value denotes relatively larger effect on accuracy than confidence.</p><p>The tilt offset manipulation is the only manipulation that yielded larger effect on accuracy than confidence, which was significantly different from the size, duration, and noise manipulations. p-value below the zero line correspond to the results of one-sample t-tests against 0 for each stimulus manipulation. Dots show individual subjects. Error bars represent SEM.</p><p>Second, we also examined the relative effects of each manipulation on d' and confidence by computing the differences in d' and confidence between the easy and hard conditions for each manipulation <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 2c</ref>). We found that the duration, size, and noise manipulations had increasingly larger effects on both d' and confidence (all 6 p's &lt; 0.05 for all pairwise comparisons between pairs of manipulations for both d' and confidence), suggesting that all three manipulations had similar relative effects on performance and confidence. In contrast, the tilt offset manipulation had a relatively large effect on d' but a relatively small effect on confidence. Indeed, the tilt offset manipulation had a significantly larger effect on d' compared to both the noise (t(27) = 4.23, p = 2.42 x 10 -4 , BF 10 = 119) and size manipulations (t(27) = 10.5, p = 5.47 x 10 -11 , BF 10 = 1.76 x 10 8 ). However, tilt offset had a significantly smaller effect on confidence compared to the noise manipulation (t(27) = -4.36, p = 1.68 x 10 -4 , BF 10 = 165) and numerically smaller but not significantly different effect on confidence from the size manipulation (t(27) = -1.33, p = 0.19, BF 01 = 2.26).</p><p>To directly compare the effects of each manipulation on d' vs. confidence, we computed the z-score differences between d' and confidence <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 2d</ref>). Specifically, we z-scored the differences between the easy and hard conditions across manipulations for d' and confidence separately. We then examined the difference between these two z-scores:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">(Δ ! ) − (Δ )</formula><p>. We found that size and noise had significantly negative z-score differences (Size: t(27) = -3.89, p = 5.86 x 10 -4 , BF 10 = 54.1; Noise: t(27) = -2.92, p = 0.007, BF 10 = 6.28), indicating a larger effect on confidence than accuracy. Duration also exhibited a negative z-score difference, but this effect was not significant (t(27) = -1.60, p = 0.122, BF 01 = 1.61). In contrast, tilt offset was the only manipulation that demonstrated significantly positive z-score differences (t(27) = 7.56, p = 3.90 x 10 -8 , BF 10 = 3.63 x 10 5 ), indicating a larger effect on accuracy than confidence. Critically, the z-score difference for tilt offset was significantly higher than for the size, noise, and duration manipulations (all 3 p's &lt; 0.001 and BF 10 &gt; 10 5 for all pairwise comparisons). Size, noise, and duration exhibited relatively similar z-score differences, though the z-score difference for duration was closer to 0 due to the fact that duration had negligible effects on both d' and confidence (Size vs duration: t(27) = 2.19, p = 0.04, BF 10 = 1.55; Size vs noise: t(27) = 0.39, p = 0.70, BF 01 = 4.65; Duration vs noise: t(27) = 1.74, p = 0.09, BF 01 = 1.32). Overall, these results suggest that the size, noise, and duration manipulations have similar relative effects on d' and confidence, while tilt offset impacts d' more than confidence compared to the other manipulations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2">Experiment 2</head><p>In Experiment 1, we manipulated size, duration, noise and tilt offset independently.</p><p>Specifically, when manipulating one variable, all other variables were given a default, baseline value. This design allows us to compare the different manipulations but leaves it unclear whether the manipulations interact with each other. To address this question, in Experiment 2, we jointly manipulated four stimulus features using a 2x2x2x2 experimental design. Since duration demonstrated minimal impact on both confidence and accuracy in Experiment 1, we replaced the duration manipulation with spatial frequency manipulation in Experiment 2. We first examined the effects of each manipulation on accuracy and confidence (as in Experiment 1) and then analyzed the interactions between the different manipulations.</p><p>To qualitatively examine the effects of each manipulation on accuracy and confidence, we first plotted confidence against performance (d') for each manipulation while combining across the remaining three manipulations <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3a)</ref>. As expected, confidence increased with d' for all four manipulations. Critically, the relationship between confidence and d' was close to identical for the size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulations, but was very different for the tilt offset manipulation. . The relationship between confidence and d' was nearly identical for the size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulations, but was very different for the tilt offset manipulation. (b) The slope of the linear regression line plotting confidence against d' for each stimulus feature. A larger slope would denote a larger increase in confidence for each unit increase in d'. A similarly larger slope was found for size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulations. All of them were larger than the slope of the tilt offset manipulation. (c) d' and Confidence difference between each stimulus manipulation's easy and hard conditions. The tilt offset manipulation produced a significantly larger d' difference, as compared to the size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulation, but yielded no significant differences in confidence difference. Note that the figure only highlights comparisons that change direction for d' vs. confidence. (d) z-scored differences between d' and confidence for each stimulus manipulation. A positive value denotes relatively larger effect on accuracy than confidence. p-value below the zero line correspond to the results of one-sample t-tests against 0 for each stimulus manipulation. The tilt offset manipulation is the only manipulation that yielded larger effect on accuracy than confidence, which was significantly different from the size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulations. Dots show individual subjects. Error bars represent SEM.</p><p>As in Experiment 1, we quantitatively examined the relative effect of each manipulation on d' and confidence by computing the slope ( ) of the linear regression which shows the change in confidence for each unit increase in d' <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3b</ref>). We found that the size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulations exhibited very similar, large slopes (Size: = 0.70, Spatial frequency: = 0.66, Noise: = 0.60; p &gt; 0.1 and BF 01 &gt; 3 for all three pairwise comparisons; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3b</ref>). In contrast, the tilt offset manipulation exhibited a significantly smaller slope ( = 0.26), as compared to spatial frequency (t(26) = 3.61, p = 0.001, BF 10 = 27.5), noise (t(26) = 4.0, p = 4.60 x 10 -4 , BF 10 = 67.6), and size (t(26) = 2.28, p = 0.031, BF 10 = 1.84). These findings replicated and extended results from Experiment 1, showing that the size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulations have similarly large effects on confidence compared to their impact on d', whereas the tilt offset manipulation has a substantially smaller effect on confidence compared to its effect on d'.</p><p>Further, as in Experiment 1, we also examined the relative effects of each manipulation on d'</p><p>and confidence by computing the difference in d' and confidence between the easy and hard conditions for each manipulation while combining across all remaining manipulations <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3c</ref>). We found that, compared to each other, the size, noise, and spatial frequency manipulations had increasingly larger effects on both d' and confidence (p &lt; 0.05 for all 6 pairwise comparisons), suggesting that all three of these manipulations had similar relative effects on performance and confidence. In contrast, the tilt offset manipulation had a larger effect on d' but a smaller effect on confidence. Specifically, the tilt offset manipulation had a significantly larger effect d' compared to size (t(28) = 4.31, p = 1.80 x 10 -4 , BF 10 = 154), spatial frequency (t(28) = 2.53, p = 0.017, BF 10 = 2.90), and noise (t(28) = 3.27, p = 0.003, BF 10 = 13.3).</p><p>However, tilt offset had a significantly smaller effect on confidence compared to spatial frequency (t(28) = 2.18, p = 0.037, BF 10 = 1.54) and noise (t(28) = 2.08, p = 0.047, BF 10 = 1.27) and numerically smaller effect (though non-significant) on confidence compared to size (t(28) = 1.41, p = 0.171, BF 01 = 2.09).</p><p>Similarly, we computed the z-score differences between d' and confidence ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3d)</ref>. We found that size demonstrated significantly negative z-score differences (t(28) = -2.16, p = 0.04, BF 10 = 1.45), indicating a larger effect on confidence than accuracy. Spatial frequency and noise also exhibited a negative z-score difference, but the effects were not significant (Spatial frequency: t(28) = -1.21, p = 0.23, BF 01 = 2.60; Noise: t(28) = -1.12, p = 0.27, BF 01 = 2.86).</p><p>In contrast, tilt offset is the only manipulation that demonstrated significantly positive zscore differences (t(28) = 8.14, p = 7.24 x 10 -9 , BF 10 = 1.76 x 10 -6 ), indicating larger effect on accuracy than confidence. Critically, the z-score difference for tilt offset was significantly higher than for the size, noise, and spatial frequency manipulations (all 3 p's &lt; 0.001 and BF 10 &gt; 80 for all pairwise comparisons). Size, noise and spatial frequency showed relatively similar z-score differences (all 3 p's &gt; 0.1 and BF 01 &gt; 2 for all pairwise comparisons). These results demonstrate that the size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulations have similar effects on d' and confidence, while the tilt offset manipulation stood out in affecting d' more than confidence compared to all other manipulations. Overall, these results from Experiment 2 successfully replicated and expanded the results from Experiment 1, showing that size, noise, and spatial frequency manipulations exhibit similar relationship between d'</p><p>and confidence, whereas tilt offset was different from all other manipulations in that it affected d' more than confidence.</p><p>Critically, the design of Experiment 2 also allowed us to examine how the different manipulations interact with each other. To this end, we analyzed all six possible two-way interactions among the size, spatial frequency, noise, and tilt offset manipulations for both d'</p><p>and confidence <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Figure 4)</ref>. We found that all two-way interactions involving tilt offset yielded significant supraadditive effects on both d' (Size vs. Tilt offset: F(1, 28) = 21.0, p = 8.69 x 10 -5 ; Spatial frequency vs. Tilt offset: F(1, 28) = 26.4, p = 1.89 x 10 -5 ; Noise vs. Tilt offset:</p><p>F(1, 28) = 26.5, p = 1.87 x 10 -5 ) and confidence (Size vs. Tilt offset: F(1, 28) = 10.4, p = 0.003;</p><p>Spatial frequency vs. Tilt offset: F(1, 28) = 31.7, p = 5.03 x 10 -6 ; Noise vs. Tilt offset: F(1, 28) =</p><p>14.4, p = 7.38 x 10 -4 ). Specifically, the tilt offset manipulation increased d' and confidence more when the other manipulations (size, noise, or spatial frequency) were easy compared to when they were difficult. Contrary to the supraadditive interactions we observed for the tilt offset manipulation, the remaining manipulations showed either subadditive interactions or no interactions between each other. Specifically, we found subadditive interaction between the size and noise manipulations for both d' (F(1, 28) = 18.2, p = 2.03 x 10 -4 ) and confidence (F(1, 28) = 73.7, p = 2.50 x 10 -9 ). Specifically, the noise manipulation increased d' and confidence less when the size manipulation was easy compared to when they were difficult. We also found subadditive interaction between the noise and spatial frequency but only for d' (F(1, 28) = 7.16, p = 0.012). There was no interaction between noise and spatial frequency for confidence (F(1, 28) = 1.19, p = 0.28). Finally, there was also no interaction between size and spatial frequency for either d' (F(1, 28) = 0.09, p = 0.76) or confidence (F(1, 28) = 0.62, p = 0.44). These results demonstrate that the tilt offset manipulation stands out in that it is the only manipulation that produces supraadditive interaction effects for either d' or confidence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Effects of each manipulation on confidence for correct vs. error trials (folded-X pattern)</head><p>Confidence is typically thought to increase with easier trials for correct responses but to decrease with easier trials for error responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hangya et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sanders et al., 2016)</ref>. This pattern, known as the folded-X pattern, can be used to understand how different stimulus features interact with the confidence generation process <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Rausch et al., 2018;</ref>. Thus, we also analyzed how confidence changes for correct and error responses in each stimulus manipulation.</p><p>Across both experiments, we observed violations of the canonical folded-X pattern for all stimulus manipulations except tilt offset ( <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>). In Experiment 1, for the size, duration, and noise manipulations, easier conditions increased confidence in both correct trials (Size: β = 0.311, t(26) = 7.03, p = 1.80 x 10 -7 ; Duration: β = 0.113, t(26) = 4.82, p = 5.40 x 10 -5 ; Noise: β = 0.514, t(26) = 8.75, p = 3.18 x 10 -9 ) and error trials (Size: β = 0.260, t(26) = 7.47, p = 6.23 x 10 -8 ;</p><p>Duration: β = 0.07, t(26) = 1.88, p = 0.07; Noise: β = 0.374, t(26) = 5.55, p = 7.86 x 10 <ref type="bibr">-6</ref> ). This joint increase in confidence regardless of the response accuracy shows that size, duration, and noise conditions violated the folded-X pattern. However, for the tilt offset manipulation, easier conditions increased confidence in the correct trials (β = 0.247, t(26) = 7.32, p = 8.97 x 10 -8 ), but not in the error trials (β = -0.05, t(26) = -1.21, p = 0.24), which resembles the canonical folded-X pattern. The same pattern emerged in Experiment 2 as well. Specifically, for size, spatial frequency, and noise manipulations, easier conditions increased confidence for both correct trials (Size: β = 0.249, t(28) = 6.61, p = 3.62 x 10 -7 ; Spatial frequency: β = 0.342, t(28) = 6.14, p = 1.24 x 10 -6 ; Noise: β = 0.282, t(28) = 8.87, p = 1.25 x 10 -9 ) and error trials (Size: β = 0.175, t(28) = 6.07, p = 1.50 x 10 -6 ; Spatial frequency: β = 0.162, t(28) = 3.12, p = 0.004;</p><p>Noise: β = 0.176, t(28) = 4.56, p = 9.14 x 10 -5 ). In contrast, for the tilt offset manipulation, easier conditions increased confidence in the correct trials (β = 0.215, t(28) = 8.10, p = 8.13 x 10 -9 ), but decreased confidence in the error trials (β = -0.105, t(28) = -5.57, p = 5.79 x 10 -6 ).</p><p>These results demonstrate that the size, spatial frequency, duration, and noise manipulations violated the folded-X pattern and instead showed a joint increase in confidence for correct and error trials. In contrast, the tilt offset manipulation stood out in being the only manipulation that demonstrated the canonical folded-X pattern. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. Effects of each manipulation on confidence for correct vs. error trials (folded-X pattern). In both experiments, the canonical folded-X pattern (where easier conditions lead to a confidence increase for correct trials but a confidence decrease for error trials) only appeared for the tilt offset manipulation. All other stimulus manipulations (size, duration, noise, and spatial frequency) led to violations of the folded-X pattern, such that easier conditions led to increased confidence for both correct and error trials. The green and red lines denote the confidence for correct and incorrect trials, respectively. Error bars represent SEM. Statistical results show the significance of the one-sided t-test to determine if the average slope was significantly different from zero. The purple background highlights the tilt offset results, which are the only ones to exhibit the canonical folded-X pattern.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Discussion</head><p>We investigated the effects of multiple stimulus manipulations on confidence and accuracy.</p><p>Across two experiments, we manipulated size, duration, noise, spatial frequency, and tilt offset in an orientation discrimination task. We found that the tilt offset manipulation stands out in three different ways. Specifically, it is the only manipulation that (1) affects accuracy more strongly than confidence, (2) demonstrates the canonical folded-X pattern, and <ref type="formula">3</ref>exhibits supraadditive interactions with the other manipulations for both confidence and accuracy. In contrast, the other manipulations showed remarkably similar effects on confidence and accuracy despite the vast differences in how they impact the appearance of the stimuli. Overall, these results reveal surprisingly similar effects among four visually distinctive stimulus manipulations and a prominently different fifth manipulation. These results can be used to predict how untested stimulus manipulation would affect confidence and accuracy.</p><p>Several studies have found that different manipulations may sometimes produce different confidence-accuracy relationships. For instance, manipulating the variance of the elements in an ensemble averaging task affects confidence more than accuracy compared to manipulating the mean of the ensemble <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Boldt et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Spence et al., 2016)</ref>. Likewise, in an orientation discrimination task, a contrast manipulation affects confidence more than accuracy, whereas a tilt offset manipulation affects accuracy more than confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Xue et al., 2024)</ref>. However, such studies do not reveal if each manipulation has its own influence on the confidence-accuracy relationship, or if most manipulations conform to only a few patterns. Our results demonstrate that multiple visually distinctive stimulus manipulations produced just two distinct patterns of confidence-accuracy relationship. Specifically, except for the tilt offset manipulation which affects accuracy more than confidence, all other stimulus manipulations (i.e., size, duration, noise, and spatial frequency) have a relatively larger effect on confidence than accuracy. Critically, these stimulus manipulations demonstrate very similar confidence-accuracy relationship as indicated by the consistent slopes across different manipulations. Our results thus extend previous research by suggesting that, despite the existence of many possible stimulus manipulations, there may be a limited number of possible confidence-accuracy relationships that such manipulations could produce.</p><p>The folded-X pattern has been proposed as the statistical signature of confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sanders et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">cf. Rausch &amp; Zehetleitner, 2019)</ref>. However, numerous studies have reported violations of this pattern <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Hellmann et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Kiani et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Rausch et al., 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Rausch et al., , 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Xue et al., 2024)</ref>. Our results confirm that violations of the folded-X pattern are rather common. In fact, four of our five manipulations (size, duration, noise, and spatial frequency) showed violations of the folded-X pattern. Instead, these manipulations exhibited a double-increase pattern where easier conditions led to a confidence increase for both correct and error trials. Together with previous results, our study thus casts doubt on whether the folded-X pattern should be regarded as a fundamental feature of confidence judgments.</p><p>To our knowledge, only one previous study has examined the interactions between the effects of different manipulations on confidence. That study found no interaction between manipulating the mean color and manipulating the color variance in a color ensemble task <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Boldt et al., 2017</ref> was the only one to exhibit the folded-X pattern, and it alone showed supraadditive interactions with other manipulations. In our experiments, tilt offset is the task-defining stimulus feature in that it was the value of the stimulus tilt that determined the correct answer on each trial. In contrast, all other manipulations made it easier or harder to perceive the tilt value but did not define the correct stimulus category. This line of thought leads to the prediction that one would expect fundamentally different effects to emerge for manipulations that affect the task-defining features vs. manipulations that affect any nontask-defining stimulus feature.</p><p>A separate and non-mutually exclusive possibility is that what differentiates task offset from all other manipulations is how noticeable the manipulation is. Indeed, the tilt offset manipulation was perceptually subtle (e.g., in Experiment 1, the average tilt values for clockwise stimuli were 46.75°, 48.5°, and 52°, which are not easy to tell apart). In contrast, all other non-task-defining stimulus manipulations were readily apparent (e.g., durations of 33/100/500ms and sizes of 2.5°/5°/7.5° are easy to tell apart). Thus, it is possible that this difference in how noticeable a stimulus manipulation is drives the behavioral differences between the tilt offset and all other manipulations. In particular, subjects may use cues about the likely difficulty of the trial in their when making confidence judgements, as has been</p><p>proposed by the weighted evidence and visibility model <ref type="bibr">(WEV model;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hellmann et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Rausch et al., 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Rausch et al., , 2021</ref>. In addition, such heuristic incorporation of the perceived difficulty into confidence computations has been shown to allow for the emergence of both the folded-X and the double-increase patterns <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Rausch &amp; Zehetleitner, 2019)</ref>. Thus, it is possible that heuristic computations that involve estimating difficulty based on the perceived features of a stimulus could explain the observed difference between tilt offset and all other manipulations.</p><p>Based on these considerations, we can begin to predict how future yet untested manipulations would affect accuracy and confidence. Specifically, we would predict that manipulations of task-defining features that are also not readily noticeable would produce the effects associated with the tilt offset manipulation here. That is, such manipulations would have relatively more impact on accuracy than confidence, exhibit the folded-X pattern, and interact with all other non-task-defining stimulus manipulations supraadditively. In contrast, manipulations of non-task-defining features that are also readily noticeable would produce the effects associated with noise, duration, spatial frequency, and size. That is, such manipulations would have relatively less impact on accuracy than confidence, exhibit the double-increase pattern (violating the folded-X pattern), and show either no interactions or subadditive interactions among themselves. This proposed dichotomy is sufficiently robust to explain many existing findings with clearly distinguishable stimulus manipulations <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Boldt et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Kiani et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Moran et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Rausch et al., 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Rausch et al., , 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sanders et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Spence et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Xue et al., 2024)</ref>. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Kiani et al. (2014)</ref> found that manipulating the motion coherence (non-taskdefining feature) in a motion direction discrimination task produced the double-increase pattern. Conversely, in a task where subjects were required to judge the dominant color in an ensemble containing unequal amount of white and black squares, manipulating the proportion of the two colored squares (task-defining feature) created the canonical folded-X pattern <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Moran et al., 2015)</ref>. Overall, our interpretation is general enough to encompass many different stimulus manipulations and can potentially enable predicting the effects of new, untested manipulations applied to a range of perceptual tasks.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Task and experimental design. (a)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Experiment 1 behavioral results. (a) Relationship between confidence ratings and sensitivity(d')</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Experiment 2 behavioral results. (a) Relationship between confidence ratings and sensitivity(d')</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>All two-way interaction effects among stimulus manipulations for d' and confidence in Experiment 2. All interactions with the tilt offset manipulation (left) produced a consistent and similar supraadditive interaction for both d' and confidence. Interactions among all other stimulus manipulation (right) exhibited either no or subadditive interactions. Error bars represent SEM; p-values show interactions effects for two-way repeated measures ANOVAs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). In contrast, we observed numerous interactions on both accuracy and confidence. Specifically, the tilt offset manipulation demonstrated supraadditive interaction with all other stimulus manipulations on both confidence and accuracy. In contrast, size, noise, and spatial frequency exhibited either subadditive interactions or no interactions on accuracy and confidence. Critically, these interaction effects are unlikely to be artifacts of floor or ceiling effects because both d' and confidence values remained far from the central question raised by our work is what makes the tilt offset manipulations different from all others. Indeed, that manipulation had a unique confidence-accuracy relationship, it</figDesc><table><row><cell>boundaries (confidence values lied between 2.23 and 2.92; range = 1-4; d' values lied</cell></row><row><cell>between 1.0 and 2.52; range = 0-4.87). Our results demonstrate that interactions between</cell></row><row><cell>different manipulations are likely to be rather common but do not yet clarify the</cell></row><row><cell>mechanisms underlying these different interactions.</cell></row></table><note>A</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sensory noise increases metacognitive efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shekhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">148</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="437" to="452" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xge0000511.supp</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0000511.supp" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of evidence reliability on sensitivity and bias in decision confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Boldt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>De Gardelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xhp0000404</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xhp0000404" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1520" to="1531" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence reflects a noisy decision reliability estimate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Boundy-Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ziemba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L T</forename><surname>Goris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-022-01464-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-022-01464-x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive history biases result from confidence-weighted accumulation of past choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Urai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Donner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.jneurosci.org/content/38/10/2418.abstract" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2418" to="2429" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accounts of the confidenceaccuracy relation in recognition memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Busey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tunnicliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Loftus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Loftus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03210724</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03210724" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">jsPsych: A JavaScript library for creating behavioral experiments in a Web browser</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>De Leeuw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-014-0458-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-014-0458-y" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-evaluation of decision-making: A general Bayesian framework for metacognitive computation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000045</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000045" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forced-choice staircases with fixed step sizes: Asymptotic and small-sample properties</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Garcıá-Pérez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Vision Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1861" to="1881" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0042-6989(97</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0042-6989(97" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="340" to="344" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weighting Mean and Variability during Confidence Judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Gardelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mamassian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0120870</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0120870" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Feedback on Perceptual Decision-Making and Metacognition: Reduction in Bias but No Change in Sensitivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Haddara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/09567976211032887</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/doi.org/10.1177/09567976211032887" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="275" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Mathematical Framework for Statistical Decision Confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hangya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Sanders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kepecs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1840" to="1858" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/NECO_a_00864</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/NECO_a_00864" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simultaneous modeling of choice, confidence, and response time in visual perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hellmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zehetleitner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rausch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000411</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000411" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1521" to="1543" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence Is Influenced by Evidence Accumulation Time in Dynamical Decision Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hellmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zehetleitner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rausch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s42113-024-00205-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s42113-024-00205-9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Brain &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="313" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational framework for the study of confidence in humans and animals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kepecs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2012.0037</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2012.0037" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1322" to="1337" />
			<date type="published" when="1594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates, computation and behavioural impact of decision confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kepecs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Uchida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zariwala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nature07200</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nature07200" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">455</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7210</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="231" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice Certainty Is Informed by Both Evidence and Decision Time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Corthell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1329" to="1342" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2014.12.015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2014.12.015" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relative blindsight in normal observers and the neural correlate of visual consciousness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Passingham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.0607716103</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0607716103" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18763" to="18768" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Controlling for Participants&apos; Viewing Distance in Large-Scale, Psychophysical Online Experiments Using a Virtual Chinrest</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Joo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Yeatman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Reinecke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-019-57204-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-57204-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The signal processing architecture underlying subjective reports of sensory awareness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Maniscalco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/nc/niw002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/nc/niw002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroscience of Consciousness</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2016</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Post choice information integration as a causal determinant of confidence: Novel data and a computational account</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2015.01.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2015.01.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="147" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence and certainty: Distinct probabilistic quantities for different goals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pouget</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kepecs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.4240</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4240" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="366" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural network RTNet exhibits the signatures of human perceptual decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rafiei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shekhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-024-01914-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-024-01914-8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Suboptimality in perceptual decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Denison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X18000936</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X18000936" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Confidence in masked orientation judgments is informed by both evidence and visibility. Attention, Perception, &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rausch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hellmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zehetleitner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13414-017-1431-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13414-017-1431-5" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="154" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Modelling visibility judgments using models of decision confidence. Attention, Perception, &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rausch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hellmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zehetleitner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13414-021-02284-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13414-021-02284-3" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3311" to="3336" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The folded X-pattern is not necessarily a statistical signature of decision confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rausch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zehetleitner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007456</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007456" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-Making, Errors, and Confidence in the Brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Rolls</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Grabenhorst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Deco</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2359" to="2374" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1152/jn.00571.2010</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00571.2010" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signatures of a Statistical Computation in the Human Sense of Confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Sanders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hangya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kepecs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="506" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2016.03.025</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.03.025" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sources of Metacognitive Inefficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shekhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2020.10.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2020.10.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Nature of Metacognitive Inefficiency in Perceptual Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shekhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000249</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000249" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How do humans give confidence? A comprehensive comparison of process models of perceptual metacognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shekhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xge0001524</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0001524" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">153</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="656" to="688" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computations underlying confidence in visual perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Dux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Arnold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2015-53185-001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">671</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pupil-linked arousal is driven by decision uncertainty and alters serial choice bias</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Urai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Donner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/ncomms14637</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms14637" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">14637</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognitive confidence and affect -two sides of the same coin?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Voodla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Uusberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Desender</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition and Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02699931.2025.2451795</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02699931.2025.2451795" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dissociable effects of stimulus reliability and boundary distance on confidence and accuracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/865fs</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/865fs" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognition in human decision-making: Confidence and error monitoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Summerfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2011.0416</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2011.0416" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1310" to="1321" />
			<date type="published" when="1594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Variance misperception explains illusions of confidence in simple perceptual decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zylberberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Roelfsema</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sigman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.concog.2014.05.012</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.concog.2014.05.012" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Consciousness and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="246" to="253" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
