<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">ATTENTION AND NEGLECT UNDER SCARCITY</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brandon</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tomm</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eldar</forename><surname>Shafir</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Princeton School of Public and International Affairs Princeton University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiaying</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<email>jiayingz@psych.ubc.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute for Resources</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Environment and Sustainability</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology Institute for Resources, Environment and Sustainability University of British Columbia Vancouver</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>V6T 1Z4</postCode>
									<region>B.C., Canada</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">ATTENTION AND NEGLECT UNDER SCARCITY</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:45+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Scarcity</term>
					<term>visual attention</term>
					<term>memory</term>
					<term>decision making</term>
					<term>public policy Classifications: Psychological and cognitive sciences; economic sciences scarcity</term>
					<term>visual attention</term>
					<term>memory</term>
					<term>decision making</term>
					<term>public policy</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Scarcity poses challenging demands on the mind that can make escaping scarcity difficult. Using eyetracking and behavioral evidence, we find that scarcity induces an attentional focus, enhancing processing of scarcity-relevant information, while at the same time causing a failure to notice peripheral material, including information that may have proven beneficial in alleviating the scarcity condition. Participants were randomly assigned to a scarcity condition (with a small budget) or a control condition (with a large budget) while ordering a meal from a menu in a lab setting, while their eye gaze was tracked. We found that, compared to controls, participants under financial scarcity looked more at price information but less at the food items, calories and a discount that could alleviate their budget constraint (Experiment 1). In a subsequent memory test, participants under scarcity recalled price information more accurately than control participants (Experiment 2), and likewise those under calorie scarcity recalled calorie information more accurately than controls (Experiment 3). The results were replicated in a larger participant sample, where those under scarcity were less likely to request the discount than control participants (Experiment 4, Experiment 5 as a pre-registered replication). This neglect could be due to limited attention to peripheral information under scarcity (Experiment 6). These results support the notion that scarcity induces an attentional focus on scarcity-relevant information, while causing neglect elsewhere, including of beneficial information that can alleviate the scarcity condition. The findings help explain a range of counter-productive behaviors under scarcity and suggest ways to think about policy design and implementation to better guide attention and prevent neglect.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Significance Statement</head><p>When people have insufficient resources, they are required to adapt their behaviors under the resource constraint. In this paper we examined how people under scarcity attended to and remembered information in the environment and made subsequent decisions. We found that people under scarcity increased their visual attention to price information and were more accurate in their recall of the information. But they also showed a neglect of other information, even useful information that could alleviate their resource constraint. Consequentially, people under scarcity were less likely to take advantage of the benefit that was available to them. These results suggest that scarcity draws attention to the focal task at the expense of peripheral information, which helps explain some counterproductive behaviors of people under scarcity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Contexts of scarcity are a pervasive aspect of the human experience. Despite significant progress in poverty alleviation, recent estimates are that around 9% of the world's population (711 million people) currently live on less than $1.90 a day (World <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Bank, 2020)</ref>. Even in higherincome countries, poverty rates are substantial: 11.4% in the United States (Census <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bureau, 2021)</ref>, and 6.4% in Canada <ref type="bibr">(Statistics Canada, 2022)</ref>. Scarcity can also occur in other resources such as time, calories, companionship . A growing literature on the psychology of scarcity has documented a variety of meaningful impacts of scarcity on the mind. In this literature, scarcity is defined as a condition in which a person feels they have insufficient resources to cope (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">De Bruijn &amp; Antonides, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Zhao &amp; Tomm, 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, 2018</ref>.</p><p>In other words, scarcity instigates the experience of not having enough. While a scarcity mindset is partly subjective, resource scarcity can be manipulated by making a valuable resource more or less available. While some studies conceptualized scarcity in subjective terms (e.g., with respect to social reference groups, <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Tully &amp; Sharma, 2022)</ref>, in the current study we opt for a definition by manipulating the monetary resources available to cope with the demand.</p><p>A number of studies have shown that scarcity can lead to adaptations that enhance people's performance. For example, people under scarcity consume resources more efficiently <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Shah, Mullainathan, &amp; Shafir, 2012)</ref>; have more stable perceptions of the value of goods <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Shah, Shafir, &amp; Mullainathan, 2015)</ref>; are better at detecting imminent dangers <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Frankenhuis &amp; Nettle, 2020)</ref>; respond faster to scarcity-related words <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Gutierrez &amp; Hershey, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Shapiro &amp; Burchell, 2012)</ref>; and, with financial scarcity, are more likely to know the prices of goods, ranging from supermarket purchases to the cost of a taxi, despite lower taxi use .</p><p>These psychological adaptations extend beyond financial scarcity. For example, people who are hungry are more likely to detect food-related images or words on a computer screen compared to people who have recently eaten <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Piech, Pastorino, &amp; Zald, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Radel &amp; Clément-Guillotin, 2012)</ref>. People who are thirsty are more likely to focus on water-related cues <ref type="bibr">(Aarts, Dijksterhuis, &amp; De Vries, 2001)</ref>. People who have alcohol use disorder or who are on a diet are more likely to attend to alcohol and food-related cues, respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Stetter, Ackermann, Bizer, Straube, &amp; Mann, 1995)</ref>. These examples support the notion that scarcity prioritizes relevant information and focuses attention on scarcity-relevant tasks.</p><p>The drawback of focused attention and cognitive resources under scarcity is the neglect of other potentially helpful information in the environment. With a cognitive system of finite capacity, people can only attend to and process a limited amount of information at a time <ref type="bibr">(Baddeley, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Luck &amp; Vogel, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Miller, 1956;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Pashler, Johnston, &amp; Ruthruff, 2001</ref>).</p><p>Engaging in one process consumes cognitive resources that may otherwise have been devoted to another, thus causing interference. For example, studies on inattentional blindness <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Simons &amp; Chabris, 1999)</ref> show that performing a demanding task (e.g., counting how often a basketball is passed around) results in the neglect of a salient event (e.g., a man dressed as a gorilla walking through the court). Salient information in the environment may be neglected despite being clearly visible to the eyes <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Rock &amp; Gutman, 1981)</ref>. Of course, such cognitive limitations can have serious consequences, such as impaired driving <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Strayer, Drews, &amp; Johnston, 2003)</ref>.</p><p>In the context of scarcity, the heightened focus required to manage scarce resources can impair performance on other tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Mani et al., 2013)</ref>. People of lower-income are more likely than those with higher-incomes to think about money and costs in mundane everyday situations that are not directly about finances <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Shah et al., 2018)</ref>. Low-income manufacturing workers in India were more worried about finances, were less focused and showed more attentional errors at work before getting paid than after <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Kaur et al., 2021)</ref>. Financial scarcity has also been shown to reduce verbal interactions from parents to children <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Ellwood-Lowe et al., 2022)</ref>. Scarcity of time has been found to contribute to unhealthy food choices and reduced physical activity, along other time-management mishaps <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Venn &amp; Strazdins, 2017</ref>).</p><p>In the current study, we examine the attentional, memory, and behavioral effects of scarcity in a single paradigm, exploring the interplay of scarcity's positive and negative consequences in an everyday task. Specifically, we hypothesize that competing demands for cognitive resources can result in attentional trade-offs where people focus on information relevant to the task at hand (e.g., staying within the budget) but at the same time fail to attend to peripheral information that can be beneficial (e.g., noticing a discount). In other words, scarcity results in attentional enhancement of scarcity-relevant information but also causes neglect. The enhanced attentional focus has memory benefits, with greater recall of scarcity-relevant information, but the peripheral neglect has negative consequences, namely, failure to take advantage of an available benefit.</p><p>To investigate the attentional trade-offs under scarcity we conducted six experiments.</p><p>Participants were randomly assigned to a scarcity condition with a small budget or a control condition with a large budget. Their task was to order a meal from a menu, and their eye gaze on the menu was tracked via an eyetracker or with the BubbleView technique. We first examined participants' attention to the dishes, price information, calorie information, and a discount offered at the bottom of the menu while they decided which food to order (Experiment 1). We found that participants in the scarcity condition attended more to price information but neglected the discount. Following the increased attention to prices, participants showed better memory recall for information relevant to their financial scarcity in a subsequent surprise memory test (Experiments 2 and 3). We then extended the methods of Experiment 1 to a larger online sample and found that the attentional neglect under scarcity caused participants to fail to use a moneysaving discount, which, paradoxically, would alleviate the scarcity condition (Experiments 4 and 5). Finally, we investigated the possibility that the neglect under scarcity could be attributable to less flexibility in the allocation of attention to peripheral information (Experiment 6). The results provide a cognitive explanation for neglectful behaviors often observed in scarcity contexts, and have policy implications for better serving those in scarcity conditions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1</head><p>The goal of this experiment was to examine the effects of scarcity on attention. We predict that attention is drawn to the scarcity-relevant task at hand, potentially neglecting peripheral information, including some which may alleviate the scarcity condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>One hundred and ninety undergraduate students (152 female, 35 male, 3 unspecified; mean age=20.39 years, SD=3.92) were recruited from the Human Subject Pool at the Department of Psychology at the University of British Columbia (UBC), and participated in the experiment for course credit. The sample size was determined by a power analysis assuming a minimum effect size d of 0.41 and power of 0.8 in an independent-samples t-test. All experiments were approved by the UBC Behavioural Research Ethics Board (H13-02686). Participants in all experiments reported normal or corrected-to-normal vision and provided informed consent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimuli and Procedure</head><p>Participants completed the study one at a time in a lab testing room seated in front of a computer with an SMI RED-250 Mobile Eyetracking System (a sample rate of 60Hz). Each participant was presented with a restaurant menu containing 24 food items. The price and calories of each item were listed in the middle and right columns of the menu, respectively <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>). A discount clause was shown on the bottom of the menu ("You may ask for an 18% student discount."). The menu subtended 12.4° of visual angle in width and 16.2° in height.</p><p>Participants were randomly assigned to a scarcity condition (N=95) with a small budget ($20) or a control condition (N=95) with a large budget ($100) that they could use to order the meal. They were instructed to view the menu and think about what they would like to order, as if they were ordering a meal from a restaurant. They had unlimited time to place the order, were not to exceed their budget, but were not required to spend it all. Once they had decided on their order, participants reported the items verbally to the experimenter sitting next to them.</p><p>The eye gaze of each participant was monitored throughout the experiment using the SMI eyetracker. To examine which part of the menu was attended to, the menu was divided into four areas of interest: food items (left column), price information (middle column), calorie information (right column), and discount clause (on the bottom). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>The heat maps of average dwell time duration for the scarcity and control conditions are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. While there was no time limit, we found that participants in the control condition took longer to order (M=89.44 seconds, SD=40.55 seconds) than those in the scarcity We calculated the proportional dwell time (dwell time spent in each area divided by total dwell time on the menu) and the proportional fixations (number of fixations in each area divided by the total number of fixations on the menu) as two primary measures of visual attention in each area of interest ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). In addition, outliers (participants with more than 2.5 standard deviations away from the mean in each measure) were excluded from further analysis (between 1 and 4 participants in total). For the food items, participants in the scarcity condition spent less proportional dwell time (M=33.66%, SD=20.40%) than those in the control condition (M=51.98%, SD=35.09%)  Participants under scarcity paid less attention to the peripheral discount information (which, paradoxically, could have alleviated their budgetary constraint).</p><p>Due to a procedural glitch the number of participants who requested the discount was not recorded. And while those under scarcity looked less at the discount than did control participants, there was no reliable difference in the number of participants who reported noticing the discount when asked [X 2 (1,190)=0.09, p=.76]. Experiments 4 and 5 were designed to address these shortcomings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2</head><p>One potential consequence of the greater attention to prices under scarcity would be better memory for prices. This is supported by evidence that visual working memory can be construed as visual attention preserved internally over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Chun, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Chun, Golumb, &amp; Turk-Browne, 2011)</ref>. Theories of feature-based of attention also predict selective facilitation in visual processing for task-relevant features <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Hayden &amp; Gallant, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Jehee, Brady, &amp; Tong, 2011)</ref>. We conducted Experiment 2 to examine the effects of scarcity on recall, as a result of attentional prioritization. We predict that scarcity will facilitate recall specifically for price information, but not for other types of information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants, Stimuli and Procedure</head><p>Sixty undergraduate students (43 female, 17 male; mean age=19.95 years, SD=2.30) from UBC participated in the experiment for course credit. To increase memory demand, we now presented participants with a menu that consisted of 50 rather than 24 food items. As in Experiment 1, each item included price and calorie information. Participants were asked to place a meal order from the menu like they would in a restaurant. As before, there was no time limit and participants were randomly assigned to a scarcity ($20, N=30) or a control condition ($100, N=30). Immediately after placing their order, participants were given a surprise memory test asking them to recall as many menu food items as possible. For each item recalled, they were also asked to recall its price and calorie information as accurately as possible. Participants typed their responses onto a spreadsheet on the computer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>To measure recall, we calculated the average absolute error between the recalled prices and calories and the actual prices and calories for each participant <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Figure 3)</ref>  Furthermore, any differences in the ordering experience of those under financial scarcity manifested only in improved price recall -not in recall for calorie content.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3</head><p>To extend the findings of Experiment 2 to a different scarcity domain, we examined how calorie scarcity affects recall of calorie information. We predict that imposing a calorie budget would facilitate recall specifically for calorie information, but not for price information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants, Stimuli and Procedure</head><p>Sixty undergraduate students (49 female, 11 male; mean age=20.03 years, SD=2.11) from UBC participated in the experiment for course credit. The stimuli and procedure were identical to those of Experiment 2, except that participants were now randomly assigned to a calorie scarcity condition (the order could not exceed 500 calories, N=30) or a control condition (order could not exceed 2000 calories, N=30). As before, participants placed an order from the menu as if ordering from a restaurant. They were then given a surprise memory test, where they recalled as many menu items as they could, along with the items' price and calorie information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>This time participants in the calorie scarcity condition were more accurate in calorie recall (Mean error=44.60 calories, SD=31.99 calories) than those in the control condition (Mean  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Figure 4</ref>). Experiments 2 and 3 find that scarcity selectively facilitates memory recall of scarcityrelevant information, consistent with Experiment 1's findings of greater attention devoted to that information. In both Experiments 2 and 3, although relatively less attention was presumably paid to peripheral information, we did not see a significant decline in recall of that information. That is, calorie recall was similar for the finance scarce and control participants in Experiment 2, and price recall was similar for the calorie scarce and control participants in Experiment 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 4</head><p>Experiment 4 was similar to the first two experiments, but now included an improved procedure intended to shed light on the potential impact under scarcity of reduced peripheral attention on participants' utilization of the discount information. The discount was now more generous and the procedure to obtain it was made simpler. The announcement at the bottom of the menu now read: "Type 'special' with your order to get your entire meal for free (up to $60)!" Thus, participants simply had to type "special" with their order to obtain the discount.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Participants were drawn from a US-based population on Amazon Mechanical Turk (Mturk). We first collected a sample of N=429 participants who completed the study on Mturk and we then excluded any participant who responded with the same IP address as a previous participant. We also excluded, all before data analysis, participants who exceeded their budget or who spent less than 10 seconds viewing the menu. We also excluded from data analysis all participants who were more than 2.5 standard deviations from the mean on any other measure.</p><p>After exclusions, we retained a sample of N=344 participants (185 female, 155 male, 4 unspecified; mean age=37.35 years, SD=12.33 years).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimuli and Procedure</head><p>Participants were randomly assigned to the scarcity ($20, N=145) or the control condition ($100, N=199), and viewed a menu similar to that used in Experiment 1 on their web browser. required to use their cursor to reveal the underlying content via a fovea-like circular area around the mouse (similar to the BubbleView technique; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Kim et al., 2017)</ref>. The cursor movements thus dynamically revealed the menu behind the mask (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref>). The location of the cursor was tracked as a proxy for visual attention. After viewing the menu, participants typed their order on the next page. They then performed a surprise memory test where they were shown the menu with the items, prices, and calorie information missing, and were asked to recall as many food items as possible, along with their prices and calories as in Experiment 2. Finally, participants' demographic information was collected. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>Similar to Experiment 1, participants in the control condition, with substantially larger budgets, spent more time viewing the menu (M=95.42 seconds, SD=62.21 seconds, versus M=80.63 seconds, SD=53.30 seconds; [t(330)=2. <ref type="bibr">28, p=.023, d=0.26]</ref>) and more money on the order <ref type="bibr">(M=$25.43,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD=$8.69,</ref><ref type="bibr">versus M=$15.22,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD=$3.92 [t(338)</ref>=13.14, p&lt;.001, d=1.52]) than participants in the scarcity condition. As in Experiment 1, we calculated the proportional dwell time of the cursor in each area of interest to measure visual attention ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6</ref>).  Requesting the discount. As in Experiment 1, scarcity appears to draw attention to price information at the expense of peripheral, potentially beneficial information. Significantly fewer participants in the scarcity condition (15.86%) requested the discount than did participants in the control condition (33.17%) [X 2 (1)=13.10, p&lt;.001, Cramer's V=.20] <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Figure 7</ref>). This suggests a behavioral consequence of attentional neglect under scarcity. Those who stood to benefit the most from the discount were less likely to notice and request it.   <ref type="bibr">p=.338]</ref>. This suggests that the difference in price recall may be due to the small number of recall items in the scarcity condition. We also measured memory of the discount amount ($60) and found that participants in the scarcity condition were less likely to correctly recall the discount (20.00% of participants) compared to participants in the control condition (38.69% of participants; X 2 (1,344)=13.75, p&lt;.001, Cramer's V=0.20). Participants in the scarcity condition who requested the discount. We compared the behavior of participants in the scarcity condition (15.86%) who requested the discount to that of the entire group of control participants <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">(Figure 9)</ref>. This is to see if those under scarcity adopted the behaviors of participants with a larger budget once they knew their budget, with the discount, was effectively larger. Indeed, we found that the discount-requesters in the scarcity condition looked at prices for a similar proportion of time (M=9.67%, SD=7.71%) as participants in the control condition (M=12.14%, SD=8.27%) [t(213)=1. <ref type="bibr">34, p=.183, d=0.31]</ref>. They also looked at the food items for a similar proportion of time (M=48.96%, SD=14.19%) as the control participants (M=53.11%, SD=14.48%) [t(218)=1. <ref type="bibr">30, p=.194, d=0.29]</ref>, and at the caloric information for a similar proportion of time (M=4.05%, SD=3.83%) as the controls (M=4.38%.  We also compared the discount requesters to the non-requesters in the scarcity condition ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref>). Interestingly, discount requesters did not spend more money on the order (M=$14.74, SD=$4.33) than non-requesters in the scarcity condition <ref type="bibr">(M=$15.23,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD=$3.95)</ref> [t(143)=0. <ref type="bibr">53, p=.596, d=0.12]</ref>, and they also spent significantly less than participants in the control condition <ref type="bibr">(M=$25.43,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD=$8.69) [t(217)=5.80,</ref><ref type="bibr">p&lt;.001,</ref><ref type="bibr">d=1.56]</ref>. This could be due to the possibility that discount requesters still anchored on the original budget, instead of the larger budget they requested for. Discount-requesters looked less at price information (M=9.67%, SD=7.71%) than non-requesters in the scarcity condition (M=17.65%, SD=10.88%) <ref type="bibr">[t(139)=3.29, p=.001, d=0.85]</ref>. This suggests that the attentional effects of scarcity can be reduced as soon as budget constraints are relaxed, even if spending allocation does not change significantly as a result. For calorie information, we found that participants in the scarcity condition who requested the discount (M=4.05%, SD=3.83%) looked at calories for a similar amount of time as participants in the scarcity condition who did not (M=5.59%, SD=5.37%) [t(142)=1. <ref type="bibr">31, p=.191, d=0.33]</ref>. Discount-requesters also looked at the food items (M=48.96%, SD=14.19%) similarly to the non-requesters (M=46.61%, SD=16.03%) <ref type="bibr">[t(142)=0.66, p=.513, d=0.16]</ref>. As expected, participants in the scarcity condition who requested the discount looked more at the discount (M=14.53%, SD=5.19%) than participants who did not request the discount (M=0.85%, SD=1.63%) <ref type="bibr">[t(136)=23.34, p&lt;.001, d=3.56]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 5</head><p>Results of Experiment 4 replicated those in Experiments 1 and 2 with a larger online sample. To increase the robustness of these findings, we further conducted a pre-registered replication of Experiment 4 (https://osf.io/9j4hu), seeking to replicate three key findings: participants in the scarcity condition look more at prices than control participants (finding 1); participants in the scarcity condition look less at the discount than control participants (finding 2); and participants in the scarcity condition are less likely to request the discount than control participants (finding 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Based on the effect sizes observed in Experiment 4, we did a power analysis using G*Power to determine the sample size in this experiment. To replicate finding 1, we need a minimum of 248 participants (d=0.46, power=0.95); to replicate finding 2, we need a minimum of 480 participants (d=0.33, power=0.95); and to replicate finding 3, we need a minimum of 430 participants (Cramer's V=.20, power=0.95). To meet a minimum sample size of 480, we first ran 738 participants from a US-based population on Mturk. Based on pre-registered exclusion criteria, we removed participants who did not complete the study, had duplicate IP address, overspent their budget, viewed the menu for less than 10 seconds, provided nonsensical</p><p>responses for the open-ended questions at the ordering phase or recall test, or were 2.5 SDs away from the mean of any measure. After exclusions, we were left with a final sample of 552 participants (280 female, 272 male, mean age=35.98 years, SD=11.29 years).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimuli and Procedure</head><p>We used the same stimuli and procedure as in Experiment 4. Participants were randomly assigned to the scarcity condition ($20, N=252) or the control condition ($100, N=300). After submitting their order, participants performed the surprise recall test.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>As in Experiment 4, participants in the control condition spent more time viewing the menu (M=92.31 seconds, SD=69. <ref type="bibr">21 seconds,</ref><ref type="bibr">versus M=75.40 seconds,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD=49.59 seconds,</ref><ref type="bibr">[t(531)=3.19,</ref><ref type="bibr">p=.002,</ref><ref type="bibr">d=0.28])</ref>, and spent more money on the order <ref type="bibr">(M=$25.23,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD=$11.58,</ref><ref type="bibr">versus M=$15.17,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD=$4.04)</ref> [t(540)=13.10, p&lt;.001, d=1.16]) than participants in the scarcity condition. As before, we calculated the proportional dwell time in each area of interest. The gaze heatmap is presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 11</ref>.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 6</head><p>The prior experiments consistently showed that financial scarcity draws attention to price information but reduces attention to the discount offer located on the bottom of the menu.</p><p>To see if this neglect was driven by differential attention to the periphery in those under scarcity and those who are not, we conducted Experiment 6 where we replaced the discount with a neutral statement about the restaurant located on the bottom of the menu.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Participants were recruited from a US-based population on Mturk. The same exclusion criteria as Experiments 4 and 5 were used. After exclusions, a final sample of 401 participants was analyzed (236 female, 162 male, 3 unspecified; mean age=37.53 years, SD=12.18 years).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimuli and Procedure</head><p>The stimuli and procedure were identical to those of Experiments 4 and 5, except that the peripheral discount offer was now replaced by a neutral statement, of similar character length, at the bottom of the menu ("This restaurant has served customers using local ingredients since 1960!").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>As in previous experiments, participants in the scarcity condition (N=196) looked more at prices (M=18.10%, SD=9.36%) than participants in the control condition (N=205, M=12.27%, SD=7.75%) [t(385)=6.69, p&lt;.001, d=0.68] <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 13</ref>). Participants in the scarcity condition also looked less at the food items (M=49.59%, SD=13.55%) than the control participants (M=54.80%,  <ref type="bibr">83, p=.407, d=0.08]</ref>). This suggests that scarcity might still allow a cursory glance, perhaps as a form of minimal vigilance, while still retaining attentional bias toward scarcity-relevant information. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attention to the periphery (neutral statement vs. useful discount)</head><p>To further explore attention to the periphery, we compared participants' dwell time for the neutral statement in Experiment 6 to their dwell time for the discount offer in the same region in Experiment 4. We conducted a two-way ANOVA on dwell time (Experiment: 4 discount vs. 6 statement x Condition: scarcity vs. control), and found a significant interaction [F(1,722)=7.44, p=.007, ηp 2 =0.01], where participants in the control condition increased their attention to the peripheral information when it was a useful discount (4.80%) compared to a neutral statement (1.82%), more than did participants in the scarcity condition (3.06% vs. 1.66% respectively).</p><p>This suggests a more flexible broadening of attention when peripheral information matters among controls than among scarcity participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>The current study examined the attentional, memory, and behavioral consequences of scarcity. Compared to those with a larger budget, participants operating with a tight financial budget attended more to price information, which in turn decreased attention to other information in the environment. In the current case of a restaurant menu, this included calorie information, food items, and even a beneficial discount (Experiment 1). Whereas those with a constrained budget were focused on what they could afford, those with a larger budget had the cognitive "luxury" to think about what food they would like to eat, along with its calorie contents, and were also able to notice the offered discount. The focus on price at the expense of other information could help explain the rising obesity epidemic in low-income communities <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Townsend, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>The attentional prioritization corresponded to enhanced recall of price information among participants under financial scarcity (Experiment 2), and to better recall of calorie information among participants under caloric scarcity (Experiment 3), consistent with the notion of increased attention and improved recall of scarcity-relevant information under scarcity conditions. This is consistent with findings that low-income individuals know better than higher-income individuals how much things cost . The findings suggest that scarcity fundamentally shapes the allocation of attention, increasing attention to scarcity-relevant tasks, while inducing neglect of peripheral information that might have proven beneficial.</p><p>One discrepancy in the memory recall results between Experiment 2 and Experiment 4 is that the better recall accuracy of prices under scarcity in Experiment 2 disappeared after controlling for the number of items recalled in Experiment 4. This could be due to a number of differences in the designs of the two experiments. First, the menu in Experiment 2 contained more items (50 items) than the menu in Experiment 4 (24 items), and the larger number may have increased the variability of items that could be encoded in Experiment 2. Second, participants in Experiment 2 recalled more items (around 7 and 8 items) than those in Experiment 4 (around 4 items) which may be a floor effect in the small number of recalled items.</p><p>Third, participants in Experiment 2 were students who completed the experiment in a highly controlled lab setting, whereas participants in Experiment 4 were online from Mturk and we could not control their setting during the experiment. Despite the inconsistent results on memory recall, we were still able to replicate the attentional effects under scarcity across experiments.</p><p>The neglect of peripheral information can at times further aggravate the conditions of scarcity. We extended the methods of Experiment 1 to a larger online sample and found that participants under scarcity were less likely to pay attention to and take advantage of a moneysaving discount that could have alleviated their scarcity condition (Experiment 4). The neglect of the discount among scarcity participants was replicated in a pre-registered study (Experiment 5).</p><p>The attentional neglect observed in Experiments 4 and 5 could be explained by a narrowing of spatial attention to the focal task under scarcity (i.e., ordering a meal within a small budget), with less attention left for the periphery. To directly test attention to the periphery, we replaced the discount offer with a neutral statement and found no difference in dwell time on the periphery between the scarcity and control conditions (Experiment 6). This suggests that control participants were better able to broaden their attention to peripheral information when it proved useful, in contrast with participants under scarcity who, vigilant glances notwithstanding, were less able to flexibly redirect their attention.</p><p>The rigidity of attention under scarcity may help explain a range of behaviors that make escaping poverty difficult, such as the inability to shift attention from financial dimensions to non-monetary aspects of mundane events <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Shah et al., 2018)</ref>, from short-term spending to longterm savings <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Demirguc-Kunt et al., 2018)</ref>, and from immediate costs of enrollment to future benefits of social services (FNS, 2020). Past theories hold that people remain in poverty because they lack proper education (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bernheim, Garrett, &amp; Maki, 2001)</ref> or have character flaws (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Salling &amp; Harvey, 1981</ref>). Here we suggest that the context of scarcity demands attention, causes neglect of potentially useful information, and shapes memory and subsequent decision making. This insight has broad implications. For example, a full 20%-50% of households in the US who qualify for social services do not use these programs, despite the net benefits these programs provide <ref type="bibr">(FNS, 2020)</ref>. In OECD countries, 20%-60% of eligible households are not enrolled in social benefit programs <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Hernanz, Malherbet, &amp; Pellizzari, 2004)</ref>. In Belgium, between 57%-76% of eligible individuals are not enrolled in a guaranteed income program <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bouckaert &amp; Schokkaert, 2011</ref>; see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Dubois &amp; Ludwinek, 2015)</ref>. One reason provided by the current study is that people under scarcity may not attend to these programs and services because they are preoccupied by more urgent financial matters (e.g., bills to pay). But this problem can be solved by making the beneficial services more salient, for example by presenting the enrollment information along with people's paycheck or bills that they tend to prioritize.</p><p>Another solution is sending reminders via texts or phone calls to catch people's attention. Future studies can test if interventions that make social services more salient increase enrollment.</p><p>In conclusion, the current study provides several theoretical and practical implications.</p><p>First, the study offers a cognitive account on how scarcity distorts information processing by increasing attention to scarcity-relevant information (e.g., prices) away from other information (e.g., calories) and even beneficial information that helps alleviate scarcity. This attentional trade-off may help explain some of the counter-productive behaviors (e.g., neglect) under poverty. Second, the study presents first evidence on attentional rigidity under scarcity where attention to peripheral beneficial information is harder to shift under scarcity. This helps explain why certain interventions failed to capture attention in low-income individuals. Third, the study provides some modest insight on how to design interventions to better serve low-income individuals by making critical, beneficial information more available to their focused attention.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Materials</head><p>Additional results in Experiment 5.</p><p>Attention on the menu. As in Experiment 4, all attentional results reported were proportional dwell time. While we found that participants in the scarcity condition looked more at prices and less at the discount than participants in the rich condition, we found no differences in time viewing the food items (scarcity condition: M=49.11%, SD=14.99%; control condition: <ref type="bibr">22, p=.224, d=0.11]</ref> or the calorie information (scarcity condition: M=4.25%, SD=4.31%; control condition: M=4.47%, SD=4.76%) <ref type="bibr">[t(540)=0.56, p=.576, d=0.05]</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure S1</ref>). Memory recall. We first removed 20 participants from the following analyses because their recall errors were greater than $100, because the total budget for the control condition was $100. We found that participants in the scarcity condition made smaller errors in price recall (mean absolute error=$0.73, SD=$0.70) compared to participants in the control condition (mean absolute error=$1.07, SD=$1.07) <ref type="bibr">[t(495)=4.09, p&lt;.001, d=0.38]</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure S2</ref>). There was no difference in the calorie recall errors between participants in the scarcity condition (mean absolute error=146.19 calories, SD=119.27 calories) and the control condition (mean absolute error=136.92 calories, SD=107.10 calories) [t(497)=0. <ref type="bibr">91, p=.361, d=0.08]</ref>. Similar to the results of Experiment 4, these findings show how scarcity prioritizes attention to price information and enhances memory recall for price information, but not for calorie information.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure S3</ref>).</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">M=50.70%, SD=15.39%) [t(541)=1.</formula><p>As expected, discount-requesters in the scarcity condition looked more at the discount (M=12.78%, SD=5.06%) than participants in the control condition (M=4.67%, SD=5.88%)</p><p>[t(319)=6. <ref type="bibr">93, p&lt;.001, d=1.48]</ref>. As in Experiment 4, discount-requesters in the scarcity condition recalled price information with comparable accuracy (mean absolute error=$0.78, <ref type="bibr">SD=$0.65)</ref> with participants in the control condition (mean absolute error=$1.07, SD=$1.07) [t(296)=1. <ref type="bibr">40, p=.163, d=0.33</ref>], suggesting that participants in the scarcity condition who requested the discount behaved like those in the control condition. These results replicated those in Experiment 4. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure S3</ref>. Experiment 5 attention results of those who requested the discount in the scarcity condition. The proportional dwell time in each area of interest between participants who requested the discount in the scarcity and all participants in the control condition (error bars reflect ±1 SEM, ***p&lt;.001).</p><p>In the scarcity condition, discount requesters looked more at the discount (M=12.78%, SD=5.06%) than those who did not request the discount (M=1.05%, SD=1.84%) [t(238)=23.83, p&lt;.001, d=3.08] ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S4</ref>). However, discount requesters and non-requested looked similarly at prices (requesters: M=14.91%, SD=10.15%; non-requesters: M=16.54%, SD=9.82%)  The proportional dwell time in each area of interest between participants who requested the discount vs. those who did not in the scarcity condition (error bars reflect ±1 SEM, ***p&lt;.001).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Experiment 1 eye gaze distribution. A heat map of eye gaze showing the distribution of average dwell time for participants: Left: in the scarcity condition (budget of $20); Right: in the control condition (budget of $100). Warmer colors represent longer average dwell time.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Experiment 1 eyetracking results. Proportional dwell time and proportional fixations in each area of interest for participants in the scarcity and control conditions (error bars reflect ±1 SEM, ***p&lt;.001, **p&lt;.01, *p&lt;.05).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>For the discount clause, participants in the scarcity condition spent less time (M=0.66%, SD=1.10%) attending to the discount than those in the control condition (M=1.75%, SD=2.15%)[t(181)=4.31, p&lt;.001, d=0.64]. They also made fewer fixations on the discount clause (M=0.78%, SD=1.20%) than the controls (M=1.68%, SD=1.10%) [t(181)=3.52, p=.001, d=0.52].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Experiment 2 price and calorie recall. Absolute error in price and calorie recall for participants in the scarcity and control conditions (error bars reflect ±1 SEM; *p&lt;.05).The higher accuracy in price recall in the scarcity condition occurred despite the fact that participants in the scarcity condition spent less time placing their order (although the difference was not significant; Scarcity: M=67.13 seconds, SD=31.73; Control: M=84.56 seconds,SD=46.18 seconds [t(55)=1.67, p=.101, d=0.44]), and ordered fewer items (Scarcity: M=2.03 items, SD=0.57; Control: M=3.48 items, SD=1.74 items, [t(56)=4.25, p&lt;.001, d=1.12]). The difference in price recall accuracy persists after controlling for the number of items recalled (Scarcity: M=7.10 items recalled; Control: M=8.57 items recalled; F(1,55)=7.27, p=.009).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Experiment 3 price and calorie recall. Absolute error in price and calorie recall for participants in the calorie scarcity and control conditions (error bars reflect ±1 SEM; *p&lt;.05).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Experiment 4 menu and BubbleView technique. Left: the menu used for Experiments 4 and 5. Right: participant view of the menu using the BubbleView technique, where a cursor is used to reveal the menu behind the mask.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Experiment 4 distribution of attention using BubbleView. A heat map of cursor position showing the distribution of dwell time for participants, Left: in the scarcity condition (budget of $20); Right: in the control condition (budget of $100). Warmer colors represent longer average dwell time.Attention on the menu. As captured inFigure 7, and consistent with Experiment 1, participants in the scarcity condition spent more time looking at prices (M=16.56%, SD=10.93%,  versus M=12.14%, SD=8.27% [t(333)=4.21, p&lt;.001, d=0.46), and less time looking at the food items (M=47.27%, SD=15.40%, versus M=53.11%, SD=14.48) [t(338)=3.57, p&lt;.001, d=0.39])    than participants in the control condition. There was no significant difference in dwell time on calorie information (Scarcity: M=5.22%, SD=4.96%, versus Control: M=4.38%, SD=4.72%)    [t(334)=1.57, p=.118, d=0.17]). However, participants in the scarcity condition spent less time looking at the discount on the bottom of the menu (M=3.06%, SD=5.12%) compared to control participants (M=4.80%, SD=5.47%) [t(332)=2.95, p=.003, d=0.33].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Experiment 4 results. Proportional dwell time in each area of interest for participants in the scarcity and control conditions (error bars reflect ±1 SEM, ***p&lt;.001, **p&lt;.01, *p&lt;.05).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Memory</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Experiment 4 price and calorie recall. The absolute error in price recall and calorie recall between participants in the scarcity and control conditions (error bars reflect ±1 SEM; ***p&lt;.001, *p&lt;.05).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>SD=4.72%)[t(214)=0.33, p=.744, d=0.08]. They spent a larger proportion of time (M=14.53%, SD=5.19%) looking at the discount compared to participants in the control condition (M=4.80%,SD=5.47%) [t(215)=8.11, p&lt;.001, d=1.83]. Finally, discount-requesters in the scarcity condition recalled price information with the same accuracy (Mean error=$1.26, SD=$1.09) as those in the control condition (Mean error=$1.23, SD=$1.04)[t(216)=0.32, p=.746, d=0.08]. These results suggest that those initially under scarcity shifted their attention to look much like participants with a larger budget once they realized they had access to a discount alleviating their budgetary constraint.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Experiment 4 attention results of participants who requested the discount in the scarcity condition. Proportional dwell time in each area of interest for scarcity participants who requested the discount and for control participants (error bars reflect ±1 SEM, ***p&lt;.001).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 10 .</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Experiment 4 attention results of participants who requested vs. did not request the discount in the scarcity condition. Proportional dwell time in each area of interest for scarcity participants who requested the discount vs. those who did not (error bars reflect ±1 SEM, ***p&lt;.001, **p&lt;.01).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 11 .</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Experiment 5 distribution of attention using BubbleView. A heat map showing the distribution of dwell time for the participants, Left: in the scarcity condition (budget of $20). Right: in the control condition (budget of $100). Warmer colors represent longer average dwell time. The pre-registered analyses are shown in Figure 12. First, participants in the scarcity condition spent a larger proportion of time looking at price information (M=16.36%, SD=9.85%) compared to control participants (M=12.28%, SD=8.26%) [t(538)=5.26, p&lt;.001, d=0.45]. Second, participants in the scarcity condition spent a smaller proportion of time looking at the discount (M=2.29%, SD=3.94%) compared to control participants (M=4.67%, SD=5.88%) [t(534)=5.38, p&lt;.001, d=0.48]. Third, participants in the scarcity condition were less likely to request the discount (11%) than participants in the control condition (28%) [X 2 =23.36, p&lt;.001, Cramer's V=.21]. All three pre-registered analyses replicated the findings in Experiment 4. Additional results of this experiment are presented in the supplementary materials.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure 12 .</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Experiment 5 pre-registered analyses. Proportional dwell time on prices and discount, and likelihood of requesting the discount for participants in the scarcity and control conditions (error bars reflect ±1 SEM; ***p&lt;.001).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>SD=12.84%)[t(389)=3.90, p&lt;.001, d=0.39], and they also looked less at the calorie information (M=3.54%, SD=3.97%) than the control participants (M=4.44%,SD=4.43%) [t(390)=2.09, p=.037, d=0.21]. There was no significant difference between scarcity and control participants in the brief amount of time spent looking at the peripheral statement at the bottom of the menu (Scarcity: M=1.66%, SD=1.94%; Control: (M=1.82%, SD=1.86% [t(390)=0.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>Figure 13 .</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Experiment 6 attention results. Proportional dwell time in each area of interest for participants in the scarcity and control conditions (error bars reflect ±1 SEM, ***p&lt;.001, *p&lt;.05).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Figure S1 .</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Attentional results for Experiment 5. Proportional dwell time on food items and calories (error bars reflect ±1 SEM).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>Figure S2 .</head><label>S2</label><figDesc>Memory results for Experiment 5. Recall errors in price and calorie information between participants in the scarcity condition and the control condition (error bars reflect ±1 SEM; ***p&lt;.001).Participants in the scarcity condition who requested the discount. As inExperiment 4, discount-requesters in the scarcity condition (N=28) performed comparably to participants in the control condition (N=300). Discount-requesters in the scarcity condition spent comparable proportions of time looking at price information (scarcity condition: M=14.91%, SD=10.15%; control condition: M=12.28%, SD=8.16%) [t(317)=1.59, p=.112, d=0.29], the food items (scarcity condition: M=45.11%, SD=11.43%; control condition: M=50.70%, SD=15.39%) [t(323)=1.87, p=.062, d=0.41], and calorie information (scarcity condition: M=2.74%, SD=2.14%; control condition: M=4.47%, SD=4.76%) [t(319)=1.87, p=.063, d=0.47] (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>[t(247)=0.82, p=.410, d=0.16], food items (requesters: M=45.11%, SD=11.43%; non-requesters: M=49.62%, SD=15.34%) [t(244)=1.50, p=.134, d=0.33], or calorie information (requesters: M=2.74%, SD=2.14%; non-requesters: M=4.44%, SD=4.52%) [t(246)=1.94, p=.054, d=0.48].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head>Figure S4 .</head><label>S4</label><figDesc>Experiment 5 attention results of those who requested vs. did not request the discount in the scarcity condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>[t(183)=4.32, p&lt;.001, d=0.64]. They also made fewer fixations (M=35.36%, SD=21.12%) on the food items than the control participants (M=47.59%, SD=28.56%)[t(184)=3.32, p=.001,   d=0.49]. In contrast, for price information, participants in the scarcity condition dwelled longer at prices (M=21.08%, SD=17.99%) than those in the control condition (M=14.38%, SD=17.11%)[t(184)=2.60, p=.010, d=0.38]. They also made more fixations on prices (M=22.14%, SD=16.72%) than those in the control condition (M=13.64%, SD=11.08%) [t(180)=4.03, p&lt;.001,   d=0.59]. This suggests that, compared to control participants, those under scarcity paid less attention to the names of dishes and more attention to their prices while deciding what to order.To see if scarcity enhanced attention to all numerical information, we examined attention to the calorie information. Participants in the scarcity condition dwelled less on calories (M=2.92%, SD=2.92%) than those in the control condition (M=4.35%, SD=4.33%)[t(185)=2.65,   p=.009, d=0.39]. They also made fewer fixations on calories (M=3.37%, SD=2.99%) than the controls (M=4.69%, SD=4.75%)[t(181)=2.24, p=.026, d=0.33]. Participants under scarcity paid attention specifically to price information.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. Participants in the scarcity condition (Mean error=$1.22, SD=$0.84) were reliably more accurate than controls in their price recall (Mean error=$21.97, SD=$1.24) [t(56)=2.68, p=.009, d=0.71]. However, there was no reliable difference between conditions in calorie recall [t(56)=0.92, p=.359, d=0.24].</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>error=71.61 calories, SD=43.51 calories) [t(57)=2.71, p=.009, d=0.71], but there was no reliable difference in price recall between conditions (Scarcity: Mean error=$2.62, SD=$1.34; Control: Mean error=$3.19, SD=$2.01; [t(57)=1.27, p=.208, d=0.33]). The difference in calorie recall accuracy persists after controlling for the number of items recalled (Scarcity: M=8.60 items recalled; Control: M=8.40 items recalled; F(1,56)=7.26, p=.009). As predicted, recall of calorie information was selectively enhanced among the calorie scarce participants</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Participants in the scarcity condition recalled fewer items than participants in the control condition (Scarcity: M=4.11 items, SD=1.32 items; Control: M=4.52 items, SD=0.86 items [t(330)=3.44, p=.001, d=0.37]), and showed better recall of prices than control participants (Scarcity: Mean absolute error=$0.95, SD=$0.84; Control: Mean absolute error=$1.23, SD=$1.04 [t(324)=2.54, p=.012, d=0.29]). There was no difference in recall accuracy of calorie information between conditions (Scarcity: Mean absolute error=161.27 calories, SD=112.38 calories; Control: Mean absolute error=143.94 calories, SD=99.87 calories [t(322)=1.46, p=.146, d=0.16]; seeFigure 8). However, after controlling for number of items recalled, there was no difference in price recall error[F(1,337)=2.48, p=.116]  or calorie recall</figDesc><table><row><cell>error [F(1,328)=0.92,</cell></row></table><note>recall.</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Bram Scheerlinck and Desmond Fung for assistance with data collection. We also thank Anuj Shah, Sendhil Mullainathan, Supreet Kaur, Darko Odic, Alan Kingstone, Rebecca Todd, Luke Clark, Peter Graf, and the members in the Zhao Lab for helpful comments. </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Availability</head><p>Data for all six experiments are publicly available on the Open Science Framework website (link to project: https://osf.io/83va2/).</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the psychology of drinking: Being thirsty and perceptually ready</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Aarts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dijksterhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="631" to="642" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Working memory. The Psychology of Learning and Motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="89" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the non-takeup of social assistance using register data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bargain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Immervoll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Viitamäki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Economic Inequality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="375" to="395" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>No claim, no pain</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Education and saving: The long-term effects of high school financial curriculum mandates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bernheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Maki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="465" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memos to the Council of behavioural-Economics Advisors: A</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bertrand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mullainathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shafir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">behavioural-Economics View of Poverty. AEA Papers and Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A first computation of non-take-up behaviour in the &apos;leefloon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">I C O L A S</forename><surname>Bouckaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schokkaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>KULeuven, Centrum voor Economische Studieën</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<pubPlace>Leuven</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low numeracy is associated with poor financial wellbeing around the world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bruine De Bruin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">260378</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Income and Poverty in the United States: 2020</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Census</forename><surname>Bureau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.census.gov/library/publications/2021/demo/p60-273.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual working memory as visual attention sustained internally over time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1407" to="1409" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A taxonomy of external and internal attention. Annual review of psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Golomb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Turk-Browne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="101" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Poverty and economic decision making: A review of scarcity theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>De Bruijn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Antonides</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theory and Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Global Findex Database 2017: Measuring financial inclusion and the fintech revolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Demirguc-Kunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>World Bank Publications</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Access to social benefits: Reducing non-take-up</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Dubois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ludwinek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Luxemboug: Publications Office of the European Commission</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What causes the word gap? Financial concerns may systematically suppress child-directed speech</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Ellwood-Lowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Foushee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">13151</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Faul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Erdfelder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-G</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Buchner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioural, and biomedical sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G*</forename><surname>Power</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behaviour Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Envy Up, Scorn Down: How Status Divides Us. NY: Russell Sage Foundation. Food and Nutrition Service (FNS, 2020)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.fns.usda.gov/SNAP/estimates-state-snap-participation-rates-2017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">U.S. Department of Agriculture</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Estimates of state Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program participation rate in 2017</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The strengths of people in poverty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Frankenhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nettle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaze cueing of attention: visual attention, social cognition, and individual differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Frischen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bayliss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Tipper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="694" to="724" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of retirement worry on information processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gutierrez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hershey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, and Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="264" to="277" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Journal of Neuroscience</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Take-Up of Welfare Benefits in OECD Countries: A Review of the Evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Hernanz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Malherbet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pellizzari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>OECD Publishing</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combined effects of spatial and feature-based attention on responses of V4 neurons</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hayden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Gallant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Vision research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1182" to="1187" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">World Energy Outlook</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.iea.org/newsroom/news/2016/november/world-energy-outlook-2016.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Energy Agency</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-08-16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention improves encoding of task-relevant features in the human visual cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Jehee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8210" to="8219" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Getting to the top of mind: How reminders increase saving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Karlan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3393" to="3411" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do financial concerns make workers less productive</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kaur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28338/w28338.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">National Bureau of Economic Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Published online</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BubbleView: An interface for crowdsourcing image importance maps and tracking visual attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Bylinskii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Borkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Gajos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Durand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pfister</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Computer-Human Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can Nudges Increase Take-up of the EITC?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Linos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Prohofsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ramesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rothstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Unrath</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Evidence from Multiple Field Experiments (No. w28086</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Bureau of Economic Research</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The capacity of visual working memory for features and conjunctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Luck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Vogel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">390</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Poverty impedes cognitive function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mullainathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shafir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">341</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="976" to="980" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The magical number seven, plus or minus two: Some limits on our capacity for processing information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">81</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Scarcity: Why having too little means so much</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mullainathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shafir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Henry Holt and Company</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention and performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pashler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ruthruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="651" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">All I saw was the cake: Hunger effects on attentional capture by visual food cues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Piech</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Pastorino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Zald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appetite</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="579" to="582" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence of motivational influences in early visual perception: Hunger modulates conscious access</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Radel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Clément-Guillotin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="234" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of inattention on form perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gutman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">275</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">It&apos;s all relative: Competition and status drive interpersonal perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M T</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1193" to="1201" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Poverty, personality, and sensitivity to residential stressors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Salling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Harvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Environment and Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some consequences of having too little</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mullainathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shafir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">338</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="682" to="685" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scarcity frames value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shafir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mullainathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="402" to="412" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Money in the mental lives of the poor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mullainathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shafir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring financial anxiety</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Burchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, and Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="103" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Journal of Neuroscience</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gorillas in our midst: Sustained inattentional blindness for dynamic events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Simons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Chabris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1059" to="1074" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Canada&apos;s First Poverty Reduction Strategy</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.canada.ca/en/employment-social-development/programs/poverty-reduction/reports/strategy.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistics Canada</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of diseaserelated cues in alcoholic inpatients: results of a controlled</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Stetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ackermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Straube</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">alcohol Stroop&quot; study. Alcoholism: Clinical and Experimental Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="593" to="599" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cell phone-induced failures of visual attention during simulated driving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Strayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Drews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Obesity in low-income communities: prevalence, effects, a place to begin</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Dietetic Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer wealth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tully</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/jmp-2015-update/en" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Consumer Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="143" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Your money or your time? How both types of scarcity matter to physical activity and healthy eating</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Venn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Strazdins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Science &amp; Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">172</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="98" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Poverty and Shared Prosperity 2020: Reversals of Fortune</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">World</forename><surname>Bank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1596/978-1-4648-1602-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://openknowledge.worldbank.org/bitstream/handle/10986/34496/9781464816024.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<publisher>World Bank</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Washington, DC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>License: Creative Commons Attribution CC BY 3.0 IGO</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Augmented Cognition: Enhancing Cognition and Behavior in Complex Human Environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Tomm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10285</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="78" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Attentional trade-offs under resource scarcity</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological responses to scarcity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Tomm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Oxford Research Encyclopedia of Psychology</title>
		<editor>Braddick, O.</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
