<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Evidence of Psychological Targeting but not Psychological Tailoring in Political Persuasion Around Brexit</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Joint First</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>O'neill</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Joint First</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lee De-Wit</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">University Lecturer</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Psychology and Language Science O&apos;Neill</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Christopher</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Stephen</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Psychology and Language Science De-Wit</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Lee ; Cambridge University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="institution">Cambridge University Press</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Evidence of Psychological Targeting but not Psychological Tailoring in Political Persuasion Around Brexit</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">Date Submitted by the Author: n/a</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:00+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>persuasion</term>
					<term>judgment and decision-making</term>
					<term>personality</term>
					<term>moral foundations theory</term>
					<term>psychological tailoring Subject Category: Psychology and Psychiatry Results Type: Novel Result</term>
					<term>Negative Result MA</term>
					<term>MSc. 2 Position: Former Masters student at UCL; Qualifications: BSc</term>
					<term>MSc</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>There are numerous associations between psychological characteristics and political values, but it is unclear whether targeting messages tailored to these psychological characteristics can influence political decisions. Two studies (N=398, N=395) tested whether psychological-based argument tailoring could influence participants&apos; decision-making. We constructed arguments based on the 2016 Brexit referendum; Remain supporters were presented with four arguments supporting the Leave campaign, tailored to reflect the participant&apos;s strongest (/weakest) moral foundation (Loyalty or Fairness) or personality trait (Conscientiousness or Openness). We tested whether individuals scoring high on a trait would find the tailored arguments more persuasive than individuals scoring low on the same trait. We found clear evidence for targeting, particularly for Loyalty, but either no evidence or weak evidence, in the case of Conscientiousness for tailoring. Overall, the results suggest that targeting political messages could be effective, but provide either no, or weak evidence that tailoring these messages influences political decisionmaking.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Adverts targeted and tailored to psychological traits have been shown to be effective in non-political domains <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Matz et al. 2017)</ref> but given the alleged roles of Cambridge Analytica and AggregateIQ in recent political campaigns, the question of whether psychologically tailored and targeted arguments are effective in political contexts has important social implications.</p><p>Research has demonstrated that personal and moral values reliably correlate with political decisions in the US and UK <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Gerber et al. 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Graham et al. 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Sibley et al. 2012)</ref> and so targeting and tailoring arguments in line with these values could be effective <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . In addition to the research showing the effectiveness of personality-based tailoring in advertising <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Hirsh et al. 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Matz et al. 2017)</ref>, there is some evidence that Moral Foundations Theory (MFT) can be effective in tailoring political arguments <ref type="bibr">Willer, 2013, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Voelkel and Feinberg, 2017)</ref>, although the combined role of tailoring and targeting based on individual differences in Moral Foundations has not been tested. Moreover, while some longitudinal research has suggested an influence of personality on political decisions over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ekstrom and Federico, 2018)</ref> the exact role personality plays within political decisionmaking is still under debate <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Hatemi et al. 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Overall, the efficaciousness of psychologically tailored arguments and psychological targeting remains largely untested within the political domain while the causal influence of psychological constructs like Personality and Moral Foundations in political decision-making requires further investigation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Objective</head><p>To investigate psychological-based argument targeting and tailoring, and the potential causal influence of personality and moral foundations in political decision-making, this study sought to test four hypotheses 5 in terms of the targeting and tailoring of arguments for Leaving the European Union:</p><p>1. In-group loyalty tailored arguments will be more effective for Remain-supporting voters who are high on the Moral Foundation of Ingroup Loyalty. 2. Fairness tailored arguments will be more effective for Remain-supporting voters who are high on the Moral Foundation of Fairness. 3. Openness tailored arguments will be more effective for Remain-supporting voters who are high on the personality trait Openness. 4. Conscientiousness tailored arguments will be more effective for Remainsupporting voters who are high on the personality trait Conscientiousness.</p><p>Loyalty and Fairness (study 1) were chosen because they had previously been effective in moral framing research in the US, with Loyalty particularly appealing to conservatives, and Fairness to liberals <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Voelkel and Feinberg, 2017)</ref>. Openness and Conscientiousness (study 2) <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Tailoring refers to the matching of one's psychological characteristics with phrases used in discourse in an attempt to persuade. Targeting refers to presenting discourse to those who's psychological characteristic most closely aligns with the position of the discourse. were chosen because, of the big 5 personality traits, they have shown the most robust links to liberal and conservative political attitudes respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Gerber et al. 2010)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1 -Moral Foundations</head><p>398 Remain supporting participants 6 undertook an abbreviated 7 Moral Foundations Questionnaire (MFQ) and received MFT-based arguments tailored to the foundations of Loyalty and Fairness.</p><p>The research design was mixed; there was one independent variable, message tailoring with two levels -tailored or control. To ensure participants were assigned to the condition reflecting their most (or least) dominant trait, participants first completed a Moral Foundations questionnaire measuring their Loyalty and Fairness. Two standardised z-scores -one for each trait -were created for each participant 8 . Participants were then assigned to read either the Loyalty or Fairness arguments based on their most extreme (highest or lowest) score, to maximise the power of the design. Those in the Loyalty condition received arguments tailored to high Loyalty, and a non-tailored control, whilst those in the Fairness condition received an argument tailored to high Fairness and a non-tailored control.</p><p>Post the Moral Foundation Questionnaire participants read four counter-attitudinal arguments: three MFT tailored arguments and one non-tailored control. The control argument was included to test the causal influence of argument tailoring on decisionmaking; participants high vs low on Loyalty and Fairness are not expected to rate a nontailored control any differently.</p><p>After each argument participants were asked three questions about the argument, two measuring their attitude to the argument (argument credibility and argument compellingness) and one measuring behavioural intentions (intention to vote for a party making this argument) on a scale from 0 to 10 9 .</p><p>Prior to the analysis participants were assigned to a high or low Loyalty (/Fairness) condition based on the average Loyalty (/Fairness) score in the sample. Those with scores less than or equal to the average were considered low.</p><p>A similar study with Leave supporting participants was discontinued due to a small sample size (N = 83).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2 -Personality</head><p>A second study following the exact same procedure was conducted to assess the effect of personality-based argument tailoring. 395 Remain supporting participants undertook an 6 See Methodology addendum for full recruitment details. 7 Both MFQ and BFI were shortened such that participants only answered the questions pertaining to Loyalty (α = .68) and Fairness (α = .60) and Conscientiousness (α = .84) and Openness, (α = .81) respectively. 8 Based on participant's own score on each trait in addition to world average (UK average for Study 2) and standard deviation for each trait. 9 See Dependent variables for full details. Again, a study investigating Leave supporting participants was discontinued due to a small sample size (N = 65).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Given the mixed design the primary statistical interest was the interaction effect between the high and low conditions across the tailored and control arguments. The secondary interest was a between-subjects test of whether participants high on a given moral foundation (/personality) trait rated the arguments differently from those low on the same trait. Given participants rated the arguments on three separate dependent variables -Credibility, Compellingness and Vote -the statistical threshold for the paired comparisons was set to p = 0.0167.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1 -Moral Foundations</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Loyalty condition</head><p>Two-Way Mixed ANOVA 10 results showed a significant main effect of Moral Foundation condition (high vs. low) on argument scores F(1, 1172) = 302.96, p &lt; .001, p 2 = .21. There was also a significant main effect of argument type (tailored vs. control) on argument scores F(1, 1172) = 14.97, p &lt; .001, p 2 = .013. However, there was no significant interaction effect for Loyalty, F(1, 1172) = .0001, p = .99, p 2 &lt; 0.001.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>[Insert WalkerFig1 here]</head><p>To investigate the between-subjects effects across the arguments Independent t-tests were conducted. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2 -Personality</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conscientiousness condition</head><p>Two-Way Mixed ANOVA results showed a significant main effect of personality condition on argument scores, F(1, 1166) = 16.18, p &lt; .001, p 2 = .014. There was also a significant main effect of argument type on argument scores, F(1, 1166) = 12.78, p &lt; .001, p 2 = .011. There was a marginally non-significant interaction effect for Conscientiousness, F(1, 1166) = 3.41, p = .065, p 2 = 0.003.</p><p>[Insert WalkerFig3 here] Independent t-tests indicated no significant differences for the tailored arguments in terms of credibility, t(145.93) = 2.00, p = .024, d = .3. However, those high on Conscientiousness found the arguments significantly more compelling, t(135.12) = 2.33, p = .010, d = .35 and displayed a significantly greater intention to vote, t(131.05) = 2.56, p = .006, d = .39 than those low on Conscientiousness.</p><p>There were no significant differences across the non-tailored control argument: credibility, t(137.49) = .81, p = .42, d = .12, compellingness, t(134.97) = .50, p = .62, d = .07 and vote intention t(128.39) = 1.05, p = .30, d = .16.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Openness condition</head><p>Two-Way Mixed ANOVA results showed no significant main effect of personality condition on argument scores, F(1, 1136) = 3.15, p = .076, p 2 = .003. There was a significant main effect of argument type on argument scores, F(1, 1136) = 19.95, p &lt; .001, p 2 = .02. There was no significant interaction effect for Openness, F(1, 1136) = 2.45, p = .12, p 2 = 0.002.  On the non-tailored control argument there were no significant difference in terms of credibility, t(160.7) = -.62, p = .54, d = -.09 or compellingness, t(138.31) = -2.08, p = .04, d = -.32. There was a significant difference in terms of vote intention with those low on Openness displaying a greater intention to vote than those high on Openness, t(140.85) = -3.02, p &lt; .01, d = -.46).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussions</head><p>Across all four traits there was either no or weak evidence for the interaction between targeting and tailoring. There were however clear effects of targeting, such that participants high or low on a trait rated arguments differently in a manner consistent with that traits association with more liberal or conservative politics. The strength and consistency of these differences differed substantially across traits. The strongest and most consistent difference was between individuals high and low on Loyalty. This difference was a large effect for the arguments tailored towards Loyalty (d = 0.89-1.58) but also large for the non-tailored argument (d = 0.68-1.33), and there was no interaction. The lack of an interaction between targeting and tailoring for Loyalty suggests that whilst targeting might be effective, these results do not enable us to be certain that receptivity to the moral value of Loyalty is critical; this difference could be mediated by other psychological or demographic differences between these groups. It should be noted however that, whilst the non-tailored argument contained less references to Loyalty, it did contain some (for example to 'British students'), which may have been sufficient to appeal to participants high on Loyalty.</p><p>Conscientiousness was the only trait where participants in the high compared to low groups displayed a difference between tailored and non-tailored arguments across the pairwise comparisons. The difference between those high and low on Conscientiousness for the tailored arguments, in conjunction with the lack of differences across the non-tailored control argument is at least consistent with the idea that personality-based argument tailoring can influence political-based decision-making. However, the absence of a significant interaction effect cautions the veracity of this interpretation. Detecting interaction effects often requires more power however, so the pattern of pair wise comparisons suggests this result is worth testing with a larger sample.</p><p>Participants high on Fairness consistently rated the Leave arguments as less persuasive than those low on Fairness across the tailored and non-tailored arguments. Participants high on Openness (compared to low) only differed in their evaluation of one outcome (vote intention) for the non-tailored arguments. For both Fairness and Openness there was no interaction. The lack of hypothesised effects across the Fairness and Openness conditions suggests that argument tailoring is particularly unlikely to prove effective in the absence of thoughtful targeting. In this instance the lack of an effect for Fairness and Openness could reflect the incongruence between the public discourse surrounding the Leave position and these psychological constructs.</p><p>Finally, it should be noted, all of these arguments were tested using arguments for Leaving the EU presented to Remain supporting participants. It would clearly be informative to extend this test to Leave supporting participants with arguments in favour of Remaining. Previous literature has highlighted associations between Loyalty and Conscientiousness and F o r O p e n P e e r R e v i e w conservativism, and Openness and Fairness with liberalism, so the pattern of targeting effects found here should theoretically be reversed when making arguments for Remaining in the EU.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusions</head><p>The results reveal that participants high or low on different traits respond differently to arguments for Leaving the EU. Some of these differences are large, with Remain supporters high on Loyalty consistently finding arguments much more persuasive than Remain supporters low on Loyalty. Some of these differences are more marginal, with participants high on Openness finding arguments for Leaving less compelling than participants low on Openness only in one instance. Across all of the traits however there is no convincing evidence that the combination of targeting and tailoring is effective. The only potential exception is the case of Conscientiousness, in which participants high on this trait (compared to low) found the tailored arguments more persuasive but showed no difference on the non-tailored argument. Even in this case however the interaction between personality trait and message tailoring was not significant. Thus the results show substantive evidence for psychological targeting, but weak or no evidence for psychological targeting and tailoring. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Inventory questionnaire (B-5) and received personality-based arguments tailored to the traits of Conscientiousness and Openness.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>[</head><label></label><figDesc>Insert WalkerFig4 here] Independent t-tests indicated there was no significant differences across the tailored arguments: credibility, t(165.56) = -.62, p = .73, d = -.09, compellingness, t(176.7) = -.50, p = .70, d = -.07 and vote intention, t(181.73) = -1.18, p = .88, d = -.16.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Evidence of Psychological Targeting but not Psychological Tailoring in Political Persuasion Around Brexit.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>F o r F o r F o r O p e O p O p n P e n e n</cell></row><row><cell>e e r R P e e r P e e r</cell></row><row><cell>e v i e w R e v i e w R e v i e w</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>significant main effect of argument type on argument scores F(1, 1058) = 64.98, p &lt; .001, p 2 = .06. There was no significant interaction effect for Fairness, F(1, 1058) = 2.86, p = .09, p 2 = 0.003.</figDesc><table><row><cell>[Insert WalkerFig2 here]</cell></row><row><cell>Independent t-tests indicated significant differences across each of the tailored arguments</cell></row><row><cell>with those low on Fairness finding the arguments more credible, t(110.17) = -2.16, p =</cell></row><row><cell>.0165, d = -.34, more compelling, t(101.92) = -3.33, p &lt; .001, d = -.54 and showing more</cell></row><row><cell>intention to vote, t(99.04) = -3.42, p &lt; .001, d = -.56 than those high on Fairness.</cell></row><row><cell>This pattern of significant differences between those high and low on Loyalty was also</cell></row><row><cell>evident across the non-tailored control argument with those low on Fairness finding it more F credible, t(98.71) = -2.81, p &lt; .01, d = -.46, more compelling, t(90.82) = -3.34, p &lt; .01, d = -.49 and showing a greater intention to vote, t(82.01) = -3.3, p &lt; .01, d = -.47 than those high on o r Fairness.</cell></row><row><cell>O p</cell></row><row><cell>e n</cell></row><row><cell>P e e r</cell></row><row><cell>finding it more credible, t(199.29) = 4.83, p &lt; .001, d = .68, more compelling, t(169.27) = 6.54, p &lt; .001, d = R e v i e w</cell></row><row><cell>1.2 and showing more intention to vote, t(155.78) = 6.49, p &lt; .001, d = 1.33 than those low</cell></row><row><cell>on Loyalty.</cell></row><row><cell>Fairness condition</cell></row><row><cell>Two-Way Mixed ANOVA results showed a significant main effect of Moral Foundation</cell></row><row><cell>condition on argument scores, F(1, 1058) = 32.28, p &lt; .001, p 2 = .03. There was also a</cell></row></table><note>The Independent t-tests indicated that individuals high on Loyalty significantly differed from those low on Loyalty across the tailored arguments, finding them more credible, t(200.57) = 6.35, p &lt; .001, d = .89, more compelling, t(177.84) = 8.63, p &lt; .001, d = 1.5 and showing more intention to vote, t(169.6) = 8.63, p &lt; .001, d = 1.58. This pattern of significant differences between those high and low on Loyalty was also evident across the non-tailored control argument with those high on Loyalty</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">The focus on a 2x2 Mixed ANOVA was a post-hoc decision that deviates from our pre-registration report. The use of this analysis was based on the unexpected findings across the control conditions and guidance from our reviewers. Whilst paired comparisons were planned separately for the 3 rating measures (credible, compelling, vote intention), for simplicity these were combined for the ANOVA.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality and Political Preferences Over Time: Evidence From a Multi-Wave Longitudinal Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Ekstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Moral Roots of Environmental Attitudes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Feinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Willer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797612449177</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797612449177" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Gulf to Bridge: When Do Moral Arguments Facilitate Political Influence?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Feinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Willer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167215607842</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167215607842" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1665" to="1681" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality and political attitudes: Relationships across issue domains and political contexts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Gerber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dowling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Ha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0003055410000031</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0003055410000031" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Political Science Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Liberals and Conservatives Rely on Different Sets of Moral Foundations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Haidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nosek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0015141</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0015141" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1029" to="1046" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Genetic Influences on Political Ideologies: Twin Analyses of 19 Measures of Political Ideologies from Five Democracies and Genome-Wide Findings from Three Populations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hatemi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Medland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Klemmensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Oskarrson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Littvay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dawes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.devcel.2010.12.007.Peroxiredoxin</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.devcel.2010.12.007.Peroxiredoxin" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Genetics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personalized Persuasion: Tailoring Persuasive Appeals to Recipients&apos; Personality Traits</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Hirsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Bodenhausen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797611436349</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797611436349" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="578" to="581" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological targeting as an effective approach to digital mass persuasion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Matz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kosinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stillwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1710966114</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1710966114" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality and political orientation: Metaanalysis and test of a Threat-Constraint Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Sibley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Duckitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jrp.2012.08.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jrp.2012.08.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="664" to="677" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Morally Reframed Arguments Can Affect Support for Political Candidates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Voelkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Feinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1948550617729408</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1948550617729408" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychological and Personality Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
