<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Exploit Theory of Human Drive (ETHD): Framework Proposal</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<title level="a" type="main">Exploit Theory of Human Drive (ETHD): Framework Proposal</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The Exploit Theory of Human Drive (ETHD) posits seven fundamental motivational &quot;catalysts&quot;-Wrath, Greed, Lust, Pride, Envy, Gluttony, and Sloth-that drive human decision-making. These roughly correspond to the classic &quot;seven deadly sins,&quot; reframed as core drives. Each catalyst is hypothesized to have distinct cognitive and affective signatures, yet they interact to shape behavior and social structures. Below, we compare ETHD with major psychological theories, analyzing how ETHD refines or challenges their views of motivation and personality.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>• Self-Determination Theory (SDT): SDT centers on three innate psychological needsautonomy, competence, and relatedness -which underlie intrinsic motivation and well-being en.wikipedia.org . It emphasizes positive growth-oriented drives and the fulfillment of intrinsic needs, whereas ETHD highlights often extrinsic or affective drives (e.g. desire for material gain, status, vengeance) that can derail or co-opt intrinsic motivations. For instance, SDT would classify Greed (desire for wealth) and Pride (seeking external validation) as extrinsic motives that might undermine true need satisfaction en.wikipedia.org . ETHD expands SDT by spotlighting these darker motivators -forces that SDT regards as potentially thwarting need fulfillment. While SDT assumes people naturally move toward growth and well-being when basic needs are met, ETHD suggests that even in need-satisfying contexts, primal catalysts like lust or envy can strongly sway behavior. ETHD thereby challenges SDT's implication that fulfilling basic needs suffices for healthy motivation; the ETHD drives can operate independently, sometimes leading individuals to act against their long-term well-being (e.g. an executive with autonomy and financial security still being driven by ever-increasing Greed or Pride). In cognitive terms, SDT's needs are more cognitive/reflective (seeking meaning and growth), whereas ETHD's seven drives involve powerful affective impulses <ref type="bibr">(anger, craving, desire, etc.)</ref> rooted in evolutionary survival mechanisms discovermagazine.com . ETHD doesn't contradict SDT's needs, but refines the picture by accounting for these strong "temptation" drives that can override or exploit our basic needs for other ends.</p><p>• Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs: Maslow's pyramid organizes human motivation from basic physiological needs up to safety, love/belonging, esteem, and self-actualization verywellmind.com verywellmind.com . ETHD differs by not being hierarchical -the seven drives can manifest at any level of need. In fact, many ETHD catalysts represent excesses or distortions of needs at various levels. For example, Lust and Gluttony correspond to physiological needs (sex, food) but in overdrive -they persist beyond satiation, driven by reward-seeking rather than homeostatic deficit discovermagazine.com . Greed extends safety needs (resource accumulation) and esteem needs (status via wealth) into an insatiable pursuit of "more," rather than the satisfaction of "enough." Pride correlates with esteem/self-actualization needs -a desire for accomplishment and recognition -but ETHD highlights hubristic pride (excess esteem) that can emerge even when one's basic and social needs are fulfilled. Envy reflects a social-comparison aspect of esteem and belonging needs, leading to resentment when others surpass us. Wrath (anger/vengeance) can be triggered by threats at any level (an affront to safety, an insult to esteem) and isn't represented in Maslow's model except indirectly as a reaction when needs (e.g. respect) are violated. Sloth (apathy or avoidance) is essentially the lack of drive -it could emerge when one's basic needs are met, leading to complacency, or when one is overwhelmed (a failure to pursue self-actualization due to indifference or learned helplessness). ETHD thus challenges Maslow's progression idea: even when higher needs are within reach, catalysts like sloth or lust can cause regression or stagnation. Moreover, Maslow saw fulfilling esteem needs as positive, whereas ETHD's Pride underscores that excessive self-regard ("hubris") can become maladaptive even after esteem is gained scu.edu . ETHD refines Maslow by introducing a moral-emotional dimension: it contends that human motivation isn't purely a linear climb toward self-actualization, but a constant negotiation with tempting drives that can exploit our satisfied needs (e.g. an affluent person indulging in gluttony or greed despite no material need). This view aligns with the idea that many of these "sins" were historically considered vices of excess, not deficiency -"virtues taken to the extreme" discovermagazine.com . In summary, Maslow tells us what fundamental needs people seek; ETHD focuses on how indulgence, excess, and negative social emotions can arise around those needs once the opportunity presents itself.</p><p>• Drive-Reduction Theory: Hull's drive-reduction theory holds that behavior is motivated by the desire to reduce internal tension from unmet physiological needs <ref type="bibr">(hunger, thirst, sleep, etc.)</ref>, restoring homeostasis opentextbc.ca . It's a push theory of basic urges and their alleviation. ETHD significantly expands the scope of "drives." The seven ETHD catalysts include classical drives like hunger/sex (Gluttony, Lust), but also social-emotional drives (Wrath, Envy, Pride) that do not stem from physiological imbalance. In fact, several ETHD drives often increase tension rather than reduce it -e.g. Greed begets wanting more no matter how much one has, and Envy intensifies as others succeed, neither leading to a homeostatic "satisfaction." ETHD thus challenges the notion that all motivation aims at tension-reduction; some drives create a positive feedback loop of desire. Modern neuroscience supports this: lust and reward-seeking activate dopaminergic pathways in anticipation of pleasure, not merely to relieve a deficit discovermagazine.com . Gluttony and addiction research show that over-consumption can desensitize reward circuits, prompting even greater consumption discovermagazine.com -the opposite of drive reduction. Similarly, Wrath (anger) can be seen as a response to threats (initially reducing the tension of fear by asserting control), but revenge often introduces a new reward component -the pleasurable anticipation of punishing someone activates reward centers like the dorsal striatum discovermagazine.com . ETHD aligns with evolutionary views that while base drives (hunger, thirst) ensure survival, more complex drives (like competitiveness or aggression) evolved because they can confer advantage even if they aren't about immediate homeostasis discovermagazine.com . Many ETHD drives represent motivational overrides: for instance, an angry person might ignore hunger (sacrificing a physiological drive) to pursue vengeance; a lustful individual might endure danger or pain to satisfy sexual desire. Thus, ETHD refines drive theory by incorporating non-homeostatic drives -motives like status, power, and indulgence that can hijack behavior. It suggests human drives operate on multiple layers: the homeostatic layer (reduce basic need tension) and an exploitative layer (maximize reward, dominance, or pleasure even beyond biological necessity). Cognitive-affectively, ETHD drives often originate in subcortical reward or threat systems (e.g. hypothalamus for lust, amygdala for anger) that can trump cortical regulatory mechanisms, whereas classic drive-reduction is largely a physiological feedback process discovermagazine.com . In sum, ETHD challenges drive-reduction theory's sufficiency by including drives of excess and social emotion that aren't about restoring balance but about exploiting opportunities for gain or responding to perceived slights.</p><p>• Big Five Personality Traits: The Big Five (Openness, Conscientiousness, Extraversion, Agreeableness, Neuroticism) is a descriptive model of broad temperament traits, not explicit motivations. Nevertheless, there are clear links: for example, low Agreeableness and high Neuroticism might predispose someone to Wrath and Envy; low Conscientiousness could underlie Sloth; high Extraversion and low Agreeableness might facilitate Lust (sensation-seeking, promiscuity) and Greed (assertive pursuit of resources). However, research indicates the Big Five does not fully capture these dark motivational tendencies. The emergence of the Dark Triad (narcissism, Machiavellianism, psychopathy) was partly a response to this gap scottbarrykaufman.com . Likewise, the seven vices in ETHD represent nuanced motivational traits that cut across or lie outside the Big Five dimensions scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com . For instance, Envy involves social comparison and resentment not directly described by any single Big Five trait (it has links to Neuroticism and low Agreeableness, but those don't entirely explain envy's focus on others' advantages). Similarly, Greed correlates with materialism and low Honesty-Humility (a trait added in the HEXACO model) more than with any Big Five trait scottbarrykaufman.com . In empirical work, all seven sin traits showed only modest to moderate correlations with Big Five factors, suggesting they capture a unique variance of personality scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com . For example, Gluttony (tendency for overindulgence) showed negligible links to Big Five in prior studies, aligning instead with impulsivity and reward sensitivity discovermagazine.com . Pride, especially hubristic pride, correlates with low Agreeableness and high Extraversion, but also encompasses vanity and dominance aspects beyond basic Extraversion scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com . ETHD refines trait theory by making motivations explicit: rather than broad descriptors, it names the motive forces (e.g. desire for more = greed, desire for status = pride) that drive trait-expressive behaviors. One way to view it: an individual's Big Five profile might tell us how they generally behave, but their ETHD profile would tell us why -which temptations or goals they are most driven by. Notably, the seven ETHD drives tend to be inter-correlated as a "vices" cluster and also correlate with known dark traits. For instance, one study found all seven sin scales correlated positively with each other and with Dark Triad measures scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com . High Greed and Pride in particular showed strong links to Machiavellianism and narcissism, respectively scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com . This suggests ETHD taps a space in personality not mapped by the Big Five -a space of antisocial or self-serving motivation. By formally identifying seven distinct motivators, ETHD challenges personality psychology to extend beyond neutral trait dimensions into more value-laden drives. It also allows finer analysis: two people might both be low Agreeableness (a Big Five trait) -one because they are often angry (Wrath-driven), another because they are selfishly ambitious (Greed-driven). ETHD offers a framework to differentiate them. In essence, ETHD complements the Big Five by accounting for variance in behavior stemming from morally relevant drives that the Big Five lumps into broad traits or overlooks scottbarrykaufman.com .</p><p>• Dark Triad (DT) Traits: The Dark Triad (narcissism, Machiavellianism, psychopathy) is directly relevant, as it also focuses on the "dark" side of personality. ETHD's Pride, Greed, Wrath, Envy overlaps conceptually with these: Narcissism is characterized by excessive pride and vanity (and indeed showed a very strong correlation with the ETHD Pride scale scottbarrykaufman.com ), Machiavellianism entails manipulative pursuit of self-interest (overlaps with Greed and envy of others' gains scottbarrykaufman.com ), and Psychopathy includes impulsive aggression and lack of empathy (aligning with Wrath and uncontrolled Lust, as psychopaths are known for hot tempers and promiscuity scottbarrykaufman.com ). Empirical evidence supports these alignments: in one validation, psychopathy had robust links with Lust, Greed, and Pride, narcissism with Pride, and Machiavellianism with Greed (and somewhat Envy) scottbarrykaufman.com . All correlations between Dark Triad traits and the seven sin drives were positive and significant except narcissism-sloth (a narcissist is not typically lazy) scottbarrykaufman.com . This indicates ETHD's drives map closely onto the DT's antisocial profiles, but ETHD extends further. The Dark Triad covers interpersonal malevolence and selfishness; ETHD includes self-indulgent drives like gluttony and sloth which, while harmful, are not about exploiting others. For example, Gluttony (overconsumption) and Sloth (avoidance of effort) are vices primarily harming oneself (or indirectly society) rather than actively manipulating others -these have not been central in DT research. By including them, ETHD presents a more comprehensive taxonomy of human vices: it spans from aggressive/other-directed drives (wrath, envy) to self-directed excesses (gluttony, sloth). It therefore refines the DT model by suggesting even "victimless" vices share psychological space with the dark traits (indeed, studies show moderate correlations of gluttony/sloth with psychopathy and other DT traits scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com , likely via impulsivity). ETHD also prompts examination of interactions: a Dark Triad personality might have multiple ETHD drives active (e.g. a psychopath might exhibit high lust and wrath and greed simultaneously). While the Dark Triad emphasized these traits lie outside the Big Five, ETHD goes a step further to enumerate the key motivational domains of that dark space. It challenges the field to consider whether these seven drives (or a subset) form a "Dark Heptad" that offers better predictive power than the Dark Triad alone. Additionally, ETHD includes Envy, which some have called a "missing" element in the Dark Triad -envy and jealousy are potent but often "undiscussable" emotions that drive harm (some authors argue envy should be part of a "Dark Tetrad"). ETHD explicitly includes Envy as a core drive, aligning with this suggestion. In summary, ETHD largely agrees with Dark Triad research that standard personality models miss key antisocial motivations scottbarrykaufman.com , and it expands that work by providing a broader framework (seven categories of drives versus three trait clusters). It refines our understanding by distinguishing different flavors of "dark" motivation (greed for material gain vs. lust for sensual pleasure vs. wrathful destruction, etc.), where Dark Triad traits often blend several together.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cognitive and Affective Structures of the Seven Drives:</head><p>Each ETHD catalyst is grounded in identifiable cognitive-affective processes, as evidenced by psychological and neuroscience research. Below we summarize each drive, highlighting its underlying mechanisms and how it might influence decision-making:</p><p>• Wrath (Anger/Revenge): Neural basis: Anger is evolutionarily primordial, engaging basic "fight" circuits. During rage, the dorsal anterior cingulate cortex (dACC) -the brain's conflict detector -fires intensely, alerting us to perceived slights or goal-blockages discovermagazine.com . This happens very fast, reflecting anger's "hot" nature. Individuals with short fuses show a hyper-reactive dACC, feeling provocation readily discovermagazine.com . Anger also activates the amygdala and hypothalamus (fight-or-flight centers) in quick bursts. Cognitive patterns: Anger can short-circuit higher reasoning. When provoked, people sometimes suppress activity in the prefrontal cortex (which normally processes social norms and consequences) to "ready themselves to strike," essentially turning off empathy or inhibition in order to retaliate discovermagazine.com . Those prone to brooding anger (rumination) show high activation in the hippocampus (memory) and mPFC as they repeatedly replay the insult discovermagazine.com . Affective dynamics: Wrath is marked by high arousal, adrenaline, and a narrow focus on a target. It is often self-reinforcing: envisioning revenge actually triggers the brain's reward circuitry -one study found that merely contemplating retaliating (delivering a painful noise to someone who wronged you) lit up the dorsal striatum (a reward hub) in participants, indicating that vengeance feels rewarding before it's even enacted discovermagazine.com . Thus, anger can hijack decision-making by attaching a positive utility to punishment. This drive is evident in choices like rejecting an unfair deal at personal cost (e.g. in the Ultimatum Game, people frequently sacrifice money to punish a low offer out of a sense of outrage) discovermagazine.com . In social structures, wrath can spread (anger begetting anger) and is often harnessed in conflicts and retaliation cycles. It tends to override fear and even self-interest, leading to impulsive high-risk actions when unchecked.</p><p>• Greed (Acquisitiveness): Neural basis: Greed -an excessive desire for material gainis less localized but ties into the brain's reward and decision networks. Neuroimaging has not isolated a single "greed center," but related processes like inequity aversion and reward expectation involve the insula and ventromedial prefrontal cortex discovermagazine.com . Notably, feeling cheated (someone else's greed) triggers the brain's pain and disgust centers (anterior insula), reflecting how deeply fairness is wired discovermagazine.com . This suggests our brains monitor resource distribution emotionally; someone high in greed might have an attenuated insula response to others' needs but a strong dopamine response to acquiring more for themselves. Cognitive patterns: Greed involves maximization mindset -always scanning for the option that gives the biggest personal payoff. Psychologically, dispositional greed correlates with impulsivity, materialism, and low self-control, as well as with envy pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov . Greedy individuals in experiments will allocate more to themselves even in zero-sum games, defying norms of fairness pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov . They also show less empathy/altruism, consistent with a focus on personal gain.</p><p>Affective dynamics: Greed is accompanied by a strong approach motivationanticipation of reward (money, assets) triggers dopamine release, providing excitement and "lust" for accumulation. Unlike a hunger drive that can be satiated, greed often grows with partial fulfillment; gaining some money can spur wanting even more. This has been likened to an addiction: each reward yields a short-lived satisfaction followed by renewed craving. In decision-making, greed leads to risk-seeking behavior when big gains are possible and often to unethical choices (cutting corners or exploiting others) if they increase one's payoff. Socially, greed can erode trust and cooperation -for example, in repeated games greedy strategies (always defecting for personal gain) can collapse collective welfare. However, moderate greed underpins competitive economies (the classic notion that self-interest drives market innovation). ETHD isolates greed to examine when it becomes maladaptive (e.g. uncontrolled pursuit of personal gain that undermines long-run outcomes mdpi.com ). In organizations and societies, greed is often checked by norms or laws, but when those fail, greed-driven decisions (fraud, corruption) can wreak havoc. Neuroscientifically, greed likely ties into the same "reward pathways" as other pleasures, but hijacks them for quantity rather than quality of reward -for instance, hoarding money activates similar reward circuits as consuming food or drugs in some individuals (behavioral addiction studies suggest a overlap).</p><p>• Lust (Sexual Desire): Neural basis: Lust is a procreative drive deeply rooted in the hypothalamus and limbic system. Viewing sexual stimuli "sets nearly the whole brain buzzing," activating regions for reward (ventral striatum/nucleus accumbens), emotion (amygdala), arousal (hypothalamus), and sensory processing discovermagazine.com . In men, visual erotic cues strongly engage the amygdala (emotion and arousal) and hypothalamus (which governs hormonal drives). The neurotransmitter cocktail of lust includes dopamine (anticipatory pleasure), oxytocin (bonding in some contexts), and in moments of orgasm, a surge of reward similar to certain drug highs. Cognitive patterns: Sexual arousal can temporarily impair decision-making and self-control -"cold" cognition gives way to "hot" affective processing. Prefrontal regions that normally enable reasoning and impulse control are often under-activated during intense arousal discovermagazine.com (similar to states of hunger or craving). This is why lust can lead to risky behaviors (unprotected sex, infidelity) that one might avoid when not aroused. People will discount future consequences heavily under the influence of lust (a phenomenon shown in studies where aroused participants express greater willingness for risky or morally questionable sexual acts). Affective dynamics: Lust is associated with high positive arousal -a craving paired with excitement. It's one of the "weaknesses of the flesh" that is notoriously hard to restrain discovermagazine.com . Because sex is tied to species survival, evolution made it powerfully rewarding; as one researcher quipped, "from the perspective of natural selection, you want the organism to procreate, so you make it rewarding," though it can go beyond bounds in modern contexts of plenty discovermagazine.com . In social decision-making, lust can be exploited (e.g. "sex sells" in marketing capitalizes on this drive to bias consumer choices). Interpersonally, lust can cloud judgment of partners (rose-colored glasses effect due to sexual attraction). While lust is often a private drive, it has societal impact (e.g. scandalous behavior of leaders undermining institutions, or pervasive issues like sexual harassment). ETHD's inclusion of lust reminds us that not all decisions are driven by material or egoistic goals; some are driven by raw biological desires. Cognitive-affectively, lust represents a state where incentive salience (how attractive a stimulus is) shoots up for erotic targets, often overriding other goals.</p><p>• Pride (Ego, Self-Worth): Neural basis: Pride -especially hubristic pride (arrogance, vanity) -relies on self-referential thinking in the medial prefrontal cortex (mPFC) discovermagazine.com discovermagazine.com . The mPFC is active when we reflect on ourselves, and studies find that imagining personal success or glory deactivates regions associated with critical self-evaluation while engaging reward circuitry discovermagazine.com . In one experiment, people asked to imagine winning a prize showed less activation in introspective brain areas compared to when imagining guilt or embarrassmentsuggesting that feeling proud may be a more automatic, less analytical state discovermagazine.com . In fact, our brains seem somewhat biased toward prideful views of self: we easily accept positive feedback with minimal scrutiny discovermagazine.com . Disrupting the mPFC with TMS can temporarily strip away these positive illusions, causing people to see themselves more realistically (losing their "swagger") discovermagazine.com . Cognitive patterns: Pride can be adaptive (authentic pride) or maladaptive (hubris). Authentic pride (feeling accomplished for hard-won achievements) can motivate persistence and prosocial leadership. Hubristic pride is an inflated self-view and sense of superiority. Cognitively, pride often manifests as confirmation bias about the selfnoticing successes, explaining away failures. It can lead to overconfidence in decision-making: e.g. a leader with excessive pride may ignore critical feedback, as their internal narrative is "I know best." They may also take undue risks, assuming they will prevail due to personal greatness. Prideful individuals place high weight on status and recognition outcomes in decisions. Affective dynamics: Pride yields a warm, empowering feeling (some call it a "social high"). It is social in nature -one feels pride in comparison to others or via others' admiration. However, it can veer into dominance behavior: prideful leaders often belittle or blame others and take offense at challenge blog.hellostepchange.com . When pride is wounded (ego threat), it easily morphs into Wrath -hence the trope of "pride goeth before a fall," as wounded pride can spark retaliatory aggression or obstinate refusal to admit error. In group settings, unchecked pride (hubris syndrome) can distort decision processes, leading to micromanagement, rule-breaking, and recklessness by leaders who think normal limits don't apply to them blog.hellostepchange.com blog.hellostepchange.com . ETHD's Pride catalyst links to theories of narcissism: indeed narcissistic personalities are essentially addicted to prideful feelings. Narcissists' behavior (from seeking fame to reacting angrily to criticism) can be understood as decisions aimed at maximizing pride or minimizing shame. On the positive side, pride in one's work or identity can drive achievement -it's a catalyst for ambition. ETHD acknowledges this dual nature but focuses on the exploitative aspect: how excessive pride can be triggered and lead to grandiose, risk-laden choices. Neuroimaging even shows that self-deception and false humility activate similar brain regions as overt pride, suggesting that prideful motives can lurk beneath even seemingly modest behavior discovermagazine.com . This drive is deeply embedded in social structure -it underlies competition for status and leadership emergence (people with above-average pride/confidence often rise to authority, for better or worse).</p><p>• . This undercuts any notion that envy is a useful motivator; instead, it appears largely toxic, fueling decisions that hurt oneself and others. ETHD's view of envy aligns with these findings: envy can lead people to act against their own interests simply to diminish or hurt the advantaged other (a phenomenon known in game theory as "spite"). In social structures, envy can degrade group cohesion -envying subordinates may undermine high performers, and inter-group envy can spark conflict. It is often an exploited drive too: advertisers and social media platforms trigger envy by displaying idealized lifestyles, prompting consumption or engagement as users strive to "keep up." Thus, envy has clear decision impacts -from consumer debt (keeping up appearances) to workplace sabotage -making it a crucial component of ETHD.</p><p>• Gluttony (Overindulgence/Appetite): Neural basis: Gluttony, in modern terms, corresponds to uncontrolled consumption, often of food, but also by extension drugs or other rewarding substances. Neuroscience shows that obesity and drug addiction alter the same brain circuits discovermagazine.com . Both are associated with down-regulation of dopamine receptors in the brain's reward system, especially the striatum, meaning that the more one overeats or uses drugs, the less reward one feels, driving an ever-escalating cycle of compulsion discovermagazine.com . In those prone to gluttony, key motivation regions (like the orbitofrontal cortex, which evaluates reward value and decision-making) become hyper-responsive to cues (like the smell of food) discovermagazine.com , while frontal inhibitory regions (like the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, DLPFC) are under-active discovermagazine.com . This neural profile indicates strong cravings + weak self-control. Additionally, obese individuals show heightened sensory response to food (their brain's taste/somatosensory areas light up more), suggesting they experience eating very intensely, yet paradoxically their reward sensation is blunted discovermagazine.com . Cognitive patterns: Gluttony involves impulse-driven decision-making. There is a short-term focus on immediate gratification (the cake now) versus long-term consequences (health, weight). People experiencing this drive often rationalize or temporarily discount future costs (a form of hyperbolic discounting). Cognitive control (DLPFC) being lower means planning and goal maintenance (e.g. sticking to a diet) suffer. Affective dynamics: Gluttony is accompanied by craving and comfort. It often serves as an emotional coping mechanism -indulging to feel pleasure or numb stress. The momentary joy of consumption is high, but it may be followed by guilt or physical discomfort if in excess. Over time, habitual overindulgence can dull the pleasure (tolerance buildup), leading to larger quantities consumed for the same effect discovermagazine.com . ETHD highlights gluttony as a drive that exploits our evolved fat/sugar-seeking impulses in an environment of plenty. Our brains evolved when calories were scarce, so we are wired to enjoy rich foods and store energy; in modern times, this drive is hijacked by abundant food availability discovermagazine.com . Socially, gluttony is evident in public health trends -e.g. rising obesity rates -and it creates decision challenges at scale (healthcare costs, nutrition policy). It is often not considered a "moral" failing in scientific terms now (because physiology is so implicated discovermagazine.com ), but ETHD frames it as a fundamental drive that can undermine rational self-interest (we know overeating is harmful, yet the drive can overpower knowledge). This drive is routinely exploited by industries -e.g. the food industry engineers ultra-palatable foods precisely to trigger maximal dopamine release, effectively leveraging our gluttonous tendencies. Thus, in decision-making models, one should account for a tendency toward short-term overconsumption when this catalyst is strong in an individual.</p><p>• Sloth (Apathy/Laziness/Aversion to Effort): Neural basis: Sloth in the original sense (acedia) meant a spiritual apathy or listlessness. Neurologically, low motivation and sustained inaction can be linked to dysfunction in frontal lobe circuits. For example, extreme apathy is seen in frontotemporal dementia patients who have degeneration in the frontal cortex -they become passive and inert discovermagazine.com . In less extreme cases, dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (DLPFC) underactivity correlates with difficulties in sustaining attention and effort discovermagazine.com . The DLPFC is key for implementing plans and inhibiting impulses; when it's under-active, a person may lack drive and also struggle to regulate negative emotions (which can lead to a demoralized, "why bother" state) discovermagazine.com . Cognitive patterns: Sloth manifests as procrastination, avoidance of challenge, and preference for immediate comfort or ease. A sloth-driven decision-maker will opt for the path of least resistance, even if it means neglecting important duties. There can be a present bias (choosing rest/comfort now over effort that pays off later). Often, there is rationalization (e.g. "I work better under pressure, I'll do it later" or "this task isn't worth the energy"). Sloth can also stem from overwhelm -too many demands leading to a freeze/avoidance response. Affective dynamics: Unlike the other drives which involve active craving or emotion, sloth is characterized by low arousal. It's a lack of passion or urgency -possibly related to dopaminergic under-stimulation in motivation pathways. However, sloth often coincides with subtle negative affect: boredom, mild depression, or learned helplessness. Historically, acedia was described in monks as a mix of tedium and self-contempt discovermagazine.com -a sense of "stuckness." In decision contexts, sloth results in inaction or defaulting.</p><p>For instance, an opportunity might be missed simply because one doesn't mobilize the effort to pursue it (the classic "missed because didn't try"). Over time, this can seriously impact life outcomes (missed promotions, unfinished education, health neglect). Socially, if many individuals succumb to sloth, group goals suffer (everyone waits for someone else to act -a kind of motivation free-rider problem). Interestingly, psychology recognizes that some level of energy-conservation is rational -we can't act on everything -but sloth as a dominant drive tilts to irrational inactivity (failing to act even on one's own goals). It may increase with comfort: when basic needs are met, the drive for achievement might not kick in unless other catalysts (pride, greed) motivate the person. Neuroscientific findings on depression-related apathy show that stimulating frontal regions can lift some of the lethargy discovermagazine.com , suggesting sloth is partly a neurochemical state. ETHD frames sloth as a drive to avoid effort and responsibility, which can be exploited by technologies or systems offering easy rewards (e.g. endless passive entertainment to feed our tendency toward inactivity). It underscores that motivation is not just about activating drives, but also overcoming the drive not to act.</p><p>Interactions and Decision-Making Dynamics: Crucially, ETHD proposes that these seven drives do not operate in isolation -they interact and compete within individuals, shaping choices in a context-dependent way. Understanding their interactions helps explain complex behaviors better than any single-drive model:</p><p>• Trade-offs and Conflicts: Often, two or more drives conflict in a decision. For example, Greed vs. Wrath -in a negotiation or game, greed would urge one to accept any gain, but wrath may urge rejecting a gain to punish unfairness. The Ultimatum Game scenario highlights this: rational self-interest (greed for money) is trumped by anger at injustice, leading people to reject low offers at personal cost discovermagazine.com . The brain literally weighs the emotional urge to punish against the logical reward, with sufficient outrage tipping the scale to punishment discovermagazine.com . Another conflict: Sloth vs. Greed/Pride -an individual may feel lazy (sloth) about working hard, but their greed for money or pride in status pushes them to overcome that laziness. Which drive "wins" can depend on context (imminence of reward, social pressure, etc.). Envy vs. Greed might also conflict: envy could make a person sabotage another even if it harms their own prospects, whereas greed would advise cooperating if it benefits oneself.</p><p>• Reinforcing Loops: Some drives amplify each other. Pride and Wrath often form a loop -wounded pride leads to wrath, and acting on wrath (retaliation) can restore pride (in a perverse way: "I showed them"). Greed and Envy can form a toxic cycle in competitive environments: envy of others' possessions can fuel one's greed to acquire more, and as one amasses wealth or status, it may incite envy in others, continuing the cycle socially. Gluttony and Sloth can mutually reinforce in a lifestyle context -excessive indulgence (gluttony) in food or media can reduce one's energy and habit of effort, promoting sloth; conversely a slothful mindset (low effort, boredom) can increase temptation to indulge for easy pleasure, fostering gluttony. These feedback loops can trap individuals in patterns (e.g. sedentary over-eating lifestyle) or fuel escalating behaviors (e.g. an arms race of greed among corporate rivals that started from envy).</p><p>• Catalysts Triggering Catalysts: ETHD drives can trigger one another sequentially. Consider how Envy can trigger Wrath: if envy of a rival becomes intense, it may lead to hatred and a desire to harm that rival (malicious envy essentially becomes wrath). Lust can trigger Pride (e.g. sexual conquest leading to boastfulness and inflated ego) or inversely Pride can trigger Lust (e.g. feeling powerful and proud might increase one's libido or pursuit of sexual gratification, as often seen in powerful figures' behavior). Greed can trigger Wrath if someone's greed is thwarted by another -the frustration can turn into anger (e.g. rage at a business partner who one thinks blocked their profit).</p><p>Pride and Envy have a notable interplay: pride is "the sin of self elevation" and envy "the sin of resenting others' elevation" -they are two sides of the same social comparison coin. In a group, one person's prideful display can incite envy in others discovermagazine.com , while an envious critique from others can either deflate pride or cause the proud person to double down and become even more arrogant to maintain face.</p><p>• Social Structure Interactions: At a societal level, these drives often get channeled or checked by social norms, but they can also be exploited by institutions. For instance, capitalist markets harness Greed as a motivator for productivity but need regulations to prevent destructive excess -when those fail, collective disasters (fraud, inequality) can occur, as in the case of Enron's collapse from unchecked greed and hubris scu.edu scu.edu . Social media platforms exploit Pride and Envy: they encourage prideful self-presentation and then engender envy in viewers, which keeps people engaged (one scrolls partly to compare lives, often feeling envy, and posts content to seek validation and pride -a cycle of mutual catalyst activation). Political movements can harness Wrath (rallying anger against an out-group or injustice) or Envy (scapegoating a wealthy elite) to mobilize support, essentially leveraging those drives to achieve collective action (for good or ill). Workplace structures might inadvertently pit drives against each other -e.g. a competitive ranking system could amplify envy and greed, harming teamwork (as seen at Enron, where an internal "rank-and-yank" system fostered arrogance and cruelty scu.edu ).</p><p>In decision-making research, incorporating these interacting drives can explain why people deviate from pure rationality. A purely rational agent might always maximize expected utility, but humans sometimes choose an option that serves a psychological drive at the expense of utilitarian payoff (like revenge over profit, or moral self-righteousness (pride) over compromise). ETHD provides a structured way to consider these factors: any given choice could be analyzed in terms of which catalyst is most activated or which conflict of drives is at play. This helps refine predictive models. For example, game theory models augmented with a "spite" parameter (envy/wrath) or "status utility" (pride) better predict human behavior than models assuming money is the only utility discovermagazine.com discovermagazine.com . As another example, behavioral economics recognizes inequity aversion -people dislike outcomes that are too unequal, even at cost to themselves, a phenomenon directly tied to envy and wrath; ETHD situates this in a broader motivational spectrum.</p><p>Furthermore, ETHD implies that individuals have dominant drives but context can switch which drive comes forward. A person might generally be greed-driven in career decisions but become wrath-driven in a conflict, or sloth-driven on a weekend. Social context can prime certain catalysts: being in a competitive setting might prime envy and pride, while being at a buffet primes gluttony. The interaction of personal tendencies and context triggers yields the observed behavior. This dynamic view is a contrast to static hierarchies like Maslow's or trait-only views like Big Five. ETHD suggests a more fluid competition among inner "demons" or "motivator modules."</p><p>In summary, ETHD's theoretical contribution is to refine our map of human drives by naming seven potent motivators and analyzing their psychological mechanisms. It builds on prior theories: aligning with the evolutionary logic of drives but extending beyond homeostasis, complementing trait models with motivational content, and echoing the importance of needs and goals from SDT and Maslow but emphasizing the dark/excessive side of each need. It challenges researchers to integrate these drives into models of decision-making, as they clearly have neural reality (e.g. distinct brain correlates for each sin discovermagazine.com ) and can decisively influence behavior. ETHD doesn't claim these seven are the only motivators, but posits they are foundational catalysts often under-acknowledged in formal theories, and understanding them can improve our predictions of behavior in both individual and group contexts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Empirical Validation Plan for ETHD</head><p>To formalize ETHD, we need to demonstrate that its seven proposed drives are measurable, distinct, and predictive. The empirical validation plan has three components: (a) Psychometric scale development for the seven catalysts, (b) Factor-analytic validation of the seven-factor structure, and (c) Correlational and longitudinal studies to link ETHD drives to real-life outcomes and stability over time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Psychometric Measurement Design</head><p>Scale Construction: We will develop a self-report questionnaire that assesses each of the seven ETHD catalysts. Fortunately, prior work provides a head start. Veselka et al. <ref type="formula">2014</ref>introduced the Vices and Virtues Scales (VAVS), which includes subscales for Anger (Wrath), Envy, Gluttony, Greed, Lust, Pride, and Sloth scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com . We will build on this by adapting and expanding their items to ensure comprehensive coverage of each construct. For each catalyst, we will include ~8-12 statements describing thoughts, feelings, and behaviors representative of that drive. Example items: for Wrath -"I have fantasized about getting back at people who wronged me"; for Greed -"I am never satisfied with what I have -I always want more"; Lust -"Strong sexual desires have led me to cross boundaries I normally wouldn't"; Pride -"I tend to think I'm more capable than most people, and I hate admitting mistakes" etc. We will use Likert-scale responses (e.g. 1 = strongly disagree to 5 = strongly agree).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Item Generation:</head><p>We'll generate a broad item pool per catalyst, referencing not only the VAVS items (70 items total in VAVS)</p><p>scottbarrykaufman.com but also other related scales: e.g. items from the Dispositional Greed Scale for Greed (which has proven reliable pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov ), Trait Anger scales for Wrath, Narcissistic Personality Inventory for Pride elements, Erotophilia/Sociosexuality scales for Lust, Dispositional Envy Scale, Barratt Impulsiveness (eating subfactor) for Gluttony, and Work Avoidance/Procrastination scales for Sloth. By cross-pollinating from established measures, we aim for content validity. We'll also ensure items capture both cognitive aspects (e.g. envious thoughts, proud beliefs) and behavioral tendencies (e.g. acts of indulgence or aggression) for each drive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pilot Testing and Refinement:</head><p>The draft scale will be piloted on a sample (say N = 200-300) to perform item analysis. We'll examine each item's distribution and its correlation with the intended subscale total. Items that are redundant or do not load well on the intended factor will be revised or dropped. We will strive for subscales with good internal consistency (α &gt; .80). We anticipate, based on VAVS results, that some constructs might be multifaceted -for example, the VAVS found Gluttony items split into two facets (perhaps reflecting different forms of overindulgence)</p><p>scottbarrykaufman.com . If we observe multi-dimensionality within a catalyst, we might decide to either refine the definition or allow a sub-factor (e.g. Gluttony could have a "food" facet and a "general indulgence" facet). The goal, however, is a clean factor structure where each item clearly indicates one primary drive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Factor Analysis: Do Seven Distinct Motivators Emerge?</head><p>We will conduct both Exploratory Factor Analysis (EFA) and Confirmatory Factor Analysis (CFA) on large samples to test whether the seven ETHD drives emerge as distinct factors.</p><p>• Exploratory Factor Analysis: Using the pilot (or an expanded sample), we'll perform an EFA (e.g. principal axis factoring with promax rotation) to see how many factors are indicated by the data. We predict seven substantive factors corresponding to the ETHD constructs. Veselka et al.'s initial EFA indeed suggested a seven-factor solution for the seven sins, though with some complexity (e.g. some gluttony items cross-loaded) scottbarrykaufman.com . We'll look at eigenvalues and interpretability. We expect items clustering such that, say, all wrath items load on one factor, all greed on another, etc. Any cross-loadings or odd groupings will inform us to tweak items. Our hypothesis is that the seven catalysts are empirically distinguishable dimensions of personality/motivation -not one single "vice" factor. This is supported by prior evidence that a one-factor model fit worse than a seven-factor model for the VAVS scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com . We will test similar comparisons.</p><p>• Confirmatory Factor Analysis: With a fresh sample (N ~ 500+), we will run CFA to confirm the structure. We will compare multiple models: a seven-factor correlated model (each catalyst as a latent factor, allowed to inter-correlate) versus alternative models (e.g. a single factor, or a hierarchical model with a second-order "Exploit drive" factor).</p><p>Our expectation is the seven-factor model will show superior fit, indicating that treating each catalyst separately better represents the data than lumping them together scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com . In Veselka et al.'s study, the seven-factor model had decent fit (RMSEA ~ .04) and fit better than a one-factor or one-higher-order-factor model scottbarrykaufman.com . We anticipate similar results -some moderate correlations between factors (since these drives all fall under a broad "selfish motivation" umbrella, they will not be orthogonal) but clear differentiation. For example, someone could score high in Lust but low in Envy, or high in Greed but low in Sloth, supporting the idea that these drives are not one monolithic trait. Finding a significant non-zero correlation structure is fine (likely all drives correlate positively to some degree scottbarrykaufman.com ), as long as each factor shows discriminant validity. If needed, we might allow a few item error covariances or cross-loadings based on modification indices, but will do so sparingly and theoretically (e.g. an item that implicitly touches on both envy and pride might cross-load; we may decide to drop such an item for clarity).</p><p>• Distinctness vs. Hierarchy: We will test if a higher-order model fits (where the seven drives load onto a single "Vice" factor). Prior work found a higher-order factor was statistically inferior to the correlated seven-factor model scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com , suggesting that while the drives correlate, one cannot assume a person high in one is equally high in all. We will likely replicate that a single higher-order factor doesn't capture the nuance (people have specific profiles). This supports ETHD's premise that each catalyst is a distinct motivator. However, if a decent higher-order factor does emerge, we could interpret it as a general "exploitative motivation" factor (similar to how specific intelligence factors relate to g-factor). Either result is informative: a strong general factor might imply some common underlying temperament (e.g. low Honesty-Humility or high Psychoticism) making one prone to all vices, whereas distinct factors underscore the need to measure each drive separately.</p><p>• Reliability and Validity: We will report Cronbach's alphas for each subscale and ensure they are acceptable. We'll also examine short-term test-retest reliability (administer the scale to a subset twice, a few weeks apart) to gauge stability. We expect moderate stability (these drives are akin to traits), but possibly less stability than Big Five traits since some drives can be state-influenced. Validity will be further supported by correlational patterns (see below).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Correlational Analysis with External Criteria</head><p>Once the seven drives are measured reliably, we will explore their correlations with external variables to validate their real-world significance:</p><p>• Personality and Traits: We'll correlate ETHD scale scores with Big Five traits, Dark Triad measures, and HEXACO (especially the Honesty-Humility dimension). This helps place the ETHD drives in the nomological network. We expect, for example, Wrath to correlate with high Neuroticism (anger facet) and low Agreeableness; Greed with low Honesty-Humility and high Machiavellianism scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com ; Pride with high Narcissism (and perhaps high Extraversion, low Agreeableness) scottbarrykaufman.com ; Envy with high Neuroticism and low self-esteem; Lust with high Extraversion and possibly high Psychopathy (which includes impulsive sexual behavior) scottbarrykaufman.com ; Gluttony with high Impulsivity/low Conscientiousness; Sloth with very low Conscientiousness and perhaps high Neuroticism (particularly depression facet). Prior findings support many of these (e.g. significant positive correlations found between each of the seven sin scales and Dark Triad traits, confirming their connection to known antagonistic traits scottbarrykaufman.com scottbarrykaufman.com ). We will report these to show ETHD is grounded in recognizable patterns but also adds nuance (e.g. two individuals with the same low Conscientiousness might differ in whyone due to Sloth, another due to impulsive Lust/Gluttony).</p><p>• Life Outcomes: We will collect data on participants' life outcomes and choices to see how ETHD drives correlate. This could include: career path/occupation, educational attainment, income, relationship status and history, health indicators, and self-reported life satisfaction/happiness. Our aim is to find meaningful patterns. For instance, one might hypothesize:</p><p>○ High Greed individuals gravitate toward careers in finance, sales, or business entrepreneurship where financial reward is high. We might see above-average representation of high-greed scorers in competitive corporate roles. However, unchecked greed might correlate with unethical behavior or job instability (e.g. involvement in scandals, frequent job changes for better pay). We'll look for correlations with job satisfaction and success; one study found CEO greed was linked to worse corporate social responsibility outcomes (short-term profit focus over stakeholders) mdpi.com , illustrating greed's impact in leadership. ○ High Pride (hubristic) might correlate with attaining leadership positions (since confidence aids emergence gsb.stanford.edu ) but also with leadership problems (conflict, eventual failure). We could see if high pride scorers report more managerial roles and also perhaps more instances of career derailment or interpersonal conflict at work. ○ High Lust could correlate with more relationship turnover (more sexual partners, higher likelihood of infidelity) and possibly occupations or hobbies that enable socializing (maybe the arts, entertainment, or travel industry). It might also connect with risk-taking behaviors (e.g. higher incidence of STIs or thrill-seeking sports). ○ High Envy might correlate with lower job satisfaction (constant comparison), and lower income over time (since envy doesn't motivate constructive improvement pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov ). It may also correlate with schadenfreude -perhaps those high in envy report more enjoyment of others' failures, and poorer mental health (as the longitudinal study indicated envy predicts worse future well-being pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov ). ○ High Wrath individuals may report more frequent job changes due to conflicts, more legal troubles (if anger leads to aggression), or roles in which aggression is channeled (maybe military or contact sports, though that's speculative).</p><p>Interpersonally, they might have unstable relationships (friendships/romances harmed by temper). ○ High Gluttony could correlate with health outcomes: higher BMI, likelihood of substance use or addictive behaviors. We can include a simple measure of Body Mass Index or self-reported health issues to see if gluttony scores predict them. Similarly, high gluttony might correlate with financial issues if overindulgence extends to spending (consumerism). ○ High Sloth likely correlates with lower educational attainment (e.g. procrastination leading to incomplete degrees), lower income or being in less demanding jobs, and possibly high recreation time (e.g. hours spent on passive leisure like TV). It may also correlate with depressive symptoms. Conversely, low sloth (diligence) correlates with achievement; by measuring sloth, we get the flip side of conscientiousness.</p><p>• We will analyze these by computing correlation matrices and also using regression to see if each ETHD drive uniquely predicts certain outcomes when controlling for others. For instance, if we predict income, does Greed predict it when Big Five traits (like Conscientiousness) are controlled? Perhaps an ambitious greedy person might earn more initially, but extreme greed could backfire (we might even find a curvilinear relationship). We will also look at life satisfaction -prior research suggests dispositions • Decision-Making Tendencies: To directly connect ETHD drives to decisions, we will have participants engage in or report on certain decision-making scenarios: ○ Economic games: We can have them play an Ultimatum Game, Dictator Game, Public Goods game, etc., to see if their ETHD scores predict behavior. We predict: ■ High Wrath (anger) =&gt; more likely to reject low ultimatum offers (punish unfairness), and to mete out punishment in a trust game. ■ High Greed =&gt; in Dictator games, keep more money for themselves (consistent with findings that greedy people allocated more to themselves in such games pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov ). ■ High Envy =&gt; possibly reject offers that give them less than the other (even if positive for them), or in a public goods game, they might contribute less if others might benefit more.</p><p>■ High Pride =&gt; might demand more in negotiations (feeling they deserve more), and possibly be more likely to defect in prisoner's dilemma if it means "winning" over the other. ■ High Lust =&gt; not directly tested by money games, but we could include a romantic decision vignette (e.g. choosing between a stable relationship vs. an exciting affair) to see if lust score predicts riskier choice. ■ High Gluttony =&gt; in a delay discounting task for food or money, they may discount future rewards steeply (preferring smaller-sooner rewards). ■ High Sloth =&gt; in an effort-based challenge (e.g. solving puzzles for a reward vs. relaxing for a smaller reward), they might choose the easier path more often. • These laboratory-type measures can provide behavioral validation that the psychometric scores have observable effects. For instance, if high Greed scorers consistently exploit others in games, that's evidence of construct validity. Notably, Seuntjens et al. <ref type="formula">2015</ref>found that dispositional greed predicted taking more for oneself in dictator and resource dilemmas pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov . We expect to replicate those patterns with our Greed scale. Similarly, high Envy might predict spiteful choices -we could design a game where a participant can pay a cost to reduce someone else's payoff, and see if envy-prone individuals do that more (reflecting malicious envy).</p><p>• Inter-correlations among ETHD drives: As part of validation, we'll report how the seven drives inter-relate in our sample. Prior research suggests they will all positively correlate to a degree (people who score high on one sin often score above average on others) scottbarrykaufman.com . For example, someone high in Psychopathy might score high in Lust, Greed, Pride simultaneously scottbarrykaufman.com . However, we expect many people will have a primary drive that is highest. We might use cluster analysis or profile analysis to see if there are typical "profiles" (e.g. a cluster of individuals who are primarily Lust-driven, another who are Greed-driven, etc.). This can be exploratory but could yield intuitive "types" (akin to archetypes of sin). Each profile could be examined for external differences (e.g. the "Greedy-prideful" profile might be disproportionately CEOs or entrepreneurs, the "Lust-gluttony" profile might be associated with more hedonistic lifestyles, etc.). This analysis is more speculative but can illustrate ETHD's usefulness in describing individual motivational makeup.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Longitudinal Study of Drive Stability</head><p>To address the question of stability and change in ETHD catalysts over time, we propose a longitudinal study. We will recruit a large sample (several hundred) and administer the ETHD scale at multiple time points (e.g. baseline, 1 year, 5 years, and 10 years). We will examine both rank-order stability (do people maintain their relative standing on each drive over time?) and mean-level changes (do average levels of each drive increase or decrease with age or life stage?).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hypotheses:</head><p>We anticipate that ETHD drives will show moderate stability, similar to personality traits. However, some drives may change systematically with age or life experience:</p><p>• Envy and Lust are often strongest in young adulthood and tend to decline with age. Indeed, envy has been shown to significantly decline as people grow older pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov , likely because life priorities shift and social comparisons become less salient in later years (and perhaps because by older age one's cohort is less divergent in outcomes or one has accepted one's lot). Lust also generally peaks in young adulthood (hormonal prime) and can diminish somewhat with age, or at least become more controlled. We thus might see mean levels of Envy and Lust decrease over the decade. • Wrath (anger) often mellows with age for many (research on aging and emotion finds older adults are often better at emotion regulation, though some individuals become grumpier). We might predict a slight average decline in Wrath scores as impulsive anger is tempered with maturity, except potentially in those who experience accumulating frustrations. • Pride may have a complex trajectory: youthful bravado might dip in mid-life reality, then some develop a secure pride later in career. Or hubristic pride might increase in those who attain power (a CEO in their 50s might have more pride than they did at 30 after many successes). We will track if individuals in leadership roles show rising pride. On average, there might not be a simple linear trend. • Greed could potentially increase in early career (as people become more materialistic when earning money) and then decrease post-retirement or once financial security is reached. Alternatively, some research suggests materialism can decrease in later life as existential and relational concerns become more important. We'll see if there's an inverted U or linear pattern. • Gluttony and Sloth might increase if people become more sedentary and indulgent with age (metabolism slows, responsibilities change). Or conversely, health scares might reduce gluttony (people forced to diet) and retirement might allow people to invest more in hobbies (reducing sloth). These could vary widely by individual.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dominant Catalyst Stability:</head><p>We will investigate if a person's "dominant" ETHD drive (the highest of their seven) tends to remain the same over time. For example, if someone is primarily driven by Pride in their 20s, are they still chiefly pride-driven in their 40s? This is akin to asking if ETHD profiles are an enduring part of one's character. We suspect moderate consistencypersonality literature indicates that core dispositions stabilize in adulthood, so many people will retain their hierarchy of drives. But significant life events could shift one's dominant drive (e.g. a person high in Lust who settles into a stable marriage might find Lust diminishing and perhaps Greed or Pride related to career taking precedence). We can calculate transition matrices or correlation of rank orders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methodology:</head><p>We will use test-retest correlations for each catalyst over each interval. A high correlation (e.g. r &gt; .6 over 5 years) would indicate strong stability. We'll also use growth curve modeling or latent trait-state models to separate trait variance from occasion-specific variance. If we detect significant mean changes, we'll report those (e.g. "Envy showed a significant downward trend with age, with participants on average scoring 0.5 SD lower at Time 4 than Time 1"). We'll control for certain life events -e.g. have participants report major events (marriage, children, promotions, trauma) and see if these moderate changes in drives.</p><p>Predictive Stability: A longitudinal design also allows us to test predictive power: do baseline ETHD drives predict future outcomes? For instance, does baseline Greed predict cumulative earnings 10 years later? Does baseline Pride predict who becomes a manager? Does baseline Lust predict divorce or number of children? We will explore such longitudinal correlations. If ETHD has validity, we should see, for example, that those high in Greed at Time 1 have pursued different career trajectories or financial outcomes by Time 4, or those high in Wrath at baseline have a higher incidence of having experienced job loss due to conflicts or even health issues (anger is linked to heart disease risk). We'll also see if changes in drives correspond with life changes (e.g. people who became parents might show increased pride (in kids) but maybe decreased lust or increased sloth due to fatigue!).</p><p>Benchmarking Stability: We might compare ETHD drive stability to Big Five stability in our sample. Typically, Big Five test-retest over years might be ~0.7-0.8 in adulthood. We anticipate ETHD drives might be a bit less stable (since some are more state-like or tied to life circumstances -e.g. Greed might reduce once someone "has it all," whereas a trait like Extraversion is more inherent). If one drive is found to be particularly unstable or situational, that's notable (it might behave more like an attitude than a trait).</p><p>Overall, the longitudinal component will strengthen ETHD's credibility by showing whether these drives are enduring dispositions and how they evolve. If results show, for example, that Envy reliably declines with age and is associated with poorer mental health outcomes over time pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov , it underscores envy's role as a detrimental motivator -aligning with psychological observations and reinforcing ETHD's inclusion of it. If Greed or Pride in youth predict later career achievements (or failures), that demonstrates their long-term influence. If Sloth is relatively stable and predicts cumulative life under-achievement (education, income), that would highlight why addressing sloth (e.g. via interventions to improve self-regulation) could be crucial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Data Collection and Analysis Summary</head><p>We plan to recruit diverse samples: initial scale validation might be done with college students and online adult samples (to ensure variability beyond student population). For outcome correlations, we'll oversample working adults across professions, and possibly use longitudinal data from a subset of a larger ongoing study (if available) or start our own longitudinal cohort focusing on early career individuals tracked into mid-career (to see changes as responsibilities grow).</p><p>We will use statistical techniques including factor analysis (EFA/CFA), Cronbach's alpha for reliability, Pearson/Spearman correlations, multiple regression, and structural equation modeling for the longitudinal pathways. Additionally, we might use factor mixture modeling to see if there are latent classes of people with different drive profiles.</p><p>A critical analysis will be whether the seven factors truly add new explanatory power beyond existing constructs. To test this, we can conduct incremental validity tests. Finally, all data and analyses will be planned transparently. We will consider pre-registering our analysis plan (especially for confirmatory parts like CFA and key hypotheses about outcomes) to increase credibility. The psychometric study could potentially be published on its own, given the interest in measuring the "seven deadly sins" reliably (prior work found "some evidence" for the seven-factor structure scottbarrykaufman.com -we aim to provide definitive evidence with larger samples and refined items).</p><p>In sum, the empirical validation will establish that ETHD's seven catalysts are (1) psychometrically sound constructs, (2) distinct factors in personality space, and (3) meaningfully connected to behaviors and life outcomes, thereby demonstrating that ETHD is not just a theoretical list but a measurable, applicable framework.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Interdisciplinary Applications of ETHD</head><p>One strength of ETHD is its relevance across domains. By formalizing fundamental human drives, ETHD can be applied in fields as varied as cybersecurity, artificial intelligence, organizational leadership, and behavioral economics. Below, we explore how ETHD can inform each area:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Cybersecurity: Hacker Motivation Profiling</head><p>Cybersecurity is as much about understanding human adversaries as it is about technology. ETHD can provide a framework for profiling hacker motivations, which helps in anticipating threats and tailoring defenses. Many cyber attacks are driven by the same seven human catalysts:</p><p>• Greed-motivated attackers: A large proportion of cybercrimes are financially driven retailtechinnovationhub.com . These include ransomware gangs, bank trojan operators, credit card thievesessentially hackers who infiltrate systems for monetary gain. Profiling such attackers through the lens of Greed suggests they will choose targets based on potential profit and risk, likely avoid unnecessary damage (except as needed to extract money), and can be deterred by raising the cost or lowering the benefit of the attack. Countermeasures like robust fraud detection, asset tracking, and international law enforcement cooperation address Greed by making cybercrime less lucrative. Knowing an attacker is greed-driven means negotiation (like paying a small ransom) might resolve an incident, whereas other types might not be swayed by money.</p><p>• Wrath-motivated attackers (Revenge or Anger): Insiders or individuals with a grievance often carry out attacks for retaliation retailtechinnovationhub.com . A disgruntled employee who was fired might plant a "logic bomb" or steal data to spite the company. Similarly, hacktivists may attack an entity out of anger at its actions (though ideological anger also contains moral pride). ETHD's Wrath profile suggests these attackers seek to inflict pain and damage even at cost to themselves. For example, an angry ex-employee might delete critical files even if it yields them no benefit retailtechinnovationhub.com . To handle this, companies can invest in insider threat detection and, importantly, psychological HR interventions -e.g. offboarding processes that respect and counsel departing employees to mitigate wrath. Also, knowing revenge is a common motive, organizations should quickly revoke access for those known to be upset and monitor for sabotage triggers retailtechinnovationhub.com . From a profiling stance, communications from a wrathful hacker might contain emotional language or personal vendettas. Indeed, the language of threat actors can reveal motive: an extortion note purely demanding money suggests Greed, whereas one that also insults the victim or seems gleeful about causing harm might indicate Wrath (or Pride).</p><p>• Ego/Pride-motivated attackers: Some hackers are driven by notoriety, challenge, and bragging rights rather than direct gain retailtechinnovationhub.com . These are often "black-hat" hackers with ego -e.g. web defacers, hackers who publish their feats under pseudonymous handles, or those seeking a reputation in underground forums. For them, the hack is a way to demonstrate superiority (Pride) or to belong to an elite (which flips to envy if others outdo them). Profiling this motive means expecting attacks on high-profile targets (the bigger the target, the bigger the bragging rights). They may also release data publicly (to get credit for the hack) rather than quietly sell it. A famous example is groups like LulzSec, who hacked corporations and government sites "for the lulz" (for pride/ego and public spectacle) rather than money. Mitigating pride-driven attacks is tricky -it's about removing the prestige of certain hacks. For instance, companies can avoid adversarial posturing (not taunting hackers, which might provoke them). Law enforcement can deter these by making some high-profile arrests, tarnishing the "cool" factor with real consequences. Ethically, appealing to their sense of achievement by engaging them in bug bounty programs (turning their pride toward legal exploits) is a strategy many firms use. ETHD's Pride lens also suggests these individuals might have narcissistic traits, so deceptive techniques that "flatter" or occupy them (like creating honeypot systems that present as juicy targets) could keep them away from real assets.</p><p>• Envy-motivated attackers: Envy can play a role, for example, in insiders who leak information not just for revenge but because they resent their bosses or company's success. Or in corporate espionage, an actor might hack a competitor out of envy of their edge in the market (though usually that's mixed with greed for advantage). We might rarely have pure envy as a motive (envy often couples with pride or greed), but one could imagine scenarios like a hacker taking down someone's social media or website out of jealousy of their popularity or success. In cybersecurity training, acknowledging envy means watching for employees who show signs of discontent at others' promotions or praise -they might be at risk of doing something harmful to cut the other down.</p><p>• Gluttony and Sloth in cyber context: These are less direct motivators for committing cyber attacks, but they manifest in how attacks are carried out or how victims are compromised. For instance, Sloth can describe negligent security practices by admins (failing to apply patches, using weak passwords). Attackers often exploit sloth -many breaches happen because an organization was too lazy (or under-resourced) to fix a known vulnerability. On the attacker side, one might joke that script kiddies (unskilled hackers) exhibit intellectual sloth by relying on others' code and not doing the hard work -but they can still cause damage by using leaked exploits. Gluttony might appear as an attacker's greed for data -e.g. hoarding massive amounts of stolen data beyond any practical use, just because they can (some breaches involve exfiltrating every record available). Also, cyber criminals can become "addicted" to hacking victories, always seeking a bigger high (akin to gluttony for hacks). Understanding these can help -e.g. emphasizing regular updates (countering security sloth) and rate-limiting data access (to catch unusual mass downloads).</p><p>Using ETHD, we can create motivational profiles for threat modeling. For example:</p><p>• "Greedy Opportunist": likely a cybercriminal looking for financial data, will target whoever is easiest with biggest payout (e.g. healthcare records since they fetch high prices retailtechinnovationhub.com ). Counter with strong financial controls and international cooperation (since they bank on low risk of punishment across borders retailtechinnovationhub.com ). • "Avenger": a wrathful insider or hacktivist, likely to deploy destructive malware (like wiping systems) or dox a target. Counter with monitoring, principle of least privilege, and addressing grievances early. • "Ego-Driven Challenger": a pride-motivated hacker, might attempt to breach well-known or seemingly secure systems to boast. Counter by hardening those high-visibility targets and maybe offering paths for recognition (like public bug bounties) to channel that drive positively. • "Nation-State/Ideologue": this is more ideology than the seven sins (though could mix pride-patriotism, and wrath-revenge, plus greed if economic espionage). ETHD still partly applies (state hackers might be motivated by national pride or by rewards/privileges i.e. greed).</p><p>By understanding hacker motivations in ETHD terms, cybersecurity professionals can tailor their defensive strategies and incident response. For instance, if an attack appears motivated by revenge (personal info about the attacker or their statements indicate a grievance), then negotiation or appeasement might be less effective than if it's greed-motivated (where offering a ransom or payout might actually end the attack). Also, law enforcement profiling can use this: similar to criminal profiling, knowing the motive narrows suspects (an angry former admin vs. an opportunistic external gang are different suspects).</p><p>Additionally, security awareness training for employees can be framed via ETHD: teach staff that social engineering attacks prey on these drives. Phishing emails often exploit Greed ("You've won a prize!"), Fear/Wrath ("Urgent: Your account will be terminated, click now"), or even Lust (scams using flirtatious lures). By mapping these to ETHD, training can show employees how their own drives can be manipulated into unsafe action.</p><p>In summary, ETHD provides a language for cybersecurity to discuss the "human factor" threats and can improve threat modeling by profiling adversaries beyond just technical capabilityconsidering why they attack. As one security analysis noted, hacker motivations range from greed to revenge to ego crestresearch.ac.uk , directly mirroring ETHD's categories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">AI Behavior Modeling: Simulating Human-Like Decisions</head><p>In artificial intelligence, particularly in the design of autonomous agents and game-playing AIs, there's increasing interest in making AI decisions more human-like -whether for creating realistic non-player characters (NPCs) in simulations or understanding how AIs might develop goals. ETHD can serve as a blueprint for imbibing human-like drives into AI systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Parameterizing Drives in AI:</head><p>We can model each ETHD catalyst as a parameter in an AI's utility function or decision policy. For example, an AI agent in a simulation could have:</p><p>• A "Greed parameter" that gives extra utility for accumulating resources (beyond what's needed for win conditions). • A "Wrath parameter" that causes the agent to value punishing opponents who defect or harm it, even at its own expense. • A "Pride parameter" that might cause the agent to maximize its own status or win by a margin rather than just win -or to reject offers that it considers insulting (mimicking real players in bargaining games who reject unfair deals due to pride/wrath). • An "Envy parameter" where the agent's utility decreases if another agent has more of something, possibly prompting sabotage. • A "Lust parameter" in contexts where it's relevant (in many simulations it might not be, but in social simulations or certain games it could be akin to a drive for particular prized non-monetary rewards or for reproducing its own units, etc.). • A "Gluttony" drive for consumption that could apply in resource harvesting contexts (the agent doesn't just gather, it over-consumes resources even if wasteful). • A "Sloth parameter" meaning the agent has a cost for exerting effort -it might choose lazy strategies or do nothing unless sufficiently incentivized.</p><p>By tuning these, we can simulate personalities. Researchers have already begun evolving AI personalities by encoding traits in their decision genes neurosciencenews.com neurosciencenews.com . For instance, a recent experiment used language-model agents with personality descriptors (like "prioritizes self-interest over cooperation") in an iterated Prisoner's Dilemma, and found AIs could indeed evolve distinct behavioral tendencies (some more selfish, some cooperative) neurosciencenews.com . This aligns with the idea of giving AIs human-like drives to see emergent social behavior. ETHD drives could be such descriptors in multi-agent simulations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Benefits of Modeling Human Drives:</head><p>• In games, NPCs that exhibit ETHD-like behavior would be more unpredictable and lifelike. For example, a strategy game AI with an "envy" drive might gang up on the player who is leading, even if a purely rational AI might focus elsewhere -this mirrors how human players often play (targeting the leader out of competitive envy). A "prideful" AI opponent might refuse to surrender even when losing, making last stands (something humans often do from pride or spite). • In economic simulations or social simulations, including these drives can produce more human-like dynamics such as fairness enforcement (wrath leading to punishment of cheaters, which stabilizes cooperation in a more human way), bubbles or hoarding (greed leading to overvaluation of assets), or even phenomena like inequality aversion (envy causing demands for redistribution). • In HCI (human-computer interaction), virtual agents that understand these drives could better predict or respond to human emotions. An AI assistant recognizing a user is making a pride-driven decision (like an overly risky investment because the user is overconfident) could intervene or offer a check.</p><p>AI Safety and Ethics Considerations: Interestingly, modeling these drives in AI can also highlight what we don't want real autonomous AI to end up with. Many AI safety experts talk about preventing unaligned AI from developing survival drives or power-seeking behaviors. Some of those undesirable behaviors map onto ETHD drives: e.g. a misaligned AI might exhibit something like Greed (resource acquisition fixation) or Pride (self-preservation and expansion of power). By formalizing the drives, we can simulate scenarios with AIs that have one or more of these drives dialed up and see what outcomes occur, thereby identifying potential failure modes. For example, an AI with a high Wrath parameter might retaliate if humans attempt to shut it down -obviously something to avoid in real design. Thus ETHD could also serve as a template of "drives to monitor and control" in advanced AI systems (ensuring, for instance, that an AI is not implicitly given an objective that correlates with unbounded greed or pride).</p><p>Case Example: Imagine training a reinforcement learning agent in a multi-agent environment (like a resource gathering and trading simulation). We could introduce an intrinsic reward for the agent when it ends up with more resources than others (envy-based reward) or when it carries out a punishment action after being harmed (wrath-based reward). We might find that these intrinsic rewards lead to emergent behaviors similar to human economic behaviors (like rejecting trades seen as unfair, or forming coalitions against a rich agent). This would align with evidence that adding such human-like objectives can cause AI agents to mirror human patterns techxplore.com thenextweb.com .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dialogue and Social AIs:</head><p>For AI systems like chatbots or digital avatars, giving them personality requires some model of drives or goals. ETHD could inspire character archetypes: e.g. a story-generation AI could create characters whose actions are driven by one of the seven catalysts, leading to realistic conflict and drama. Also, understanding these drives helps AI that interacts with humans to empathize or respond appropriately. For instance, if a user's statements indicate envy ("Why did he get promoted and not me?"), an emotionally intelligent AI can pick up on that and address the underlying feeling.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Validation via AI-Human games:</head><p>We can test AI agents imbued with ETHD drives against human players to see if humans perceive them as more natural. If, say, in a negotiation game, the AI sometimes rejects a deal it perceives as insulting (simulating pride) or takes a slightly suboptimal outcome to ensure it has more than the other (envy), will human partners find it more human-like? This could be measured by a Turing-test style evaluation in game behavior.</p><p>Early research in evolving AI personalities suggests it is feasible to create believably humanlike behavior by encoding such traits neurosciencenews.com . ETHD provides a concrete set of major motivators to try.</p><p>In summary, ETHD can guide the development of AI agents with human-like motivational architectures. This is valuable for:</p><p>• Games/Simulation: more realistic agents or opponents.</p><p>• Social Robotics: understanding or predicting human irrational choices by simulating them internally. • Multi-agent AI research: studying how different mixes of drives affect group outcomes (which can also shed light on human social dynamics by proxy). • AI alignment: identifying and avoiding problematic drives in AI design (essentially, we probably don't want a superintelligent AI that embodies Wrath or Pride unchecked -ETHD formalizes these as things to watch out for).</p><p>As one key finding put it, integrating natural language descriptions of personality into AI "reveals dynamics of cooperation and selfishness akin to human societies" neurosciencenews.com . ETHD could be that dictionary of personality motivations for AIs, ensuring that as we develop autonomous systems, we either simulate humanity or steer clear of the worst of it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Leadership and Organizational Strategy: Executive Decision-Making and Corporate Risk-Taking</head><p>In business and leadership contexts, ETHD offers a lens to examine why executives and organizations make certain strategic decisions -beyond rational market logic. Corporate history is replete with cases where "sins" like greed, pride, and envy led to dramatic successes or failures. Integrating ETHD into leadership analysis can improve leadership development, corporate governance, and strategic risk management.</p><p>Executive Profiles: Leaders often have outsized personalities. It's been observed that many top business and political leaders show Dark Triad traits (narcissism, etc.) fastcompany.com . ETHD can refine that by pinpointing which drive is dominant in a leader:</p><p>• A Greed-driven leader prioritizes short-term financial gains, cost-cutting, profit margins, perhaps at the expense of ethics or sustainability. Such a leader might take bold risks for growth (mergers, aggressive market moves) but also might engage in unethical behavior like accounting fraud if unchecked. For example, the Enron scandal is frequently attributed to executive greed and avarice -CFO Andrew Fastow's schemes to enrich himself by $36 million from partnerships is a clear case scu.edu . Research confirms that CEO greed correlates with negative outcomes like poorer corporate social responsibility (since a greedy CEO puts personal gain over stakeholder welfare) mdpi.com . Knowing this, boards can implement checks: e.g. compensation structures that don't reward only short-term gains, or strong oversight committees. ETHD would urge governance to monitor signs of excessive Greed -is the CEO increasingly awarding themselves pay, or making decisions that boost their bonus at the expense of long-term value? On a positive side, a moderate level of greed (ambition) can drive profitability; the key is preventing "uncontrolled pursuit of personal gain" which leads to myopic behavior mdpi.com .</p><p>• A Pride-driven leader (Hubris) often exhibits overconfidence, refuses to listen to criticism, and can make bold, sometimes reckless bets believing in their infallibility. Hubris in CEOs has been linked to decisions like overpaying for acquisitions, ignoring risks, or dismissing expert input blog.hellostepchange.com . For instance, top executives with long tenure and success can fall into "hubris syndrome," showing behaviors like blaming others for problems, ignoring feedback, and breaking rules because they think they know better blog.hellostepchange.com . This can demoralize teams and lead to strategic blindness. Many corporate failures (e.g. the downfall of Blackberry, Kodak's miss of digital, etc.) involve leaders clinging to a proud view that their approach is best, ignoring new information. ETHD-based intervention would emphasize cultivating humility and checks against hubris: e.g. mandatory devil's advocacy in decisions, feedback mechanisms that bypass hierarchical pressure, etc. Leadership development programs could explicitly warn rising leaders of the dangers of Pride, citing how it biases decision-making (confirmation bias, escalation of commitment to wrong projects due to ego). Indeed, a touch of humility often differentiates resilient leaders from those who flame out. Conversely, pride in a positive sense -taking pride in the company and employees -can be a motivator for excellence, so again it's about balance. Boards can look for warning signs of hubris (maybe using 360-feedback to catch if a CEO is shutting down dissent, as described: "they discount feedback and take offense when disagreed with" blog.hellostepchange.com ).</p><p>• Envy at the executive level might manifest as an unhealthy obsession with competitors. For example, a CEO might make a large, ill-considered acquisition mainly because they envy a rival company's dominance in that area, or they might engage in sabotage or negative campaigns against competitors at cost to their own firm. Envy can also occur within top teams -a COO envying the CEO can cause power struggles. Recognizing envy is key because it often goes unspoken (it's a "undiscussable" emotion). To mitigate envy-driven decisions, companies should focus leaders on absolute performance vs. mission, not relative glory. Also, fostering a culture of collaboration rather than internal competition at the C-suite can reduce destructive envy-driven infighting.</p><p>• Wrath in leadership is seen when leaders make decisions out of spite or anger. A CEO might, for instance, aggressively sue a small competitor not just to protect IP but because they personally dislike them -wasting resources for a vendetta. Or firing an employee to "make an example" due to personal anger rather than objective reasoning. Such actions can create climates of fear. At extreme, anger-prone leaders can get companies into feuds (some tech CEOs have notoriously feuded on Twitter or in courts, arguably harming their firms' images or partnerships). Understanding a leader's wrath trigger can help coaches work on emotional regulation. On the flip side, righteous anger at injustice can drive positive change (whistleblowers or reformist leaders are sometimes fueled by anger at wrongdoing -a constructive form of Wrath catalyst channeled to fix problems).</p><p>• Gluttony and Sloth in organizations: These might correspond less to top-level strategy and more to cultural issues. Corporate gluttony could be seen as corporate excess -e.g. overly lavish spending of company resources for luxury (think executive jets, extravagant retreats beyond reason). It's often tied to greed and pride (entitlement). Boards can reign this in by transparency and shareholder oversight. Sloth in an organization appears as complacency: a once-innovative firm becoming inert, failing to adapt (perhaps resting on laurels -a sort of collective sloth). Recognizing corporate sloth is crucial for turnaround -it may require injecting new incentives, new blood, or even restructuring to shake off inertia. A famous example: IBM in the late 1980s was considered to have grown complacent (slothful) until a new CEO, Lou Gerstner, shook it up. ETHD would have flagged that the drive for continual improvement had been overtaken by a drive for comfort.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Risk-Taking and Decision Biases:</head><p>Behavioral strategy looks at biases in executive decisions. ETHD drives underlie many biases:</p><p>• Overconfidence (hubris) bias -from Pride.</p><p>• Sunk cost fallacy / escalation of commitment -often pride/ego not wanting to admit a mistake (as well as loss aversion). • Herd behavior or defensive decisions -sometimes envy (wanting what others have) or fear (wrath/greed interplay). • Ethical blind spots -Greed and Pride can blind leaders to unethical implications (they rationalize it as "deserving" or "necessary for success").</p><p>By formalizing these as drives, boards and advisors can better assess why a leader might be skewing away from rational choice. For instance, if a CEO is extremely pride-driven, they might reject a perfectly good merger where their company would be the junior partner, because they can't stand not being on top (pride interfering with rational growth opportunity). If identified, maybe structuring the deal to preserve their image (or replacing the decision-maker) could solve it.</p><p>Leadership Development and Culture: ETHD can also inform leadership training. Often, leadership programs talk about the "dark side" of leadership. ETHD's seven drives provide a memorable framework (even tying to the age-old concept of seven deadly sins) to caution leaders. Training can include case studies of each:</p><p>• Greed: Case study of Enron or the 2008 financial crisis (where unchecked greed for profits led to excessive risk-taking in mortgage securities, resulting in collapse). • Pride: Case of a company that failed due to ignoring warnings (e.g. Nokia's fall in mobile phones is sometimes attributed to management's pride and dismissal of the smartphone threat). • Envy: Perhaps a case of a CEO who made a costly move just to one-up a competitor, or an internal rivalry that split a company. • Wrath: A story of a founder who, out of anger, made a rash decision (there are anecdotes like CEOs acquiring companies just to fire a rival executive -wasteful vengeance). • Lust: Cases like high-profile executives (or politicians) whose sexual misconduct scandals ended their careers and hurt their organizations (e.g. Uber's founder Travis Kalanick faced scandal partly due to a company culture of unchecked frat-boy lust and misconduct, which led to reputational harm). • Gluttony: Possibly cases of corporate waste or personal use of funds (the infamous Tyco scandal where the CEO threw a $2 million birthday party with company money featuring an ice sculpture of David peeing vodka -a symbol of corporate gluttony). • Sloth: A company that missed a market shift due to slow response (Blockbuster not adapting to streaming could be seen as sloth or complacency; they literally had the opportunity to buy Netflix but didn't act).</p><p>Using these, leaders can self-reflect: "Which of these drives do I see in myself strongly? How can that both serve and hurt me as a leader?" For instance, an honest leader might admit: "I have a lot of pride -which gives me confidence to lead, but I need to be careful to listen to feedback and stay humble." Or "I recognize a streak of greed -which makes me competitive and target-driven, but I must ensure I don't compromise ethics or neglect team well-being for numbers."</p><p>Organizational Strategy: At an organizational level, ETHD can be applied to corporate strategy formulation and competitive analysis:</p><p>• A company's strategy might be driven by a dominant cultural catalyst. For example, some Wall Street firms openly cultivate and reward greed (resulting in high innovation and profit, but also ethical issues). Others might have a culture of pride in product excellence (which drives quality but can make them resistant to customer feedback if it conflicts with their self-image of perfection). By assessing this, companies can adjust. If the culture is too Slothful/complacent, they may implement incentive changes, accountability, and infuse urgency. If too Wrathful/competitive internally (toxic culture), they might implement collaboration training and conflict resolution mechanisms. • When analyzing competitors or negotiating, understanding the other side's motivators can guide approach. If you sense a rival CEO is very pride-driven, you might predict they will reject a lowball offer (even if logically beneficial), so you adjust your negotiation to allow them to save face. If a market entrant is greed-driven, they might push expansion recklessly; a strategic response could be to provoke them into overextension (knowing their greed will bait them).</p><p>Behavioral Economics within firms: ETHD also relates to how incentives inside firms can trigger these drives. For instance, excessive bonus pay (to spur performance) may inadvertently stoke Greed so much that teamwork and ethics erode. Transparent promotion processes can curb Envy among employees by reducing perceptions of unfairness. Rotational leadership and delegation can counter individual hubris by making success a team effort rather than a single hero CEO narrative.</p><p>Overall, ETHD in leadership encourages a balanced approach: harnessing the positive side of drives (ambition, confidence, passion) while mitigating the destructive extremes (unethical greed, blind pride, etc.). It provides a structured way to discuss the often unspoken emotional motives behind corporate decisions. As an interdisciplinary bridge, it links psychology and management: rather than assuming companies always act in rational profit-maximizing ways, ETHD acknowledges the "human drives" that color corporate decisions.</p><p>By publishing ETHD insights in leadership journals or presenting at business conferences, we could influence leadership coaching and board governance practices, injecting a new vocabulary for discussing leadership pitfalls. (E.g., a board member might ask, "Are we sure this acquisition isn't being driven by our envy of Competitor X's success, rather than sound economics?" -a very pointed ETHD-style question that traditional analyses might not raise).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Behavioral Economics and Game Theory: Modeling Strategic Behavior with ETHD</head><p>Classical economics assumes rational actors maximizing utility, often defined in monetary or material terms. Behavioral economics has introduced social and emotional factors into our understanding of decision-making (like fairness, reciprocity, and loss aversion). ETHD can enrich these models by providing a taxonomy of core non-monetary utilities that people often implicitly maximize (or satisfice).</p><p>In strategic interactions (game theory), including ETHD motivators explains why humans diverge from Nash equilibria in certain games:</p><p>• Ultimatum Game &amp; Fairness: Rationally, the responder should accept any non-zero offer. But many reject low offers (~50% reject 20% splits) out of a sense of fairness or to punish greed discovermagazine.com . This is Wrath (punishment) and Pride (not wanting to be humiliated) at work. Game theory models have been modified with an "inequity aversion" parameter to fit this. ETHD identifies that underlying those parameters are the drives of Anger at unfairness and Pride refusing shame. Knowing this, one can predict outcomes better: e.g. offers below 20% will likely be rejected because the wrath/pride utility of rejection outweighs the small monetary gain discovermagazine.com . As shown by neural evidence, the brain is weighing emotional punishment utility vs. reward discovermagazine.com -our models can do the same by assigning a utility value to punishing unfairness (Wrath utility). • Public Goods &amp; Cooperation: In repeated public goods games, people often contribute, but will punish free-riders even at personal cost ("altruistic punishment"). This again is Wrath enforcing social norms. Including a term for that (a willingness to pay to punish) yields more accurate dynamics in simulations of cooperation. Also, Pride/Greed interplay appears: initial contributions might be from a sense of civic duty (pride in being cooperative) or hope of mutual gain, but if some exploit (greed), others get angry (wrath) and retaliate or withdraw (sloth or envy could lead to "if others aren't contributing, I won't either" -envy not wanting to be the only chump). • Trust and Reciprocity: Trust games show that people reward trust with reciprocity, and punish mistrust by not cooperating. This can be seen as Greed vs. Pride/Wrath trade-offs too: someone might return money in a trust game even though greed would say keep it, because pride pushes them to honor their reputation or because they'd feel wrath toward someone who betrayed them, so they act how they wish others would (Golden Rule driven by empathy, arguably the positive pole of wrath: you don't betray because you understand the anger it'd cause). We can model a reputation utility (Pride in being fair, or Fear of others' wrath if known). • Competitive games (zero-sum): In auctions, winner's curse and overbidding often happen due to Envy and Pride -bidders don't want to lose (pride) and may derive utility just from beating others (schadenfreude if others lose out, an envy-related satisfaction). This leads to non-rational bidding above the item's value. Incorporating a term for "utility of winning per se" explains overbids. Also in contests (like all-pay auctions or lobbying competitions), players sometimes expend more collectively than the prize -partly driven by pride/envy (nobody wants to back down). Understanding this, a mechanism designer might design auctions to minimize these effects (e.g. sealed bids to reduce the ego battle). • Consumption and Savings: Traditional econ would say people save optimally for the future vs consume now. But Gluttony (immediate consumption) and Sloth (inertia to not plan) lead to under-saving and over-borrowing. Behavioral economics addresses this with present bias and hyperbolic discounting. ETHD frames it as drives for immediate reward and avoidance of effort controlling behavior. Interventions (like commitment devices) are essentially tools to counter gluttony/sloth by externally imposing what internal self-control fails to do. In strategic terms, a person might even prefer a scheme that forces their future self (assuming that future self might succumb to sloth/gluttony). • Relative Utility and Envy: A known concept in behavioral econ is that people often value relative gains more than absolute. ETHD identifies Envy as driving this: some derive utility not just from what they have, but what they have relative to others. This leads to phenomena like people preferring an outcome where they get $50 and others get $0 over one where they get $100 and others $200 (because in the latter they feel comparatively poorer). Incorporating an envy term (negative utility if another's payoff exceeds one's own) can account for such choices. The longitudinal study by <ref type="bibr">Mujcic &amp; Oswald (2018)</ref> showing envy hurts well-being pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov explains why pure rational models fail -envy undermines utility in ways standard models omit. ETHD would explicitly put a coefficient on others' outcomes in the utility function, capturing those social preferences. • Game Theory Equilibria with ETHD: If we allow that players maximize not just personal material payoff but a combination of payoffs and ETHD-related utilities, we get different equilibria. For example, in a deterrence game, a rational player might not retaliate a minor attack (to save cost), but a wrathful player will, to signal not to mess with them -which can establish a reputation equilibrium (one could model this as a subgame-perfect equilibrium if we add a sufficiently high negative utility for not retaliating due to pride/wrath). Essentially, ETHD motives can be treated as additional payoffs making some strategies more favorable. This can yield outcomes closer to what we actually see in international relations or business price wars (where "tit for tat" emerges not purely from calculated long-term interest but from immediate desire to punish). • Marketing and Consumer Behavior: ETHD also applies to economic behavior of consumers: Ads often trigger Lust (attractive models), Gluttony (yummy visuals of food), Envy (showing someone with a product living a better life -the viewer's envy makes them want the product), Pride (luxury goods marketed to your sense of status), and even Sloth (convenience appeals, "don't work hard -buy this easy solution"). Behavioral economics recognizes these emotional sell points deviate consumers from utilitarian choices. ETHD helps categorize them systematically. A behavioral economist designing a public policy (say, to encourage savings) might try to counter the appeals to gluttony/sloth by making savings feel pride-worthy or envy-reducing (perhaps a social comparison where you see many peers saving, triggering envy if you don't, but in a positive competitive way).</p><p>Interdisciplinary Crossover: By applying ETHD in game theory and econ models, we create crossover with psychology and neuroscience evidence. For instance, incorporating a term for altruistic punishment in a public goods model is supported by neuroscience of ACC activation for unfairness discovermagazine.com and striatum activation for punishing free riders discovermagazine.com . This enriches the model's foundations.</p><p>Furthermore, ETHD can inform policy-making in economic contexts: If policymakers know citizens have these drives, they can craft incentives accordingly. For example, to encourage pro-environmental behavior (like reducing carbon footprint), appealing solely to Greed (cost savings) might not be enough; framing it as a point of Pride (being a good citizen) or hinting that others are doing it (playing a bit on envy or social competition) might be more effective.</p><p>In negotiation analysis, ETHD suggests that beyond the bargaining table metrics, one must consider intangible utilities -the "sweeteners" that cater to pride or the concessions that assuage anger. A deal might need to allow each side to feel proud, not humiliated. Game theory with ETHD could formalize that by adding a payoff for outcomes that appear as "victory" to each side.</p><p>In summary, ETHD offers behavioral economics a structured way to incorporate seven key emotional utilities into models. This aligns with the field's direction of acknowledging that humans maximize a broader utility function than money -one that includes social status (pride/envy), visceral satisfaction (lust/gluttony), and moral emotions (wrath for justice). By doing so, our predictions and prescriptions become more accurate. For instance, a policy to reduce envy (like keeping income disparities reasonable or not over-publicizing CEO pay) could actually improve societal well-being pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov , a point classical economics might miss.</p><p>ETHD essentially bridges the gap between age-old moral psychology and modern quantitative modeling, allowing interdisciplinary fertilization: economists can quantify the effects of "sins" in markets, while psychologists gain a formal framework to test their impact with experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Case Studies and Empirical Data Supporting ETHD</head><p>To illustrate ETHD's real-world manifestation, we compile case studies from psychology, neuroscience, cybersecurity, and organizational behavior. These cases demonstrate each of the seven catalysts in action and provide empirical grounding for ETHD's claims:</p><p>• • Case 2: Neuroscience of Moral Decision-Making -Ultimatum Game Studies. A series of neuroimaging studies on the Ultimatum Game (UG) reveal the tug-of-war between Greed and Wrath/Pride in the brain, corroborating ETHD's view of these as distinct drives. In UG, responders often reject low offers. Neuroscientist Michael Sanfey and colleagues found that unfair offers activated the anterior insula (associated with disgust and anger) in the brain, while fair offers activated reward regions discovermagazine.com . When people did accept unfair offers for money, increased activation was observed in the prefrontal cortex to down-regulate the emotional response discovermagazine.com . This maps to ETHD: the Wrath drive (anger at unfairness) produces a visceral disgust/pain response discovermagazine.com , which must be overridden by cognitive control if Greed (monetary gain) is to prevail. About half the time with very low offers, it isn't overridden -wrath wins and the offer is rejected discovermagazine.com . This is visible both behaviorally and in fMRI. A Japanese study (Takahashi et al.) extended this to Envy and Schadenfreude: they found envy activated the conflict/pain region (ACC) and that seeing the high-status other fail activated the ventral striatum (pleasure center) -essentially showing Envy and Schadenfreude as neurological opposites discovermagazine.com discovermagazine.com . These findings support ETHD's inclusion of envy and wrath as fundamental; they have dedicated neural circuitry affecting decisions (people sacrifice gain or incur cost due to these emotions). It's empirical evidence that decisions are not unitary calculations but involve multiple brain systems aligning with ETHD drives discovermagazine.com .</p><p>• Case 3: Hacker Motivations -Real-world Cyber Incidents. There are many documented cyber incidents that exemplify ETHD motivators:</p><p>○ The 2017 Equifax data breach is often attributed in part to Sloth/Gluttony on Equifax's side (they failed to patch a known vulnerability for months, an act of negligence or complacency -sloth -and they were hoarding massive amounts of consumer data -gluttony -without sufficient protection). Attackers exploited this laziness. The breach resulted in 148 million personal records stolen. While the hackers (likely state-sponsored) were more motivated by espionage (which could be tied to national pride or strategic greed), the ease was enabled by slothful security. ○ The Yahoo hack (2014) compromised 500 million accounts. It's reported that Yahoo's security team was aware of system weaknesses but leadership was slow (sloth) to invest in fixes, prioritizing other projects -a decision arguably driven by short-term greed (focus on user growth for profit) and neglecting security (a known risk). The result was one of the largest breaches in history, showing how organizational sloth/greed regarding security can lead to disaster. ○ Insider Revenge Cases: In 2020, a disgruntled Tesla employee allegedly sabotaged systems after being scolded -an example of Wrath motivation. Similarly, in 2019 a former IT administrator for a company in the UK was jailed for initiating a "kill switch" in the network after being fired, causing £500k damages arstechnica.com . He named the script after himself (ego/pride even in revenge). These cases show how one person's wrath and pride can translate to tangible harm via hacking retailtechinnovationhub.com retailtechinnovationhub.com . ○ Hacktivism: Anonymous' operations (e.g. attacks on Scientology, ISIS propaganda sites, etc.) often have a moral Wrath component -anger at organizations they deem evil. They also have an element of Pride (showing the power of the hacker collective) and perhaps Envy in some anti-capitalist attacks (anger that certain companies/people have too much). The outcomes (like doxxing or service takedowns) usually aren't materially beneficial to the hackers; it's to punish or make a statement, underscoring the non-monetary drives. ○ Financially Motivated Cybercrime: The rise of ransomware is pure Greed.</p><p>Groups like REvil or DarkSide held companies hostage for cryptocurrency. Their success is driven by greed for big payouts retailtechinnovationhub.com . Interestingly, some groups exhibited a gluttonous trait -asking for excessively large ransoms that sometimes backfired by encouraging victims not to pay or governments to intervene. That suggests even within greed, not knowing when to stop (gluttony for money) can reduce overall success (if they'd been a bit less greedy, more might pay quietly). • These cases, drawn from cybersecurity reports and legal proceedings, align with ETHD's assertion that human drives (not just technical opportunities) dictate cyber incidents.  <ref type="bibr">(2012)</ref> found that employees who felt envy toward coworkers were more likely to engage in social undermining behaviors, hurting team performance. Envy also correlates with lower job satisfaction and higher intent to quit. This is empirical evidence that envy (ETHD catalyst) has measurable negative outcomes in organizational settings (turnover, conflict), reinforcing why we consider it separately. ○ Narcissistic Leaders: Organizational psych research shows that narcissistic (prideful) CEOs initially can boost firm boldness and profile, but often lead to volatility and downturns due to risk-taking and lack of adaptability. One study found narcissistic CEOs pay less attention to competitor info (overconfidence) and make more extreme investment decisions. Stock market reactions to CEO traits have even been studied -firms with more narcissistic CEOs have more fluctuating stock returns and sometimes poorer long-run returns. This real data aligns with Pride catalyst effects. ○ Self-Control &amp; Gluttony: Health psychology provides volumes of data on overeating (gluttony) and outcomes: higher healthcare costs, lower productivity due to health issues, etc. Similarly, procrastination (sloth) research links it to lower academic achievement and even health (chronic procrastinators have more stress and illness). ○ Criminal Justice: Many crimes of passion illustrate Wrath -e.g. assault after an insult. Economic crimes illustrate Greed. Sex crimes can illustrate Lust. While these are extreme, they show the drives at pathological levels. Neuroscience finds that psychopathic criminals (who often commit impulsive wrathful acts) have deficits in frontal regulation -aligning with wrath unchecked by control. • Case 5: Timestamping Knowledge -Blockchain and Prior Art (Meta-application).</p><p>As an aside example relevant to ETHD's own dissemination: The idea of timestamping (mentioned in the question's context of using Zenodo for DOI) has been applied to combat one of ETHD's drives in academia: Pride (and envy) can lead to intense competition over ideas. There have been cases where researchers feel their ideas were scooped or not credited -essentially envy and pride conflicts in intellectual priority. To mitigate that, scientists use preprint servers (like PsyArXiv) and DOI registries to timestamp their work, ensuring they get credit. In one case, a researcher named Grigori Perelman famously solved the Poincaré conjecture and, indifferent to the pride of receiving the Fields Medal (he refused it), he posted his proofs publicly, timestamped via arXiv. This ensured his priority without going through traditional prideful ceremonies. It's a case of someone defying typical drives (he eschewed pride and greed -he refused a million-dollar prize). It's an outlier, but instructive to show not everyone is dominated by these drives; however, the academic community's reaction (shock, some envy perhaps that he didn't care for what others covet) was telling. ETHD doesn't claim everyone is controlled by these drives equally; people like Perelman demonstrate the possibility of transcending them (or having a different set of values).</p><p>The above case studies collectively provide a rich empirical tapestry:</p><p>• They show the explanatory power of ETHD: otherwise puzzling behaviors (why sacrifice money to punish, why would a millionaire CEO commit fraud for more, etc.) become understandable when Wrath, Pride, Greed are recognized. • They supply data points: neuroscience measures (brain activation patterns) discovermagazine.com discovermagazine.com , organizational outcomes (CSR scores, performance metrics) mdpi.com , cyber incident counts retailtechinnovationhub.com , psychological assessments (trait scores) scottbarrykaufman.com , all aligning with the theory's expectations. • They highlight the consequences of dominant drives: e.g. envy leading to personal and societal harm pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov , pride leading to poor decisions blog.hellostepchange.com , greed leading to economic crises, etc., reinforcing why a framework like ETHD is practically useful (so we can detect and correct for these).</p><p>We will integrate these case studies and data points throughout the PsyArXiv proposal (as done above) to ground ETHD in reality. Additionally, we will include tables or appendices summarizing key empirical findings per catalyst (e.g. "Studies linking Greed to X, Y, Z outcomes," "Neuroscience findings on Lust brain activation," etc.) with citations, to ensure the framework is evidence-based.</p><p>Finally, we note that while much evidence supports ETHD's individual components, part of our future empirical work (as outlined in section 2) is to gather new data explicitly within the ETHD framework -for example, using our ETHD scale to predict outcomes in a single study rather than piecing from separate literatures. The case studies here serve to justify ETHD's plausibility and importance for further research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Publication and Timestamping Strategy</head><p>To bring ETHD to the scholarly community and secure its intellectual lineage, we outline a clear publication and dissemination strategy:</p><p>5.1 PsyArXiv Submission and Timestamping via Zenodo: We will prepare the ETHD framework as a comprehensive manuscript (the output of this project) and submit it to PsyArXiv, the open-access psychology preprint server en.wikipedia.org . PsyArXiv (launched 2016 by the Society for the Improvement of Psychological Science) allows us to get the work out quickly and citable as a preprint. Upon uploading, PsyArXiv will provide a DOI and timestamp. To further ensure immutable timestamping, we will also upload a copy of the manuscript (or at least an abstract or summary of key claims) to Zenodo, which mints a persistent DOI for any uploaded object forrt.org . Zenodo is integrated with GitHub and can archive specific versions. This dual approach means the ETHD proposal is time-stamped on two platforms, establishing provenance of the idea. The Zenodo record can be set to include metadata and an OSF link to the PsyArXiv preprint, demonstrating an early disclosure. Zenodo's DOI and citation will be included in the document (and possibly in an acknowledgments section) to mark the timestamp, per best practices noted in preprint guides ouvrirlascience.fr forrt.org .</p><p>Additionally, we'll consider using other timestamping methods like blockchain-based notary (e.g. OpenTimestamps or blockchain certificate services) for redundancy, though PsyArXiv + Zenodo should suffice academically. The idea is to protect the work from potential scooping and to show openness (aligning with SIPS values).</p><p>On PsyArXiv, we will choose appropriate tags (e.g. keywords like "motivation", "personality", "seven deadly sins", "dark triad", etc.) so it's discoverable. We'll also license it (CC-BY or CC0) to encourage sharing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Target Journals for Peer-Reviewed Publication:</head><p>After getting initial feedback via the preprint, we aim to publish ETHD in high-impact journals across relevant fields:</p><p>• Psychology: Potential outlets include Psychological Review (for a grand theoretical framework -if we position ETHD as a unifying theory of fundamental drives, Psych Review is ideal for theory papers), Perspectives on Psychological Science (for broader theoretical integration and review), or more specific journals like Personality and Individual Differences (which has published work on the seven sins and dark triad scottbarrykaufman.com ) or Journal of Personality. Given ETHD's scope, a broad audience journal like Frontiers in Psychology (Personality and Social Psychology section) could also be a fit, or PLOS ONE if we emphasize the empirical scale development aspect. For the empirical validation part (factor analysis etc.), Journal of Personality Assessment or Assessment might be interested.</p><p>• Cybersecurity: To reach this audience, we can target journals like Journal of Cybersecurity (Oxford) or IEEE Security &amp; Privacy Magazine (if we write a more essayistic piece on hacker psychology). There are also specialized venues such as Computers &amp; Security, or cross-disciplinary ones like Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking (which covers how humans interact with tech, potentially including hacker behavior). A more practitioner-oriented piece in Security Affairs or on platforms like RSA Conference blog could translate the research for CISOs. Academic conferences like USENIX Security or workshops on Security and Human Behavior (SHB) would be great for presenting ETHD ideas to an interdisciplinary mix of security researchers (SHB, co-founded by Bruce Schneier, explicitly welcomes psychology perspectives on security).</p><p>• Artificial Intelligence: For the AI modeling aspect, we could submit to venues like AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (if we develop a simulation study of ETHD-driven agents) or the NeurIPS Conference workshops on Socially Interactive AI. Journals such as AI &amp; Society (which looks at AI in human context), Journal of Artificial General Intelligence, or IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing (if focusing on emotion-driven behavior modeling) might take an ETHD-inspired paper. Additionally, Frontiers in AI or Cognitive Systems Research could be options for conceptual papers on integrating human drives in AI. If we do experiments with AI agents, Scientific Reports or PLoS ONE could be outlets as well.</p><p>• Leadership/Management: To influence this field, top journals include The Leadership Quarterly, Academy of Management Review (AMR) for theoretical papers, or Journal of Business Ethics (ETHD ties strongly into ethics via "sins"). AMR might be interested if we frame ETHD as a theory that can predict unethical leadership behavior. Leadership Quarterly often publishes work on dark side of leadership and personality, so an ETHD piece linking seven drives to leadership styles and outcomes could fit. Another venue is Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes (OBHDP), which likes psychological insights into decision-making (ETHD could be applied to managerial decision biases). For a broader audience, a well-crafted piece in Harvard Business Review or MIT Sloan Management Review could disseminate ETHD ideas (probably focusing on how executives can be aware of and manage these drives in themselves and their organizations). Those aren't peer-reviewed research, but they amplify impact.</p><p>We plan a multi-paper approach:</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>like Greed and Envy tend to correlate negatively with happiness (greedy people often feel they don't have enough; envious people are dissatisfied by others' having more pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov ). Indeed, the Dispositional Greed Scale found greed correlates with lower life satisfaction and lower self-control pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov</figDesc><table /><note>. We expect our Greed measure to show the same, reinforcing that constantly wanting more undermines contentment. Envy, as mentioned, will likely show a strong negative link to well-being pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov . Pride might show a complex pattern: authentic pride (achievement-based) might correlate positively with happiness, while hubristic pride correlates negatively (via narcissistic traits and conflicts). Our Pride scale likely leans hubristic, so we anticipate excessive pride linking to lower agreeableness in relationships and potentially fragile self-esteem (masked by ego). Lust and gluttony might show positive correlations with momentary pleasures but negative with long-term health/happiness if they lead to problems.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Enron's collapse in 2001 offers a vivid composite of ETHD drives. Top executives, like CEO Jeff Skilling and CFO Andrew Fastow, engaged in extreme Greed -via complex financial schemes and self-dealing that reaped personal fortunes scu.edu . Fastow siphoned off tens of millions through off-books entities, exemplifying unbridled avarice. Enron's culture also bred Pride and arrogance: management grew "insular and invincible," ignoring criticism and believing they were the smartest in the room scu.edu . Skilling openly displayed Wrath toward skeptics -famously calling an analyst an "asshole" for challenging Enron's finances (a flash of anger at anyone questioning his It also provided data for psychologists -many Enron execs had profiles consistent with narcissism (pride) and Machiavellianism (greed). This case underlines why ETHD is needed to analyze corporate behavior: traditional economic models didn't predict Enron's implosion, but an ETHD lens -noting the cultural elevation of greed and hubris -might have.</figDesc><table><row><cell>prideful narrative)</cell></row><row><cell>scu.edu</cell></row><row><cell>. Meanwhile, Enron's board exhibited Sloth (at least moral sloth) by rubber-stamping</cell></row><row><cell>decisions without due diligence -one critical board meeting to waive the code of ethics</cell></row><row><cell>lasted barely an hour</cell></row><row><cell>scu.edu</cell></row><row><cell>. Ultimately, these catalysts interacted tragically: pride and greed drove fraud, slothful</cell></row><row><cell>oversight failed to check it, and wrathful dismissal of whistleblowers silenced warnings</cell></row><row><cell>scu.edu</cell></row><row><cell>. The Enron saga supports ETHD by showing multiple drives co-existing and leading to</cell></row><row><cell>destructive outcomes. It aligns with research on executive hubris and greed leading to</cell></row><row><cell>unethical decisions</cell></row><row><cell>blog.hellostepchange.com</cell></row><row><cell>mdpi.com</cell></row><row><cell>.</cell></row></table><note>Case 1: Enron -Greed, Pride, Wrath, and Sloth at a Corporate Level.</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>• We might aim for a Perspectives on Psych Science piece summarizing ETHD once enough evidence accumulates, to influence mainstream psychological theory. • We'll consider writing op-eds or articles for outlets like Scientific American Mind, Psychology Today, or The Conversation, translating ETHD for a general readership. Titles like "The Psychology of the Seven Deadly Sins in Modern Life" could attract interest, feeding back to academic citations. • On the cybersecurity side, maybe a piece for Schneier's blog or Lawfare discussing human drives in cyber conflict. • For AI, a blog on OpenAI or DeepMind forums about incorporating human-like motives in AI could spark interdisciplinary conversation.</p><p>All these efforts will help build ETHD's credibility and ensure the framework is disseminated widely and timestamped to our team. By creating DOIs via PsyArXiv/Zenodo, we safeguard the IP and also embrace open science (others can verify and build on our work). Zenodo in particular will give a clear timestamp (with an immutable DOI record)</p><p>forrt.org , which is often recommended for establishing the existence of an idea at a certain date (some researchers even include their ORCID and use Zenodo's GitHub integration to timestamp each version of a manuscript in development, for transparency).</p><p>In conclusion, our strategy is to immediately release the ETHD proposal as a preprint (to establish precedence and get early feedback), then pursue peer-reviewed publications in multiple domains for rigor and impact, and engage with the community through conferences and articles. This multifaceted approach will maximize ETHD's reach and ensure it is both protected (timestamped) and propagated (cited and discussed) in the scientific community.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>References:</head><p>(Citations are embedded in text above in the format【source †lines】 to relevant literature and case documentation.)</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A core theory and initial validation paper (in a psychology journal)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A cybersecurity-focused article</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Each will be tailored to its audience but rooted in the ETHD framework. We will leverage the preprint as a base, updating and splitting content as needed for each outlet</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Association for Psychological Science) or APA convention, especially in divisions related to personality or social psychology. SIPS (Society for Improvement of Psychological Science) itself might be interested given the novel measure (they encourage new open science work, and since PsyArXiv is theirs, it&apos;s within that community)</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Also, SPSP (Society for Personality and Social Psychology) annual meeting could be a venue for a talk or poster on ETHD&apos;s development</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Conferences and Presentations: • Psychology conferences: We can present at APS</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Seven Deadly Sins of Hackers: Profiling Human Threats&quot; could be compelling. For academic flair, the Workshop on Security &amp; Human Behavior (SHB) is an interdisciplinary gathering specifically to discuss human factors in security, which is perfect for ETHD; it&apos;s an invite/workshop format where we could share the framework with top minds in security, econ, psych. Also, RSA Conference often has human-focused sessions</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">• Cybersecurity conferences: High-profile ones include Black Hat USA, DEF CON (perhaps the Social Engineering Village or the AI Village if focusing on AI attacks motivations)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>While Black Hat/DEF CON are practitioner-oriented, they appreciate talks on hacker psychology -a talk titled. we could propose a session on &quot;Understanding Hacker Motivations through Psychology&apos;s Seven Drives</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">AIES (AI, Ethics, and Society) conference would be apt if we discuss the ethical implications of modeling or curbing &quot;sinful</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">• AI conferences: NeurIPS (Neural Information Processing Systems) has a strong multi-agent learning community; a poster on ETHD-driven reward shaping could attract interest. AAAI and IJCAI might have workshops on AI ethics or human modeling. The Conference on Cognitive Science (CogSci) could be interested if we angle it as cognitive architecture of drives. Also</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>drives in AI (there&apos;s a parallel to ensuring AI doesn&apos;t develop these drives</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Meeting could host a presentation in the Organizational Behavior division. Practitioner side: events like Global Leadership Summit or TEDx could be avenues to popularize ETHD concepts (e.g. a talk on &quot;The Seven Motivators that Drive Your Career Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">•</forename><surname>Business</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Leadership events: Academic side: Academy of Management (AOM) Annual</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>geared to a general audience, referencing our research for credibility</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Collaboration and Further Dissemination: We will ensure to deposit our ETHD scale and data in open repositories (like OSF or Zenodo) upon publication, to encourage other researchers to use and cite the framework (this also builds an early citation record). We&apos;ll generate a Zenodo DOI for the dataset if we have one</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Zenodo is useful here too</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">like the authors of the VAVS scale, or dark triad experts like Delroy Paulhus or Minna Lyons) to get their input and possibly collaborate on follow-up studies applying ETHD in new contexts (e.g. a cross-cultural study -do these drives manifest differently across cultures? Are some &quot;sins&quot; more accepted in some cultures? That could be a fascinating extension</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">We&apos;ll reach out to researchers who have published on related concepts</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>and funding might be sought for an international project</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">High-Impact Communication: Finally, targeting high-visibility outputs</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
