<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive Bias and Mate Choice</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dawson</surname></persName>
							<email>c.g.dawson@bath.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">†School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Claverton Down</addrLine>
									<postCode>BA2 7AY</postCode>
									<settlement>Bath</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive Bias and Mate Choice</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Unrealistic optimism</term>
					<term>personality</term>
					<term>assortative mating</term>
					<term>household decision making</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Sexual mates resemble each other on physical traits, personality factors and political opinion. We extend this line of research to one of the most prominent cognitive biases, unrealistic optimism-the tendency for individuals to overestimate the chance of favourable outcomes occurring and underestimate the chance of bad. Using data from a national representative sample of the English population over age 50, we find that there is a moderate alignment of mates on cognitive bias, similar in range to broad personality factors. Importantly, we also provide evidence that these similarities are driven by direct selection on bias rather than social homogamy, and initial mate choice rather than transmission mechanisms, such as persuasion and imitation. We discuss the implications of mate selection on cognitive bias in the context of household decision-making, income inequality and intergenerational transmission.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Assortative mating is the tendency for humans and non-humans to choose mates who are more similar (positive) or dissimilar (negative) to themselves more frequently than would be expected under a random mating pattern. Whilst negative assortative mating has been observed in humans-for instance, people tend to be more attracted to the odors of those who are genetically different in their acquired immune systems, promoting heterozygosity in the children <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Wedekind, Seebeck, Bettens &amp; Paepke, 1995)</ref>-assortative mating is almost universally positive, with similarities between partners for physical characteristics such as height <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Stulp, Simons, Grasman &amp; Pollet, 2017)</ref>; weight and body mass index <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Speakman, Djafarian, Stewart &amp; Jackson, 2007)</ref>; personality factors such as sensations seeking <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Glicksohn &amp; Golan, 2001</ref>) and the Big 5 personality factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Jessica &amp; Lee, 2023)</ref>; emotional intelligence <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Śmieja &amp; Stolarski, 2018)</ref>; risk and time preferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Arrondel &amp; Frémeaux, 2016)</ref>; and political attitudes <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Alford, Hatemi, Hibbing, Martin &amp; Eaves, 2011)</ref>. However, there appears to be no published work on the question of spousal concordance on cognitive bias.</p><p>This article attempts to address this gap in the literature, by focusing on assortative mating in the context of one of the most prominent and pervasive judgemental biases, unrealistic optimism-the tendency for individuals to overestimate the chance of favourable outcomes occurring and underestimate the chance of bad <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Weinstein, 1980)</ref>. Unrealistic optimism has been documented in many domains, from people underestimating the likelihood of developing a drinking problem or getting divorced <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Weinstein, 1980)</ref> to overestimating their future earnings <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Dawson, 2017)</ref> and their chances of starting a successful business (de Meza, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Dawson, Henley &amp; Arabsheibani, 2019)</ref>. Like all judgemental biases, unrealistic optimism distorts the decision-making process, leading to decision errors and negative outcomes for the individual owing to increased risky behaviour, failure to take precautions or insufficient preparation <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Shepperd, Waters, Weinstein &amp; Klein, 2015</ref>). This is a major omission. The modus operandi of behavioural science is to identify dysfunctional behaviours and to document their consequences for individual decision-making.</p><p>However, many decisions are made at the household level, involving two or more decisionmakers, which warrants a consideration of household bias. Indeed, in our study, nearly 77% of respondents reported having an equal say when asked about responsibility for the big financial decisions in the household. Just as the similarity between spouses in terms of education, for instance, can lead to a concentration of wealth among households <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Greenwood, Guner, Kocharkov &amp; Santos, 2014)</ref>, so can spousal concordance on cognitive bias.</p><p>In this article, we used a large, unbalanced panel of couples drawn from a nationally representative sample of the English population over age 50 and investigated whether spouses are concordant on unrealistic optimism. Unrealistic optimism is operationalized as the difference between a person's subjective survival beliefs and an objective probability derived from actuarial life expectancy tables. Survival expectations, like all expectations, play a crucial role in economic models of behaviour. For instance, according to the life-cycle model in economics, survival expectations are an important determinant of retirement, investments, annuities, and savings <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bloom, Canning &amp; Graham, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Hurd, 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Sheshinski, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Wolfe, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Wu, Stevens &amp; Thorp, 2015)</ref>. Importantly, empirical evidence has shown that subjective survival probabilities can meaningfully impact real economic activity through its impact on these decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hamermesh, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Hurd, Smith &amp; Zissimopoulos, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hurd, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Puri &amp; Robinson, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Wu, Stevens &amp; Thorp, 2015)</ref>. We also have the rare opportunity to measure the bias on a repeated basis, allowing us to capture the bias with more precision, limiting important issues surrounding random errors, measurement error, and regression toward the mean <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dawson, 2023)</ref>.</p><p>A further important question is how partner similarity can arise. Here, the literature speaks to three mechanisms. First, phenotypic assortative mating, where mates are selected because of the degree of similarity of a trait they hold to a corresponding trait of their prospective mate. Phenotypic assortative mating is consistent with the "likes-attract" hypothesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Buston &amp; Emlen, 2003)</ref> and with the predictions of attitude transmission modelswhere people have a preference to have children with similar traits to their own which creates an incentive to look for partners with similar traits. Second, social homogamy, where mates tend to come from similar social backgrounds. If these social backgrounds are correlated with unrealistic optimism, spousal concordance on unrealistic optimism may simply be a by-product of social homogamy. Last, partners may become more similar over time. This could be achieved via persuasion or imitation, or simply because spouses tend to share the same experiences over time which eliminates any initial discordance.</p><p>Our findings reveal positive assortative mating on cognitive bias, similar in size to spousal concordance on broad personality factors. We find little to modest evidence of the role of social homogamy and partner convergence, suggestive of phenotypic assortment based on mate choice. We also reject the hypothesis that spousal concordance on unrealistic optimism may simply reflect previous empirical findings regarding spousal concordance on Big Five personality factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Jessica &amp; Lee, 2023)</ref>. Taken together, our results suggest, that to some extent, cognitive bias are concentrated in households, which has wide ranging implications for intra-household decision making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>The English Longitudinal Study of Ageing (ELSA) is based on data collected from participants aged over 50, who originally took part in the Health Survey for England, which is an annual national survey. ELSA is broadly representative of the population of older people in England <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Steptoe, Breeze, Banks &amp; Nazroo, 2013)</ref>. Starting in 2002, ELSA involves re-interviewing participants approximately every two years. It includes a broad range of measures including those of physical and mental health, wellbeing and importantly, two questions on subjective survival beliefs, which forms the basis of measuring unrealistic optimism. The analytic samples include data from all households in which there was a heterosexual couple (cohabiting married and non-married couples) and who both gave valid responses to the dependent, independent and control variables used in the subsequent analysis. For respondents who had cohabitation spells with different partners we use data only from their first observed cohabitation spell. We use two different measures of unrealistic optimism from the two questions on subjective survival beliefs, which yields two analytic samples. The first, with 43,580 person-Wave observations from 9,398 individual respondents (4,699 heterosexual couples) and the second, with 20,622 person-Wave observations from 6,326 individual respondents (3,163 heterosexual couples).</p><p>A potential concern when investigating assortative mating, is that correlations within households may be driven by spouses or partners coordinating on how to answer different questions. Indeed, in ELSA households with more than one eligible respondent, respondents could be interviewed individually, or, interviewed at the same time (in a single session) using concurrent interviewing techniques-where the same block of questions was asked alternately of each person. However, five of the ELSA modules (Cognitive Function, Expectations, Effort and Reward, Psychosocial Health and Final Questions) are deemed as 'private modules'. These 'private modules' were administered with no other household members present, and in the case of concurrent interviewing, whilst the first respondent was completing the 'private modules', the second respondent was asked to complete a self-completion module in a separate room.</p><p>The two respondents then switched places. Our key measures of optimism are derived from the 'Expectations' module which forms part of the 'private modules' block, which ensures that collaboration by couples is ruled out.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Unrealistic optimism</head><p>To be able to assess the within-couple correlation of optimism bias we must be able to evaluate optimism at the individual level that is, to compare a participant's expectation with a statistically derived true expected value. This is the approach we take in the realm of subjective survival probabilities. In short, our key measure of optimism in the analyses that follows is defined as = − , where is the subjective survival probability for each individual, , at Wave, and is the statistically derived true expected value based upon population life tables.</p><p>Specifically, to measure we utilize responses to a probabilistic question on survival asked in every wave of ELSA. Specifically, ELSA asks all individuals "What are the chances that you will live to be or more?" Where is a target age depending on the age of the respondent. Panel A of <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> reports which target age respondents in each age range were asked about and the number of observations and individuals in each age range. We call this measure of the "variable target age task". In addition, in Waves 3 to 9, all respondents under the age of 70 are asked "What are the chances that you will live to be 85 or more?" Panel B of <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> reports the relevant statistics for this further subjective survival probability task.</p><p>We call this measure of the "static target age task". Responses to both questions are coded on a range from 0 to 100. To make sure people understand the scoring rule, participants answer a practice question reading "Let's try an example and start with the weather. What do you think the chances are it will be rainy tomorrow? Where 100 means a 100 percent chance of rainy weather and you can say any number from 0 to 100. For example, if you think there is a good chance that it will be rainy tomorrow, you might say there is an 80 percent chance of rain." To illustrate the variation of optimism in the analytic samples, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> plots the subjective survival responses against the objective probabilities. Specifically, we used a binned scatterplot to describe the relationship. The binned scatterplot groups the x-axis variable (the objective or actuarial probabilities) into 1500 equal-sized bins and then computes the mean of the y-axis variable (subjective survival probability) within each bin, then creates a scatterplot of these data points. We also include in each panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>, the estimated linear relationship where we regress the subjective survival probabilities on the actuarial life expectancy. Panel are more pessimistic than males ( = −3.65; <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Perozek, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Wu, Stevens &amp; Thorp, 2015)</ref> which is statistically significant, = 27.27, &lt; 0.001. Panels C and D repeat the process for the static target age task. Specifically, Panel C plots the relationship for men. The result of the regression indicates that raising actuarial life expectancy by one percent raises subjective survival probabilities by 1.09 percent ( = 1.09, 95% CI = [0.80, 1.38], = 7.33, &lt; 0.001). Again, for women, as depicted in Panel D, the relationship is similar ( = 0.90, 95% CI = [0.50, 1.29], = 4.43, &lt; 0.001). As above, females ( = −4.30) are more pessimistic than males ( = 0.91) which is statistically significant, = 15.48, &lt; 0.001. Note. Binned scatterplot, which plots the mean subjective survival probabilities for the 1500 equal-sized bins of actuarial probabilities. (A) Male sample: variable target age task. (B) Female sample: variable target age task. (C) Male: static target age task. (D) Female: static target age task. In all panels the solid line is a 45-degree line and the dashed line is the estimated linear relationship where we regress the subjective survival probabilities on the actuarial life expectancy. We also create random, spherical noise around data points so that data points are not plotted on top of each other.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analytic Strategy</head><p>For ease of exposition, the analytic strategy focuses on our optimism measure which is derived from the variable target age task. However, the analytic strategy is analogous for our optimism measure which is computed from the static target age task.</p><p>In a cross-sectional survey, measured discrepancies between subjective and actuarial probabilities can reflect a permanent component reflecting a systematic psychology bias (trait unrealistic optimism) and a stochastic component reflecting random errors in judgment.</p><p>Moreover, differences in survival unrealistic optimism may not only reflect measurement error, but also may capture heterogeneity in the task at hand. As we have illustrated, our optimism task is heterogenous within and across respondents, stemming from heterogeneity in the target age or the respondent's proximity to a specific target age. Indeed, in Wu, Stevens and Thorp (2015) a polynomial in current age and the respondents target age are important predictors of subjective survival probabilities. To address these issues, we exploit the longitudinal nature of the data. Specifically for each individual, , at Wave, , we estimate the following equation separately for each biological sex, = ( , ), using linear fixed-effect regression:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">= − = ∑ , 3 =1 + + + + (1)</formula><p>where we control for age (in cubic form), ; a series of binary variables for target age,</p><p>; and a series of binary variables for survey Wave, -which controls for timespecific factors which may affect the forecasting task. Lastly, is the usual disturbance term and, captures the intrinsic or trait component of unrealistic optimism, which are the individual specific fixed-effects net of the influences from age, target age and time-specific factors. This individual-level measure of trait optimism is extracted from Equation 1 and utilized throughout our subsequent analysis. Not only does this procedure allow use to remove the influence of age and target age, but it also allows more precision in identifying trait optimism. Averaged over a number of periods, the noise in the optimism measure will be diminished though not completely eliminated. 1 Columns 1 and 2 of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table S2</ref> in the Supplemental Material reports the respective male and female estimates of Equation 1 (see columns 3 and 4 of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table S2</ref> for the respective male and female estimates of Equation 1, where optimism is constructed from the static target age task). As was illustrated in both Panel A and B of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>, optimism increases for older target ages (i.e., when the actuarial probabilities are lower).</p><p>To estimate the interspousal correlation between spouses, using ordinary least squares (OLS) and one observation per couple, we regress the trait unrealistic optimism of the male partner on that of the female partner for all cohabiting married and non-married couples as displayed in Equation 2. When measuring the degree of spousal concordance on unrealistic optimism, using age and sex specific actuarial life tables helps to account for exogenous differences that exist within-couples in the same household. However, it still leaves our</p><p>unrealistic optimism measures open to many potential alternative interpretations. Most prominent, interspousal correlations may be attenuated by within-couple differences in other life span-influencing factors (i.e., lifestyle factors, objective health or differences in genetic longevity). This concern is only partially mitigated by the literature reporting that couples share lifestyles that promote longevity or assortatively mate around life span-influencing factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Guner, Kulikova &amp; Llull, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Rawlik, Canela-Xandri &amp; Tenesa, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Ruby et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Fortunately, ELSA does provide information on various life span-influencing factors. If spousal concordance on optimism is attenuated by differences in these life span-influencing factors characteristics between spouses, spousal concordance should increase if we restrict the correlation to the set of couples in which both spouses share these life span-influencing factors.</p><p>Alternatively, we can control for within-couple level differences in these factors,</p><p>− . This is the approach we take. Specifically, we include within-couple differences for smoker status and alcohol consumption; mother's/father's age when she/he died setting the value to the oldest age reported in the panel of the respondent's mother/father for those whose mother/father remained alive throughout the panel (and including a binary variable for whether respondent's mother/father remained alive throughout the panel); and controls for chronic illnesses and medical condition's described in more detail in the <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> caption.</p><p>Further, to test whether interspousal correlations in unrealistic optimism are a product of social homogamy-that is, to identify the interspousal correlations between unrealistic optimism only-we follow Dohmen, Falk, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Huffman and Sunde (2012)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Arrondel and Frémeaux (2016)</ref> and control for the relevant observable characteristics of both members of each couple, and . Specifically, we control for date of birth; ethnicity;</p><p>religion; university/college degree; the number of dependent children in the household; economic activity; annual labour market income; annual household total income (the sum of employment income, state and private benefit income, asset income and other income); net total household wealth (the sum of savings, investments, physical wealth and housing wealth after financial debt and mortgage debt has been subtracted); mother and fathers education; main carer's main occupation when respondent was 14; self-assessed general health; and region of residence.</p><p>Where our control variables vary within-individual across the Waves (i.e., alcohol consumption, economic activity, annual labour market income, self-assessed general health),</p><p>we use individual Wave-averaged measures. Also, some of the social homogamy controls are measured at the couple level (i.e., the number of dependent children in the household, annual household total income, net total household wealth, region of residence), where these controls vary within-couple across the Waves, we use couple Wave-averaged measures. In some additional tests, we also analyse whether our unrealistic optimism measures are proxies for the personality constructs studied in psychology. This is important as spousal concordance on unrealistic optimism may simply reflect previous empirical findings regarding spousal concordance on Big Five personality factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Jessica &amp; Lee, 2023)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">= + + ∑ − + ∑ + ∑ +<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Last, but not least, a crucial question is to determine whether the similarity between spouses is the result of matching or due to the convergence of preferences. That is, whether couples may become more similar over time. This could be achieved via persuasion or imitation, or simply because spouses tend to share the same experiences over time which eliminates any initial discordance. For this we rely on data for a subsample of couples, where length of cohabitation data is available. Using the mean reported cohabitation length for each couple, ℎ , we estimate whether interspousal correlations of unrealistic optimism are affected by cohabitation length by estimating the following equation via OLS regression:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">= + + ℎ + ( ℎ × ) +<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where measures the interspousal correlation when the length of cohabitation is zero and measures the extent to which the interspousal correlation differs by the level of cohabitation length. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table S1</ref> in the Supplemental Material presents an overview of the sample characteristic of our analytic samples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Validating optimism</head><p>Prior to our analysis of interspousal correlations in unrealistic optimism, we investigate whether our measure of survival optimism generalizes to other types of expectations. To do this, we compare our optimism measure to the survey respondent's assessment of future economic conditions. Specifically, respondents are asked in every Wave "What are the chances that the value of your house will [text fill] over the next year?" Respondents are randomly allocated a "text fill" of "increase" or "decrease", "5" or "10"%. We perform fractional probit models in which the dependent variable is the respondent's subjective probability assessment of house values for each possible random allocation. Results are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>, and the  Notes: Main entries are semi-elasticities, that is, a % change in the dependent variable from a one-unit change in the independent variable. t-statistics using clustered standard errors by the individual in brackets. Panel A (B) uses the standardized optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. All regressions include controls for age (in cubic form); sex; ethnicity; marital status; university/college degree; the number of children in the household; economic activity; annual labour market income; annual household total income (the sum of employment income, state and private benefit income, asset income and other income); net total household wealth (the sum of savings, investments, physical wealth and housing wealth after financial debt and mortgage debt has been subtracted); smoking and alcohol consumption; self-assessed general health; mother's/father's age when she/he died setting the value to the oldest age reported in the panel of the respondent's mother/father for those whose mother/father remained alive throughout the panel (and including a binary variable for whether respondent's mother/father remained alive throughout the panel); binary variables for the presence of each of the following illnesses: chronic lung disease such as chronic bronchitis or emphysema; asthma; arthritis (including osteoarthritis, or rheumatism); osteoporosis, sometimes called thin or brittle bones; cancer or a malignant tumour (excluding minor skin cancers); Parkinson's disease; any emotional, nervous or psychiatric problems; Alzheimer's disease; dementia, organic brain syndrome, senility or any other serious memory impairment; and binary variables for the presence of each of the following conditions: high blood pressure or hypertension; angina; a heart attack (including myocardial infarction or coronary thrombosis); congestive heart failure; a heart murmur; an abnormal heart rhythm; diabetes or high blood sugar; a stroke (cerebral vascular disease); high cholesterol; and a series of binary variables for survey wave and region of residence. Panel A also includes controls for target age. Significance levels *** 1%,** 5%, * 10%.</p><p>Maintaining beliefs that are inconsistent with the rational processing of objective data requires the psychological mechanics of motivated reasoning. These psychological mechanisms include selective recall, where past successes are recollected with more ease than failures <ref type="bibr">(Benabou &amp; Tirole, 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Histed, Pasupathy &amp; Miller, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Huffman, Raymond &amp; Shvets, 2022)</ref>; asymmetric or optimistic belief updating, whereby good news receives more weight than bad news <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Garrett &amp; Sharot, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Sharot, Korn &amp; Dolan, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Zimmermann, 2020)</ref>; or indeed, by attributional style-attributing past successes to one's own skill, whilst attributing failures to bad luck <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Langer &amp; Roth, 1975)</ref>. In this view, as a further test we investigate whether those with high survival optimism are more prone to motivated reasoning.</p><p>To do this, we compare our optimism measure to respondents' perceptions of memory compared to two years ago, whilst controlling for current and past objective performance in a word recall task.</p><p>Respondents are asked in Waves 2, 3, 4, 7, 8 and 9 "Compared to two years ago, would you say your memory is better now, about the same, or worse now than it was then?" In all</p><p>Waves of data, ELSA also assessed respondents' memory, using an immediate and delayed word recall task. Specifically, participants were read a series of 10 words and immediately afterwards were asked to recall as many words as possible, in any order. Participants were then asked again, later in the interview, to recall as many words as possible. Scores form the immediate and delayed word recall task were summed together to produce a single measure, which we refer to as `Word Recall'. In <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> we report the estimates from ordered probit models in which the dependent variable is the respondent's subjective assessment of memory compared to two years ago. We use the same controls as described in the caption of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>As in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>, Panel A (B) of <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> reports the estimates from our optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. Whilst optimists will tend to have overly positive memories of past performance, maintenance of the optimism bubble requires the biased information processing that overwhelmingly favors welcome information over unwelcome information. Optimists will therefore be the most (least) likely to reason that they have experienced improvements (declines) in their memory. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> confirms this hypothesis. Notes: Main entries are marginal effects, that is, a change in the probability of the dependent variable from a oneunit change in the independent variable. t-statistics using clustered standard errors by the individual in brackets. Panel A (B) uses the standardized trait optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. All regressions include the full set of controls described in the <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> caption. Significance levels *** 1%,** 5%, * 10%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assortative mating of spouses</head><p>We now turn our attention to measure the degree of assortative mating on bias. That is, estimating Equation 2. We consider Equation 2 across nested models. In Model 1, we estimated the spousal correlation of bias without any control variables. In Model 2, we add controls for lifestyle factors, objective health and differences in genetic longevity for both members of each couple. Finally, in Model 3, we add social homogamy controls for both members of each couple as identified in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Dohmen, Falk, Huffman and Sunde (2012)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Arrondel and Frémeaux (2016)</ref>.</p><p>We use standardized versions of the trait optimism measures, where standardization is conducted separately for males and females.  &lt;0.001*** Column 2 = Column 3 a &lt;0.001***</p><p>Notes: Main entries are marginal effects, t-statistics using robust standard errors in brackets. Panel A (B) uses the standardized trait optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. Within-couple differences in longevity controls include within-couple differences for smoking and alcohol consumption; mother's/father's age when she/he died setting the value to the oldest age reported in the panel of the respondent's mother/father for those whose mother/father remained alive throughout the panel (and including a binary variable for whether respondent's mother/father remained alive throughout the panel); binary variables for the presence of each of the following illnesses: chronic lung disease such as chronic bronchitis or emphysema; asthma; arthritis (including osteoarthritis, or rheumatism); osteoporosis, sometimes called thin or brittle bones; cancer or a malignant tumour (excluding minor skin cancers); Parkinson's disease; any emotional, nervous or psychiatric problems; Alzheimer's disease; dementia, organic brain syndrome, senility or any other serious memory impairment; and binary variables for the presence of each of the following conditions: high blood pressure or hypertension; angina; a heart attack (including myocardial infarction or coronary thrombosis); congestive heart failure; a heart murmur; an abnormal heart rhythm; diabetes or high blood sugar; a stroke (cerebral vascular disease); and high cholesterol. Social homogamy controls include for each member of the couple: date of birth; ethnicity; religion; university/college degree; the number of dependent children in the household; economic activity; annual labour market income; annual household total income (the sum of employment income, state and private benefit income, asset income and other income); net total household wealth (the sum of savings, investments, physical wealth and housing wealth after financial debt and mortgage debt has been subtracted); mother and fathers education; main carer's main occupation when respondent was 14; self-assessed general health; and region of residence. Where the control variables vary within individual across the Waves (i.e., alcohol consumption, economic activity, annual labour market income, self-assessed general health) we use individual Wave-averaged measures. Also, some of the social homogamy controls are measured at the couple level (i.e., the number of dependent children in the household, annual household total income, net total household wealth, region of residence), where these controls vary within-couple across the Waves, we use couple Wave-averaged measures. a This reports the p-value of the Wald test that the 'Female partner trait optimism' coefficient is equal across the nested models. Significance levels *** 1%,** 5%, * 10%.</p><p>We begin by discussing the spousal correlations of bias without controls, as reported in Column 1. Spousal correlations for unrealistic optimism are 0.194 (0.201) in Panel A (B), suggesting moderate correlation of spouses on bias. In Column 2 we included the within-couple differences on the factors that may objectively affect longevity. Spousal correlation for unrealistic optimism increased only slightly in magnitude, from 0.194 to .220 (0.201 to 0.229)</p><p>in Panel A (B). These differences although small in magnitude are statistically significant, &lt; 0.001, and reflect that controlling for factors that objectively will contribute to differences in expectations within-couples, allows us to measure spousal concordance on bias with more precision.</p><p>To In Column 3 we included controls for social homogamy. The spousal correlations fall slightly in magnitude, from 0.220 to .172 (0.229 to 0.158) in Panel A (B), with the differences being statistically significant, &lt; 0.001. However, the size of the effect is much less than would be expected if spousal concordance was due to social homogamy. In this case, our spousal correlations should drop to near zero. However, our spousal correlations remain significantly greater than zero even when spouses come from the same groups, suggesting the correlation is not a by-product of the pool of likely mates but is instead the result of active selection.</p><p>Assortative mating of spouses on scale use. Spikes at focal points of 0, 0.5 and 1 are common in subjective probability data (d <ref type="bibr">'Uva, O'Donnell &amp; Van Doorslaer, 2020)</ref>. The spousal correlations on bias, may therefore not reflect concordance on bias but by patterns of scale use being shared by partners <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Dohmen, Falk, Huffman &amp; Sunde, 2012)</ref>. In this view, as a robustness check, we repeat the analysis above but include a further set of controls, for both members of each couple, that capture the use of focal points. Specifically, focal point controls are the average usage of each of the focal points 0, 0.5 and 1. The results of this procedure are reported in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table S3</ref> of the Supplemental Material and indicate that our results are not driven by a similar tendency of spouses to choose focal point of the subjective survival probability scales.</p><p>Optimism versus personality. Spousal concordance in personality type has been frequently documented by psychologists. A further question is whether our unrealistic optimism measures are proxies for the personality constructs studied in psychology. In which case, spousal concordance on unrealistic optimism is a by-product of spousal concordance on personality. To test this proposition, we use data on the Big Five personality traits-Extraversion, Agreeableness, Conscientiousness, Neuroticism and Openness to experience-which were assessed at Wave 5 using a version of the Midlife Development Inventory, which has previously used in the US Health and Retirement Survey <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Lachman &amp; Weaver, 1997)</ref>. This reduces our sample of couples from 4699 to 2327 (3163 to 1777) when using the optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. We find positive assortative mating in the Big Five personality traits, ranging from correlations of 0.09 for Neuroticism to 0.203 for Openness (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table S2</ref> of the Supplemental Material). This is in the typically range found in the psychology literature. Optimism is also positively correlated with the Big Five personality traits, for Extraversion, Agreeableness, Conscientiousness and Openness, and negatively correlated with Neuroticism (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table S4</ref> of the Supplemental Material). These correlations are consistent with the research on dispositional optimism and personality <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Sharpe, Martin &amp; Roth, 2011)</ref>. For the new analytic samples, we repeat our spousal concordance analysis whilst additionally controlling for the personality traits of each member of the couple.</p><p>Importantly, the spousal correlations for optimism are essentially unchanged compared to when personality traits are omitted (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table S5</ref> of the Supplemental Material).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spousal optimism concordance and length of cohabitation.</head><p>In Wave 3 of ELSA, respondents are asked to complete an additional Life History module, that asked questions pertaining to each cohabiting partner the respondent listed in their lifetime, up to 10 relationships. These questions included year started living together, marital status, whether divorced, and year relationship ended. From the Life History module, we create the average length in years of the respondent's current cohabitation spell, for cohabiting married and non-married couples. This reduces our sample of couples from 4699 to 2440 (3163 to 1658) when using the optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. For plotted distributions of length of cohabitation spell for our analytic samples, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S1</ref> of the Supplemental Material. As the data source are from a representative sample of the population over age 50, the average length of cohabitation is higher than might be optimal to test whether partners become more similar over time, although we do have substantial between couple variation. For instance, the mean cohabitation length is 37 (33.24) years, with a standard deviation of 12.35 (9.90) when using the trait optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. To estimate the interspousal correlation between spouses, we regress the trait unrealistic optimism of the male partner on that of the female partner and an interaction term of the mean cohabitation length of the couple, as displayed in Equation 3. The results are displayed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table   5</ref>. As we include an interaction term, the coefficient on female partner trait optimism measures the interspousal correlation when the length of cohabitation is zero. In addition, the interaction term measures the extent to which the interspousal correlation differs by the level of cohabitation length. The general finding is that the optimism of spouses is about as similar when they first cohabit as when they have cohabited for decades. This provides further evidence of phenotypic assortative mating on bias, rather than the convergence on optimism caused by the shared environment of mate pairs or indeed the influence on each other after mate choice has already taken place. Notes: Main entries are marginal effects, that is, a change in the probability of the dependent variable from a oneunit change in the independent variable. t-statistics using clustered standard errors by the individual in brackets. Panel A (B) uses the standardized trait optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. For a full description of the controls see the <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> caption. Significance levels *** 1%,** 5%, * 10%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Most decisions with far-reaching implications are made by groups rather than by individuals.</p><p>For instance, couples in most European countries are the dominant category of economic decision units. More than this, in many day-to-day life contexts such as savings, investments in the stock markets, and insurance and retirement provisions, the decisions have consequences for the household and as such should be decided upon jointly. Whilst an extensive literature has documented how cognitive biases are an important dimension of such decisions-since the turn of the millennium, over 4,000 articles have been published on cognitive biases-as far as we are aware, no previous research has assessed the extent to which biases are concentrated in households. This is an important omission, and this article is a starting point to address this gap in the literature.</p><p>We provide evidence from a nationally representative longitudinal survey, that unrealistic optimism, one of the most established psychological "biases", is to some extent concentrated in household. We do this in the context of bias in subjective survival expectations, which like all beliefs, are fundamental to key household economic decisions such as savings <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Salm, 2010)</ref>, retirement <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Hurd, Smith &amp; Zissimopoulos, 2004)</ref>, annuity consumption <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Inkmann, Lopes &amp; Michaelides, 2011)</ref> and portfolio choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Puri and Robinson, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Spaenjers &amp; Spira, 2015)</ref>. The magnitude of spousal concordance on bias is in line with the evidence of positive assortative mating in personality research, and that these spousal similarities appear to be driven by direct selection on bias rather than social homogamy or indeed partner convergence.</p><p>Our results therefore suggest, consistent with most empirical work, that humans do not use an "opposites-attracts" decision rule in mating choice. Indeed, our findings are consistent with the active positive assortative mating, described as "likes-attract" <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Buston &amp; Emlen, 2003)</ref> and the attitude transmission models, where people have a preference to have children with similar traits to their own which creates an incentive to look for partners with similar traits. In the case of the transmission model there are therefore intergenerational consequences, as the pairing of similar people will increase the proportion of homozygous progeny <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Robinson et al., 2017</ref>) which could perhaps contribute to the strong persistence in economic outcomes across generations <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Modalsli, 2023)</ref>.</p><p>The question of whether and to what extent judgemental biases are concentrated within couples, also establishes may avenues for future research. For instance, in studying collective models of decision-making-whereby the choices of individuals are influenced by its interaction with the group-to understand how household similarities or differences in bias affect household wealth and portfolio choice. In this respect, whilst group decisions are closer to risk-neutrality than individual decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(He, Martinsson, Sutter, 2012)</ref> research has shown that groups with homogeneous opinions and beliefs have the greatest tendency toward biased decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Schulz-Hardt, Frey, Lüthgens &amp; Moscovici, 2000)</ref>. Notes: Panel A (B) is for the sample where the standardized trait optimism measure is computed from the variable (static) target age task. Annual household total income is the sum of employment income, state and private benefit income, asset income and other income. Net total household wealth is the sum of savings, investments, physical wealth and housing wealth after financial debt and mortgage debt has been subtracted. Mother's/father's age when she/he died sets the value to the oldest age reported in the panel of the respondent's mother/father for those whose mother/father remained alive throughout the panel. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SUPPLEMENTAL MATERIAL</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>A</head><label></label><figDesc>of Figure 1 plots the relationship for men focusing on the variable target age task. The result of the regression indicates that raising actuarial life expectancy by one percent raises subjective survival probabilities by 0.47 percent ( = 0.47, 95% CI = [0.44, 0.49], = 33.99, &lt; 0.001). For women, as depicted in Panel B, the relationship is almost identical ( = 0.47, 95% CI = [0.44, 0.50], = 29.13, &lt; 0.001). In both Panel A and B, optimism increases for older target ages (i.e., when the actuarial probabilities are lower). As with previous studies, subjective survival probabilities are generally pessimistic and females ( = −10.37)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>The relationship between subjective survival probabilities and actuarial life expectancy.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>put these correlations in perspective, personality traits, such as Openness, have demonstrated slight tendencies toward mate concordance ( = 0.12; Botwin, Buss &amp; Shackelford, 1997) whilst Extraversion, Neuroticism and impulsivity produce interspousal correlations of less than .10 (Alford, Hatemi, Hibbing, Martin &amp; Eaves, 2011; Botwin, Buss &amp; Shackelford, 1997). Similar in magnitude are the estimates of spousal concordance on weight ( = 0.12; Allison et al., 1996). Whilst higher level of spousal concordance has been found when assessing dimensions of sensation seeking (0.25 ≤ ≤ 0.29; Glicksohn &amp; Golan, 2001), height ( = 0.23; Stulp, Simons, Grasman &amp; Pollet, 2017), economic preferences (0.20 ≤ ≤ 0.30; Arrondel &amp; Frémeaux, 2016) and emotional intelligence ( = 0.27; Śmieja &amp; Stolarski, 2018).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Target age depending on the age of the respondent.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Age of respondent</cell><cell>Target age ( )</cell><cell>Number of</cell><cell>Number of</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>observations</cell><cell>individuals</cell></row><row><cell>Panel A</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>50-65</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>24803</cell><cell>7068</cell></row><row><cell>66-69</cell><cell>80</cell><cell>6085</cell><cell>3723</cell></row><row><cell>70-74</cell><cell>85</cell><cell>6092</cell><cell>3250</cell></row><row><cell>75-79</cell><cell>90</cell><cell>3954</cell><cell>2122</cell></row><row><cell>80-84</cell><cell>95</cell><cell>2022</cell><cell>1156</cell></row><row><cell>85-99</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>624</cell><cell>392</cell></row><row><cell>100-104</cell><cell>105</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>105-109</cell><cell>110</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>110-119</cell><cell>120</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell></cell><cell>43580</cell><cell>9398</cell></row><row><cell>Panel B</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>50-69</cell><cell>85</cell><cell>20622</cell><cell>6326</cell></row><row><cell>To measure</cell><cell cols="3">we utilize the past and projected numbers surviving at exact age from</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">the 2020-based (United Kingdom) life tables obtained from the Office of National Statistics</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">(ONS). These tables give historic and projected life expectancies by single year of age and sex</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">for each year 1981 to 2070. To construct the objective probabilities, as well as using age and</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">sex specific data, we also control for projected changes in mortality throughout a person's life.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>caption describes the control variables employed to equalize differences across individuals. Panel A (B) of Table 2 presents the estimates from our optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. The results indicates that our measure of optimism correlates to generalized expectations, even after we control for a barrage of controls.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fractional probit regressions measuring the relationship between optimism and house price expectations. Dependent variable: Probability that the value of your house will [increase or decrease] by [5% or 10%] over the next year</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Increase 5% Increase 10% Decrease 5%</cell><cell>Decrease 10%</cell></row><row><cell>Panel A</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Optimism</cell><cell>0.030***</cell><cell>0.022***</cell><cell>-0.011***</cell><cell>-0.008**</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[7.598]</cell><cell>[5.747]</cell><cell>[-2.693]</cell><cell>[-2.146]</cell></row><row><cell>Number of observations</cell><cell>9679</cell><cell>9647</cell><cell>9791</cell><cell>9569</cell></row><row><cell>Number of individuals</cell><cell>5570</cell><cell>5500</cell><cell>5567</cell><cell>5558</cell></row><row><cell>Mean dependent variable</cell><cell>.38</cell><cell>.282</cell><cell>.35</cell><cell>.303</cell></row><row><cell>Panel B</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Optimism</cell><cell>0.028***</cell><cell>0.013***</cell><cell>-0.012**</cell><cell>-0.012***</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[5.983]</cell><cell>[3.137]</cell><cell>[-2.512]</cell><cell>[-2.646]</cell></row><row><cell>Number of observations</cell><cell>4656</cell><cell>4535</cell><cell>4621</cell><cell>4599</cell></row><row><cell>Number of individuals</cell><cell>3123</cell><cell>3076</cell><cell>3145</cell><cell>3138</cell></row><row><cell>Mean dependent variable</cell><cell>.334</cell><cell>.234</cell><cell>.381</cell><cell>.33</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Ordered probit regressions measuring the relationship between optimism and perception of memory.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Dependent variable: Perception of memory compared to two years ago</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Worse</cell><cell>About the same</cell><cell>Better</cell></row><row><cell>Panel A</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Optimism</cell><cell>-0.029***</cell><cell>0.027***</cell><cell>0.002***</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-6.519]</cell><cell>[6.518]</cell><cell>[5.972]</cell></row><row><cell>Word recall score</cell><cell>-0.002*</cell><cell>0.002*</cell><cell>0.000*</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-1.727]</cell><cell>[1.726]</cell><cell>[1.723]</cell></row><row><cell>Lagged word recall score</cell><cell>-0.001</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-1.284]</cell><cell>[1.283]</cell><cell>[1.288]</cell></row><row><cell>Number of observations</cell><cell>24633</cell><cell>24633</cell><cell>24633</cell></row><row><cell>Number of individuals</cell><cell>7766</cell><cell>7766</cell><cell>7766</cell></row><row><cell>Mean dependent variable</cell><cell>.362</cell><cell>.629</cell><cell>.009</cell></row><row><cell>Panel B</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Optimism</cell><cell>-0.029***</cell><cell>0.026***</cell><cell>0.002***</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-5.345]</cell><cell>[5.335]</cell><cell>[4.880]</cell></row><row><cell>Word recall score</cell><cell>-0.004**</cell><cell>0.003**</cell><cell>0.000**</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-2.268]</cell><cell>[2.268]</cell><cell>[2.217]</cell></row><row><cell>Lagged word recall score</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>-0.001</cell><cell>-0.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[0.532]</cell><cell>[-0.533]</cell><cell>[-0.530]</cell></row><row><cell>Number of observations</cell><cell>11075</cell><cell>11075</cell><cell>11075</cell></row><row><cell>Number of individuals</cell><cell>4690</cell><cell>4690</cell><cell>4690</cell></row><row><cell>Mean dependent variable</cell><cell>.331</cell><cell>.659</cell><cell>.01</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>reports the main findings. Estimates are from OLS regressions, using one observation per couple. As before, Panel A (B) reports the estimates from our optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>OLS regressions measuring spousal concordance on trait optimism.</figDesc><table><row><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>OLS regressions measuring spousal concordance on trait optimism by length of</figDesc><table><row><cell>cohabitation period.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell></row><row><cell>Dependent variable:</cell><cell>Male trait</cell><cell>Male trait</cell><cell>Male trait</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>optimism</cell><cell>optimism</cell><cell>optimism</cell></row><row><cell>Panel A</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Female partner trait optimism</cell><cell>0.251***</cell><cell>0.297***</cell><cell>0.218***</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[4.101]</cell><cell>[4.940]</cell><cell>[3.687]</cell></row><row><cell>Mean cohabitation length</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.003*</cell><cell>0.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[1.495]</cell><cell>[1.819]</cell><cell>[0.068]</cell></row><row><cell>Female partner trait optimism × Mean</cell><cell>-0.002</cell><cell>-0.003*</cell><cell>-0.002</cell></row><row><cell>cohabitation length</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-1.602]</cell><cell>[-1.808]</cell><cell>[-1.225]</cell></row><row><cell>R-squared</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.089</cell><cell>0.238</cell></row><row><cell>Number of couples</cell><cell>2440</cell><cell>2440</cell><cell>2440</cell></row><row><cell>Within-couple differences in longevity controls</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>Social homogamy controls</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>Column 1 = Column 2 a</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.225</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Column 2 = Column 3 a</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.014**</cell></row><row><cell>Panel B</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Female partner trait optimism</cell><cell>0.241***</cell><cell>0.290***</cell><cell>0.219**</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[2.941]</cell><cell>[3.545]</cell><cell>[2.578]</cell></row><row><cell>Mean cohabitation length</cell><cell>0.003</cell><cell>0.005*</cell><cell>-0.001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[1.401]</cell><cell>[1.920]</cell><cell>[-0.319]</cell></row><row><cell>Female partner trait optimism × Mean</cell><cell>-0.001</cell><cell>-0.002</cell><cell>-0.002</cell></row><row><cell>cohabitation length</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-0.473]</cell><cell>[-0.719]</cell><cell>[-0.711]</cell></row><row><cell>R-squared</cell><cell>0.041</cell><cell>0.098</cell><cell>0.241</cell></row><row><cell>Number of couples</cell><cell>1658</cell><cell>1658</cell><cell>1658</cell></row><row><cell>Within-couple differences in longevity controls</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>Social homogamy controls</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>Column 1 = Column 2 a</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.390</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Column 2 = Column 3 a</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.149</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table S1 .</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Descriptive statistics.</figDesc><table><row><cell>at 18 Stroke</cell><cell>0.02 0.08</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.02 0.05</cell><cell>0.02 0.04</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.03 0.03</cell></row><row><cell>19 or over Cholesterol</cell><cell>0.02 0.49</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.03 0.45</cell><cell>0.03 0.47</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.04 0.40</cell></row><row><cell>Main carer's main occupation when Lung disease</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.05</cell></row><row><cell>respondent was 14: Asthma</cell><cell>0.14</cell><cell cols="2">Panel A</cell><cell>0.17</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell cols="2">Panel B</cell><cell>0.16</cell></row><row><cell>Armed Forces Arthritis</cell><cell>Male 0.03 0.40</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Female 0.02 0.51</cell><cell cols="2">Male 0.02 0.35</cell><cell>Female 0.02 0.44</cell></row><row><cell>Manager or senior official Osteoporosis</cell><cell>Mean/ 0.05 0.04</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Mean/ 0.06 0.16</cell><cell cols="2">Mean/ 0.06 0.03</cell><cell>Mean/ 0.07 0.12</cell></row><row><cell>Running own business Cancer</cell><cell cols="2">frequency 0.07 0.16</cell><cell cols="2">frequency 0.08 0.14</cell><cell cols="2">frequency 0.07 0.11</cell><cell>frequency 0.08 0.13</cell></row><row><cell>Subjective survival probabilities Professional or technical Parkinson's disease</cell><cell>58.89 0.15 0.02</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>64.44 0.16 0.01</cell><cell cols="2">49.56 0.17 0.01</cell><cell>55.80 0.18 0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Actuarial probabilities Administrative, clerical or secretarial Psychiatric disorder</cell><cell>62.54 0.07 0.10</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>74.81 0.07 0.16</cell><cell cols="2">48.65 0.07 0.12</cell><cell>60.09 0.07 0.17</cell></row><row><cell>Optimism Skilled trade Alzheimer's disease</cell><cell>-3.65 0.28 0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-10.37 0.27 0.01</cell><cell>0.91 0.27 0.00</cell><cell></cell><cell>-4.30 0.26 0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Age Caring, leisure, travel or personal Dementia or memory impairment</cell><cell>65.65 0.03</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>62.95 0.02</cell><cell cols="2">60.71 0.01</cell><cell>58.43 0.01</cell></row><row><cell>Date of birth services Number of observations</cell><cell cols="2">1943.90 0.02 21790</cell><cell cols="2">1946.60 0.02 21790</cell><cell cols="2">1950.35 0.02 10311</cell><cell>1952.63 0.01 10311</cell></row><row><cell>Target age: 75 Sales or customer service Number of individuals</cell><cell>0.52 0.03 4699</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.62 0.03 4699</cell><cell>0.04 3163</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.02 3163</cell></row><row><cell>Target age: 80 Plant, process or machine drivers</cell><cell>0.15 0.09</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.13 0.08</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.09</cell></row><row><cell>Target age: 85 Other jobs</cell><cell>0.15 0.13</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.13 0.13</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.12</cell></row><row><cell>Target age: 90 Something else</cell><cell>0.10 0.04</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.08 0.04</cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.04</cell></row><row><cell>Target age: 95 Casual jobs</cell><cell>0.06 0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.04 0.01</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>Target age: 100 Retired</cell><cell>0.02 0.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.01 0.01</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>Ethnicity: white Unemployed</cell><cell>0.98 0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.98 0.01</cell><cell>0.97 0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.97 0.01</cell></row><row><cell>Religion: religious Sick / disabled</cell><cell>0.63 0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.71 0.01</cell><cell>0.63 0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.74 0.01</cell></row><row><cell>Religion: no religion Self-assessed general health:</cell><cell>0.21</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell>0.27</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.17</cell></row><row><cell>Religion: missing Excellent</cell><cell>0.16 0.15</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.15 0.17</cell><cell>0.09 0.19</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.09 0.20</cell></row><row><cell>Married Very good</cell><cell>0.95 0.33</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.95 0.34</cell><cell>0.93 0.36</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.93 0.37</cell></row><row><cell>University/college degree Good</cell><cell>0.26 0.32</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.18 0.31</cell><cell>0.30 0.29</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.24 0.29</cell></row><row><cell>Employee Fair</cell><cell>0.29 0.15</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.32 0.14</cell><cell>0.44 0.12</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.47 0.11</cell></row><row><cell>Self-employed Poor</cell><cell>0.10 0.05</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.05 0.04</cell><cell>0.15 0.04</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.07 0.03</cell></row><row><cell>Retired Smoking and alcohol consumption:</cell><cell>0.54</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.46</cell><cell>0.35</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.30</cell></row><row><cell>Unemployed Current smoker</cell><cell>0.01 0.11</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.00 0.11</cell><cell>0.01 0.12</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.01 0.12</cell></row><row><cell>Long-term sick Drinking: almost every day</cell><cell>0.03 0.20</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.03 0.13</cell><cell>0.04 0.18</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.03 0.12</cell></row><row><cell>Other Drinking: five or six days a week</cell><cell>0.02 0.08</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.14 0.06</cell><cell>0.02 0.09</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.13 0.06</cell></row><row><cell>Annual labour market income Drinking: three or four days a week</cell><cell cols="2">8537.56 0.17</cell><cell cols="2">4959.44 0.13</cell><cell cols="2">13183.02 0.20</cell><cell>7726.16 0.15</cell></row><row><cell>Number of children in household Drinking: once or twice a week</cell><cell>0.10 0.28</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.10 0.25</cell><cell>0.14 0.28</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.14 0.27</cell></row><row><cell>Annual household total income Drinking: once or twice a month</cell><cell cols="2">31581.35 0.10</cell><cell cols="2">31581.35 0.12</cell><cell cols="2">36415.33 0.10</cell><cell>36415.33 0.13</cell></row><row><cell>Net total household wealth Drinking: once every couple of months</cell><cell cols="2">416123.29 0.05</cell><cell cols="5">416123.29 463011.33 463011.33 0.08 0.05 0.08</cell></row><row><cell>Father finished education: Drinking: once or twice a year</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.09</cell></row><row><cell>Missing Drinking: not at all in the last 12</cell><cell>0.16</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.17</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.08</cell></row><row><cell>Never went to school months</cell><cell>0.00 0.07</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.00 0.12</cell><cell>0.00 0.06</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.00 0.11</cell></row><row><cell>14 or under Parental longevity and objective</cell><cell>0.53</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.51</cell><cell>0.53</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.50</cell></row><row><cell>at 15 health:</cell><cell>0.15</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.16</cell><cell>0.20</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.21</cell></row><row><cell>at 16 Father alive</cell><cell>0.07 0.05</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.07 0.07</cell><cell>0.09 0.08</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.09 0.11</cell></row><row><cell>at 17 Mother alive</cell><cell>0.02 0.10</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.03 0.15</cell><cell>0.03 0.18</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.04 0.24</cell></row><row><cell>at 18 Father's age when he died</cell><cell>0.02 73.38</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.02 73.52</cell><cell cols="2">0.02 74.26</cell><cell>0.03 74.40</cell></row><row><cell>19 or over Mother's age when she died</cell><cell>0.04 78.70</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.04 78.78</cell><cell cols="2">0.05 79.15</cell><cell>0.05 79.01</cell></row><row><cell>Mother finished education: High blood pressure</cell><cell>0.52</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.38</cell></row><row><cell>Missing Angina</cell><cell>0.16 0.11</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.16 0.06</cell><cell>0.08 0.07</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.08 0.03</cell></row><row><cell>Never went to school Heart attack</cell><cell>0.01 0.10</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.01 0.03</cell><cell>0.01 0.07</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.01 0.02</cell></row><row><cell>14 or under Congestive heart failure</cell><cell>0.52 0.02</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.50 0.01</cell><cell>0.49 0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.48 0.01</cell></row><row><cell>at 15 Heart murmur</cell><cell>0.17 0.07</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.17 0.08</cell><cell>0.24 0.05</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.22 0.06</cell></row><row><cell>at 16 Arrhythmia</cell><cell>0.07 0.18</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.08 0.14</cell><cell>0.10 0.14</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.11 0.10</cell></row><row><cell>at 17 Diabetes</cell><cell>0.02 0.18</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.03 0.11</cell><cell>0.03 0.16</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.04 0.10</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table S2 .</head><label>S2</label><figDesc>Linear fixed-effect regressions to elicit trait optimism.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Panel A</cell><cell cols="2">Panel B</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell>(4)</cell></row><row><cell>Dependent variables:</cell><cell>Optimism</cell><cell>Optimism</cell><cell>Optimism</cell><cell>Optimism</cell></row><row><cell>Predictors</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>Female</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">The Cronbach's alpha, which measures the level of internal reliability of optimism across Waves is 0.9 for men and 0.88 for women, which suggests high reliability. To calculate the Cronbach's alpha, we use optimism scores that are residualized on age (in cubic form), target age and Wave. Similarly. to calculate the Cronbach's alpha for optimism using the static target age task, we use optimism scores that are residualized on age (in cubic form) and Wave. Here, Cronbach's alpha is 0.9 for men and 0.89 for women.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Notes: Panel A (B) is for the sample where the standardized trait optimism measure is computed from the variable (static) target age task. Panel A (B) is based on a single estimate per couple, = 2,440 ( = 1,658). A normal density is also plotted in each graph, with the same mean and variance as the estimated data.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> <ref type="table">Table S3</ref><p>. OLS regressions measuring spousal concordance on trait optimism.</p><p>(1) &lt;0.001*** Column 2 = Column 3 a &lt;0.001*** Notes: Main entries are marginal effects, t-statistics using robust standard errors in brackets. Panel A (B) uses the standardized trait optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. Focal point controls are the average usage of each of the focal points 0, 0.5 and 1 for each member of the couple. Within-couple differences in longevity controls include within-couple differences for smoking and alcohol consumption; mother's/father's age when she/he died setting the value to the oldest age reported in the panel of the respondent's mother/father for those whose mother/father remained alive throughout the panel (and including a binary variable for whether respondent's mother/father remained alive throughout the panel); binary variables for the presence of each of the following illnesses: chronic lung disease such as chronic bronchitis or emphysema; asthma; arthritis (including osteoarthritis, or rheumatism); osteoporosis, sometimes called thin or brittle bones; cancer or a malignant tumour (excluding minor skin cancers); Parkinson's disease; any emotional, nervous or psychiatric problems; Alzheimer's disease; dementia, organic brain syndrome, senility or any other serious memory impairment; and binary variables for the presence of each of the following conditions: high blood pressure or hypertension; angina; a heart attack (including myocardial infarction or coronary thrombosis); congestive heart failure; a heart murmur; an abnormal heart rhythm; diabetes or high blood sugar; a stroke (cerebral vascular disease); and high cholesterol. Social homogamy controls include for each member of the couple: date of birth; ethnicity; religion; university/college degree; the number of dependent children in the household; economic activity; annual labour market income; annual household total income (the sum of employment income, state and private benefit income, asset income and other income); net total household wealth (the sum of savings, investments, physical wealth and housing wealth after financial debt and mortgage debt has been subtracted); mother and fathers education; main carer's main occupation when respondent was 14; self-assessed general health; and region of residence. Where the control variables vary within individual across the Waves (i.e., alcohol consumption, economic activity, annual labour market income, self-assessed general health) we use individual Wave-averaged measures. Also, some of the social homogamy controls are measured at the couple level (i.e., the number of dependent children in the household, annual household total income, net total household wealth, region of residence), where these controls vary within-couple across the Waves, we use couple Wave-averaged measures. a This reports the p-value of the Wald test that the 'Female partner trait optimism' coefficient is equal across the nested models. Significance levels *** 1%,** 5%, * 10%. Notes: The Big Five personality traits were measured using self-ratings of 26 adjectives. Respondents were asked to rate the degree to which each adjective described them, using a four-point Likert scale (ranging from 1 to 4). Each personality trait was calculated by obtaining the average of the ratings defining that trait. The adjectives making up each trait were as follows: extraversion: outgoing, friendly, active, talkative and lively (Cronbach's alpha = 0.75); agreeableness: warm, helpful, soft-hearted, sympathetic and caring (Cronbach's alpha = 0.80); conscientiousness: organised, responsible, thorough, hardworking and careless (Cronbach's alpha = 0.67); neuroticism: moody, worrying, nervous and calm (Cronbach's alpha = 0.68); and openness to experience: creative, imaginative, intelligent, curious, sophisticated and adventurous (Cronbach's alpha = 0.79). The first column reports spousal correlations of the Big Five personality traits, whilst the second and third column reports the correlation between unrealistic optimism and the Big Five personality traits, for men and women, respectively. Panel A (B) uses the standardized optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. Significance levels *** 1%,** 5%, * 10%. Notes: Main entries are marginal effects, t-statistics using robust standard errors in brackets. Panel A (B) uses the standardized trait optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. Within-couple differences in longevity controls include within-couple differences for smoking and alcohol consumption; mother's/father's age when she/he died setting the value to the oldest age reported in the panel of the respondent's mother/father for those whose mother/father remained alive throughout the panel (and including a binary variable for whether respondent's mother/father remained alive throughout the panel); binary variables for the presence of each of the following illnesses: chronic lung disease such as chronic bronchitis or emphysema; asthma; arthritis (including osteoarthritis, or rheumatism); osteoporosis, sometimes called thin or brittle bones; cancer or a malignant tumour (excluding minor skin cancers); Parkinson's disease; any emotional, nervous or psychiatric problems; Alzheimer's disease; dementia, organic brain syndrome, senility or any other serious memory impairment; and binary variables for the presence of each of the following conditions: high blood pressure or hypertension; angina; a heart attack (including myocardial infarction or coronary thrombosis); congestive heart failure; a heart murmur; an abnormal heart rhythm; diabetes or high blood sugar; a stroke (cerebral vascular disease); and high cholesterol. Social homogamy controls include for each member of the couple: date of birth; ethnicity; religion; university/college degree; the number of dependent children in the household; economic activity; annual labour market income; annual household total income (the sum of employment income, state and private benefit income, asset income and other income); net total household wealth (the sum of savings, investments, physical wealth and housing wealth after financial debt and mortgage debt has been subtracted); mother and fathers education; main carer's main occupation when respondent was 14; self-assessed general health; and region of residence. Where the control variables vary within individual across the Waves (i.e., alcohol consumption, economic activity, annual labour market income, self-assessed general health) we use individual Wave-averaged measures. Also, some of the social homogamy controls are measured at the couple level (i.e., the number of dependent children in the household, annual household total income, net total household wealth, region of residence), where these controls vary within-couple across the Waves, we use couple Wave-averaged measures. Personality controls include the Big Five personality traits which were measured using self-ratings of 26 adjectives. Respondents were asked to rate the degree to which each adjective described them, using a four-point Likert scale (ranging from 1 to 4). Each personality trait was calculated by obtaining the average of the ratings defining that trait. The adjectives making up each trait were as follows: extraversion: outgoing, friendly, active, talkative and lively (Cronbach's alpha = 0.75); agreeableness: warm, helpful, soft-hearted, sympathetic and caring (Cronbach's alpha = 0.80); conscientiousness: organised, responsible, thorough, hardworking and careless (Cronbach's alpha = 0.67); neuroticism: moody, worrying, nervous and calm (Cronbach's alpha = 0.68); and openness to experience: creative, imaginative, intelligent, curious, sophisticated and adventurous (Cronbach's alpha = 0.79). a This reports the p-value of the Wald test that the 'Female partner trait optimism' coefficient is equal across the nested models. Significance levels *** 1%,** 5%, * 10%.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The politics of mate choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Alford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hatemi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hibbing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Eaves</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="362" to="379" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assortative mating for relative weight: genetic implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Allison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Neale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Kezis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Alfonso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Heshka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Heymsfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Genetics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="111" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">For richer, for poorer&apos;: Assortative mating and savings preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Arrondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Frémeaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">331</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="518" to="543" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-confidence and personal motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bénabou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="871" to="915" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Willpower and personal rules</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bénabou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tirole</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Political Economy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="848" to="886" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Longevity and life-cycle savings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bloom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Canning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Scandinavian Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="338" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality and mate preferences: Five factors in mate selection and marital satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Botwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Buss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shackelford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive processes underlying human mate choice: The relationship between self-perception and mate preference in Western society</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Buston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Emlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8805" to="8810" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The upside of pessimism− Biased beliefs and the paradox of the contented female worker</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="228" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Looking on the (B) right Side of Life: Cognitive Ability and Miscalibrated Financial Expectations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Curb your enthusiasm: Optimistic entrepreneurs earn less</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>De Meza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Henley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Arabsheibani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="69" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The intergenerational transmission of risk and trust attitudes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Dohmen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Falk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Huffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Sunde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Review of Economic Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="677" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who can predict their own demise? Heterogeneity in the accuracy and value of longevity expectations☆</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Uva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>O'donnell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Van Doorslaer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of the Economics of Ageing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">100135</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Optimistic update bias holds firm: Three tests of robustness following Shah et al. Consciousness and Cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Garrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sharot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality, cognitive style and assortative mating</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Glicksohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Golan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1199" to="1209" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Marry your like: Assortative mating and income inequality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Greenwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Guner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kocharkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="348" to="353" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Marriage and health: Selection, protection, and assortative mating</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Guner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kulikova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Llull</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="166" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Expectations, life expectancy, and economic behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Hamermesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="389" to="408" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Group decision making under risk: An experiment with student couples</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martinsson</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sutter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economics Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="693" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning substrates in the primate prefrontal cortex and striatum: sustained activity related to successful actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Histed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pasupathy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="244" to="253" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mortality risk and bequests</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hurd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica: Journal of the econometric society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="779" to="813" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective probabilities in household surveys</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hurd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="543" to="562" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of subjective survival on retirement and social security claiming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hurd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Zissimopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="761" to="775" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Persistent overconfidence and biased memory: Evidence from managers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Huffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Raymond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shvets</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3141" to="3175" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How deep is the annuity market participation puzzle?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Inkmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Lopes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Michaelides</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Review of Financial Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="319" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assortative preferences for personality and online dating apps: Individuals prefer profiles similar to themselves on agreeableness, openness, and extraversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jessica</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">208</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">112185</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Midlife Development Inventory (MIDI) personality scales: Scale construction and scoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Lachman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Weaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
			<pubPlace>Waltham, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Brandeis University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heads I win, tails it&apos;s chance: The illusion of control as a function of the sequence of outcomes in a purely chance task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Langer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="951" to="955" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multigenerational persistence: Evidence from 146 years of administrative data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Modalsli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Human Resources</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="929" to="961" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using subjective expectations to forecast longevity: Do survey respondents know something we don&apos;t know? Demography</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Perozek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimism and economic choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Puri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Financial Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indirect assortative mating for human disease and longevity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Rawlik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Canela-Xandri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tenesa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Heredity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="106" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Genetic evidence of assortative mating in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kleinman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Graff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Vinkhuyzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Couper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Visscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimates of the heritability of human longevity are substantially inflated due to assortative mating</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ruby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kermany</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Noto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Curtis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ball</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Genetics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">210</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1109" to="1124" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective mortality expectations and consumption and saving behaviours among the elderly</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Salm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Canadian Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1040" to="1057" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biased information search in group decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schulz-Hardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lüthgens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Moscovici</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="669" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How unrealistic optimism is maintained in the face of reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sharot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Korn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1475" to="1479" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimism and the Big Five factors of personality: Beyond neuroticism and extraversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Sharpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="946" to="951" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A primer on unrealistic optimism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Shepperd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Waters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Weinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="237" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Note on longevity and aggregate savings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sheshinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scandinavian Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assortative mating for emotional intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Śmieja</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stolarski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective life horizon and portfolio choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Spaenjers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Spira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="94" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assortative mating for obesity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Speakman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Djafarian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="316" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cohort profile: the English longitudinal study of ageing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Steptoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Breeze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Banks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nazroo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Epidemiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1640" to="1648" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assortative mating for human height: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Stulp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Simons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Grasman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Pollet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Human Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">22917</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MHC-dependent mate preferences in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wedekind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Seebeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bettens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Paepke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1359" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">260</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="249" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unrealistic optimism about future life events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Weinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="806" to="820" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceived longevity and early retirement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wolfe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Review of Economics and Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="544" to="551" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cohort and target age effects on subjective survival probabilities: Implications for models of the retirement phase</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Thorp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dynamics of motivated beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zimmermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Notes: Main entries are marginal effects, t-statistics using clustered standard errors by the individual in brackets. Panel A (B) uses the optimism measure computed from the variable (static) target age task. In Panel A we control for age (in cubic form); target age (reference category: 75) and a series of binary variables for survey Wave. In Panel B we control for age (in cubic form) and a series of binary variables for survey Wave</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Significance levels *** 1%,** 5%, * 10%</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
