<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Attentional Dynamics Explain the Elusive Nature of Context Effects</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Murrow</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
							<email>wrholmes@iu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences and Cognitive Science Program</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Indiana University Yanjun Liu</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of New South Wales</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics and Astronomy, Vanderbilt University William M. Hayes Psychology Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Binghamton University State University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Cognitive Science Program and Department of Mathematics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indiana University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1101 E 10th St</addrLine>
									<settlement>Bloomington</settlement>
									<region>IN</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Cognitive Science Program</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1001 E. 10th St. Bloomington</addrLine>
									<postCode>47405</postCode>
									<region>IN</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Attentional Dynamics Explain the Elusive Nature of Context Effects</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>multi-alternative decision making</term>
					<term>evidence accumulation models</term>
					<term>attention</term>
					<term>similarity</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Context effects in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice are pervasive and yet, paradoxically, elusive at the same time. For example, simple changes to the spatial layout of alternatives on the screen can nullify or reverse the effects. Despite the success of dynamic decision models in explaining the occurrence of context effects, a coherent theory for understanding their elusiveness is currently lacking. We introduce a novel theoretical framework that relies on attention modulated comparisons to explain the elusive nature of context effects. We show via simulation that our model produces the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects simply by assuming that more time is spent comparing alternatives that are more similar. However, when more time is spent comparing dissimilar alternatives, model simulations reveal a reversal of the attraction and compromise effects. The empirical support for this model-based prediction is assessed by manipulating similarity-based attention in separate experiments for the three context effects (total N = 887). Further, by allowing the spatial organization of information to constrain the attention process, the model can explain changes in context effects induced by display layout. We show that the model&apos;s spatial attention mechanism allows it to capture presentation order effects in a reanalysis of previously published data. Finally, we develop a continuous approximation of the full model that permits fitting of choices and response times. In summary, the proposed framework provides a new tool for understanding not only the existence of context effects in choice, but also the attentional factors that lead to null or reversed context effects.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attentional Dynamics Explain the Elusive Nature of Context Effects</head><p>Context effects in decisions, and more specifically the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects, have long been of interest in the study of decision making as examples of violations of principles of classic economic theories of choice. Observance of these violations has prompted the development of numerous theoretical models (for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bhatia, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Noguchi and Stewart, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Roe et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Trueblood et al., 2014)</ref> attempting to explain the decision processes responsible for them, particularly the three previously mentioned context effects. While these theories posit a range of different possible mechanisms, a significant majority incorporate some notion of attention as a critical process influencing the way in which alternatives are evaluated <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Trueblood, 2022)</ref>.</p><p>We build on this line of research to develop a simple yet powerful model of attention modulated preference formation in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice. This theory not only accounts for the presence of the classic context effects, but also how changes in attention processes can nullify and even reverse these effects. This theory thus unifies a large body of past research, both empirical and theoretical, that have attempted to understand why context effects arise and why they appear to be simultaneously both universal (appearing in numerous choice domains) and fragile (disappearing or reversing in some studies).</p><p>In the following sections, we discuss the concept of contextual sensitivity in choice and describe the three classic context effects. We then provide a brief overview of formal theories that aim to explain the existence of these effects. The quest to model context effects has been challenged by recent findings demonstrating the fragility of these effects. We discuss the evidence for this fragility before introducing our modeling framework, which uses attention processes to explain why context effects sometimes arise and other times disappear or reverse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Contextual sensitivity and context effects</head><p>Many of the decisions we make in our lives involve choices among multiple options that have multiple attributes. Imagine you are planning your next vacation. As part of that process, you need to select a flight, rental car, and hotel room. Each one of these choices involves multiple options (e.g., different airlines) that vary on many different features (e.g., price, departure time, length of layover, seat availability, etc.). The question of how people make decisions in these complex tasks has intrigued researchers in psychology, marketing, neuroscience, and behavioral economics for decades. One of the key findings related to multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice is that people's decisions often display contextual sensitivity. A specific example of contextual sensitivity occurs when people's choices among existing options can be influenced by the introduction of new alternatives, a phenomenon known as a context effect.</p><p>To illustrate context effects in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice, consider the scenario of selecting a flight for an upcoming trip. Imagine you are deliberating between two options. One flight (call this flight A) has a good departure time, but is expensive, and the other flight (call this flight B) has an inconvenient departure time, but is more affordable. In this case, there is a trade-off between convenience of departure time and affordability. Now, imagine you learn of a new flight option (call this flight C) that departs at the same time as flight B, but is more expensive then flight B. In this scenario, flight C is not a very good option because it is dominated by flight B. Even though you would never select flight C, it makes flight B look more appealing and you end up selecting flight B over flight A. This phenomenon is known as the attraction effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Huber et al., 1982)</ref> and is one example of a context effect in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice.</p><p>Early research on context effects was aimed at showing violations of principles of classic economic theories of choice such as simple scalability, regularity, and independence of irrelevant alternatives <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Huber et al., 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Tversky, 1972)</ref>. After this early work in the 1970s and 1980s, research on context effects in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice proceeded along two related branches. One branch was concerned with empirical investigations of the effects in a wide variety of tasks and species <ref type="bibr">(e.g., monkeys, honeybees, hummingbirds, etc.)</ref>. This research painted a picture that context effects were "universal" since they seemed to show up everywhere. However, about a decade ago, research started suggesting the story was much more nuanced. Studies were published showing null or even reversed context effects (for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Spektor et al., 2021)</ref>. This led to some researchers calling into question the importance of context effects altogether <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Frederick et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Huber et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>The other main branch of research in this area was concerned with developing formal theories to explain the presence of context effects, leading to the development of numerous cognitive (for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bhatia, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Noguchi and Stewart, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Roe et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Trueblood et al., 2014)</ref> and neural models (for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Dumbalska et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Landry and Webb, 2021</ref>) of these effects. The desire to have a formal theory is rooted in the fact that these effects cannot be explained by classic decision theories (e.g. classic utility models). Thus, the primary goal of modelers was developing theories to account for and explain the existence of context effects, often with a single set of parameters <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">(Trueblood et al., 2015)</ref>. Most of these models were not developed to explain null or reversed context effects. Thus, we currently do not have a rigorous theoretical framework to explain why reversals and null effects occur.</p><p>In this paper, we focus on three well-established context effects: the attraction <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Huber et al., 1982)</ref>, similarity <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">(Tversky, 1972)</ref>, and compromise <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Simonson, 1989)</ref> effects. In all three effects, choices between two options, X and Y , are influenced by a third option Z. The three options are defined in terms of two attributes, a 1 and a 2 . For the following explanations, let us assume that X a 1 &lt; Y a 1 and X a 2 &gt; Y a 2 (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1)</ref>. The relationship between the third option Z and X and Y determines the specific type of context effect.</p><p>We use the term target to refer to the option that is traditionally advantaged with the inclusion of the third option. Likewise, we use the term competitor to refer to the option that is traditionally disadvantaged with the inclusion of the third option. In the literature, there are different ways of measuring context effects. One method of measuring context effects is to compare binary choices between the target and competitor to ternary choices between the target, competitor, and decoy. Another method is to compare two different ternary choice sets, one with a decoy targeting option X and one with a decoy targeting option Y . In this paper, we use the all-ternary method because it tends to produce larger effect sizes <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">(Wedell, 1991)</ref>.</p><p>Using the all-ternary method, we calculate a measure called the Relative Choice Share of the Target (RST; <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Berkowitsch et al., 2014)</ref> and provide an alternative version of this measure in the supplement. The RST calculates the probability of selecting the target divided by the probability of selecting the target or competitor: pr(T )/(pr(T ) + pr(C)). More specifically, if Z X is a third option that enhances X (i.e., X is the target in the choice set {X,Y, Z X }) and Z Y is a third option that enhances Y (i.e., Y is the target in the choice set {X,Y, Z Y }), then the RST is defined as RST = pr(X|{X,Y, Z X }) + pr(Y |{X,Y, Z Y }) pr(X|{X,Y, Z X }) + pr(Y |{X,Y, Z Y }) + pr(X|{X,Y, Z Y }) + pr(Y |{X,Y, Z X })</p><p>A standard context effect occurs when RST &gt; 0.5, which implies that the target is selected more often in the presence of the third option than the competitor. 1</p><p>In the attraction effect, the third option is a dominated decoy that is similar but inferior to either X or Y . Specifically, let A X be a decoy similar, but inferior to X and A Y be a decoy similar, but interior to Y as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. In the attraction effect, the target is the option that is similar to, but dominates the decoy (e.g., X in the choice set {X, Y , A X }). Likewise, the competitor is the dissimilar option (e.g., Y in the choice set {X, Y , A X }).</p><p>In the similarity effect, the third option is similar and competitive to either X or Y . In particular, let S X be similar and competitive to Y and S Y be similar and competitive to X as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. In the similarity effect, the target is the dissimilar option (e.g., X in the choice set {X, Y , S X }) and the competitor is the similar option (e.g., Y in the choice set {X, Y , S X }). In the similarity effect, the two similar options compete with one another and split the choice shares.</p><p>The result is that the dissimilar option (i.e., the target) is selected more often relative to the competitor.</p><p>In the compromise effect, the third option is an extreme option that makes either X or Y appear as a compromise. Specifically, let C X be an extreme option such that X appears as a compromise between C X and Y . In this case, we have the following relationship among attributes: C a 1 X &lt; X a 1 &lt; Y a and C a 2 X &gt; X a 2 &gt; Y a 2 . Let C Y be an extreme option such that Y appears as a compromise between C Y and X. Here we have C a 1 Y &gt; Y a 1 &gt; X a 1 and C a 2 Y &lt; Y a 2 &lt; X a 2 . In the compromise effect, the target is the compromise option (e.g., X in the choice set {X, Y , C X }) and the competitor in the extreme option (e.g., Y in the choice set {X, Y , C X }).</p><p>We note that the descriptions above refer to classical context effects where options X and Y are assumed to fall on a line of indifference (dashed gray line in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). When the options do not fall on the indifference line, the context effects are altered. A disadvantaged target (i.e., one below the indifference line) often results in stronger context effects than an advantaged target (i.e., one above the indifference line) <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Evangelidis et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">X Y A X A Y C X C Y S Y S X Attribute 1 Attribute 2 Figure 1</formula><p>Locations of standard decoys in two-dimensional attribute space: Two core alternatives (X and Y) are shown along with attraction (A), similarity (S), and compromise (C) decoys. The subscripts denote the option that is traditionally advantaged by the inclusion of the decoy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Models of context effects</head><p>As previously mentioned, researchers studying context effects in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice have developed formal computational models to explain the underlying cognitive processes that give rise to the effects (for reviews, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Busemeyer et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Trueblood, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Wollschlaeger and Diederich, 2020)</ref>. Many of these models are based on the Evidence Accumulation Modeling (EAM) framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Ratcliff, 1978)</ref> and assume that evidence or preference for different options accumulates over the course of deliberation. Each option is associated with an accumulator that tracks the preference state for that option over time. The final decision is determined by the accumulator with the greatest amount of preference at a fixed time point (external stopping rule) or by the accumulator that reaches a decision threshold first (internal stopping rule). A key advantage of EAM models is their ability to simultaneously account for choices and response times.</p><p>Although existing EAM models make different assumptions about the nature of preference accumulation and the cognitive mechanisms that produce the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects, one thing that most of the models have in common is the idea that attention is important for explaining context effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Trueblood, 2022)</ref>. In decisions between multiple options with multiple attributes, it is impossible to attend to all of the information at once, and so attention is assumed to fluctuate between different pieces of information over the course of deliberation. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Noguchi and Stewart (2014)</ref> used eye-tracking to show that individuals repeatedly compare options in pairs along a single dimension in context effects experiments.</p><p>Models of context effects typically assume that preference accumulates based on the information attended to at each time point. For example, multialternative decision field theory <ref type="bibr">(MDFT;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Roe et al., 2001</ref>) assumes that at each time point, a particular attribute is stochastically attended to and the value of each option on that attribute is compared to the average of the values of the other options. Similarly, the multiattribute linear ballistic accumulator model <ref type="bibr">(MLBA;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Trueblood et al., 2014)</ref> assumes that options are compared in a pairwise fashion on each attribute, with attention weights that depend on the similarity of the options involved in a particular comparison. Thus, attention appears to be a critical feature for understanding how context effects arise in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice. This article will expand on this observation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The elusive nature of context effects</head><p>An interesting but puzzling feature of context effects is they are both universal and fragile.</p><p>For example, previous research has explored how context influences preferences across a variety of different domains including perception <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Trueblood, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Trueblood et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al., , 2015</ref>, inference <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(Trueblood, 2012)</ref>, similarity judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(Yearsley et al., 2021)</ref>, memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Maylor &amp; Roberts, 2007)</ref>, gambles <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Farmer et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Wedell, 1991)</ref>, and motor planning decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Farmer et al., 2015)</ref>. This work aimed to answer the question, do context effects, which are often found in consumer choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Evangelidis et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Huber et al., 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Simonson, 1989)</ref>, generalize to other domains? Results show that these phenomena can arise outside of consumer choice (e.g., in perceptual decisions about the size of rectangles; <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Trueblood et al., 2013)</ref>. In addition, research in developmental psychology and behavioral ecology has shown that the attraction effect occurs in children <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Zhen &amp; Yu, 2016)</ref>, monkeys <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Parrish et al., 2015)</ref>, frogs <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Lea &amp; Ryan, 2015)</ref>, honeybees <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Latty &amp; Trueblood, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Shafir et al., 2002)</ref>, hummingbirds <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bateson et al., 2003)</ref>, and even slime molds <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Latty &amp; Beekman, 2011)</ref>. Thus, there is a sense that contextual sensitivity is a universal property of multi-alternative choice behavior.</p><p>Despite the seemingly ubiquitous nature of contextual sensitivity, the three classic effects are also very fragile. First, very few participants produce all three effects within a single experiment even though most people show the effects in isolation (i.e., in separate experiments, <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al., 2015)</ref>. Second, there are large individual differences in the strength and co-occurrence of the effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Liew et al., 2016)</ref>. Third, there is evidence that the attraction effect is much stronger in abstract, stylized stimuli as opposed to natural stimuli <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Frederick et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Fourth, the effects are quite sensitive to task features such as the spatial arrangement and presentation order of the alternatives <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Cataldo &amp; Cohen, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Evans et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hasan et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Spektor et al., 2018)</ref>. This has led to the recent conclusion that context effects are elusive (for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Spektor et al., 2021</ref>).</p><p>The present paper introduces a new modeling framework with the goal of explaining the diverse patterns of behavior observed in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice. This framework builds off of the prior observation that attention, and in particular the way it dynamically alters the evaluation of choice alternatives, has a potentially critical role in producing these patterns of behavior. Whereas past efforts have attempted to produce these specific context effects, our goal here is to not only understand their presence, but also why they appear to be fragile and how they may be manipulated empirically.</p><p>The aim of the present paper is to propose a modeling framework that builds on and extends the ideas formalized in existing EAM models. Our goal is not to introduce a new model to compete with existing models in a head-to-head comparison, but rather to use the proposed framework to develop a better understanding of the role of attention in the decision process and what its effects on behavior might look like. With this in mind, we do not build a single model of attention, but rather a more general framework to evaluate different models of attention and attention-related factors. Using this framework, we show that seemingly subtle changes in attention can lead to a complex pattern of standard, null, and reversed context effects. We corroborate the modeling results with new experiments and the reanalysis of published data. In totality, our results support prior studies positing that attention may be (partly) responsible for context effects. We however take a step further and illustrate how either intrinsic or extrinsic changes in the attention process can lead to a wide range of seemingly contradictory empirical observations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Theoretical Framework for Attention and Decision-making</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Model Description</head><p>Based on the rich theory of evidence accumulation in psychology and neuroscience <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>, we develop a new computational modeling framework of multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice where preferences are constructed over time through a sequence of attention modulated comparisons. In this way, we integrate hypotheses for how attention affects information acquisition with EAM models of preference formation to study their joint effects on decisions. We note that this is a framework rather than a single model and thus it is designed to incorporate a range of different possible assumptions regarding the form of comparisons and attention. Here we briefly describe the overarching idea of this approach with further detail below.</p><p>In the most general form, we will assume that:</p><p>• Evidence (or preference) for an alternative is sampled by comparing it to some referent along a single attribute at any given time. A sequence of comparisons involving different attributes and / or alternatives may occur over time, but at any point in time a single alternative is compared to a single referent on a single attribute.</p><p>• This referent could be another of the alternatives (i.e. pairwise comparison), a summary of the choice set along that attribute (e.g., the mean of the choice set), or something formed from past experience. In this article, we will primarily consider pairwise comparisons though the framework can readily accommodate other possibilities.</p><p>• Attention modulates which of the set of all possible comparisons is made. For mathematical tractability we will assume that the selection of future comparisons does not depend on the past sequence of comparisons. With this simplifying assumption, the sequence of comparisons can be described by a Markov process. This Markov process can account for a range of different potential factors such as attribute bias (preference for making comparisons on one particular attribute) or presentation format induced biases of attention.</p><p>History based, non-Markovian attention processes can be included in this framework, but they are more challenging to handle mathematically.</p><p>• The time spent on any given comparison is related to the characteristics of the alternative and referent being compared. For example, a decision maker may spend more or less time comparing an alternative and referent that are similar to each other, or alternatively the time spent could be independent of similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Mathematical Formulation</head><p>Here we describe the general mathematical formulation of this framework without discussion of specific assumptions about how attention is modulated. As noted previously, this is not a single model but rather a framework. Where useful, we will consider 3-alternative, 2-attribute scenarios for notational convenience.</p><p>Consider a choice set consisting of alternatives attribute. Then in a small interval of time ∆t, the preference accumulated for all possible alternatives is dependent on the given comparison being made:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">{(x 1 i , x 2 i )} i=1:3 .</formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">P(t + ∆t) = P(t) + ⃗ d c m ∆t.<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Here P is a vector of preferences for the alternatives and ⃗ d c m is a comparison dependent rate of accumulation, typically taken to be a simple difference between the alternative and referent along the attribute being attended to in that time interval. For example, if alternatives 1 and 3 are being compared on attribute 2, the rates of accumulation for the three alternatives would be x 2 1 − x 2 3 , 0,</p><p>x 2 3 − x 2 1 respectively where alternative 2 has a 0 rate of accumulation since it is not being attended to. Further, the rates for alternatives 1 and 3 are the same in magnitude but different in sign since a comparison that favours one option will disfavor the other.</p><p>It is clear that in this approach, the specific comparison being made determines the rate of preference accumulation. We thus next describe an attention-based model where stochastic sequences of attention impact preference accumulation. For this discussion, we will consider the case where one alternative is compared to another, though other referents can be readily incorporated with appropriate modification as previously discussed. To model a sequence of comparisons, we need to describe two things: 1) how long each comparison will last and 2) once one comparison is completed, how the next comparison is chosen. For comparison time, we will generally assume that the time spent on a particular comparison is dependent on the similarity between the two items being compared. As an example, more similar options may be compared for longer times since they are more difficult to distinguish (other assumptions are possible).</p><p>Comparison transitions will be modeled as a probabilistic Markov process, which can be described by a transition matrix. For example, if there are 6 possible comparisons (3 alternatives, 2 attributes) transitions will be modelled by a 6x6 transition matrix P. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> illustrates the modeling framework and Markov attention process.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">(A,C,1) (A,B,2) (B,C,2) (A,C,2) (B,C,1) (A,B,1) Preference Time P A P B P C (A,C,1) (B,C,2) (A,C,2) (A,B,1) (A,C,2) M 2,2 M 2,1 M 2,3 M 2,5 M 2,6 M 2,4 A) B) C) Markov Attention Process Preference Accumulation M 2,1 M 2,2 M 2,3 M 2,4 M 2,5 M 2,6 Markov Matrix Illustration (A,B,1) (A,C,1) (B,C,1) (A,B,2) (A,C,2) (B,C,2) (A,B,1) (A,C,1) (B,C,1) (A,B,2) (A,C,2) (B,C,2)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2</head><p>Visualization of the modeling framework: Panel A illustrates the Markov attention process for the situation where a decision maker is currently comparing options A and C on attribute 1. The arrows indicate the possible comparisons that the decision maker could transition to within the next time point, including the possibility of continuing to compare A and C on attribute 1. Note that the full Markov process includes all possible transitions among the 6 comparison states, but only a subset of these are shown in the figure. Panel B illustrates the 6x6 Markov matrix M that governs the sequence of comparisons. The probabilities M i, j denote the probability of transitioning from comparison i to j. The diagonal elements are the probability of remaining on the current comparison. Panel C illustrates the preference accumulation process for three options A, B, and C modulated by the Markov attention process. In the first time interval, options A and C are being compared on attribute 1 and the preference states P A and P C change accordingly. Next, the decision maker compares options B and C on attribute 2 and the preference states P B and P C change accordingly. The vertical dashed lines indicate points of transition among comparisons. This process continues until one of the preference states (P C in the figure) reaches the threshold (horizontal dotted line) triggering a choice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Detailed Model Formulation</head><p>Next we describe the attention process that governs the sequence of comparisons made in more mathematical detail. Let M c n ,c m denote the probability that, in the given time interval ∆t the decision maker terminates comparison c n and transitions to the comparison c m . This is the product of the probability of comparison c n ending and the probability of the new comparison c m being chosen conditioned on the prior one ending. Different theories regarding attention can be encoded into these two quantities. We thus first formulate the model in general terms using these two quantities, and in a later section we construct the specific form of those quantities from specific hypotheses.</p><p>Let T c n be the probability of the current comparison ending. For three alternatives and two attributes, there are 6 such probabilities. Define Q c n ,c m to be the probability of transitioning from any one comparison to another, conditioned on a transition occurring. In this language,</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">M c n ,c m =T c n • Q c n ,c m (3) M c n ,c n =1 − T c n .<label>(4)</label></formula><p>The first relation represents the probability of each comparison transition occurring while the second is the probability of continuing the current comparison. This probabilistic model of attention can be summarized in the following matrix equation</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">M = I + T • Q,<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where the quantities T and Q are matrix representations of the above quantities (indexed over the set of possible comparison) that encode factors related to attention. T is a 6x6 diagonal matrix with each diagonal element quantifying the probability that each possible comparison will stop in the given time intervals. The off-diagonal entries of Q are the conditional transition probabilities that a specific transition occurs given that a transition will occur, and the diagonal entries of Q are −1. The resulting matrix M is a Markov process describing sequences of comparisons at the discrete time points ∆t, 2∆t, 3∆t, ..., i∆t, ....</p><p>In this model we distinguish between two factors influencing patterns of attention: <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">1</ref>how long a comparison lasts and <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">2</ref>what is compared next. Here Q encodes any process that affects which comparison will be attended to next while T encodes any factors that determine how much time is spent on a particular comparison. For timing, we assume that the time spent on any particular comparison is a stochastic quantity that is exponentially distributed with a characteristic deliberation time τ c n . With this in mind and assuming that the simulation time step is sufficiently small,</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">T ∆t c n ≈ 1 τ c n ∆t.<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The ∆t super-script illustrates that this quantity depends on the computational time interval, though we will omit this superscript for notational simplicity. The specification of a basic model within this framework thus requires specifying how the quantities {τ c n } and {Q c n ,c m } depend on factors of interest. We describe a few such specific models in the subsequent sections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Similarity-based Attention</head><p>Here we illustrate how attention effects can be encoded in the deliberation time component of the model ({τ c n }) and how this factor alone can account for classic context effects in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Tversky and Simonson (1993)</ref> and many other models of context effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Trueblood et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">Wollschläger &amp; Diederich, 2012)</ref>, we consider a pairwise model where the referent to which an alternative is compared is another alternative in the choice set. A comparison then is determined by the two alternatives (i, j) being compared along with the attribute (a) that is being attended to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">c n = (i, j, a)</formula><p>. For further simplicity and to illustrate the effect of this model factor on its own, we will assume that all possible comparisons are equally likely so that Q c n ,c m is the same for all n ̸ = m.</p><p>We will consider three possible comparison time models depending on the relationship between similarity and attention (illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>):</p><p>• Similarity Variant: The more similar two alternatives are on the attribute being attended to, the longer they are compared.</p><p>• Dissimilarity Variant: The more similar two alternatives are on the attribute being attended to, the less time they are compared.</p><p>• Independent Variant: The time spent on a comparison is independent of similarity. Attribute dependent comparison time for attention variants: Sample functions illustrating the dependence of comparison times on attribute differences. In the independent attention variant (blue), attention time does not depend on attributes. In the similarity attention variant (black), more similar alternatives are compared for longer times. In the dissimilarity variant, more distinct alternatives are compared for longer times. The dashed gray line at the bottom reflects that most cases will include a minimum comparison time. For the similarity models we use a function of the shape exp(−λ|x a i − x a j |) where x a i is the value of alternative i on attribute a. For the dissimilarity model, we use a function of the form log(1 + λ|x a i − x a j |). These are convenient functions with the appropriate shape (i.e., they are both monotonic and saturate).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Psychological Plausibility of Similarity-based Attention</head><p>There is growing evidence that similarity-based attention mechanisms may play a role in multi-alternative decision-making. Rather than evaluating each option in isolation, decision-makers appear to allocate attention selectively, often in ways that reflect the similarity structure of the choice environment.</p><p>Empirical support for similarity-based attention comes from eye-tracking studies of multi-attribute choice. This research shows that people tend to fixate more often on alternatives that have similar attribute values, suggesting that attention is systematically drawn to similar options <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Russo &amp; Rosen, 1975)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Noguchi and Stewart (2014)</ref>, for example, found that during decisions involving classic context effects, eye-fixation transitions occurred most frequently between the most similar alternatives. This pattern implies that similarity helps structure attentional shifts during deliberation. Likewise, <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Russo and Rosen (1975)</ref> analyzed eye movements as participants chose among six cars. They found that participants often made pairwise comparisons organized around similarity relations -such as two cars sharing the same make. These findings suggest that similarity facilitates direct comparisons in multi-attribute decision tasks.</p><p>Theoretical models have also incorporated similarity-based mechanisms into their accounts of attention and evidence accumulation. For example, multialternative decision by sampling <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2018)</ref> proposes that the probability of evaluating an option on a given attribute increases with the similarity between its value and other values currently held in working memory. Likewise, the MLBA model <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Trueblood et al., 2014)</ref> includes mechanisms whereby similarity between alternatives affects the allocation of attentional weights to attributes.</p><p>While these models differ in implementation, they share the assumption that similarity among alternatives can influence how information is attended to and used in the construction of preferences.</p><p>Related findings in visual attention research also support the plausibility of similarity-guided attention. For example, studies of pattern recognition have found that as the similarity between targets and non-targets increases, both the number and duration of eye fixations tend to increase, suggesting greater attentional demand when differentiating between similar stimuli <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Gould, 1967)</ref>. Additional evidence comes from research on object-based attention. In these paradigms, attention spreads across an entire object rather than being confined to a single spatial location. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Egly et al. (1994)</ref> demonstrated that participants respond more quickly to targets that appear within the same object as a spatial cue, even when the target is not located at the cued position. The strength of this effect depends on the similarity between objects, with stronger cueing effects observed when objects are more dissimilar in features such as color or shape <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Hein et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Shomstein &amp; Behrmann, 2008)</ref>. Dissimilarity may enhance object individuation, making the boundaries between objects more distinct and, thereby, strengthening within-object attentional selection. Although situated within the domain of visual attention, these findings support the broader idea that similarity influences how attention is organized.</p><p>Together, these findings demonstrate that similarity shapes attentional processing across both perceptual and decision-making domains. Incorporating similarity-based attention into our modeling framework is therefore both theoretically and empirically grounded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Impact of Similarity-based Attention on Context Effects</head><p>To assess the impact of these different similarity-based attention assumptions, we performed a simulation study to explore the presence of context effects in the three-alternative, two-attribute choice domain. To do so, we fixed two alternatives that differ on each attribute but fall along the line of indifference (0.4, 0.6), (0.6, 0.4) and varied the location of a third "decoy" alternative throughout attribute space. For each decoy location, we calculated the relative share of alternative x defined as n(x)/(n(x) + n(y)) where n(x) and n(y) are the number of times x and y are chosen. We subjected three models, corresponding to the three comparison time scenarios above, to this in silico experiment. For the similarity variant, we assumed the comparison time distribution for an alternative is exponential with a mean time of τ c n = exp(−λ|x a i − x a j |). This particular functional form was inspired by <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Shepard's (1987)</ref> law of generalization which defines similarity as an exponentially decaying function of distance. The MLBA model of context effects also employed an exponential similarity function <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Trueblood et al., 2014)</ref>, drawing inspiration from the work of Shepard. For the dissimilarity variant, we used τ c n = log(1 + λ|x a i − x a j |). The independent variant does not require a parameter to describe comparison times. For this model, the mean time spent on each comparison will be the same and thus the relative time spent on each comparison is a fixed number independent of attribute values. In the similarity and dissimilarity variants, λ is a scale parameter that determines how sensitive the comparison time is to attribute differences. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows that with no additional assumptions, the similarity variant demonstrates all three context effects. For example, when an attraction decoy is located at (0.35, 0.55), the relative choice share of x = 0.74. When a compromise decoy is located at (0.05, 0.95), the relative choice share of x = 0.58. Finally, when a similarity effect decoy is located at (0.65, 0.35), the relative choice share of x = 0.57. We note that it appears that in these simulations the attraction effect is stronger than the compromise and similarity effects. Dumbalska et al. (2020) created a decoy plane plot using human data and found that the attraction effect was empirically stronger than the compromise and similarity effects (see <ref type="figure">Figure 3A</ref> in their paper). However, we caution the reader about drawing conclusions regarding the relative strength of the three effects. More empirical work is needed on this topic. We also note that these simulations use stylized stimuli, a single set of parameters, and are only intended to convey general patterns. Since we did not fit data in the generation of <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>, mismatches between these simulations and data are to be expected. Context effects simulation study: To study the effect of adding a decoy alternative to a binary choice, we fix the attribute values of two alternatives (x and y shown on the plot) and vary the location of a third "decoy" alternative. For each decoy value, N = 1000 simulations are run and the number of times each alternative (n(x), n(y), n(d)) is chosen (as determined by the preference accumulation process defined in equation 2) is recorded. Each plot shows the relative share of alternative x as a function of decoy location (n(x)/n(x) + n(y)). The indicated regions on the similarity variant demonstrate it simultaneously accounts for the three classic context effects. For these simulations, we use an attention parameter λ = 5 and threshold b = 0.2.</p><p>Given the relative simplicity of this model (only two free parameters, λ and the accumulation threshold b), we next sought to understand how these three effects manifest in the similarity variant. It is natural to expect that the alternative with the highest average rate of preference accumulation will be chosen more often. To quantify this, we simulated the model 1,000 times stochastically with example attraction, compromise, and similarity decoys. We then averaged the stochastic trajectories over time and plotted these averages as a function of time ( <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>). In the attraction decoy case, the rate of preference accumulation (seen in the slope) for the target is highest, leading to it being chosen more often. The essential reason for this is that with similarity-based attention (using an exponential function for similarity and λ = 5), proximity of the decoy to the target in attribute space leads to an increase in the time spent on target favorable comparisons, leading to the target being selected more often.</p><p>The similarity and compromise effect scenarios however show that the mean evidence traces are flat for all three alternatives. In retrospect, this is sensible since all three alternatives lie on the line of indifference (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). For every comparison that is favorable for one alternative, there is an equal and opposite comparison on the other attribute that is equally unfavorable. This leads to a net zero accumulation when averaged over many simulated model choices.</p><p>However, this is an average effect. Even when all options are on the line of indifference, random fluctuations in preference accumulation can lead to threshold crossing and a resulting choice. If the structure of this randomness is different for one of the alternatives, that could break this symmetry. To assess this, we next plotted the variance in accumulator traces. For each point in time we calculated the variance of the accumulation traces across all N=1,000 simulations ( <ref type="figure">Figure 5 bottom)</ref>. Results demonstrate that in the similarity and compromise effect scenarios, the target exhibits more variability, which breaks the symmetry between the three otherwise equal alternatives. Since the first passage time of a purely diffusive process to a boundary inversely depends on the rate of diffusion (quantified by the slope of the plotted variance here), the target is chosen more frequently in both cases.</p><p>What is the interpretation of this explanation of the compromise and similarity effects?</p><p>On average, none of these alternatives is objectively superior and thus there is no net accumulation of evidence when aggregated over many simulated choices. However, the attention process introduces intra-trial variability in the length and sequence of attention segments and therefore accumulation. Due to this variability, it is more likely that a random sequence of comparisons favoring the target will occur. This leads to it being chosen more often even in the absence of average favorability.</p><p>We next assessed the influence of the critical similarity parameter λ on these results. The attraction effect is a consequence of the mean rate of accumulation (slope) of the target being greater than that of the competitor. Thus, we quantified the difference between the slopes of the mean lines in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> for the target and competitor (T-C). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref> illustrates the difference in the mean rates of accumulation as a function of λ (top three panels). A positive difference indicates that the target has a higher mean rate of accumulation and thus is favored. These results show that the target exhibits a higher mean rate of accumulation for a range of λ values, consistent with results from <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. Similarly, the target and competitor have the same mean rate of accumulation for all λ values in the similarity and compromise cases.</p><p>We similarly quantified the slopes of the average variance traces as a function of λ. Recall that a higher variance will tend to increase the likelihood of a threshold crossing for a given alternative. Thus, we compared the slope of the variance traces for the target and competitor (T-C), as shown in the lower panels of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref>. Consistent with <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>, for the similarity and compromise effects, the variance of the target accumulator is higher than the competitor for a range of λ values. This effect is reduced at larger λ values. We hypothesize that this is a consequence of the decreasing duration of comparisons for large λ values, which reduces the magnitude of the trial-to-trial variation responsible for this increased variance.</p><p>In synopsis, the emergence of the attraction effect from this model is a result of the similarity function differentially increasing the rate of preference accumulation for the target. This is a deterministic effect. The appearance of the similarity and compromise effects are however a result of the stochastic nature of the model. In these cases, no alternative is preferred by the model. However, the interaction of the similarity based Markov process with the stochastic accumulation process leads to stochastic patterns of attention that increase the likelihood of the target being chosen in those cases. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 5</head><p>Similarity variant temporal evidence accumulation properties: To understand the genesis of context effects in the similarity variant, we track the evidence accumulation mean and variance over time for three choice sets indicative of the three context effects. To do so, we simulate 1000 independent trials for each choice set and quantify the mean and variance of the evidence state for each choice at each time (illustrated in the respective panels). For all simulations the attention parameter is λ = 5. No threshold parameter is included since only preference traces are quantified, not choices. The notation T,C, D is used here since the respective alternatives are the target, competitor, and decoy for these choice sets. Comparable figures for the independent and dissimilarity models are in the Supplemental Materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional Attention Factors</head><p>We next illustrate how other attention processes can be incorporated into the comparison transition component of the framework (the matrix Q), which is independent of the comparison time T process just discussed. In anticipation of subsequent modeling and analysis, we discuss two factors that may influence which comparisons are chosen more or less frequently. The first is attribute preference. When multiple attributes are present, it is conceivable and even likely that in many cases attributes will be given different weights in the decision process. One way to incorporate this is through the comparison transition matrix Q. For simplicity, we will assume  Accumulator mean and variance slopes as a function of λ: Here we quantify the accumulator mean and variance effect seen in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> as a function of λ. All parameters and values of the target, competitor, and decoy are the same as in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. The value of the similarity strength parameter λ is varied. For each value, we simulate 1000 independent trials and quantify the mean and variance of the traces as a function of time (see <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>). Since these traces are linear, we quantify the slope of mean and variance traces for the target and competitor. Those slopes are then subtracted (target -competitor) to quantify the difference in mean slopes and separately the difference in variance slopes as a function of λ. Red vertical lines indicate the value of λ used for simulations in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>.</p><p>two attributes here and introduce the parameter w encoding the weight for attribute 1 (and consequently 1 − w is the weight for attribute 2). Multiplying all elements of the matrix Q corresponding to attribute 1 by w (and similarly for attribute 2) naturally incorporates differential preference for attending to these attributes.</p><p>Spatial attention, arising from the presentation structure of information, is another factor that may influence decisions. For example, alternatives in different sections of a computer screen (e.g., left versus right) may receive greater attention and the comparison of physically adjacent alternatives may be more frequent. These factors can be readily incorporated into this framework through Q as well. We demonstrate this for one scenario, where comparisons of alternatives that are physically adjacent to each other are more common than those separated. Consider the three-alternative, two-attribute scenario. Assume the alternatives are ordered left (L), middle (M), and right (R) when presented. There are three spatial pairs of comparison here (LM, LR, RM).</p><p>We can define two parameters p LM , p MR indicating the probability of two of those comparisons occurring (with the third being 1 − p LM − p MR ). Combined with the aforementioned attribute weight w, this yields a three parameter model of spatial attention along with attribute preference that can be encoded in the transition matrix Q.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Similarity-based Attention Experiments</head><p>Our modeling framework predicts that similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention can lead to different patterns of choices. To further explore the differences between these two attention mechanisms, we conducted simulations calculating the difference in the RST (see equation 1; <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Berkowitsch et al., 2014)</ref> between the similarity and dissimilarity model variants. For each of the three context effects, we created 1000 sets of simulations. Similar to the simulations shown in Figures 4 and 5 we fixed two alternatives at (0.4, 0.6) and (0.6, 0.4) for all simulations.</p><p>Then, for each simulation, we selected a decoy value in the appropriate ranges for the effect.</p><p>For the attraction decoy, we randomly selected attribute values from the ranges [0.2, 0.4] and [0.4 ,0.6]. The way these values were assigned depended on the alternative we were targeting.</p><p>When the target was (0.4, 0.6), we used the first range [0.2, 0.4] for attribute 1 and the second range [0.4, 0.6] for attribute 2. When the target was (0.6, 0.4), we reversed this: we used [0.4, 0.6] for attribute 1 and [0.2, 0.4] for attribute 2. For the compromise decoy, we randomly selected one attribute value from the range [0.1, 0.3]. When the target was (0.4, 0.6), this value was assigned as attribute 1. When the target was (0.6, 0.4), this value was assigned as attribute 2. The remaining attribute was calculated by subtracting 1 from the selected value. For the similarity decoy, we randomly selected one attribute value from the range [0.6, 0.65]. When the target was (0.4, 0.6), this value was assigned as attribute 1. When the target was (0.6, 0.4), this value was assigned as attribute 2. The remaining attribute was calculated by subtracting 1 from the selected value.</p><p>Next, we selected an attribute weight parameter in the range 0.3 &lt; w &lt; 0.7. Finally, we selected attention parameters in the range 1 &lt; λ &lt; 20 for the similarity and dissimilarity model variants. For each of the 1000 simulations, we simulated 10,000 choices for the two model variants and computed RST similarity − RST dissimilarity . <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> visualizes the results by plotting a histogram of the differences for each effect.</p><p>As shown in the figure, the distribution of differences is almost entirely above zero for the attraction and compromise effects. This implies that the model framework almost always predicts a larger RST value under a similarity-based attention mechanism as compared to a dissimilarity-based attention mechanism for these two effects. This is consistent with previous simulations (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4)</ref> showing that a similarity-based attention mechanism can produce the attraction and compromise effects whereas a dissimilarity-based attention mechanism can lead to null or reserved attraction and compromise effects. The distribution of differences for the similarity effect is skewed left and centered just below zero. This implies that for the similarity effect, the model framework predicts either no difference in RST values between model variants or a larger RST value for dissimilarity-based attention as compared to similarity-based attention. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 7</head><p>Simulation study comparing similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention mechanisms: Individual plots show the difference in RST values simulated from the similarity model variant and dissimilarity model variant for the three context effects.</p><p>In the following sections, we present three behavioral experiments that were aimed at testing the model-based predictions shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> for the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects. Each experiment involved choices between three alternatives with two attributes. We manipulated similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention by asking participants to identify the pair of options with the most similar attribute values (similarity condition) or the least similar attribute values (dissimilarity condition) before making a choice.</p><p>Our primary focus is on the difference between similarity and dissimilarity attention conditions instead of the presence and absence of the three effects. There are many other factors that can influence the existence of context effects, such as the spatial arrangement of options (as discussed in a later section and in <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hasan et al. (2023)</ref> and the commensurability of attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Hayes et al., 2024)</ref>. Thus, the cleanest test of similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention is to directly compare RST values in conditions attempting to manipulate the two forms of attention. However, for each effect, we also provide information on RST values from the two attention conditions separately and note when these are consistent with the model simulations shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Transparency and openness</head><p>For Experiments 1-3, we report how we determined our sample size, all data exclusions (if any), all manipulations, and all measures in the study. All data and materials are available on the Open Science Framework (OSF) at https://osf.io/5y7mp/?view_only=1e998c595e3840a9802e1b8a95004fe0. Data were analyzed using the python package PyMC3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Salvatier et al., 2016)</ref>. This study's design and its analysis were pre-registered on OSF at https://osf.io/9bufg.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1: Attraction Effect</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>As described in the pre-registration, we targeted a sample size of approximately 300 participants with half of the participants in the similarity-based attention condition and the other half of participants in the dissimilarity-based attention condition. The sample size was based on the sample size and power analysis of the attraction effect from <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hasan et al. (2023)</ref>. 291 participants (male = 173, female = 115, non-binary = 2, unreported = 1; age: M = 42.94 , SD = 12.02) recruited via Amazon Mechanical Turk using the CloudResearch platform completed the experiment, which was approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB) at Indiana University <ref type="bibr">(#16178)</ref>. N = 149 were randomly assigned to the similarity condition and N = 142 were assigned to the dissimilarity condition. One participant was excluded from the similarity condition due to a computer error which impacted their data file. The data were analyzed only after all data had been collected. All participants were compensated $1.00 for the completion of the study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>Participants were asked to make investment decisions about businesses, based upon ratings from two financial advisors. Ratings ranged between 0 to 100 with 0 implying a very low likelihood of a good return on investment (ROI) and 100 indicating a very high likelihood of a good ROI. The attribute values of each option were based on those used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Trueblood (2012)</ref>.</p><p>Four types of businesses were used to examine the attraction effect: two focal options (X and Y ) and two attraction decoys (A x and A y ). The two decoy options were similar, but inferior to their associated focal option (e.g., A x was similar, but inferior to X). In addition to choice sets examining the attraction effect, the experiment also included filler choice sets where there was a clearly superior option (i.e., a business that dominated the others on both attributes). In total, there were 10 attraction effect trials with the A x decoy, 10 attraction effect trials with the A y decoy, and 10 filler trials. For the attraction effect trials, the specific attribute values for each option varied slightly across trials. The mean and standard deviation of the attribute values for the attraction effect options are provided in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>. The full list of stimuli are available on OSF. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedures</head><p>To examine the effect of similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention mechanisms on context effects, participants were randomly assigned to one of two between-subject conditions (similarity or dissimilarity) at the beginning of the experiment.</p><p>At the start of the experiment, participants were told that they would be making investment decisions about businesses. They were told that on each trial, they would see three different businesses and to select the one that they would like to invest in. They were also told that they would be given ratings from two financial advisors. The ratings were described to participants as providing the likelihood of a good return on investment (ROI), with a rating of 0 implying a very low likelihood of a good ROI and a rating of 100 implying a very high likelihood of a good ROI.</p><p>Additionally, participants were told that the evaluations of businesses can vary from advisor to advisor. Thus, two different financial advisors can provide different ratings. Participants were told to treat the ratings from both advisors equally. The full set of instructions are available on OSF.</p><p>At the beginning of each trial, participants were presented with three businesses and their ROI ratings from two advisors <ref type="figure">(Figure 8</ref>). For example, on trials testing the attraction effect, the three businesses consisted of the focal options X and Y and a decoy option (either A x or A y ). The options and their attributes were displayed in a table with the different options in different rows and the two attributes in separate columns. The row locations of the options were randomized.</p><p>Before making their choice on each trial, all participants completed a similarity judgment task (see <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref> for an example). In the similarity condition, participants were asked to identify the pair of options having the most similar values on each attribute, separately. First, they were queried about attribute 1 (i.e., Advisor 1) followed by attribute 2 (i.e., Advisor 2). Participants received feedback following each judgment. After both judgments, the participants selected the business they preferred <ref type="figure">(Figure 8</ref>). In the dissimilarity condition, participants were asked to identify the pair of options having the most dissimilar values on each attribute prior to the investment decisions. Similar to the similarity condition, participants were asked about attribute 1 before attribute 2 and received feedback on each judgment. After participants made their pairwise</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 8</head><p>Example of a trial in Experiments 1-3. On a given trial, participants first judged the similarity (or dissimilarity) of the options along attribute 1. Next, they judged the similarity (or dissimilarity) of the options along attribute 2. Finally, they made a decision about their preferred investment. After their choice, the participants proceeded to the next trial. An example of an attraction effect trial in the similarity condition is shown. similarity/dissimilarity judgment, the attribute values of the correct pair of options were shown in bold font and the font size of these values increased from 30 px to 45 px. Thus, the most similar/dissimilar options were shown in large, bold font when participants were making their investment decision. After making their decision, participants proceeded to the next trial.</p><p>Participants did not receive feedback about their decision. The order of the trials was fully randomized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>No participants were excluded from the analyses. We also note that the filler trials were removed from these analyses. We used a hierarchical Bayesian model to estimate the difference in RST values (equation 1; <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Berkowitsch et al., 2014)</ref> between the similarity and dissimilarity conditions. The model estimates the RST for each condition separately as well as the difference in RST values between conditions. An analysis using a modified version of RST <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Katsimpokis et al., 2023)</ref> yielded nearly identical results and is provided in the Supplemental Materials.</p><p>The model we used is an extension of the one used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Trueblood (2015)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. (2015)</ref>. It is a beta-binomial model where the number of times the target is selected follows a binomial distribution: Binomial(θ, n), where θ represents the probability that the target is selected and n is the number of times the target plus the competitor are selected. We estimated a separate θ parameter for each person. We also assumed that the person-specific θ parameters were drawn from population-level beta distributions with mean (µ) and concentration (κ) parameters.</p><p>We allowed for separate µ and κ parameters for the similarity and dissimilarity conditions. The priors for the hyper-parameters were set to be relatively vague, with µ ∼ Beta(1, 1) and κ ∼ |N(0, 10)|. The model also estimates the difference between conditions as δ = µ similarity − µ dissimilarity . See the Supplemental Materials for the graphical model. The model was fit using the python package PyMC3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Salvatier et al., 2016)</ref>. Four Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) chains with 5000 samples each were used to estimate the posterior distributions. All chains converged with R-hat values less than 1.1. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> shows the posterior mean and the 95% highest posterior density (HPD) interval for δ and the µ parameters for each condition. For δ, if the HPD interval is above 0, that suggests the similarity condition produced a larger RST value than the dissimilarity condition. If the HPD interval for µ is above 0.5, that suggests the target was selected more than the competitor, indicating an attraction effect. Likewise, if the HPD interval for µ is below 0.5, that suggests the competitor is selected more than the target, indicating a reverse attraction effect. As shown in the table, δ is positive and the HPD interval does not include zero. This shows that the similarity condition produced a larger RST value than the dissimilarity condition, in line with our model simulations shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>. Further, an attraction effect is observed in the similarity condition, and a reverse attraction effect is observed in the dissimilarity condition. In both cases, the HPD interval excludes 0.5. These results are illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref> and are in line with the model simulations shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>.</p><p>As described in the pre-registration, we also analyzed the data using only those participants who achieved at least 60% accuracy in selecting the most similar (dissimilar) attributes in the first part of each trial. As shown in the Supplementary Materials, the results are unchanged. Further, the difference (δ) is larger when restricting the analyses to those with high accuracy in detecting similar (dissimilar) attributes. This is in line with our prediction that increased attention to similar (dissimilar) options modulates the RST value.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attraction Effect Similarity Effect Compromise Effect</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 9</head><p>Behavioral results for Experiments 1-3: The relative choice share of the target for two conditions where attention was directed either towards similar options or dissimilar options for three context effects: attraction (Experiment 1), similarity (Experiment 2), and compromise (Experiment 3). Bars show the mean RST, error bars show the 95% confidence interval, and grey dots show the individual RST values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2: Similarity Effect</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Similar to Experiment 1 and as described in the pre-registration, we aimed for a sample size of around 300 participants, split between the similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention conditions. 297 participants (male = 134, female = 159, non-binary = 2, genderqueer = 1, unreported = 1; age: M = 44.19 , SD = 13.06) recruited via Amazon Mechanical Turk using the CloudResearch platform completed the experiment, which was approved by the IRB at Indiana University (#16178). N = 147 were randomly assigned to the similarity condition and N = 150</p><p>were assigned to the dissimilarity condition. One participant was excluded from the similarity condition due to a computer error which impacted their data file. Data analysis began after all data were collected, and participants received $1.00 for completing the study. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>Similar to Experiment 1, participants were asked to choose their preferred business based on the ROI ratings from two financial advisors. There were four options used to examine the similarity effect: two focal options and two similarity decoys (S x and S y ). Like Experiment 1, this experiment also included filler choice sets where there was a clearly superior option. In total, there were 10 similarity effect trials with the S x decoy, 10 similarity effect trials with the S y decoy, and 10 filler trials. For the similarity effect trials, the specific attribute values for each option varied slightly across trials. The mean and standard deviation of the attribute values for the similarity effect options are provided in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> and are identical to those used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Trueblood (2012)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedures</head><p>The procedure for Experiment 2 was identical to Experiment 1. Participants were randomly assigned to either the similarity or dissimilarity condition at the beginning of the experiment, and then completed 30 randomized trials. On each trial, participants started with attribute-wise similarity/dissimilarity judgments about the businesses based on their assigned condition. After making these judgments, participants selected the business that they preferred and then proceeded to the next trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>No participants were excluded from the analyses. Similar to Experiment 1, we used a hierarchical Bayesian model to estimate the difference in RST values between the  <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> shows the posterior mean and the 95% HPD interval for δ and the two µ parameters. As shown in the table, the HPD interval for δ is below 0, suggesting that the dissimilarity-based attention condition produced a larger RST value than the similarity-based attention condition. This result is consistent with the model simulations shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>.</p><p>Additionally, we observe a similarity effect (i.e., RST &gt; 0.5) in the dissimilarity-based attention condition and a weak reverse similarity effect (i.e., RST &lt; 0.5) in the similarity-based attention condition (see <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref>).</p><p>In the Supplemental Materials, we also analyzed the data using only those participants who achieved at least 60% accuracy in selecting the most similar (dissimilar) attributes in the first part of each trial. The results are unchanged after exclusions. Additionally, the difference (δ) is larger when restricting the analyses to those with high accuracy in detecting similar (dissimilar) attributes, consistent with our prediction that increased attention to similar (dissimilar) options modulates the RST value. to the similarity condition and N = 149 were assigned to the dissimilarity condition. Two participants were excluded from the similarity condition due to a computer error that impacted their data file. Data analysis began after all data were collected, and participants received $1.00</p><p>for completing the study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>Similar to Experiments 1 and 2, participants in Experiment 3 made investment decisions based on the ROI ratings from two financial advisors. There were four options used to examine the compromise effect: two focal options and two compromise decoys (C x and C y ). Like the other experiments, Experiment 3 also included filler choice sets where there was a clearly superior option. In total, there were 10 compromise effect trials with the C x decoy, 10 compromise effect trials with the C y decoy, and 10 filler trials. For the compromise effect trials, the specific attribute values for each option varied slightly across trials. The mean and standard deviation of the attribute values for the compromise effect options are provided in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>. Note that the distance between the compromise decoy and the target is 2-units less than the distance between the target and competitor, so that the answer to the similarity ratings is unique on each trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedures</head><p>The procedure for Experiment 3 was identical to Experiments 1 and 2. Participants were randomly assigned to either the similarity-based or dissimilarity-based attention condition at the beginning of the experiment, and then completed 30 randomized trials. On each trial, participants first made two attribute-wise similarity/dissimilarity judgments based on their condition, and then they selected their preferred business.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>No participants were excluded from the analyses. Similar to Experiments 1 and 2, we used a hierarchical Bayesian model to estimate the difference in RST values between the similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention conditions and to test for the presence of the compromise effect in each condition. The approach and model specifications were identical to Experiments 1 and 2. An analysis using a modified version of RST <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Katsimpokis et al., 2023)</ref> yielded nearly identical results (see Supplemental Materials). <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> shows the posterior mean and the 95% HPD interval for δ and the two µ parameters. As shown in the table, the HPD interval for δ is above 0, suggesting that the similarity-based attention condition produced a larger RST value than the dissimilarity-based attention condition, consistent with the model simulations shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>. Additionally, we observe a compromise effect (i.e., RST &gt; 0.5) in the similarity-based attention condition and a null effect (i.e., RST ≈ 0.5) in the dissimilarity-based attention condition (see <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref>).</p><p>As in Experiments 1 and 2, we also analyzed the data using only those participants who achieved at least 60% accuracy in selecting the most similar (dissimilar) attributes in the first part of each trial. The results are unchanged after exclusions (see Supplemental Material). Similar to Experiments 1 and 2, the difference (δ) is larger when restricting the analyses to those with high accuracy in detecting similar (dissimilar) attributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion of Experiments 1-3</head><p>Experiments 1-3 examined differences between similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention for the attraction, similarity, and compromise effects. We observed that by encouraging participants to attend to similar versus dissimilar options, we can modulate the proportion of times participants selected the target over the competitor, as measured by the RST. Further, the changes we observed in the behavioral data follow the model predictions shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>.</p><p>Additionally, the pattern of context effects we observed is generally in line with the model predictions shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. In the similarity-based attention condition, we observed strong attraction and compromise effects and a weak reverse similarity effect. The similarity model variant (right panel in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>) also predicts the presence of the attraction and compromise effects. This model can also produce the similarity effect, but only for a narrow range of similarity decoys. As shown in the figure, the similarity decoy needs to be located very close to the competitor in order for the effect to arise. It is possible that our lack of a similarity effect in the behavioral data is related to the positioning of the decoy. In the dissimilarity-based attention condition, we observed a reverse attraction effect, null compromise effect, and strong similarity effect. The dissimilarity model variant (middle panel in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>) also predicts a reverse attraction effect and a strong similarity effect. Depending on the position of the decoy, the model predicts a reverse or null compromise effect.</p><p>Overall, we find the consistency between the behavioral and model simulation results compelling. We believe these results demonstrate that similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention contributes to the elusive nature of context effects. In the next section, we explore the role of spatial attention and context effects.</p><p>Spatial Attention: Reanalysis of <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. 2015</ref> In <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. (2015)</ref> the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects were examined using the perceptual paradigm developed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Trueblood et al. (2013)</ref> where participants made decisions about the size of rectangles. In addition to studying the three effects within participants, the <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. (2015)</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Transparency and openness</head><p>All data are available on the OSF at https://osf.io/5y7mp/?view_only=1e998c595e3840a9802e1b8a95004fe0. Data were analyzed using the python package PyMC3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Salvatier et al., 2016)</ref>. This study's analysis was not pre-registered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Seventy-five participants took part in the experiment in exchange for course credit. On each trial, participants were shown three rectangles and asked to choose the one with the largest area. The rectangles were solid black and appeared on a white background. The height and width of the rectangles were varied in order to generate choice sets for the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects (similar to attributes of price and quality in studies of context effects with consumer products). For each choice set, the two focal rectangles had equal area, but one rectangle had larger height and smaller width than the other. We note that much of the research on context effects uses stimuli with clearly separable attributes (e.g., price and quality). Previous research has shown that height and width of rectangles are perceived separately and then integrated to form area estimates <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Anderson &amp; Weiss, 1971)</ref>.</p><p>Participants completed 720 trials: 160 with attraction effect choice sets, with similarity effect choice sets, 160 with compromise effect choice sets, and 240 filler trials where one rectangle was clearly the largest. For the context effects choice sets, half of the choice sets included a decoy targeting one of the two focal options and the other half of the choice sets included a decoy targeting the other focal option. The trials were fully randomized. The left to right placement of the options was also randomized, resulting in six distinct orders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>No participants were excluded from the analyses. Similar to Experiments 1-3, we used a hierarchical Bayesian model to test for the presence of the three context effects across the six different orders. The model specifications were similar to Experiments 1-3. The graphical model is provided in the supplemental materials. The model was fit using PyMC3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Salvatier et al., 2016)</ref>. Four Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) chains with 5000 samples each were used to estimate the posterior distributions. All chains converged with R-hat values less than 1.1. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref> shows the posterior mean and the 95% HPD interval for the µ parameter, estimated separately for the three effects and six orders. Results show that for some spatial orders standard effects emerge, but for other orders, null or reversed effects occur (see both <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref> and <ref type="figure">Figure 10</ref>). We hypothesize that the observed differences in RST values across the different orders reflect biases in spatial attention. In particular, we suggest that greater attention is allocated to adjacent options as compared to non-adjacent options. In particular, when the target is the middle option (i.e., CTD, DTC), it is adjacent to both the decoy and competitor. In this case, the target receives more attention and thus accumulates evidence faster than the other options, leading to standard context effects. Likewise, when the competitor is the middle option (i.e., TCD, DCT), it receives more attention, resulting in null or reversed context effects. In the remaining two cases (i.e., TDC, CDT), results are mixed.</p><p>For TDC, all three standard effects occur. However, for CDT, only a standard similarity effect occurs. We believe the difference here is the left versus right placement of the target. When the target is placed in the leftmost position, we believe it receives enhanced attention because English (the primary language of our participants) is a left-to-right writing system. For the model, we simulated synthetic data from the similarity attention variant accounting for effects of spatial location of the alternatives on attention. Specifically, we assumed that comparison of adjacent alternatives is ∼ 2.5 times more likely than comparison of non-adjacent alternatives. The alternative attribute values were in each case T = (0.4, 0.6), C = (0.6, 0.4) with D A = (0.3, 0.5), D C = (0.2, 0.8), D S = (0.55, 0.45). For the parameters, the attribute weight was w = 0.5, the threshold b = 0.2 and the attention parameter was λ = 2.5 for the attraction and similarity effects and λ = 7.5 for the compromise effect.</p><p>To further examine the impact of spatial attention biases on context effects, we performed a model simulation exercise using the similarity model variant. For these simulations, we allowed for the effects of spatial location on attention allocation. In particular, we assumed that the comparison of adjacent options is ∼ 2.5 times more likely than comparison of non-adjacent options. For these simulations, we used artificial stimuli values, not stimuli values from the task.</p><p>Our goal here is to simply show that the modeling framework can qualitatively produce the observed behavioral patterns. In a later section, we quantitatively fit and evaluate the modeling framework using this data. The attribute values for the simulations were T = (0.4, 0.6), C = (0.6, 0.4) with D A = (0.3, 0.5), D S = (0.55, 0.45), D C = (0.2, 0.8), where D A , D S , and D C are the decoys for the attraction, similarity, and compromise effects respectively. In these simulations, we fixed the attribute weight at w = 0.5, the threshold at b = 0.2 and the attention parameter at λ = 2.5 for the attraction and similarity effects and λ = 7.5 for the compromise effect (a larger value of λ more robustly produces the compromise effect).</p><p>The general qualitative pattern from the model is similar to the data. In particular, we observe standard effects when the target is the middle option and reversed / null effects when the competitor is the middle option. We also note that there are discrepancies between the model simulations and data. This suggests there are aspects of the data the model simulations fail to capture. However, the simple spatial attention process does appear to capture the gross pattern that the target gets a boost when it is the middle option.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The reanalysis of <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. (2015)</ref> revealed that the display layout of options had a large impact on the presence / absence of context effects. We hypothesized that changes in display layout might impact how attention is allocated in the task and thus alter context effects.</p><p>To this end, we conducted model simulations examining how biases in spatial attention influence context effects. The modeling results were qualitatively consistent with the behavioral findings, suggesting that simple biases in attention can have large impacts on choice behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Quantitative Evaluation of the Modeling Framework</head><p>To further evaluate the importance and influence of similarity and spatial based attention factors in these decisions, we quantitatively fit four versions of this model to the full choice-RT data from <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. (2015)</ref>. We toggle similarity and spatial factors in and out of the framework (resulting in four models). For the similarity factor, we used the same exponential dependence of deliberation time on similarity; more similar comparisons are compared for longer duration. When this factor is not included, all comparisons are distributed equally (i.e., independent model variant).</p><p>For spatial attention, we included two additional parameters (p LM , p RM ) that alter the weights for different comparisons. This accounts for potential biases for adjacent options and left versus right comparisons. When this factor is not present, all comparisons are equally probable.</p><p>The most extensive version of this model containing both factors has the following seven estimable parameters: threshold (b), attribute weight (w), non-decision time (t nd ), a drift rate scaling parameter (v scale ), the similarity decay parameter (λ), and the two spatial probability parameters (p LM , p RM ). The drift rate scaling parameter is a methodological parameter that converts attribute units into the preference domain. This is necessary for mathematical consistency (the left and right side of the preference updating equation must have the same units) and is discussed further in the Supplemental Materials. The simplest version of the model that omits both factors contains only four parameters (b, w,t nd , v scale ). We also note that we use the log of the attribute values (i.e., height and width) to handle the fact that height and width multiplicatively contribute to the area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Continuous model extension and model fitting procedure</head><p>The fully stochastic version of this model can in principle be fit to choice-RT data using simulation based methods such as the Probability Density Approximation (PDA) method <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Holmes, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Holmes and Trueblood, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Holmes et al., 2016)</ref>. This is computationally cumbersome however. We thus develop a continuous approximation to this model that utilizes stochastic differential equations in place of full stochastic simulations. Full details of the description, derivation, and validation of this are in the Supplementary Materials. We briefly note however that this approximation is theoretically grounded. It is essentially the asymptotic limit that results from taking the simulation time step in the stochastic model ∆T → 0.</p><p>The end result of this approximation is a model of the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">d ⃗ P = v scale * ⃗ vdt +⃗ σd⃗ w,<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where P is a time varying vector of preferences, ⃗ v is a vector of accumulation rates, ⃗ σ is a vector of variances, and v scale is the previously mentioned methodological scaling parameter. Note that This approximation to the stochastic model is an independent race (IR) to threshold model. That is, it is three stochastic accumulators independently racing to the choice threshold,</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">(⃗ v</formula><p>where the first one to reach that threshold is the chosen alternative. The significant benefit of this simplification is that IR models have known, analytically solvable choice-RT distributions based on the Wald / Inverse Gaussian distribution (see Supplemental Materials). This dramatically simplifies the choice-RT fitting process without sacrificing any of the core characteristics of the modeling framework.</p><p>To fit this model, we use a Bayesian approach to fit full choice-RT data, accounting for the spatial order of presented alternatives. Following prior studies, we use Differential Evolution MCMC (DEMC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">(Turner et al., 2013)</ref>. Prior to fitting these models, parameter recovery was demonstrated (Supplemental Materials) using the same experimental design and stimuli as the experiment itself.  <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref> illustrates the quality of fit for the four model variants by comparing choice proportions and mean RTs derived from the posterior mean parameter sets for each individual with those from data. Results illustrate that both similarity and spatial attention factors are needed to provide a reasonable account of the data. When only one attention factor is present, the model performs quantitatively worse. More importantly, the single factor models predict higher competitor than target choice proportions, which is qualitatively contrary to data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>We further analyzed the distribution of participants' posterior mean parameter values for the model with both similarity and spatial attention included <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">(Figure 12</ref> attribute weight is generally close to 0.5, which is reasonable since the two attributes in question are length and width of rectangles. The similarity decay parameter λ is significantly different from 0. Finally, participants broadly show an adjacency bias, but not a substantial bias for comparisons involving left or right options.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Context effects in choice, particularly the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects, have received considerable attention over the last several decades. Yet despite being observed across multiple cognitive domains <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Farmer et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Farmer et al., , 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Maylor &amp; Roberts, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Trueblood, 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Trueblood, , 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Trueblood et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Wedell, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b82">Yearsley et al., 2021)</ref> and across multiple species <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bateson et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Latty &amp; Trueblood, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Parrish et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Shafir et al., 2002)</ref>, they have proven to be simultaneously fragile <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Spektor et al., 2021)</ref>. In this paper, we introduced a novel modeling framework that explains the elusive nature of context effects. Using this framework, we demonstrate how the presence, absence, and reversal of classic context effects can be explained by variations in the attention process during evidence accumulation.</p><p>The idea that attention is important for understanding context effects is shared by most dynamic models of context effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Trueblood, 2022)</ref>. These models have, in many cases, assumed that alternatives are compared to each other in a pairwise fashion, that comparisons between more similar alternatives receive greater weight, and that all alternatives and attributes cannot be simultaneously attended to. Our work extends and generalizes these prior theories. Specifically, the framework described here assumes that only one comparison on one attribute can be attended to at any given time but that the sequence of comparisons is governed by a structured attention process. Rather than assume a fixed attention process (i.e. similarity-based), we explore a range of different attention processes and their consequences on choices. Results show that when more similar alternatives are compared for longer periods of time, the classic context effects arise. However, if that attention processes is altered (e.g., dissimilar alternative are compared for longer periods of time), the effects can disappear or reverse, as has been found in a number of recent empirical studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Cataldo &amp; Cohen, 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Evans et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Spektor et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Importantly, our framework also allows for intrinsic factors, such as an individual's attribute biases, and extrinsic factors, such as the spatial arrangement of options in the choice display, to enter into the attention process. In sum, our work illustrates that attentional dynamics are key to understanding why context effects can be simultaneously general and fragile.</p><p>We validated our modeling framework using a combination of behavioral experiments and a reanalysis of previously published data. Results from Experiments 1-3 showed that by simply encouraging participants to attend to similar versus dissimilar options, we were able to modulate the strength of the three effects in ways that were consistent with model predictions. To test whether attentional biases arising from the spatial layout of items may alter context effects, we reanalyzed data from <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. (2015)</ref>. In that study the attraction, similarity, and compromise effects occurred when the target was the middle option, whereas null or reverse effects occurred when the competitor was the middle option. Our results indicate this is a consequence of people's preference for comparing spatially adjacent options more than nonadjacent options. This result, in particular, illustrates how easily experimental factors can alter empirical findings. In summary, our findings illustrate the critical role of attention in the generation of context effects. Further, this modeling approach provides a way to disentangle different factors that may influence attention and their potential effects on observations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relationships to Other Modeling Approaches</head><p>Over the past several decades, a wide range of mathematical and computational models have been developed to account for context effects in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice.</p><p>These models span disciplines including economics, marketing, psychology, and neuroscience. They include cognitive models that focus on the dynamic processes of decision-making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Roe et al., 2001)</ref>, as well as rational models based on Bayesian belief updating (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Rigoli et al., 2017</ref>).</p><p>Our modeling framework builds on ideas from previous cognitive models of context effects, particularly the idea that attention plays an important role in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Trueblood, 2022)</ref>. Although our goal was not to introduce a new model to test against others in a head-to-head comparison, it is informative to compare and contrast the present modeling approach with alternative theories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relationship to Dynamic Cognitive Models</head><p>Most dynamic cognitive models assume that individuals shift a window of attention throughout deliberation to evaluate various options. Here we highlight three models, MDFT <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Roe et al., 2001</ref>), MLBA <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Trueblood et al., 2014)</ref>, and multialternative decision by sampling (MDbS; <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Noguchi and Stewart, 2018)</ref>, to illustrate the relationship between the current framework and existing theories. We refer readers to <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Trueblood (2022)</ref>  Additionally, both MDbS and MLBA incorporate some notion of similarity-based attention. In MDbS, the probability of evaluating the value of an option on a particular attribute is proportional to the similarity between that option's value and other values in working memory, including values retrieved from long-term memory (e.g., memory of prices from past experience).</p><p>In MLBA, the attention weight for each pairwise comparison depends on the similarity of the values being compared. The present framework allows for similarity to affect the amount of time spent on each comparison. For example, in the similarity model variant, greater similarity among options leads to longer deliberation time for the comparison of those options.</p><p>We also point out some key differences between the current framework and previous modeling approaches. The current framework is stochastic rather than ballistic as is the case for Another important distinction between our framework and past approaches is that we show that a single mechanism, namely similarity-based attention, is sufficient for producing the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4)</ref>. In other dynamic models, additional mechanisms are required to produce at least one of the three effects. For example, MDFT accounts for the attraction and compromise effects using distance-dependent lateral inhibition <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Roe et al., 2001)</ref>, MLBA accounts for all three effects using a combination of similarity-based attention and asymmetric weighting of advantages and disadvantages <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Trueblood et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Tsetsos et al., 2015)</ref>, and MDbS accounts for the similarity effect by assuming that people tend to ignore relatively small differences <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2018)</ref>. Our results show that while these factors may be present, they are not necessary and attention alone can lead to the contextual sensitivities observed in the classic effects.</p><p>Notably, MDbS was shown to qualitatively account for a broader range of behavioral phenomena beyond the three classic context effects, including (but not limited to) the effects of previously experienced values on subsequent evaluations <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Stewart et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">Ungemach et al., 2011)</ref>, the negative impact of familiarity on the attraction and compromise effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Kim &amp; Hasher, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Sheng et al., 2005)</ref>, attribute alignability <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Markman &amp; Medin, 1995)</ref>, attribute balance <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Chernev, 2005)</ref>, and attribute spacing effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Cooke &amp; Mellers, 1998</ref>) (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> in <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Noguchi and Stewart, 2018</ref> for a full list). MDbS explains many of these phenomena through its assumption that previously experienced attribute values can be sampled from long-term memory and compared to the attribute values in the immediate choice context. For example, greater familiarity with the choice domain implies that decision makers have a larger sample of attributes that they can sample from memory, which will tend to "dilute" the impact of comparisons in the immediate context and thereby weaken the attraction and compromise effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2018)</ref>. Our modeling framework could be augmented to include comparisons with previously experienced outcomes, which would allow it to capture these effects as well. Other phenomena, such as the attribute balance effect, can be explained in both MDbS and the current framework by assuming that the choice presentation format influences the likelihood of attending to different types of comparisons (e.g., comparisons across attribute dimensions, which are assumed to drive the attribute balance effect in MDbS, should be more likely when the dimensions are commensurable; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Hayes et al., 2024)</ref>. The simplicity and flexibility of our modeling framework makes it easy to incorporate additional assumptions and broaden the range of phenomena that it can explain.</p><p>Our framework explicitly models the attention process during deliberation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Gluth et al. (2024)</ref> also propose a model of how attention is allocated during multi-attribute choice. Their model provides a theory of how people search for additional information (i.e., attribute values) during deliberation. The model is implemented as a hierarchical Bayesian framework with a set of layers to represent belief distributions regarding attribute values, which subsequently serve as the foundation for belief distributions over the values of options. They apply their model to two alternative decisions where each alternative is described by multiple attributes. At the time of writing, the model does not account for context effects among three options.</p><p>Another approach is to use empirical measures of visual attention (i.e., gaze data) as input to the evidence accumulation process, as in the attentional drift diffusion model <ref type="bibr">(aDDM;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Krajbich et al., 2010)</ref>. This approach is fundamentally different from the one proposed here: One makes a priori assumptions about the way in which attention fluctuates between different pieces of information and how it influences choice, while the other uses exogenous measures of visual attention to inform the model without explaining why gaze is allocated that way in the first place.</p><p>Only a few models have attempted to explain the allocation and timing of visual fixations during the deliberation process (for example, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Callaway et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Gluth et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Jang et al., 2021)</ref>. The aDDM has proven to be quite useful as a tool for understanding the moderating effects of visual attention on value-based decision making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Fisher, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Krajbich, 2018, 2019</ref>; for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Krajbich, 2019)</ref>. It does not however attempt to understand the process responsible for the allocation of attention. Recently, gaze-dependent evidence accumulation models have also been leveraged to study context effects in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Molter et al., 2022)</ref>. However, because attention is treated as an exogenous variable in the aDDM and other gaze-dependent models, the models make no predictions for the effect that different spatial layouts, for example, will have on attention and (consequently) decision making.</p><p>The behavior of these models depends on the eye movement data that gets fed into them. In contrast, the present framework allows us to incorporate different theories about the role of spatial and other presentation-related factors into the model's attention process in order to examine their predicted effects on choice behavior. In the Future Directions section, we return to the topic of eye-tracking measures and how they might be used to supplement our modeling framework.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relationship to Rational Models</head><p>The modeling framework proposed here follows in the tradition of evidence-accumulation models <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Ratcliff, 1978)</ref>, which represent the temporal dynamics underlying choices. However, not all psychological models of context effects rely on dynamic or mechanistic processes. A second class of models stems from the tradition of rational analysis and Bayesian decision theory.</p><p>These models seek to explain context effects as rational responses to uncertainty or to the structure of the environment. Bayesian account in which the value of an option corresponds to a precision-weighted prediction error. This framework explains the three classic context effects as well as between-choice context effects (i.e., how past options impact current choices). A third approach by <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Howes et al. (2016)</ref> shows that the three context effects can be understood as expected value maximizing choices under noisy observations. In their model, context effects arise as optimal adaptations to limitations in perceptual and cognitive processing.</p><p>One key benefit of rational models is that they provide normative benchmarks for understanding behavior, showing how context effects can arise as optimal responses to uncertainty, limited information, or environmental structure. By grounding explanations in principles of Bayesian inference or expected utility maximization, these models can help clarify when seemingly irrational behaviors -such as preference reversals -may actually be adaptive.</p><p>This contrasts with cognitive models, which typically focus on the underlying mental processes and often require assumptions about attention, memory, or neural dynamics to account for the At present, we are not aware of any rational models that account for the elusive nature of context effects -specifically, why such effects sometimes appear, disappear, or even reverse. One particularly challenging case involves the influence of spatial arrangement on context effects, as highlighted in the reanalysis of <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. (2015)</ref>. It remains unclear how a purely rational framework would account for these spatial influences. In contrast, the modeling approach proposed here can capture these findings by incorporating psychologically plausible assumptions about how attention shapes the preference accumulation process. Developing rational models that can accommodate these complex patterns of behavior represent an important direction for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>An Alternative Explanation of the Elusiveness of Context Effects</head><p>Like other dynamic decision models, our theoretical framework relies on the integration and accumulation of relative comparisons during deliberation to explain the emergence of context effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Busemeyer et al., 2019)</ref>. Moreover, it uses attentional dynamics during the deliberation process to explain the elusiveness of context effects. An alternative explanation, suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Spektor et al. (2021)</ref>, is that the elusiveness of context effects is due to noisiness in the subjective representation of the choice set. Certain features of the choice task, such as the presentation modality (e.g., graphical versus numerical) of the attributes, could make it more difficult for decision makers to obtain an accurate representation of the options. Spektor et al. suggest that when decision makers first encounter a choice, there is some degree of uncertainty or noise in the representation of the options. Although the uncertainty gradually diminishes over the course of deliberation, if the level of uncertainty is high, dominance relationships and attribute orderings will be more difficult to detect, inhibiting the attraction and compromise effects and potentially leading to reversals of these effects. On the other hand, the similarity effect is less likely to be impacted by representational noise because any difficulties in detecting dominance relationships would likely influence the competitor and decoy as opposed to the target. If the level of uncertainty is low, the attraction and compromise effects should not be impacted and standard effects are anticipated.</p><p>Currently, the idea of representational noise has not been incorporated into a formal model of context effects. Future work could explore whether it is possible to extend our framework to allow for uncertainty in the attribute values that changes over time (see for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Lee and Daunizeau, 2021)</ref>. We note that there are many ways of adding noise to models and care must be taken to make sure that the addition of noise does not result in model tractability issues. As of now, our framework explains the elusive nature of context effects purely through subtle changes in attention during the deliberation process, treating the attribute values as given.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Benefits of the Current Modeling Approach</head><p>We have stressed that our proposed model is a framework in the sense that it encompasses many possible model variants. For example, we showed how three different assumptions about the relationship between similarity and deliberation time could be incorporated into the framework.</p><p>Further, attribute biases and spatial attention mechanisms can be encoded in the conditional transition matrix that contains the probabilities of switching to different comparisons. A model variant in which comparisons between adjacent options are more probable than comparisons between nonadjacent options was able to account for spatial order effects present in previously published data <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">(Trueblood et al., 2015)</ref>. The flexibility of our modeling framework is one of its primary advantages, and there are many other possible modifications that could be made.</p><p>Another advantage of the current modeling framework is that it can be fit to choice-RT data and that its parameters are recoverable (see Supplemental Materials). This is important, as other dynamic models of context effects have been shown to have relatively poor parameter recovery <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Evans et al., 2019)</ref>. Complex models with many parameters often have strong parameter trade-offs, where increases in one parameter can be compensated by decreases in another (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Miletić et al., 2017)</ref>. When this occurs, the parameters are said to be weakly identified and it is no longer possible to reliably interpret the parameter estimates. Because our model exhibits good recovery of parameters, we can use the parameters to draw inferences about the underlying cognitive processes mediating choice behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Future Directions</head><p>Future studies should further investigate the factors that influence context effects. We show that spatial order has a large influence on the three effects. In addition to spatial order, <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Spektor et al. (2021)</ref> identified presentation layout, attribute concreteness, and deliberation time as possible factors that impact context effects. Presentation layout refers to tabular presentations of options where attributes are either presented in columns (a by-attribute format) or rows (a by-alternative format). Attribute concreteness refers to the mode of presentation where options can be presented numerically (high concreteness) or visually / graphically (low concreteness). In a recent registered report, <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hasan et al. (2023)</ref> tested the influence of spatial order, presentation layout, and attribute concreteness on the attraction effect. They found that spatial order and attribute concreteness influenced the attraction effect, but presentation layout did not. Other research has identified attribute commensurability as an important factor that can influence the attraction and compromise effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Hayes et al., 2024)</ref>. When attributes are difficult to compare within an option (e.g., price and quality), the effects are stronger than when attributes are easy to compare within an option (e.g., ratings from two reviewers). <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Hayes et al. (2024)</ref> showed that an extension of the modeling framework introduced in this paper can account for this phenomenon.</p><p>Future studies should also collect process data to examine the assumptions of the proposed framework. Eye tracking methods have proven to be particularly useful for this purpose.</p><p>For example, eye tracking studies have shown that in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice tasks, pairs of options are compared on single attributes at a time <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2014)</ref>, pairs of similar options are attended to more frequently than pairs of dissimilar options <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2014</ref>, and the inclusion of asymmetrically dominated decoys focuses attention on the target option and the dominance attribute <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Marini et al., 2020)</ref>. Alternative methods, such as the hidden-attribute protocol, can also be used to shed light on process mechanisms <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Marini et al., 2022)</ref>. An obvious application of these methods to the current framework would be to test whether people do indeed transition more frequently between adjacent options than nonadjacent options, and whether the ratio of the transition frequencies between adjacent and nonadjacent options is associated with spatial order effects in choice, as predicted by the model variants incorporating spatial attention processes.</p><p>More generally, this framework can serve as a platform to understand the consequences of different attention-related factors on decision making and under what circumstances those factors may be important. A significant strength of our approach is that it allows the researcher to explicitly model attention as part of the decision process. For example, this model could be extended to account for potential sequential dependencies in attention. For mathematical tractability, we have assumed that the conditional probabilities of transitioning to different comparisons do not depend on the past sequence of comparisons. This is likely overly restrictive and can be expanded upon in future work. Alternative forms of comparison can also be investigated. We have for simplicity assumed comparisons are within-attribute and between two items in the choice set, but comparison against other exemplars may be possible. This is just a sampling of possible extensions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusions</head><p>Context effects in multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice are widely documented and yet, paradoxically, quite fragile. Their elusiveness challenges previous theories of context effects, which have largely focused on explaining the existence of the effects. In this paper, we introduced a novel computational modeling framework that relies on attention modulated comparisons to explain the fragile nature of context effects. The flexibility of our framework makes it possible to test a number of different theories about the role of attention in the deliberation process. Further, we developed and validated a tractable approximation of the full model that can be used to fit choices and response time data. Using this framework, we demonstrate how attention may be critical in understanding the simultaneous generality and fragility of these effects. Generality arises from the properties of attention allocation, while fragility is a result of the ease with which that attention can be altered either intentionally or unintentionally. In summary, the proposed framework is a powerful tool for understanding the elusive nature of context effects through the lens of attentional dynamics during deliberation.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3 Attribute dependent comparison time for attention variants: Sample functions illustrating the dependence of comparison times on attribute differences. In the independent attention variant (blue), attention time does not depend on attributes. In the similarity attention variant (black), more similar alternatives are compared for longer times. In the dissimilarity variant, more distinct alternatives are compared for longer times. The dashed gray line at the bottom reflects that most cases will include a minimum comparison time. For the similarity models we use a function of the shape exp(−λ|x a i − x a j |) where x a i is the value of alternative i on attribute a. For the dissimilarity model, we use a function of the form log(1 + λ|x a i − x a j |). These are convenient functions with the appropriate shape (i.e., they are both monotonic and saturate).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4 Context effects simulation study: To study the effect of adding a decoy alternative to a binary choice, we fix the attribute values of two alternatives (x and y shown on the plot) and vary the location of a third "decoy" alternative. For each decoy value, N = 1000 simulations are run and the number of times each alternative (n(x), n(y), n(d)) is chosen (as determined by the preference accumulation process defined in equation 2) is recorded. Each plot shows the relative share of alternative x as a function of decoy location (n(x)/n(x) + n(y)). The indicated regions on the similarity variant demonstrate it simultaneously accounts for the three classic context effects. For these simulations, we use an attention parameter λ = 5 and threshold b = 0.2.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6 Accumulator mean and variance slopes as a function of λ: Here we quantify the accumulator mean and variance effect seen in Figure 5 as a function of λ. All parameters and values of the target, competitor, and decoy are the same as in Figure 5. The value of the similarity strength parameter λ is varied. For each value, we simulate 1000 independent trials and quantify the mean and variance of the traces as a function of time (see Figure 5). Since these traces are linear, we quantify the slope of mean and variance traces for the target and competitor. Those slopes are then subtracted (target -competitor) to quantify the difference in mean slopes and separately the difference in variance slopes as a function of λ. Red vertical lines indicate the value of λ used for simulations in Figure 5.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>male = 135, female = 161, gender fluid = 1, unreported = 2, age: M = 43.62 , SD = 12.14) were recruited from Amazon Mechanical Turk using the CloudResearch platform and completed the study online (IRB #16178). Similar to Experiments 1 and 2, we intended to have approximately 150 participants per condition. N = 150 were randomly assigned</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>study also manipulated the left to right placement of the options on the screen. Each choice set had three alternatives: target (T), competitor (C), and decoy (D). Thus, participants saw a total of six distinct orders in the experiment: TCD, TDC, CTD, DTC, CDT, and DCT. The main objective of the present analysis is to examine the three effects across the six orders. The original analysis in Trueblood et al. (2015) did not take these different orders into consideration. However, Evans et al. (2021) did use this data to examine the attraction effect for the various orders. Here we also examine the compromise and similarity effects and include the attraction effect for completeness. Below we provide an overview of the methods and refer the reader to Trueblood et al. (2015) for a full description.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>et al. 2015: Behavioral results show the relative choice share of the target for six different spatial orders for three context effects. Bars show the mean RST, error bars show the 95% confidence interval, and grey dots show the individual RST values.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>,⃗ σ) are not estimable parameters. They are fully analytically constructed from the attention process (see Supplemental Materials). ⃗ v represents the average rate of accumulation properly averaged over all possible attention states. ⃗ σ represents the variability in that accumulation rate, accounting for the intrinsic variability of the attention process.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>fitting for<ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. 2015</ref> data with spatial ordering: For each of the four indicated models, we fit the choice -RT data from Trueblood et al. 2015 as described in the methods. To assess quality of fit, we plot the choice proportion and mean response time predicted by the model for each participant against the same quantities from the data. R-squared values quantify this quality of fit and the gray lines indicated the line of agreement.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 12</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Participant parameters for similarity plus spatial attention model: For each of the experimental participants, posterior mean parameter values were calculated. Histograms for λ and w are shown and the joint values of spatial attention parameters are shown.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>for a more in depth review of the role of attention in dynamic context effects models. In MDFT, the window of attention includes all options along a single attribute. In MLBA and MDbS, attention is allocated to a pair of options along a single attribute. In MDFT and MDbS, the window of attention fluctuates stochastically over time, whereas MLBA assigns deterministic attention weights to the set of pairwise comparisons. The present framework assumes an explicit sequence of comparisons over time (specifically pairwise comparisons in the model variants studied here), with a Markov process to describe the probabilities of switching to different comparisons.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>MLBA. MDbS utilizes ordinal comparisons between options instead of allowing the size of the difference between options to influence the rate of evidence accumulation as in our framework. MDFT incorporates several additional mechanisms not currently included in our framework such as distant-dependent lateral inhibition and leakage. Finally, while both MLBA and MDFT have been quantitatively tested using choice-response time data, we are unaware of such testing of MDbS. Doing so would likely require the development of a continuous approximation of the model similar to what was done here and in Evans et al. (2019).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>For example,<ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Shenoy and Yu (2013)</ref> introduced a Bayesian model in which individuals evaluate options relative to an inferred "fair market value" based on prior experience and the current choice set. Their model accounts for all three classic context effects, suggesting that such effects may emerge as rational outcomes of a decision-maker seeking to optimize choice within a relativistic framework shaped by perceived fairness. Similarly,<ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Rigoli et al. (2017)</ref> present a</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>same effects. While cognitive models are essential for capturing the mechanisms of decision-making, rational approaches complement them by revealing the potential function or purpose of observed behaviors.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary of attribute values used in Experiment 1 for the attraction effect</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Rating 1</cell><cell></cell><cell>Rating 2</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Option</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell></row><row><cell>X</cell><cell>34.30</cell><cell>1.59</cell><cell>65.90</cell><cell>1.55</cell></row><row><cell>Y</cell><cell>67.40</cell><cell>1.31</cell><cell>32.80</cell><cell>1.01</cell></row><row><cell>A x</cell><cell>28.90</cell><cell>1.97</cell><cell>60.40</cell><cell>1.65</cell></row><row><cell>A y</cell><cell>61.60</cell><cell>1.07</cell><cell>27.70</cell><cell>1.49</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results for Experiments 1-3</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Attraction</cell><cell></cell><cell>Similarity</cell><cell cols="2">Compromise</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>95% HPD</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>95% HPD</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>95% HPD</cell></row><row><cell>δ</cell><cell>0.250</cell><cell cols="3">0.205 -0.297 -0.157 -0.201 --0.112</cell><cell>0.150</cell><cell>0.102 -0.195</cell></row><row><cell>µ similarity</cell><cell>0.710</cell><cell>0.677 -0.745</cell><cell>0.474</cell><cell>0.437 -0.509</cell><cell>0.666</cell><cell>0.632 -0.699</cell></row><row><cell>µ dissimilarity</cell><cell>0.460</cell><cell>0.428 -0.492</cell><cell>0.630</cell><cell>0.605 -0.657</cell><cell>0.515</cell><cell>0.484 -0.549</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Summary of rating values used in Experiment 2 for the similarity effect</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Rating 1</cell><cell></cell><cell>Rating 2</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Option</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell></row><row><cell>X</cell><cell>34.80</cell><cell>0.89</cell><cell>74.90</cell><cell>1.07</cell></row><row><cell>Y</cell><cell>54.60</cell><cell>0.68</cell><cell>55.10</cell><cell>0.72</cell></row><row><cell>S x</cell><cell>56.00</cell><cell>0.67</cell><cell>53.70</cell><cell>1.16</cell></row><row><cell>S y</cell><cell>33.00</cell><cell>1.05</cell><cell>76.70</cell><cell>0.95</cell></row></table><note>similarity-based and dissimilarity-based attention conditions and to test for the presence of the similarity effect in each condition. The approach and model specifications were identical to Experiment 1 and an analysis using a modified version of RST (Katsimpokis et al., 2023) yielded nearly identical results and is provided in the Supplemental Materials.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Summary of rating values used in Experiment for the compromise effect</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Rating 1</cell><cell></cell><cell>Rating 2</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Option</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell></row><row><cell>X</cell><cell>38.60</cell><cell>1.43</cell><cell>62.40</cell><cell>1.62</cell></row><row><cell>Y</cell><cell>62.20</cell><cell>2.36</cell><cell>38.80</cell><cell>1.94</cell></row><row><cell>C x</cell><cell>17.00</cell><cell>3.50</cell><cell>84.00</cell><cell>3.94</cell></row><row><cell>C y</cell><cell>83.80</cell><cell>4.89</cell><cell>17.20</cell><cell>4.39</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results for the reanalysis of<ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Trueblood et al. 2015</ref> </figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Attraction</cell><cell></cell><cell>Similarity</cell><cell cols="2">Compromise</cell></row><row><cell>Order</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>95% HPD</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>95% HPD</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>95% HPD</cell></row><row><cell>TCD</cell><cell>0.424</cell><cell>0.39-0.46</cell><cell>0.516</cell><cell>0.48-0.56</cell><cell>0.467</cell><cell>0.44-0.50</cell></row><row><cell>TDC</cell><cell>0.587</cell><cell>0.54-0.63</cell><cell>0.60</cell><cell>0.56-0.64</cell><cell>0.561</cell><cell>0.52-0.60</cell></row><row><cell>CTD</cell><cell>0.563</cell><cell>0.53-0.60</cell><cell>0.604</cell><cell>0.57-0.64</cell><cell>0.569</cell><cell>0.53-0.61</cell></row><row><cell>DTC</cell><cell>0.631</cell><cell>0.59-0.67</cell><cell>0.642</cell><cell>0.60-0.68</cell><cell>0.586</cell><cell>0.55-0.63</cell></row><row><cell>CDT</cell><cell>0.499</cell><cell>0.46-0.54</cell><cell>0.546</cell><cell>0.50-0.59</cell><cell>0.475</cell><cell>0.44-0.51</cell></row><row><cell>DCT</cell><cell>0.369</cell><cell>0.33-0.41</cell><cell>0.469</cell><cell>0.43-0.51</cell><cell>0.413</cell><cell>0.38-0.45</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Note that by including both choice sets where X and Y are targets, we control for the possibility that an individual has a strong preference for either X or Y in our calculation of the RST. A strong attribute bias can also be controlled by using an alternative definition of RST as proposed by<ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Katsimpokis et al. (2023)</ref> and discussed in the supplement.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Test of a multiplying model for estimated area of rectangles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="543" to="548" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context-dependent foraging decisions in rufous hummingbirds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bateson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Healy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hurly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1521" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">270</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1271" to="1276" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rigorously testing multialternative decision field theory against random utility models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Berkowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Scheibehenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">143</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1331</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Associations and the accumulation of preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">522</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive and neural bases of multi-attribute, multi-alternative, value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fixation patterns in simple choice reflect optimal information sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Callaway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1008863</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reversing the similarity effect: The effect of presentation format</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cataldo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2018.02.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.02.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">175</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="156" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The comparison process as an account of variation in the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cataldo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="934" to="942" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context effects without a context: Attribute balance as a reason for choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chernev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiattribute judgment: Attribute spacing influences single attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mellers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">496</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A map of decoy influence in human multialternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Dumbalska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Summerfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25169" to="25178" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shifting visual attention between objects and locations: Evidence from normal and parietal lesion subjects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Egly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Driver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rafal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">161</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The asymmetric impact of context on advantaged versus disadvantaged options</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Evangelidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Levav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Simonson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="253" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The impact of presentation order on attraction and repulsion effects in decision-making. Decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dasari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">36</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response-time data provide critical constraints on dynamic models of multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="901" to="933" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The attraction effect in motor planning decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Farmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>El-Deredy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Howes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Warren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="510" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of expected value on attraction effect preference reversals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Farmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Warren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>El-Deredy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Howes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="785" to="793" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An attentional drift diffusion model over binary-attribute choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">168</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The limits of attraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Frederick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Baskin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="487" to="507" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A theory of multi-attribute search and choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Deakin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pattern recognition and eye-movement parameters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gould</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Owens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A registered report on presentation factors that influence the attraction effect</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attribute commensurability and context effects in preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of object similarity and orientation on object-based cueing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Blaschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rolke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception, &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Attention</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A practical guide to the probability density approximation (pda) with improved implementation and error characterization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian analysis of the piecewise diffusion decision model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="730" to="743" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new framework for modeling decisions about changing information: The piecewise linear ballistic accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why contextual preference reversals maximize expected value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Howes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Warren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Farmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>El-Deredy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">368</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adding asymmetrically dominated alternatives: Violations of regularity and the similarity hypothesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Puto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Let&apos;s be honest about the attraction effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Puto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="520" to="525" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal policy for attention-modulated decisions explains human fixation behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Elife</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63436</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A robust bayesian test for identifying context effects in multiattribute decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Katsimpokis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fontanesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="498" to="515" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The attraction effect in decision making: Superior performance by older adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hasher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology Section A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accounting for attention in sequential sampling models of decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual fixations and the computation and comparison of value in simple choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1298" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pairwise normalization: A neuroeconomic theory of multi-attribute choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Landry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Webb</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">193</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105221</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Irrational decision-making in an amoeboid organism: Transitivity and context-dependent preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Latty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Beekman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">278</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="1703" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How do insects choose flowers? a review of multi-attribute flower choice and decoy effects in flower-visiting insects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Latty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Animal Ecology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2750" to="2762" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Irrationality in mate choice revealed by túngara frogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">349</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6251</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="964" to="966" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trading mental effort for confidence in the metacognitive control of value-based decision-making. elife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63282</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The appropriacy of averaging in the study of context effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Liew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Howe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1639" to="1646" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attraction comes from many sources: Attentional and comparative processes in decoy effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ansani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Paglieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment &amp; Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">There is more to attraction than meets the eye: Studying decoy-induced attention allocation without eye tracking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sapienza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Paglieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Similarity and alignment in choice. Organizational behavior and human decision processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Markman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Medin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="130" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Similarity and attraction effects in episodic memory judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Maylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="715" to="723" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parameter recovery for the leaky competing accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Miletić</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Van Maanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Molter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Huettel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Heekeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Mohr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaze-dependent evidence accumulation predicts multi-alternative risky choice behaviour</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1010283</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In the attraction, compromise, and similarity effects, alternatives are repeatedly compared in pairs on single dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Noguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">132</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative decision by sampling: A model of decision making constrained by process data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Noguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">512</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rhesus macaques (macaca mulatta) exhibit the decoy effect in a perceptual discrimination task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Parrish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Beran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception, &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1715" to="1725" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Attention</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">59</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion decision model: Current issues and history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A unifying bayesian account of contextual effects in value-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rigoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mathys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Friston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1005769</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative decision field theory: A dynamic connectionst model of decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Roe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">370</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An eye fixation analysis of multialternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rosen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="276" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic programming in python using pymc3</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Salvatier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Wiecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fonnesbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PeerJ Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">55</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context-dependent violations of rational choice in honeybees (apis mellifera) and gray jays (perisoreus canadensis)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shafir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Waite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the mechanism and determinants of compromise effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Nakamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology &amp; Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="591" to="609" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rational preference shifts in multi-attribute choice: What is fair?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shenoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the annual meeting of the cognitive science society</title>
		<meeting>the annual meeting of the cognitive science society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page">35</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a universal law of generalization for psychological science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shepard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">237</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4820</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1317" to="1323" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Object-based attention: Strength of object representation and attentional guidance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shomstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Behrmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception &amp; psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="144" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice based on reasons: The case of attraction and compromise effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Simonson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="158" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention and choice across domains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1810</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaze amplifies value in decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The elusiveness of context effects in decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Spektor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="843" to="854" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When the good looks bad: An experimental exploration of the repulsion effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Spektor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hotaling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1309" to="1320" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the origin of utility, weighting, and discounting functions: How they get their shapes and how to change their shapes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reimers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="687" to="705" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative context effects obtained using an inference task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="962" to="968" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reference point effects in riskless choice without loss aversion. Decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Theories of context effects in multialternative, multiattribute choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="428" to="435" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The multiattribute linear ballistic accumulator model of context effects in multialternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">179</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The fragile nature of contextual preference reversals: Reply to Tsetsos, Chater, and Usher</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="848" to="853" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not just for consumers: Context effects are fundamental to decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="901" to="908" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Examining the mechanisms underlying contextual preference reversal: Comment on Trueblood</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<pubPlace>Brown, and Heathcote</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A method for efficiently sampling from distributions with correlated dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sederberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">368</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Elimination by aspects: A theory of choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">281</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context-dependent preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Simonson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1179" to="1189" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How incidental values from the environment affect decisions about money, risk, and delay</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ungemach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reimers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="260" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing among models of contextually induced preference reversals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wedell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">767</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Similarity, attraction, and compromise effects: Original findings, recent empirical observations, and computational cognitive process models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wollschlaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Diederich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The 2 n-ary choice tree model for n-alternative preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wollschläger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Diederich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">189</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yearsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Barque-Duran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hampton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context effects in similarity judgments</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The development of the asymmetrically dominated decoy effect in young children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zhen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
