<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Quantum Model for Serial Reproduction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2024-09-11">September 11, 2024</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiaqi</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>huangajq@iu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qizi</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fritz</forename><surname>Breithaupt</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerome</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
							<email>jbusemey@indiana.edu</email>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Quantum Model for Serial Reproduction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2024-09-11">September 11, 2024</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:12+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Quantum Cognition</term>
					<term>Serial Reproduction</term>
					<term>Group Decision Making</term>
					<term>Bayesian Modeling</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We propose a novel quantum walk framework for modeling serial reproduction, designed to effectively capture the transmission of inherently vague concepts, such as emotions and ideas, through quantum superpositions and controlled unitary operations. In a comprehensive comparison with Bayesian models using the largest dataset of reproduced narratives to date, our framework demonstrates superior predictive accuracy, surpassing Bayesian approaches in modeling non-linear relationships and multimodal distributions in emotion transmission. Furthermore, it successfully replicates recent key findings on emotion transmission in serial reproduction.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Social networks have emerged as a significant source of new information in recent years, spurring considerable interest in the study of group-level cognitive processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Easley, Kleinberg, et al., 2010)</ref>. A particularly prominent area of research focuses on understanding how information spread within a social network can influence t he b eliefs a nd decisionmaking processes of the individuals involved <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Blank, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kempe, Kleinberg, &amp; Tardos, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Lazer et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Myers, Zhu, &amp; Leskovec, 2012)</ref>. One well-known paradigm of group-level decision making is serial reproduction. In serial reproduction, participants are tasked with reproducing a given stimulus in a sequence, where the output produced by one participant becomes the stimulus for the next participant in the sequence <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bartlett, 1932)</ref>. As the most basic form of information transmission within a social network, serial reproduction has been extensively studied across various fields, i ncluding cultural transmission <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Kashima, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Kashima, Yeung, et al., 2010)</ref>, emotion transmission <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Breithaupt, Li, &amp; Kruschke, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Breithaupt, Li, Liddell, Schille-Hudson, &amp; Whaley, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Lee, Gelfand, &amp; Kashima, 2014)</ref>, and memory biases <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lyons &amp; Kashima, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xu &amp; Griffiths, 2010</ref>).</p><p>Relevant materials of this manuscript can be found in this Github repository. Part of this work is published in Cognitive Science Society Proceedings: Huang, J., Zhang, Q., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Busemeyer, J., &amp; Breithaupt, F. (2022)</ref>. A quantum walk model for emotion transmission in serial reproduction of narratives. In Proceedings of the annual meeting of the cognitive science society <ref type="bibr">(Vol. 44,</ref><ref type="bibr">No. 44)</ref>.</p><p>Bayesian Markov chain models have become a highly influential framework for understanding serial reproduction, receiving significant support from psychological research <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Huang &amp; Busemeyer, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Langlois, Jacoby, Suchow, &amp; Griffiths, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Thompson &amp; Griffiths, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xu &amp; Griffiths, 2010)</ref>. These models are particularly effective when the stimuli being reproduced have a clear "ground truth," such as in the serial reproduction of fish lengths in images. This effectiveness stems from Bayesian theory's focus on epistemic uncertainties, which arise from observational noise and lack of knowledge. However, not all uncertainties could be the best captured by epistemic uncertainties. For instance, during serial reproduction of texts, individuals often reinterpret underlying ideas and emotions in their own words rather than reproducing them verbatim. In such cases, the subjective nature of these interpretations means there is no longer a definitive "ground truth" for the reproduced texts. The resulting noise may not simply be due to observational errors or uncertainty in prior knowledge, but also to the inherent variability in how concepts are interpreted. Whether Bayesian models can effectively address tasks where the interpretations of concepts themselves are uncertain remains an open question. Additionally, a substantial body of research highlights significant deviations from the Markov property and Bayesian probabilities in the dynamics of group decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Argote, Devadas, &amp; Melone, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hinsz, Tindale, &amp; Nagao, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Krosnick &amp; Alwin, 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Krosnick, Li, &amp; Lehman, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Schulz-Hardt, Frey, Lüthgens, &amp; Moscovici, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Tschan et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Zhou &amp; Guo, 2017)</ref>. These challenges further cast doubt on the suitability of Bayesian models for modeling serial reproduction within social network contexts. The quantum walk model offers an important alternative to Markov processes for modeling human decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Busemeyer, Wang, &amp; Lambert-Mogiliansky, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Busemeyer, Wang, &amp; Townsend, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Zhang &amp; Busemeyer, 2021)</ref>. Grounded in quantum probability theory, quantum walk models can account for several key empirical violations of Markovian and Bayesian predictions in human decision-making. Notably, by representing subjective concepts as a superposition of potential values rather than as a single, fixed value, quantum walk models may provide a significant advantage in capturing the emotions and ideas within narratives compared to Markovian models <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Busemeyer, Kvam, &amp; Pleskac, 2020)</ref>. However, to date, quantum walk models have largely been restricted to explaining individual decision-making. Only a handful of attempts have been made to extend these models to encompass group dynamics <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bagarello, Gargano, &amp; Oliveri, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Khrennikov, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Mutlu &amp; Ozmen Garibay, 2021)</ref>, and these efforts have faced criticism, particularly regarding their shortcomings in capturing the asymmetric flow of information <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Zhang &amp; Busemeyer, 2021)</ref>. This situation poses an intriguing challenge: Is it possible to replicate the success of quantum models in group decision-making?</p><p>In this work, we address the above challenges by proposing a novel quantum walk model for serial reproduction. The present manuscript is structured as follows: First, we review the Bayesian Markov chain model as presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xu and Griffiths (2010)</ref>. Next we introduce our novel quantum walk model. Subsequently, we compare our model against the Bayesian model, evaluating their predictive capacities across the most exten-sive dataset available on the serial reproduction of narratives <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Breithaupt et al., 2022)</ref>. Finally, we discuss a few important a priori prediction of the quantum walk model for future testing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Bayesian Model Of Serial Reproduction</head><p>In their Bayesian model, <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xu and Griffiths (2010)</ref> conceptualized serial reproduction as a sequence of memory reconstructions, where each participant's reconstruction is shaped by a combination of their prior knowledge and the noisy observation of the stimulus they received. This process is formalized through the application of Bayes' rule, which enables participants to update their prior beliefs based on the new, albeit imperfect, information they encounter. The blending of prior knowledge with the observed stimulus inevitably introduces systematic biases into the reconstructed stimuli. As each participant in the sequence bases their reconstruction on the previous participant's output, these initial biases can accumulate or even amplify over successive reproductions, leading to substantial distortions from the original stimulus.</p><p>Formally, let A n+1 represent the n + 1-th participant in the sequence. The Bayesian model suggests that participant A n+1 forms a prior belief about the stimulus x(n) based on their prior experiences, represented as µ</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(n + 1) ∼ N (µ 0 (n + 1), σ(n + 1) 2 ). Participant A n+1 makes a noisy observation of the stimulus, modeled as x(n)|µ(n + 1) ∼ N (µ(n + 1), σ 2</formula><p>x ), where σ x represents the observation noise. The participant then reconstructs x(n) by sampling from the posterior distribution given the noisy observation µ(n + 1)|x(n), which follows a Gaussian distribution:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">N (λ(n+1)x(n)+(1−λ(n+1))µ 0 (n+1), λ(n+1)σ 2 x ). Here, λ(n + 1) = σ 2 x σ 2 x + σ(n + 1) 2 .<label>(1)</label></formula><p>In <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xu and Griffiths (2010)</ref>, participants were trained to share the same prior, so it is further assumed that σ(n + 1) = σ 0 and µ 0 (n + 1) = µ 0 are constants as a function of the step n.</p><p>Since participant A n+1 only receives the reproduced stimulus from participant A n , it is reasonable to assume that serial reproduction satisfies the Markov property, where x(n+1) depends solely on x(n). More specifically, the process by which A n+1 reconstructs x(n) from A n is modeled by a Markov chain with the following transition probability:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">p(x(n + 1)|x(n)) = p(x(n + 1)|µ(n + 1))p(µ(n + 1)|x(n))dµ(n + 1),<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where x(n + 1)|µ(n + 1) ∼ N (µ(n + 1), σ 2 x ). Using these results, we arrive at the following first-order autoregressive process:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">x(n + 1) = (1 − λ(n + 1))µ 0 (n + 1) + λ(n + 1)x(n) + ϵ(n + 1),<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where the noise term ϵ(n + 1) ∼ N (0, (1 + λ(n + 1))σ 2 x ). Conceptually, Equation 3 indicates that the reproduced stimulus x(n+1) can be seen as a weighted combination of participant <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Difference between quantum and Bayesian representation of uncertainty. The task described in this figure is to rewrite a story in one's own words. The Bayesian model (top) assumes that the level of sadness in the reproduced narrative is represented as a probability distribution over specific sadness ratings. The uncertainty in this model arises from two sources: observational noise and prior uncertainty about the true level of sadness in the narrative, both of which are epistemic. The model then rewrites the story by sampling from the posterior distribution, producing a narrative with a clearly defined sadness rating. In contrast, the quantum model (bottom) assigns an epistemic probability distribution over quantum superposition states of the level of sadness, where each state itself inherently expresses uncertainty through a probability amplitude distribution. It is only when a quantum projective measurement is made that a person interprets the story in a specific way, the superposition of states will collapse into a definite sadness rating. Unlike the Bayesian model, which rewrites the story with a clearly defined sadness rating, the quantum model rewrites in terms of a specific quantum state of sadness, introducing an additional layer of uncertainty before measurement.</p><p>A n+1 's prior mean µ 0 (n + 1) and the observed stimulus x(n), with the introduction of random noise ϵ(n + 1).</p><p>The Bayesian model introduced here is particularly effective for serial reproduction tasks where the stimulus to be replicated has a well-defined "ground truth." For instance, in the experiment conducted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xu and Griffiths (2010)</ref>, participants were tasked with reproducing the lengths of fish images they observed, which inherently possess a "ground truth" since lengths can be precisely measured. The importance of a "ground truth" in the model is further exemplified in Equation 3, where x(n) retains an exact value even when participant A n+1 experiences observation noise. In these scenarios, uncertainties can be effectively modeled using classical probability distributions and Bayesian inferences, as they are epistemic in nature: stemming from a lack of comprehensive knowledge about a system. However, in the context of transmitting ideas and emotions through texts on social networks, the notion of a "ground truth" becomes elusive: individuals may interpret the same text differently and express these ideas and emotions in their own words. For example, when reading a particular story, different people might report varying levels of sadness, leading to a scenario where there is no singular "ground truth" for x(n), as x(n) would assume different values across individuals <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Breithaupt et al., 2022)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Quantum Walk Model of Serial Reproduction</head><p>The quantum walk model introduces a novel perspective on serial reproduction. Unlike Bayesian models, which require that the attributes of a stimulus have specific, quantifiable values for accurate replication, quantum walk models propose that these attributes can exist in quantum superpositions across a range of potential values. It is crucial to understand that quantum superposition differs fundamentally from a Bayesian probability distribution: while the classical or Bayesian approach views uncertainties as epistemic-arising from a lack of knowledge-quantum superposition considers uncertainty as ontic, a fundamental characteristic of the system itself. A key distinction between the two lies in how these uncertainties are expressed: epistemic uncertainty is described by probability distributions, while ontic uncertainty is expressed through probability amplitude distributions, whose squared magnitudes represent the actual probabilities. Unlike probabilities, which are constrained to the interval [0, 1], probability amplitudes can take a wider range of values, including complex numbers. This feature allows the combination of two probability amplitude distributions to generate quantum interference effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Feynman, Hibbs, &amp; Styer, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>To further illustrate the distinction between these two types of uncertainty, consider the task of evaluating "sadness" in a story on a scale from 0 to 7 (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). The Bayesian model suggests that an objective sadness rating (e.g., 3.75) inherently exists within the narrative, assuming that people share a common understanding of "sadness," similar to how they agree on measuring the length of a fish image. In this framework, variations in empirical ratings are attributed to observational noise and individuals' differing prior expectations about the typical level of sadness in a story. In contrast, the quantum walk model treats "sadness" as an inherently uncertain concept. According to this model, there is no objective sadness rating embedded in the narrative. Instead, the sadness rating exists as a quantum superposition, becoming "objective" only when individuals interpret it through a quantum projective measurement. Thus, variations in ratings stem not only from observational noise but also from diverse interpretations of what "sadness" means, acknowledging that even the same individual may interpret the concept differently at different times. Given that ideas and emotions are intrinsically vague and deeply dependent on personal interpretation, quantum superposition offers a more fitting conceptual frame-work for their analysis. This is not to suggest that epistemic uncertainty is absent in the quantum model. Like Bayesian models, the quantum model acknowledges the presence of observational noise of the stimuli. However, unlike the Bayesian approach, which combines observational uncertainty with the uncertainty of prior belief, the quantum model treats this noise as independent from the intrinsic quantum walk process that updates the participant's prior belief. Moreover, this observational noise is not related to observing the exact value presented in the stimuli but rather to the uncertainty in observing the exact quantum state of the stimuli, which itself contains inherent uncertainty. Formally, we define the influence of observational noise by placing a Gaussian distribution over the "true" quantum state ψ(n) of the stimulus S n as perceived by participant A n+1 , denoted as N (ψ(n), σ(n + 1)),</p><p>where σ(n + 1) represents the observational noise of the A n+1 participant. Since the quantum walk process operates independently of this noise, the final distribution of quantum states after A n+1 updates their belief in response to perceiving stimulus S n will follow N (Q(ψ(n)), σ(n + 1)), where Q(x) symbolically represents the quantum walk process. The quantum walk model Q(x) that updates the belief of A n+1 can be summarized in the following three steps. The first step involves constructing a joint quantum system that represents the beliefs of both A n and A n+1 . Let ψ 0 (n + 1) denote the initial state for participant A n+1 . This initial state, analogous to the prior distribution in the Bayesian model, represents A n+1 's initial belief regarding stimulus S n . The joint system can then be mathematically represented by the composite quantum state:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">Ψ 0 (n, n + 1) = ψ(n) ⊗ ψ 0 (n + 1),<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where ψ(n) is the mean of the noisy observation of the quantum state of S n as introduced earlier, and ⊗ denotes the tensor product. 1</p><p>The second step is to model how participant A n+1 reconstruct the quantum state ψ(n) of S n . While the Bayesian model achieves this by applying Bayes' rule, the quantum model employs a transformation unique to quantum computing: the controlled unitary operator.</p><p>This operator acts on a joint system of two quantum states, treating one part of the joint system as a control state, which remains unchanged and acts as a control, and the other part as target state, which is modified based on the control state. Mathematically, the controlled unitary operator can be written as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">U (n + 1) = k i=1M i ⊗R i (n + 1),<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where k is the dimension of the control state 2 ,M i are k × k projections that act on the <ref type="bibr">1</ref> An equivalent formulation of our model using density operators is available in Huang, Zhang, Busemeyer, and . We present the quantum state formulation here, as it is more commonly used in quantum cognition and may be more familiar to most readers. However, in practical implementation, both the controlled unitary operator and the partial trace are more straightforward and efficient when implemented using density operators. For more details about the density operator construction, see Appendix 1 and 2.</p><p>2 Note, we assume here that the Hilbert Space is finite dimensional.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Component Bayesian Quantum</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Uncertainty Probability Distribution Probability Amplitude Distribution</head><p>Prior Belief N (µ 0 (n + 1), σ(n + 1) the control unitary operator can be written as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">ψ 0 (n + 1) Noisy Observation N (x(n), σ x ) N (ψ(n), σ x ) Joint State ✗Ψ 0 (n, n + 1) Belief Update Process Bayes Rule Controlled Unitary Operator Partial Trace ✗ ✓ Reproduced Stimulus x(n + 1) ψ(n + 1)</formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">U (n + 1) =M 0 ⊗R 0 (n + 1) +M 1 ⊗R 1 (n + 1),<label>(6)</label></formula><p>whereM 0 andM 1 are projections onto the basis states |0⟩ (representing tr and state |1⟩</p><p>correspondingly. In our case, since we are modeling how A n+1 's initial belief changes in response to x(n), ψ(n) is used as the control state and ψ 0 (n + 1) as the target state. The updated configuration for participant A n+1 is then given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">Ψ(n, n + 1) =Û (n + 1) •Ψ 0 (n, n + 1) = k i=1M i ψ(n) ⊗R i (n + 1)ψ 0 (n + 1).<label>(7)</label></formula><p>Conceptually, controlled unitary operators function similarly to "if statements" in classical computing: if the control state takes on a specific value i, the corresponding unitary op-erationR i is applied to the target state. However, unlike classical conditional operations, the control state can exist in a superposition of multiple values i, allowing simultaneous influence of multiple conditions on the target state.</p><p>There is one more step needed. After observing and reconstructing the stimulus x(n), participant A n+1 arrives at the joint configurationΨ(n, n + 1). However, this is not yet the final belief state of participant A n+1 , as it still includes the state of S n . To isolate the state of S n , we need to perform a quantum operation analogous to calculating the marginal distribution from a joint distribution in classical probability theory: the partial trace. Specifically, since the state of S n appears at the left-hand side of Equation 4, we compute the left partial trace. While we won't delve into the technical details of computing the partial trace here,</p><p>interested readers can find a thorough explanation in Appendix 1.</p><p>After applying the partial trace, we obtain a probability distribution over quantum states, denoted as ρ(n + 1). It is important to note that ρ(n + 1) is not a quantum superposition where uncertainty is ontic, but rather a probability mixture of quantum superposi-tions, where uncertainty is epistemic. This type of state is referred to as a mixed state. We assume that participants sample a quantum state ψ(n + 1) from ρ(n + 1), which serves as the mean of the final distribution of states N (ψ(n + 1), σ x ), representing the noisy stimulus S n+1 that the next participant, A n+2 , will observe and reproduce. This quantum walk process Q(x) continues for each n in the serial reproduction sequence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Emotion Transmissions in Serial Reproduction of Narratives</head><p>We compare the performance of quantum and Bayesian models in a specific serial reproduction task: the serial reproduction of narratives. In particular, we focus on emotion transmission within these narratives, examining how the intensity of a particular emotion evolves throughout the serial reproduction chain. For example, we investigate whether a sad story remains equally sad as it is retold and transformed along the sequence of reproductions. We chose emotion transmission as our starting point for two main reasons. First, emotions are inherently abstract concepts without a clear "ground truth," a scenario where quantum models are expected to outperform Bayesian models. Second, emotional intensities are typically measured using a one-dimensional rating scale (e.g., a number from 0 to 7, as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>), making them relatively straightforward to model.</p><p>We conducted our analysis using the dataset from <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Breithaupt et al. (2022)</ref>, the largest dataset on serial reproduction of narratives to date, comprising 19,086 reproduced narratives and 12,840 participants (OSF repository: https://osf.io/tpw5e/). Our focus was on experiment 2 of this dataset, where the initial story in the serial reproduction sequence (hereafter referred to as S 1 ) was generated by researchers, and the intensity of different emotions was assessed for the subsequent retellings. tional intensity of each retelling is evaluated by a group of 6-8 independent raters, who are not involved in the reproduction process. These raters are asked to rate the intensity of the emotion using a scale from 0 to 7, where 0 represents "not sad at all" (or the equivalent for other emotions) and 7 represents "very sad." The overall emotional intensity for each retelling, denoted as x(n), is calculated as the average of the ratings from the group, and thus does not need to be an integer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Models of Emotion Transmissions</head><p>In the previous sections, we introduced general quantum and Bayesian frameworks for modeling serial reproduction. In this section, we present specific adaptations of these frameworks to model emotion transmission. The goal of these adaptations is to predict <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: An illustration of Experiment 2 from <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Breithaupt et al. (2022)</ref>. In this experiment, three stories-S 2 , S 3 , S 4 -are sequentially generated by three different participants (writers), with S 1 serving as the original story in the sequence. For each story, a group of 6-8 independent raters, who are not involved in the serial reproduction process, evaluate the intensity of a specific emotion conveyed in the narrative. The emotion ratings for each story, denoted as x(n), are computed as the average of these raters' assessments.</p><p>a distribution of averaged ratings of S n+1 denoted as x(n + 1), given the rewritten story from S n with some averaged ratings x(n). To achieve this, we developed four versions each of the quantum and Bayesian models, which will be introduced next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Bayesian Models</head><p>We first introduce the four versions of the Bayesian models.</p><p>BS3 This version has three parameters. The first two parameters, µ 0 and σ 0 , define the Bayesian prior µ ∼ N (µ 0 , σ 0 ), which is consistent for all participants within the same serial reproduction sequence. The third parameter, observational noise σ 2</p><p>x , is also assumed to be the same for each participant in the sequence.</p><p>BSA5 This version has five parameters. Like BS3, it assumes the same Bayesian prior for all participants within the same sequence. The addition of two parameters accounts for the assumption that different participants in the same sequence will experience varying degrees of observational noise.</p><p>BSB5 This version has five parameters. It acknowledges that participants' priors within the same sequence may differ, originating from either µ 1 ∼ N (3.5 − ϕ, σ 0 ) or µ 2 ∼ N (3.5 + α, σ 0 ). Both priors share the same variance, σ 0 . The probability that a participant's prior is µ 1 is dictated by a free parameter ω, while the probability for µ 2 is its complement, 1 − ω.</p><p>The final parameter ensures that observational noise remains consistent for all participants in the sequence. This model variation was introduced because participants in experiment 2 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Breithaupt et al. (2022)</ref> were not trained to have the same prior as those in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xu and Griffiths (2010)</ref>, necessitating a model that accommodates a mix of initial beliefs about the emotional content of a story. Additionally, the decision to choose two potential priors is motivated by observations that emotional ratings frequently exhibit a bimodal distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Breithaupt et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Ullah, Amblee, Kim, &amp; Lee, 2016)</ref>.</p><p>BSAB7 This version has seven parameters. Same as BSA5, it assumes that participants' priors are derived from a mixture of two different distributions. The introduction of two additional parameters accommodates the variation in observational noises experienced by participants within the same sequence, similar to how BSA5 differs from BS3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Quantum Models</head><p>All four versions of the quantum models are developed from a general quantum model operating in a two-dimensional Hilbert space. This choice was made to reduce the computational complexity of the model, making it easier to both fit and implement. However, quantum models are not limited to two-dimensional spaces, nor are they required to compute predicted values using Equation 14. We encourage future research to explore more complex implementations beyond the current simplified framework.</p><p>In the general two-dimensional model, ψ(n) is represented as a two-by-one vector:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">ψ(n) = x(n)/7 |0⟩ + 1 − x(n)/7 |1⟩ = x(n)/7 1 − x(n)/7 ,<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where x(n) represents the averaged emotional rating of the story S n . The initial belief state of participant A n+1 is defined by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">ψ 0 (n + 1) = cos(ϕ(n)) |0⟩ + sin(ϕ(n)) |1⟩ = cos(ϕ(n)) sin(ϕ(n)) ,<label>(9)</label></formula><p>with ϕ(n) being the free parameters. The model employs a piece-wise controlled unitary operator:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">U (n + 1) =    M 0 ⊗ T (κ(n)P (n) 1 + β(n)) + M 1 ⊗ I 2 if P (n) 1 ≥ 0.5 M 0 ⊗ I 2 + M 1 ⊗ T (κ(n)P (n) 1 + β(n)) if P (n) 1 &lt; 0.5<label>(10)</label></formula><p>In Equation 10 above,</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">P (n) 1 = ||ψ(n) i || 2 ,<label>(11)</label></formula><p>is the probability function of the ith entry of ψ(n), and</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">T (κ(n)ψ(n) 1 + β(n)) = cos(κ(n)ψ(n) 1 + β(n)) − sin(κ(n)ψ(n) 1 + β(n)) sin(κ(n)ψ(n) 1 + β(n)) cos(κ(n)ψ(n) 1 + β(n)) ,<label>(12)</label></formula><p>is the 2 × 2 rotation matrix with angle κ(n)ψ(n) 1 + β(n), where κ(n) and β(n) are free parameters that controls the strength of the rotations. Conceptually, when P n(1) ≥ 0.5, U (n + 1) modifies only the first two entries of the joint state Ψ(n, n + 1) by applying a rotation matrix. Conversely, when P (n) 1 &lt; 0.5, it adjusts only the last two entries.</p><p>Finally, after applying the partial trace to Ψ(n, n + 1) to obtain ρ(n + 1), we assume that the model always samples the pure state:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">ψ(n + 1) = ρ(n + 1) 1,1 1 − ρ(n + 1) 1,1 ,<label>(13)</label></formula><p>where ρ(n + 1) 1,1 is the first diagonal entry of ρ(n + 1). This assumption simplifies the model, sacrificing some generality but significantly reducing complexity, especially when calculating likelihoods for model fitting. The expected value for the predicted emotional intensity of S n+1 , denoted asx n+1 , is then calculated as:</p><p>x(n + 1) = 7ρ(n + 1) 1,1 .</p><p>We consider this expected rating value to represent the predicted emotional rating based on ψ(n + 1). It is important to note that, due to observational noise, ψ(n + 1) represents only the mean of the final distribution of quantum states, modeled as N (ψ(n+1), σ(n+1)).</p><p>Consequently, the actual ratings x(n + 1) for story S n would follow a normal distribution N (x(n + 1), σ(n + 1)) centered around the predicted valuex n+1 .</p><p>The four versions of this two-dimensional quantum model, corresponding to each version of the Bayesian model are:</p><p>Q4 This version has four parameters. It assumes that all participants in the same sequence share the same initial belief state, with a constant ϕ(n) = ϕ, and reconstruction noise σ(n) = σ, similar to BS3. The other two parameters, κ(n) = κ and β(n) = β, are also consistent across all participants in the same chain.</p><p>QA6 This version has six parameters. Analogous to the relationship between BS3 and BSA5, QA6 introduces two additional parameters to Q4 to account for variations in the reconstruction noise, σ(n), among participants within the same chain.</p><p>QB6 This version has six parameters. Analogous to the relationship between BS3 and BSA5, it includes two different initial states, characterized by the parameters ϕ 1 and ϕ 2 .</p><p>The probability of being in the state with ϕ 1 is determined by the free parameter ω, with the probability of the alternative state being 1 − ω. It's important to note that these two states represent a mixed quantum state rather than superposition states, since ω denotes a probability, not a probability amplitude.</p><p>QAB8 This version has seven parameters. Similar to the relationship between BSB5 and BSAB7, QAB8 introduces two additional parameters to QB6 to accommodate variations in the reconstruction noise, σ(n), among participants within the same sequence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Results and Discussions</head><p>We employ maximum likelihood techniques to fit the models. Since both models use Gaussian likelihood functions and the emotional ratings are confined to the range [0, 7], we <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: Mean BIC values (left) and mean G 2 values of the test set of the generalization test (right) for each of the five emotions and each model version. The model names are indicated on the x axis, where "BS" denotes Bayesian models, and "Q" signifies quantum models. An "A" in the name represents versions with varying observation noise, and "B" indicates versions with two initial beliefs ("AB" means both are included). The numbers at the end of the names denote the number of parameters in the models. The dashed lines correspond to the lowest BIC scores or lowest G 2 of the test set for the emotion indicated by the color of the line. The smaller the BIC score and G 2 , the better the model. truncate the Gaussian distributions to this interval. A single set of parameters is fitted across all sequences that begin with the same initial story, S 1 for each version of the models. This approach assumes that all sequences starting from the same S 1 transmit emotion in a similar manner. The fitting process is carried out using the particle swarm optimization algorithm available in the MATLAB Global Optimization Toolbox. We use a swarm size of 320 and allow for a maximum of 2000 iterations. To ensure robustness against potential convergence to local minima, each model fitting is repeated three times, recognizing the possibility of multiple local minima within the quantum model. After fitting, all versions of the two models are compared using the Bayesian Information Criterion (BIC), which penalizes models based on the number of parameters:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">BIC = −2 ln(L) + k ln(n),<label>(15)</label></formula><p>where L represents the maximum likelihood, k is the number of parameters in the model, and n is the total number of data points used for fitting. The results are presented in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> (left). For each emotion, the best-performing model is consistently a quantum model, even though it incurs a penalty for using more parameters.</p><p>We complement our BIC analysis with the results of a generalization test <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Busemeyer &amp; Wang, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">LeCun, Bengio, &amp; Hinton, 2015)</ref>. In this test, we randomly select 20% of the sequences for each initial story S 1 as the test set, with the remaining 80% used as the training set. For each original story, we fit a set of parameters on the training set and then evaluate how well these fitted parameters generalize to the test set. Model performance is assessed <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>: Predictions from the best-performing versions (in terms of BIC) of both the Bayesian and Quantum models plotted against the data. The title of each subplot corresponds to the name of a selected original narrative S 1 , with each yellow data point representing a serial reproduction sequence that begins with the S 1 indicated in the title. The first five columns display S 3 versus S 4 , while the last two columns show S 2 versus S 3 . by computing G 2 = −2 ln(L) on the test set. The results are shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3 (</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Non-Linear Predictions</head><p>One potential reason for the consistent outperformance of the quantum model over the Bayesian model is its ability to predict non-linear relationships between ratings x(n) and</p><p>x(n + 1). The Bayesian auto-regressive model, constrained by a Gaussian conjugate prior, is limited to predicting only linear relationships between x(n) and x(n + 1) (see Equation</p><p>3). In contrast, the quantum model, which operates with probability amplitudes whose squared magnitudes represent probabilities, can predict non-linear relationships that better align with the empirical data (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>).</p><p>It is important to note, however, that in the probability amplitude space, the quantum model remains linear, much like the Bayesian auto-regressive model, since all matrix oper- <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: Examples of original narratives where the quantum model detects a multimodal distribution that the Bayesian model does not. The distribution shown is for the ratings of S 2 across all sequences starting from the original narratives noted in the titles. The quantum model achieving the best fit, based on the lowest mean BIC, is version "QB6," while the best-fitting Bayesian model is version "BSB5."</p><p>ations are linear processes. The non-linearity arises only when probabilities are computed by taking the square magnitudes of the quantum states. This type of non-linearity is a distinctive feature of quantum theory, which operates on complex probability amplitudes rather than direct probabilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Nielsen &amp; Chuang, 2010)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Multimodality</head><p>Another potential reason for the quantum model's superior performance over the Bayesian model is its greater sensitivity to multimodality in the data. Unlike tasks such as the reproduction of fish lengths in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Xu and Griffiths (2010)</ref>, where participants' responses follow a unimodal Gaussian distribution, emotion ratings often exhibit multimodal distributions, typically bimodal. This observation led to the development of model versions that incorporate two different Bayesian priors or two initial quantum states to account for this multimodality, as discussed earlier. While both the Bayesian and quantum models, when equipped with this feature, can predict bimodal distributions, our analysis of the fitting results revealed that the quantum models are generally more sensitive to detecting multimodal patterns than the Bayesian models. For instance, as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>, the quantum model identifies certain multimodalities that the Bayesian model fails to capture.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Emotion Transmissions</head><p>An important analysis of the dataset from <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Breithaupt et al. (2022)</ref> focuses on how emotions change throughout the serial reproduction chain. Their regression analysis reported three major findings. First, the intensity of happiness, embarrassment, and sadness is largely preserved during the serial reproduction process, with only a small decline. Second, the <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>: Regression analysis of the predictions of the quantum model. Each line represents regression result for all sequences of a given original story S 1 , with the red bold line indicating the spine of the regression model where deflection equals zero.</p><p>intensity of risk and disgust shows a noticeable decreasing trend along the chain. Third, only embarrassment exhibits a significant compression toward the mean. Our objective is to determine whether these key findings from <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Breithaupt et al. (2022)</ref> can be replicated using the quantum model. Specifically, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Breithaupt et al. (2022)</ref> used the following regression model in their analysis: for each original story S 1 of a given emotion, the rating at serial position n, denoted as µ S 1 (n), is expressed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">µ S 1 (n) = β 1 n + α S 1 exp(dn) + β 0 ,<label>(16)</label></formula><p>where β 1 represents the slope, β 0 the intercept, and d is the compression parameter. The term α S 1 is a weighting parameter specific to each original story S 1 , while β 1 , β 0 , and d are constant across all stories within the same emotion category. The term α S 1 exp(dn), referred to as "deflections," captures deviations in the ratings of individual S 1 stories from the overall mean of the emotion category. The smaller the parameter d, the greater the compression toward the mean for each S 1 .</p><p>This regression model was applied to the ratings of individual raters in . However, since our quantum model focus on predicting the mean ratings x(n)</p><p>for each story, rather than the individual ratings used to calculate x(n), we cannot fully replicate their quantitative analysis. Nevertheless, we can still compare the fitting results of the mean ratings x(n) from our data with the predictions of the quantum model using this regression framework. This comparison allows us to assess whether the quantum model qualitatively reproduces their findings by evaluating whether the slopes and compression patterns in the data align with the model's predictions. The results are shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>As the table indicates, except for the slope of embarrassment, where the quantum model's value is more than twice as small as that of the data, all other parameters from the two models are in close alignment.</p><p>The quantum model also qualitatively replicates the three major findings discussed earlier. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> shows the regression analysis results of the quantum model's predictions.</p><p>Happy and sad stories exhibit minimal change as a function of n, while disgust and risk show a noticeable decrease, with slopes approximately four times larger in magnitude than those for happy and sad, qualitatively replicating the first two findings. Additionally, embarrassment shows a much more pronounced compression toward the mean compared to the other emotions, qualitatively replicating the third finding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">General Discussion</head><p>In this work, we proposed a general quantum walk framework for modeling serial reproduction. We applied this framework to the transmission of emotions in narratives and achieved superior performance compared to the most popular Bayesian models for this task. Additionally, our quantum model successfully replicated key findings from Breithaupt et al. (2022) regarding how different emotions evolve in serial reproduction chains.</p><p>These results suggest that the quantum walk framework is robust and holds significant potential for future applications in modeling serial reproduction processes.</p><p>There are three main reasons why the quantum walk model outperforms the Bayesian model. First, the quantum model can represent inherently vague concepts, such as emotions, through quantum superposition, while the Bayesian model is better suited to concepts like physical measurements (e.g., lengths) that have a clear "ground truth" where uncertainty is epistemic. Second, the quantum model uses probability amplitudes to represent uncertainty, allowing it to generate non-linear patterns from linear processes, whereas the Bayesian model can only produce linear relationships. Third, the quantum model is more sensitive to multimodality, detecting complex patterns in the data that the Bayesian model may overlook.</p><p>Looking ahead, the quantum walk framework offers several advantages for future research. One key feature of quantum theory is the collapsing of quantum states through projective measurement, a concept that plays a central role in explaining order effects in quantum cognitive models <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Pothos &amp; Busemeyer, 2022)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Huang et al. (2022)</ref> proposed that similar order effects could arise in serial reproduction. For instance, asking participants whether story S n is sad could collapse the quantum state of S n into a definite state (in a yes/no basis), thereby altering the control state of the controlled unitary operator. This, in turn, would change the final state of the reproduced story S n+1 . However, these order effects have not yet been experimentally verified, and it remains unclear what other aspects of the quantum walk framework might be influenced by the collapse of the quantum state.</p><p>We encourage both theoretical and empirical research to further investigate potential order effects in serial reproduction and how the quantum walk framework might be adapted to account for them.</p><p>Another promising direction inspired by our model is the exploration of entanglementlike structures in group-level decision-making. At the individual level, research has reported super-correlation patterns that violate the CHSH inequality, suggesting phenomena that cannot be explained by classical probability theory assuming non-locality <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Atmanspacher &amp; Filk, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Basieva, Cervantes, Dzhafarov, &amp; Khrennikov, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Cervantes &amp; Dzhafarov, 2018)</ref>. Although these findings are often described as "quantum-like" rather than truly quantum due to the lack of proof for non-locality, they demonstrate that quantumlike entanglement may be a useful tool for modeling human cognition. Similarly, our quantum walk model has the potential to form entanglement-like systems between consecutive stimuli, such as S n and S n+1 .</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2provides an illustration of this experiment. S 1 are categorized into five emotional themes: happy (18 stories), sad (19 stories), embarrassed (19 stories), disgusted (19 stories), and risky (19 stories), resulting in a total of 96 stories and 8,243 serial reproduction sequences. Each sequence consists of three retellings, labeled S 2 , S 3 , and S 4 , with each retelling produced by a different participant who reads and reproduces the preceding narrative, S n−1 . The emo-</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Comparison of key components of the quantum and Bayesian model of serial reproduction.</figDesc><table /><note>control state, andR i are k × k unitary operators modifying the target state. When k = 2,</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Summary Table of the regression analysis. β 1 and exp(d) corresponds to parameters in the regression model in Equation 16.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Emotion</cell><cell cols="4">β 1 Quantum β 1 Data exp(d) Quantum exp(d) Data</cell></row><row><cell>Happiness</cell><cell>-0.182</cell><cell>-0.175</cell><cell>0.959</cell><cell>0.946</cell></row><row><cell>Sadness</cell><cell>-0.105</cell><cell>-0.115</cell><cell>0.923</cell><cell>0.876</cell></row><row><cell>Disgust</cell><cell>-0.470</cell><cell>-0.482</cell><cell>0.930</cell><cell>0.874</cell></row><row><cell>Risk</cell><cell>-0.344</cell><cell>-0.315</cell><cell>1.005</cell><cell>0.923</cell></row><row><cell>Embarrassment</cell><cell>-0.039</cell><cell>-0.110</cell><cell>0.863</cell><cell>0.794</cell></row><row><cell>Table 2:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>This material is based upon work supported by the Air Force Office of Scientific Research under award number FA9550-20-1-0027.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix 1: Partial Trace</head><p>To compute the partial trace of a given pure final joint stateΨ(n, n + 1), we first derive its density matrix, assumingΨ(n, n + 1) is represented as a column vector:</p><p>where † denotes the conjugate transpose ofΨ(n, n + 1). IfΨ(n, n + 1) is a k 2 × 1 vector, then ρ(n, n + 1) will be a k 2 × k 2 matrix. To compute the partial trace over S n , we take the left partial trace of ρ(n, n + 1) as follows:</p><p>where e i are the k basis vectors of ψ n (e.g., a vector with a 1 in the ith entry and 0s elsewhere), and I B is the k × k identity matrix. The resulting ρ(n + 1) is a k × k matrix, if</p><p>Note that ρ(n + 1) may not always represent a pure quantum state, as it is not necessarily a projection. In cases where ρ(n + 1) is a mixed state-meaning it represents a probability mixture of pure states-we can sample a projective density matrix M (n + 1) from ρ(n + 1). This projective density matrix M (n + 1) corresponds to a quantum superposition state ψ(n + 1), satisfying the condition:</p><p>We assume that participants will use ψ(n + 1) as the mean of a Gaussian distribution, N (ψ(n + 1), σ x ), which represents the observation noise. This Gaussian distribution is then used to reconstruct and rewrite the narrative S n+1 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix 2: Density Operator Version</head><p>We present here the density operator version of our quantum walk framework. Assuming ψ 0 (n + 1) and ψ(n) are column vectors, we first define the density operators as ρ 0 (n + 1) = ψ 0 (n + 1) • ψ 0 (n + 1) † and ρ(n) = ψ(n) • ψ(n) † . We then form a joint system of the two density operators as ρ 0 (n, n + 1) = ρ(n) ⊗ ρ 0 (n + 1).</p><p>If ψ 0 (n + 1) and ψ(n) are k × 1 vectors, then ρ 0 (n, n + 1) will be a k 2 × k 2 matrix.</p><p>The unitary operator is defined in the same way as Equation 5. Applying the unitary operator to ρ 0 (n, n + 1), we obtain:</p><p>This ρ(n, n + 1) can be shown to be equivalent to the one described in Equation 17 in Appendix 1. Finally, we take the partial trace following the same procedure outlined in Appendix 1 and sample the pure state M n+1 , which serves as the mean of the Gaussian distribution N (M n+1 , σ x ) to represent the noisy stimuli for the next participant.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The base-rate fallacy: Contrasting processes and outcomes of group and individual judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Argote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Devadas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Melone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="296" to="310" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A proposed test of temporal nonlocality in bistable perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Atmanspacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Filk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="314" to="321" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spreading of competing information in a network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bagarello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gargano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Oliveri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entropy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1169</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Remembering: A study in experimental and social psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bartlett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1932" />
			<publisher>Cambridge university press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">True contextuality beats direct influences in human decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Basieva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Cervantes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Dzhafarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khrennikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">148</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1925" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Remembering: A theoretical interface between memory and social psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Blank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="164" to="175" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Serial reproduction of narratives preserves emotional appraisals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Breithaupt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition and emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="581" to="601" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fact vs. affect in the telephone game: All levels of surprise are retold with high accuracy, even independently of facts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Breithaupt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Liddell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Schille-Hudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Whaley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2210</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparison of markov versus quantum dynamical models of human decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kvam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pleskac</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1526</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model comparisons and model selections based on generalization criterion methodology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y.-M</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="189" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical comparison of markov and quantum models of decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lambert-Mogiliansky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="433" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum dynamics of human decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="220" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Snow queen is evil and beautiful: Experimental evidence for probabilistic contextuality in human choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Cervantes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Dzhafarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">193</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Easley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Networks, crowds, and markets: Reasoning about a highly connected world</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge university press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum mechanics and path integrals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Feynman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hibbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Styer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Courier Corporation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accentuation of information processes and biases in group judgments integrating base-rate and case-specific information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Hinsz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tindale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Nagao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing serial reproduction and serial prediction of random walk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the annual meeting of the cognitive science society</title>
		<meeting>the annual meeting of the cognitive science society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A quantum walk model for emotion transmission in serial reproduction of narratives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Breithaupt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the annual meeting of the cognitive science society</title>
		<meeting>the annual meeting of the cognitive science society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maintaining cultural stereotypes in the serial reproduction of narratives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kashima</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="594" to="604" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Serial reproduction: An experimental simulation of cultural dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kashima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.-L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica Sinica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence through a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">É</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ninth acm sigkdd international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the ninth acm sigkdd international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="146" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social laser model for the bandwagon effect: generation of coherent information waves</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khrennikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entropy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">559</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An evaluation of a cognitive theory of response-order effects in survey measurement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Krosnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Alwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Public opinion quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="219" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conversational conventions, order of information acquisition, and the effect of base rates and individuating information on social judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Krosnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lehman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1140</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Serial reproduction reveals the geometry of visuospatial representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Langlois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Jacoby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Suchow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2012938118</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The science of fake news</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Baum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Benkler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Greenhill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Menczer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Others</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">359</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6380</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1094" to="1096" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deep learning. nature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lecun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">521</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="436" to="444" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The serial reproduction of conflict: Third parties escalate conflict through communication biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gelfand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kashima</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maintaining stereotypes in communication: Investigating memory biases and coherence-seeking in storytelling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lyons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kashima</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Asian Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum contagion: A quantum-like approach for the analysis of social contagion dynamics with heterogeneous adoption thresholds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mutlu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Garibay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entropy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">538</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information diffusion and external influence in networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th acm sigkdd international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 18th acm sigkdd international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum computation and quantum information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nielsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Chuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Cambridge university press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum cognition. Annual review of psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="749" to="778" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biased information search in group decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schulz-Hardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lüthgens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Moscovici</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">655</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human biases limit cumulative innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">288</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20202752</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1946" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explicit reasoning, confirmation bias, and illusory transactive memory: A simulation study of group medical decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tschan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Semmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gurtner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bizzari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Spychiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Breuer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Marsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Small Group Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="271" to="300" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From valence to emotions: Exploring the distribution of emotions in online product reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ullah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Amblee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Support Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A rational analysis of the effects of memory biases on serial reproduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A quantum walk model for idea propagation in social network and group decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entropy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">622</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The order effect on online review helpfulness: A social influence perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Support Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="87" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
