<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Speak Last and Step-by-Step: The Effect of Order and Response Mode on Legal Decisions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Mengxuan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Qiao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Speak Last and Step-by-Step: The Effect of Order and Response Mode on Legal Decisions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:16+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>legal decision-making</term>
					<term>order effect</term>
					<term>response mode</term>
					<term>belief updating</term>
					<term>Bayesian reasoning</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>How does evidence presentation order and response mode affect legal judgments? Previous research on order effects in legal decision-making has produced mixed results, possibly due to different response modes adopted in the tasks: End-of-Sequence (EoS) or Step-by-Step (SbS), which might reflect different cognitive models that fact-finders employ during evidence evaluation and integration processes. This paper investigates how response mode interacts with evidence order to influence judgments of the probability of guilt and verdict. In Study 1 (N = 159), no order effects were found in the EoS condition; but a recency effect emerged in the SbS condition. Study 2 (N = 95) revealed no order effect when the first set of evidence was judged SbS and the second set EoS. We also found that participants&apos; probability of guilt judgments were generally consistent with Bayesian predictions based on their prior beliefs and perceived strength of new evidence when it was responded SbS, but not when it was responded EoS. We discuss potential explanations for these findings and their implications for legal decision-making.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 3</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Speak Last and Step-by-Step: The Effect of Order and Response Mode on</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Legal Decisions</head><p>In the UK, the Criminal Procedures Rule -Rule 25.9(2)(k) specifies that 'the defendant may make final representations' 1 before the verdict is reached. Similarly, German Federal Ministry of Justice guarantees that 'the defendant has the last word' 2 , allowing the defence a final opportunity to influence the court's judgment. In the US, however, closing arguments typically follow a different sequence: the government presents its argument, the defence responds, and then the government presents a final rebuttal argument 3 .</p><p>From a normative perspective, evidence should be objectively and rationally evaluated, with fact-finders forming similar conclusions regardless of the presentation order. Yet extensive psychological research suggests this ideal is rarely achieved. Some studies indicate that evidence encountered earlier leads to a preliminary conclusion, which then shapes the interpretation of later evidence and subsequent judgments (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Charman et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Imhoff &amp; Nickolaus, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Tetlock, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Wells et al., 1985)</ref>. Others suggest that more recently received evidence is more accessible in memory, thus having a greater impact on judgments (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Ask et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Furnham, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Higgins, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Maegherman et al., 2022)</ref>. If the order of prosecution and defence arguments affects legal judgments, it raises significant concerns: wrongful convictions or acquittals may arise, challenging both the presumption of innocence and the principle that legal decisions should remain free from extra-legal factors.</p><p>One key factor found to influence order effects is the response mode <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hogarth &amp; Einhorn, 1992</ref>)-whether judgments are made holistically after considering all evidence <ref type="bibr">(End-of-Sequence [EoS]</ref>) or updated incrementally after each piece of evidence <ref type="bibr">(Step-by-Step [SbS]</ref>). Although <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref>  recency effects in complex tasks regardless of response mode, fact-finders might adopt different cognitive models when responses are elicited by different approaches. The story model describes a process that a coherent narrative explanation is constructed when asked for an EoS judgment (N. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Pennington &amp; Hastie, 1992)</ref>, while the belief-adjustment model describes a process of sequential adjustments to previous beliefs by the impact of new evidence during SbS judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hogarth &amp; Einhorn, 1992)</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we first review the literature on order effects in decision-making, with a particular focus on legal decisions. We then explore how response mode interacts with evidence presentation order to shape judgment outcomes, examining different cognitive models associated with each response mode. Following this, we present two studies that explore how the response mode interacts evidence presentation order to influence legal judgments. This allows us to explore which cognitive model may more accurately reflect the legal decision-making process and be associated with fewer cognitive biases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Order Effects in Legal Decisions</head><p>When individuals evaluate a sequence of information, they adjust their judgments based on newly acquired information. If the adjustment is insufficient, earlier information disproportionally influences the decision, leading to a primacy effect. Conversely, if the adjustment is excessive, newer information has a greater impact, resulting in a recency effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Keltz &amp; Adelman, 2008)</ref>. Early research centred mostly on the primacy effect. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Asch (1946)</ref>'s classic study on impression formation demonstrated that participants who were first exposed to favourable adjectives formed a more positive impression compared to those who were first exposed to unfavourable adjectives. This finding has been replicated across various domains, including impression formation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Anderson &amp; Hubert, 1963)</ref>, performance attribution (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Allen &amp; Feldman, 1974)</ref>, and even in Artificial Intelligence systems, such as ChatGPT, which showed a tendency to favour earlier labels presented in a prompt <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Wang et al., 2023)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 5</head><p>In the legal context, some early research identified a primacy effect. D. C. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Pennington (1982)</ref> found that participants were more likely to deliver guilty verdicts when witnesses and testimony indicating guilty were presented first compared to other conditions (i.e., witness and testimony indicating innocence were presented first, mixed witness and testimony were presented first). <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Tetlock (1983)</ref> also observed a primacy effect when evidence suggestive of guilt was presented first. Moreover, <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Wells et al. (1985)</ref> discovered that if the defence presented its case early on, participants were more likely to find the defendant not guilty.</p><p>Other studies have identified a recency effect in legal judgments. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Anderson (1959)</ref> observed a recency effect when participants made successive judgments based on prosecution and defence evidence presented in different orders. The same finding has been later replicated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Furnham (1986)</ref> and with various types of evidence, such as alibi and eyewitness evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Dahl et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Enescu &amp; Kuhn, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Price &amp; Dahl, 2014)</ref>, DNA and alibi evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Charman et al., 2016)</ref>, and other type of forensic evidence (e.g., hair, CCTV, and shoe prints) <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Maegherman et al., 2022)</ref>. Another study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Costabile and Klein (2005)</ref> showed a recency effect of critical evidence, in which participants who were exposed to incriminating critical evidence by the last witness rendered significantly more guilty verdicts than those who were exposed to the same piece of evidence by the first witness.</p><p>Despite some early research suggesting otherwise, most studies identify a recency effect in legal judgments. This might be due to that the primacy effect is fragile in the sense that it can easily be affected when the task requirement is adapted. For instance, when participants were asked to recall the words or perform other interrupting tasks, they paid more attention to the later information (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Anderson &amp; Hubert, 1963;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dreben et al., 1979)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Lichtenstein and Srull (1987)</ref> demonstrated that the nature of the task-whether participants are asked to make an impression, remember, or comprehend the list of information-determined whether a primacy or recency effect emerged, where primacy ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 6 effects were only observed in impression tasks. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Tetlock (1983)</ref> also found that the primacy effect diminished when participants were made aware that they would later have to justify their judgment. They explained that participants were more cautious to jump to confident conclusions from incomplete evidence and more receptive to later contradictory evidence when they felt that they held accountability for their decisions.</p><p>Memory is also a key element in making evaluative judgment <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Lichtenstein &amp; Srull, 1987</ref>)-individuals are more inclined to remember evidence that is presented later, thus later evidence has a greater influence on the subsequent verdict <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Costabile &amp; Klein, 2005</ref>).</p><p>Because legal decision-making is a complex and cognitively demanding task, fact-finders may rely on the most readily accessible and temporally salient information in memory-typically the most recently encountered evidence-to save cognitive load, leading to a recency effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Ask et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Higgins, 1996)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Mode and Cognitive Models in Legal Decision-Making</head><p>Hogarth and Einhorn (1992) identified three variables influencing order effects: series length, task complexity, and response mode. They categorised tasks consisting of two to 12 items as short series and those with more than 17 items as long series. Task complexity relates to the amount and familiarity of information in each item. Complex tasks, such as those involving legal evidence evaluation and judgments, form the main focus of this paper. The response mode describes how information is received and processed, with two primary modes: EoS and SbS. The EoS response mode requires a global assessment of all evidence to reach a single final judgment, while the SbS response mode involves adjusting one's opinion incrementally with each piece of evidence in a sequence. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref>' belief-adjustment model predicts that for short and simple tasks, an EoS response mode induces primacy effects and and SbS response mode induces recency effects. However, the EoS response mode demands more from memory and cognitive resources, as it requires integrating multiple items before reaching a ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 7 judgment-especially for complex tasks with longer series-individuals therefore shift to an SbS response mode when the task is too cognitively demanding. Their experiments also indicated a recency effect in both the EoS and SbS response modes with mixed evidence.</p><p>Reviewing 60 studies consisting of 76 data points, they concluded that the recency effect is associated with complex tasks and is independent of response mode, although only 11 studies were included in the complex category, with only 2 studies adopted an SbS response mode. A more recent review also observed the same patterns (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Keltz &amp; Adelman, 2008</ref>).</p><p>On the other hand, EoS and SbS response modes might reflect different cognitive models that individuals adopt when making legal judgments. During the SbS response mode, individuals adopt the belief-adjustment model where they form an initial judgment and adjusting it incrementally based on new evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hogarth &amp; Einhorn, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Kerstholt &amp; Jackson, 1998)</ref>. By contrast, during the EoS response mode, individuals are likely to adopt a story model, which allows individuals to evaluate and integrate all available evidence to construct a complete, coherent narrative explanation (N. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Pennington &amp; Hastie, 1988</ref>). The story model posits that fact-finders focus on the causal connections between events within a narrative. Because this process emphasises coherence over sequence, the order in which evidence is presented should have little effect on judgment outcomes. It is worth noting that N. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Pennington and Hastie (1992)</ref> found the order of evidence presentation did influence jurors' decisions-but specifically when evidence was arranged in a story-consistent order or an issue-based order, to support or disrupt the construction of a coherent causal narrative, respectively. This differs from the present study, which focuses on the presentation order of evidence sets (i.e., prosecution followed by defence vs. defence followed by prosecution), rather than the internal coherence of the narrative structure.</p><p>Differences in these mental models can lead to different legal judgments. For instance, N. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Pennington and Hastie (1992)</ref> found that participants gave more extreme judgments during global (EoS) evaluations than in SbS assessments, judging the defendant as more guilty or innocent based on a story suggestive of conviction or acquittal, ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 8 respectively. They further explain that global evaluation leads individuals to focus on the causal connections between events within the narrative, thereby downplaying inconsistent evidence. In contrast, SbS evaluations produce more moderate judgments, as individuals continually weigh new evidence against prior beliefs. Supporting this, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Kuhn et al. (1994)</ref> found that individuals with more competent reasoning skills tended to offer more moderate verdicts, implying that SbS evaluations might require more cognitive resources, which challenges <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref>'s prediction that individuals might switch from an EoS approach to an SbS approach because it is more cognitively demanding to make EoS judgments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview of Studies</head><p>Given the mixed results and inconclusive explanations of how legal judgment outcomes are influenced by response mode and its interaction with evidence order, the current research aimed to directly compare these variables in a legal decision-making task.</p><p>To our knowledge, this is the first to adopt both EoS and SbS response modes in a single judgment task.</p><p>In our studies, we presented a summary of a criminal case to the participants with a set of prosecution evidence and a set of defence evidence, where the order of sets and response modes were manipulated. We investigated how participants' judgments of the probability of guilt and verdict were influenced by these variables, as well as the Bayesian predictions calculated from their prior beliefs of guilt and the perceived strength of new evidence.</p><p>In Study 1, we compared the judgments between an all EoS context and an all SbS context. In Study 2, we looked at judgments in which the first set of evidence was judged SbS and the second set EoS. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figures 1 and 2</ref> illustrate the experimental designs for Studies 1 and 2, respectively. All materials, data, and analyses are available at the OSF repository (https://osf.io/u72fr/).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>Experimental design for Study 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>In Study 1, we investigated how the order of defence and prosecution evidence, along with the response mode, influenced participants' judgments of the perceived probability of guilt and verdict. We asked participants to make judgments under two conditions: they either provided EoS judgments after viewing the whole sets of evidence (EoS condition) or made sequential judgments after viewing each piece of evidence (SbS condition). We expected a recency effect in the SbS condition, as predicted by the belief-adjustment model. In the EoS condition, if participants adapted to an SbS approach as suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref>, a recency effect would be anticipated; on the</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2</head><p>Experimental design for Study 2.</p><p>other hand, if participants adopted a story model to construct a holistic explanation, no order effect should occur.</p><p>In addition, we investigated whether participants' probability of guilt judgments aligned with Bayesian predictions for belief updating based on their conditional probability assessments of the new evidence and prior beliefs of guilt. This assessment corresponds to the quantification of the strength of evidence as measured by the likelihood ratio, which is the standard measure in legal and forensic contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Good, 1989)</ref>. Notably, a judgment stage between evidence sets in the EoS condition was implemented to provide a 'prior' for the Bayesian calculation. If participants treated each evidence set as a distinct 'item', a recency effect could still arise in the EoS condition, as observed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 11</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 159 participants (M age = 38.3, SD age = 13.3, N Female = 79) from Prolific Academic; 78 participants were assigned to the EoS condition and 81 to the SbS condition. Participants were pre-screened for fluency in English and a platform approval rate between 95-100%. All participants provided informed consent and were reimbursed £1.50 for completing the 9-minute experiment. The study was approved by the UCL Psychology Ethics Committee (EP/2018/005).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Materials</head><p>The study employed a 2 (order: between-subject) × 2 (response mode: between-subject) × 2 (stage: within-subject [EoS condition]) or 8 (stage: within-subject [SbS condition]) mixed design. We constructed a case summary and evidence that was loosely based on the Sally Clark case 4 . The case summary included only objective and factual information. The defence and prosecution evidence sets comprised four pieces of evidence each. Participants either received the defence evidence set followed by the prosecution evidence set (DP order), or the prosecution evidence set followed by the defence evidence set (PD order). The order of evidence within each set was consistent.</p><p>We measured participants' perceived probability of guilt of the defendant on a scale from 0% to 100% by asking the question 'Based on the given evidence, what do you think is the probability that the defendant is guilty?', and verdict choices of 'Not guilty' and 'Guilty' by asking the question 'Please state your verdict for the defendant.'. Two conditional probability questions were asked at each judgment stage; examples of the conditional probability questions for one piece of prosecution evidence are:</p><p>'If the defendant is NOT GUILTY, how likely is it that the hypoxic damage to Ben's brain was caused a matter of hours before death?' 'If the defendant is GUILTY, how likely is it that the hypoxic damage to Ben's brain was caused a matter of hours before death?' All conditional probability questions were answered on a scale from 0% (Not likely at all) to 100% (Extremely likely).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants accessed the experiment on Qualtrics (www.qualtrics.com). After receiving instructions, participants read the case summary and the sets of defence and prosecution evidence in either the DP or PD order. They were randomly assigned to either the EoS condition or the SbS condition. In the EoS condition, participants provided judgments after viewing each set of evidence. In the SbS condition, participants received the evidence piece by piece and gave judgments after each piece. Participants answered questions about the probability of guilt, verdict, and conditional probabilities at every judgment stage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Main analysis</head><p>We compared participants' probability of guilt ratings in the EoS condition with responses given at stage 4 (end of the first set of evidence) and 8 (end of the second set of evidence) in the SbS condition using a 2 (order) × 2 (stage) × 2 (response mode) mixed ANOVA. We found a main effect of order, F (1, 155) = 21.66, p &lt; .001, an interaction between order and stage, F (1, 155) = 184.45, p &lt; .001, and an interaction between order, stage, and response mode, F (1, 155) = 8.03, p = .005. However, there was no main effect of stage, F (1, 155) = 0.05, p = .832, or response mode, F (1, 155) = 1.37, p = .245.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 13</head><p>Pairwise comparisons revealed a significant difference in the final probability of guilt ratings between the DP (M = 0.67) and PD orders (M = 0.48) in the SbS condition, t(155) = 3.63, p = .009, while no difference was found in the EoS condition between orders, t(155) = 0.93, p = .983 (see <ref type="figure">Figure 3)</ref>. Further Chi-squared tests showed a significant association between order and final verdict in the SbS condition, χ 2 (1, N = 81) = 6.46, p = .011; but no association in the EoS condition, χ 2 (1, N = 78) = 0.82, p = .365 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Observed vs. predicted probabilities</head><p>To calculate the individual Bayesian belief updating models, we applied Bayes' rule to predict each participant's posterior probability P (H|E), based on their stated In cases where participants gave extreme responses of '0's and '1's for the conditional probability questions, we converted those to '0.001's and '0.999's, respectively, to avoid dividing by zero.</p><p>We conducted a 2 (order) × 2 (judgment type [observed vs. predicted]:</p><p>within-subject) mixed ANOVA for the EoS condition. Stage 1 was not included in this analysis because there was no prior for the estimations for stage 1 judgments. We found a main effect of judgment type, F (1, 76) = 6.77, p = .011, and an interaction between order and judgment type, F (1, 76) = 4.32, p = .041. However, we did not find a main effect of order, F (1, 76) = 0.04, p = .950. Pairwise comparisons revealed a significant difference between the observed (M = 0.50) and predicted (M = 0.63) probabilities in the PD order, t(76) = 3.35, p = .007, but not in the DP order, t(76) = 0.37, p = .983 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5</ref>).  Further, we conducted a 2 (order) × 7 (stage) × 2 (judgment type) mixed ANOVA for the SbS condition. Again, Stage 1 was not included in this analysis. We found a main effect of order, F (1, 79) = 5.84, p = .018, a main effect of judgment type, F (1, 79) = 8.59, p = .004, an interaction between order and stage, F (3.77, 298.17) = 55.40, p &lt; .001, and an interaction between order, stage, and judgment type, F (5.80, 458.31) = 5.25, p &lt; .001 5 .</p><p>Pairwise comparisons revealed no significant differences between the observed and predicted values within the same stages in either order (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> and <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 6</head><p>Study 1: Observed and predicted probabilities in DP and PD orders in SbS condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In Study 1, we found that the order in which defence and prosecution evidence was presented did not influence participants' judgments of the probability of guilt or verdict in the EoS condition, but a recency effect emerged in the SbS condition. These results suggest that participants did not switch to an SbS approach in the EoS condition, contradicting <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref>'s model prediction. Participants might have employed the story model in the EoS condition, evaluating and integrating evidence holistically to forming a single, conclusive judgment. The additional judgment stage between evidence sets also did not disrupt the construction of an explanation that informed their final decision.</p><p>Notably, in the EoS condition, participants' probability of guilt judgments were relatively in line with Bayesian predictions in the DP order. However, the observed guilt ratings in the PD order were lower than Bayesian predictions, suggesting that after initially considering the prosecution evidence, participants revised their perception of guilt more strongly in favour of innocence than predicted, following the later presentation of defence evidence.</p><p>While observing a significant main effect of judgment type in the SbS condition, pairwise comparisons showed no significant differences between the observed probability of guilt judgments and predictions in any of the stages in either order. We, therefore, propose that participants generally adhered to Bayesian predictions relative to their own prior beliefs of guilt and evaluations of the strength of evidence when presented with items of evidence SbS. This result is consistent with previous findings (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Shengelia &amp; Lagnado, 2021)</ref>; it also confirms <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Schum and Martin (1982)</ref>'s claim that people tend to assess evidence accurately on an item-by-item basis rather than integrating it into a single comprehensive judgment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>In Study 1, we observed a recency effect when participants judged evidence in an SbS response mode. In Study 2, we would like to further confirm whether such effect was caused by the SbS processing approach of recent evidence. Therefore, in this study, we presented the first set of evidence in an SbS response mode and the second set in an EoS response mode. If later received evidence had more influence on participants' belief only because it was processed SbS, the recency effect would disappear.</p><p>Additionally, in Study 1, we found that participants' probability of guilt judgments aligned with Bayesian predictions in the DP order but not in the PD order in the EoS condition, while they were generally consistent in SbS judgments for both orders. In Study 2, we aimed to further assess whether the Bayesian alignment held in a mixed SbS + EoS condition.</p><p>ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 19</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 95 participants from Prolific Academic, pre-screened for fluency in English and had a platform approval rate of 95-100%. Individuals who have participated in previous experiments were excluded. Two participants failed the attention check questions, leaving 93 participants (M age = 36.9, SD age = 11.6, N Female = 48) for the analyses. 45 participants were assigned to the DP order and 48 were assigned to the PD order. All participants provided informed consent and were reimbursed £1.50 for the 9-minute experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Materials</head><p>We employed a 2 (order: between-subject) × 5 (stage: within-subject) mixed design. Stage 1-4 were SbS judgments of pieces of evidence in the first set and stage 5 was an EoS judgment of the second evidence set. The same materials and measurements used in Study 1 were adopted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>After reading the instructions and case summary, participants were randomly assigned to either the DP or PD order. In the DP order, participants viewed the defence evidence piece by piece and provided judgments after each piece; followed by the prosecution evidence presented all at once, after which they gave a final judgement. In the PD order, participants viewed the prosecution evidence piece by piece and provided judgments after each piece, followed by the defence evidence presented all at once and provided final judgments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 20</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Main analysis</head><p>A two-sample t-test showed no difference in the final probability of guilt ratings between the DP (M = 60.7) and PD (M = 55.4) orders, t(91) = 1.09, p = .280 (see <ref type="figure">Figure   7</ref>). Further, a Chi-squared test showed no association between order and final verdicts,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">χ 2</formula><p>(1, N = 93) = 0.57, p = .452 (see <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 7</head><p>Study 2: Final probability of guilt judgments in the DP and PD orders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Observed vs. predicted probabilities</head><p>As in Study 1, we applied Bayes' rule to calculate each participant's predicted posterior probability values using their prior beliefs and likelihood judgments of evidence.</p><p>We conducted a 2 (order) × 4 (stage) × 2 (judgment type) mixed ANOVA. The first stage was not included because there were no priors for stage 1 to calculate the Bayesian predictions. We found a main effect of order, F (1, 91) = 40.31, p &lt; .001, an interaction order, the difference was found to be not statistically significant, t(91) = 3.42, p = .067. No significant differences between the observed and predicted values were detected in stages 2 to 4 in either order, where participants made SbS judgments (see <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref> and <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>).</p><p>6 Mauchly's test indicated that the assumption of sphericity for the interaction term of order and stage had been violated (p &lt; .001), and therefore degrees of freedom were corrected using Huynh-Feldt estimates of sphericity (ϵ = 0.88).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 9</head><p>Study 2: Observed probability of guilt ratings and predicted probabilities in DP and PD orders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In Study 2, we found that the evidence presentation order did not affect participants' final judgments of the probability of guilt and verdict when the first set of evidence was evaluated SbS and the second set EoS. This result suggests that the recency effect we observed in the previous study was not merely caused by the presentation order of evidence, but the SbS processing approach of the recent evidence.</p><p>Participants' probability of guilt judgments aligned with Bayesian predictions during stages 2 to 4, where they responded SbS. However, after viewing the final evidence set and responded EoS, participants' judgments diverged from Bayesian predictions: they revised their perception of guilt of the defendant significantly lower than the prediction after considering the later presented defence evidence; and they revised their perception of guilt higher than the prediction after prosecution evidence was later presented, although in Study 1 in which participants revised the perceived probability of the defendant's guilt downward-shifting toward greater innocence than predicted-after viewing the defence evidence presented later.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>In two studies, we explored the effects of evidence presentation order and response mode on people's judgments in a legal decision-making task. We found that a recency effect emerged only when the last evidence set was processed in an SbS response mode. No order effects appeared when all evidence was processed in an EoS response mode, despite there being an additional judgment stage between the evidence sets. Moreover, no order effects were observed when the initial evidence set was processed SbS and the latter EoS.</p><p>Our results suggest that participants integrated evidence holistically in an EoS ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 24 context and reached judgments that were insensitive to the evidence presentation order.</p><p>These finding challenges <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref>'s claim, which posits that people automatically shift to an SbS approach when asked to make an EoS judgment in a complex task. Instead, participants may have applied different cognitive approaches depending on whether they evaluated evidence SbS or EoS. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref> classified simple tasks as those involving only a single item for each piece of evidence with a reasonably assumed task familiarity, while complex tasks involve a large amount of information and/or unfamiliar stimuli. The task in our experiments fits into their classification of a complex task, however, it is possible that our task was not complex enough to tax participants' cognitive load for them to switch the evaluation approach. Future studies are needed to explore how task complexity impacts the cognitive models people adopt when evaluating evidence and making legal judgments.</p><p>The recency effects we observed were reflected both in the probability of guilt judgment and verdicts, a pattern distinct from <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Maegherman et al. (2022)</ref>, who reported a recency effect only in the likelihood of guilty indications but not in the conviction rates.</p><p>The difference between our results may be due to the relatively larger amount of evidence in our study. There might be a cognitive delay in the integration of evidence and this may have weakened the recency effect in verdicts with smaller evidence sets. Despite the relatively larger evidence amount in our studies, the task remains a short series task by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hogarth and Einhorn (1992)</ref>'s classification, and this may not fully represent realistic criminal cases with extensive evidence. Future studies should incorporate the manipulation of evidence volume and explore whether there is a delay in translating the probability of guilt judgments into verdicts, and how it might interact with order effects and response mode. Additionally, we did not manipulate the internal order of individual pieces of evidence within each set, which may have limited our ability to detect potential anchoring effects. Future research could explore how the sequence of specific items might influence judgments and how this interacts with response mode.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 25</head><p>We also found that participants' probability of guilt judgments generally aligned with Bayesian predictions during the SbS response mode, supporting research suggesting that people are capable of updating their beliefs in a Bayesian fashion <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Shengelia &amp; Lagnado, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Sommer et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Thompson et al., 2013)</ref>. However, some discrepancies were shown in EoS judgments, especially after viewing the defence evidence set. This might be due to the difficulty of the task to aggregate all evidence to answer the conditional probability questions. This finding is also possibly explained by the story model, in which N. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Pennington and Hastie (1992)</ref> claim that people might not consider all evidence when making global judgments, as they may forget to include or downplay inconsistent evidence, leading their guilt judgments to depart from Bayesian predictions.</p><p>Future studies could explore this further by explicitly prompting participants to construct narratives by collecting qualitative reasoning while manipulating the response mode.</p><p>Moreover, answering the conditional probability questions might have aided participants in thinking about the probability of guilt ratings more accurately and rationally, which might explain why the values were generally consistent in the SbS stages. Future research can explore further whether asking individuals to consider the conditional probabilities of new evidence assists them in evaluating the probability of guilt.</p><p>Our findings answer the question we started this paper with, implying that who speaks the last in the courtroom matters to the outcome of legal judgments. But more importantly, the evaluation process, which might associate with different cognitive models, used by fact-finders plays a more pivotal role. It highlights the importance of evidence organisation by attorneys and investigators when building cases and deciding charges and pleas.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>predicted and observed 1 The Criminal Procedure Rules 2020 -PART 25. Procedure on plea of not guilty -Rule 25.9(2)(k) 2 Strafprozeßordnung (StPO) § 258 Schlussvorträge; Recht des letzten Wortes 3 United States Courts -Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure -Rule 29.1. Closing Argument ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 4</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 Study 1 :</head><label>31</label><figDesc>Final probability of guilt judgments in DP and PD orders in EoS and SbS conditions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>conditional probabilities, P (E|H), P (E|¬H), and their prior P (H) from the previous time-step. ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE 14 Study 1: Proportion of final verdicts in DP and PD orders in EoS and SbS conditions. P (H|E) = P (E|H) • P (H) P (E|H) • P (H) + P (E|¬H) • (1 − P [H])</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Study 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Observed and predicted probabilities in the final stage in DP and PD orders in EoS condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 8 Study 2 :</head><label>82</label><figDesc>Proportion of final verdicts in theDP and PD orders.    between order and judgment type, F (1, 91) = 10.39, p = .002, an interaction between order and stage, F (2.64, 240.12) = 37.93, p &lt; .001 6 , and an interaction between order, stage, and judgment type, F (3, 273) = 11.01, p &lt; .001. Pairwise comparisons revealed a significant difference between observed (M = 0.55) and predicted values (M = 0.70) in the final stage in the PD order, t(91) = 4.50, p = .002. While there was a descriptive difference between the observed (M = 0.61) and predicted judgments (M = 0.49) in the final stage in the DP</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Study 1: Estimated differences, t ratios, and p values of observed and predicted guilt judgments from stage 2 to 8 in DP and PD orders in the SbS condition.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Stage Order Estimate t.ratio p.value</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.525</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>-0.029</cell><cell>-0.798</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>-0.080</cell><cell>-1.646</cell><cell>0.997</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>0.072</cell><cell>1.383</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>-0.009</cell><cell>-0.223</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>-0.038</cell><cell>-0.887</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>0.032</cell><cell>0.820</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>-0.151</cell><cell>-3.586</cell><cell>0.104</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>-0.071</cell><cell>-2.174</cell><cell>0.913</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>0.067</cell><cell>1.933</cell><cell>0.974</cell></row><row><cell>7</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>-0.025</cell><cell>-0.630</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>-0.080</cell><cell>-1.868</cell><cell>0.983</cell></row><row><cell>8</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>-0.016</cell><cell>-0.364</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>0.009</cell><cell>0.203</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Study 2: Estimated differences, t ratios, and p values of observed and predicted guilt judgments from stage 2 to 5 in DP and PD orders.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Stage Order Estimate t.ratio p.value</cell></row><row><cell>2 (SbS)</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>-0.019</cell><cell>0.525</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>-0.032</cell><cell>-0.880</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell>3 (SbS)</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>-0.066</cell><cell>-1.841</cell><cell>0.894</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>0.046</cell><cell>1.342</cell><cell>0.993</cell></row><row><cell>4 (SbS)</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.051</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>-0.036</cell><cell>-1.083</cell><cell>0.999</cell></row><row><cell>5 (EoS)</cell><cell>DP</cell><cell>0.142</cell><cell>3.888</cell><cell>0.017</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PD</cell><cell>-0.162</cell><cell>-4.581</cell><cell>0.002</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">this difference was not statistically significant. This pattern is similar to what we observed</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">http://www.bailii.org/ew/cases/EWCA/Crim/2003/1020.html</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Mauchly's test indicated that the assumption of sphericity for the interaction term of 'order' and 'stage' (p &lt; .001) and the interaction term of 'order', 'stage', and 'judgment type' (p &lt; .001) had been violated, and therefore degrees of freedom were corrected using Greenhouse-Geisser (ϵ = 0.63) and Huynh-Feldt (ϵ = 0.97) estimates of sphericity, respectively.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank the anonymous reviewers for commenting on a previous version of this manuscript.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ORDER EFFECT AND RESPONSE MODE</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tutor attributions and attitude as a function of tutee performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="320" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Test of a model for opinion change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">371</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of concomitant verbal recall on order effects in personality impression formation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Verbal Learning and Verbal Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5-6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="391" />
			<date type="published" when="1963" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Forming impressions of personality. The journal of abnormal and social psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Asch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1946" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">258</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The &apos;elasticity&apos;of criminal evidence: A moderator of investigator bias</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ask</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rebelius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Granhag</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology: The Official Journal of the Society for Applied Research in Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1245" to="1259" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence evaluation and evidence integration in legal decision-making: Order of evidence presentation as a moderator of context effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Charman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Carbone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kekessie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Villalba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finishing strong: Recency effects in juror judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Costabile</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating investigators: How presentation order influences participant-investigators&apos; interpretations of eyewitness identification and alibi evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Brimacombe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">368</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The independence of evaluative and item information: Impression and recall order effects in behavior-based impression formation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dreben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hastie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1758</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Serial effects of evidence on legal decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Enescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kuhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Psychology Applied to Legal Context</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The robustness of the recency effect: Studies using legal evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Furnham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of General Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="357" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Weight of evidence and the (bayesian) likelihood ratio. Department of Statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Good</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Statistical Consulting Center</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Virginia</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Activation: Accessibility, and salience. Social psychology: Handbook of basic principles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="168" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Order effects in belief updating: The belief-adjustment model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hogarth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Einhorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combined anchoring: Prosecution and defense claims as sequential anchors in the courtroom</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Imhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nickolaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Legal and criminological psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing information order effects in a long series of evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C I K</forename><surname>Keltz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Adelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Engineering Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judicial decision making: Order of evidence presentation and availability of background information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kerstholt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology: The Official Journal of the Society for Applied Research in Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="445" to="454" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How well do jurors reason? competence dimensions of individual variation in a juror reasoning task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kuhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Weinstock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Flaton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="289" to="296" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Processing objectives as a determinant of the relationship between recall and judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lichtenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Srull</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="118" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Law and order effects: On cognitive dissonance and belief perseverance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Maegherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ask</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Horselenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Koppen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry, psychology and law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Witnesses and their testimony: Effects of ordering on juror verdicts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="318" to="333" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explanation-based decision making: Effects of memory structure on judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hastie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">521</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explaining the evidence: Tests of the story model for juror decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hastie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">189</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Order and strength matter for evaluation of alibi and eyewitness evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Price</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="150" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Formal and empirical research on cascaded inference in jurisprudence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law &amp; Society Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are jurors intuitive statisticians? bayesian causal reasoning in legal contexts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Shengelia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">519262</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Updating, evidence evaluation, and operator availability: A theoretical framework for understanding belief</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sommer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Musolino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hemmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">131</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">373</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accountability and the perseverance of first impressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social psychology quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do jurors give appropriate weight to forensic identification evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Kaasa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Empirical Legal Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="359" to="397" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hooi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2310.13206</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Primacy effect of chatgpt. arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The timing of the defense opening statement: Don&apos;t wait until the evidence is in</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Wrightsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Miene</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="758" to="772" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
