<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Competition Dynamics of Approach and Avoidance Motivations Following Interpersonal Transgression</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Zhejiang Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>321004</postCode>
									<settlement>Jinhua</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Neuroscience Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">NYU Grossman Medical Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10016</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Virginia Tech Carilion Fralin Biomedical Research Institute</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>24016</postCode>
									<settlement>Roanoke</settlement>
									<region>VA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhewen</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weijian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Zhejiang Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>321004</postCode>
									<settlement>Jinhua</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Biosciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>WC1E 6BT</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Dr</roleName><forename type="first">Hongbo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
							<email>hongbo.yu@psych.ucsb.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California Santa Barbara</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>93106</postCode>
									<settlement>Santa Barbara</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Dr</roleName><forename type="first">Xiaolin</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology and Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Shanghai Key Laboratory of Mental Health and Psychological Crisis Intervention</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">East China Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200062</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Santa Barbara Santa Barbara</addrLine>
									<postCode>CA93106</postCode>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology and Cognitive Science East China</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200062</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Competition Dynamics of Approach and Avoidance Motivations Following Interpersonal Transgression</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:19+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>social transgression</term>
					<term>guilt</term>
					<term>mouse-tracking</term>
					<term>decision dynamics</term>
					<term>multi-attribute decision 44</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Two behavioral motivations co-exist in transgressors following an interpersonal transgressionapproaching and compensating the victim, and avoiding the victim. Little is known about how these motivations arise, compete, and drive transgressors&apos; decisions. The present study adopted a social interaction task to manipulate participants&apos; (i.e., the transgressor) responsibility for another&apos;s (i.e., the victim) monetary loss and measure the participants&apos; tradeoff between compensating the victim and avoiding face-to-face interactions with the victim. Following each transgression, participants used a computer mouse to choose between two options differing in the amount of compensation to the victim and the probability of face-to-face contact with the victim. Results showed that as participants&apos; responsibility increased, (1) the decision weights on contact avoidance relative to compensation increased, and (2) the onset of the contact-avoidance attribute was expedited and that of the compensation attribute was delayed. These results demonstrate how competing social motivations following transgression evolve and determine social decision-making and shed a light on how motivations modulate the dynamics of decisionmaking in general.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Interpersonal transgressions, as breaches of social norms, moral values, or mutual respect, are ubiquitous and inevitable in social life <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2)</ref>. In its basic form, interpersonal transgressions take place in dyads consisting of a transgressor and a victim, in which the transgressor voluntarily or accidentally commits an action (or omission) that constitutes the transgression, and the victim is the recipient of such action (or omission). Interpersonal transgressions have costly consequences to both the transgressor and the victim, in the form of both material/physical and mental/psychological losses <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref>. On the victim's side, in addition to material/physical losses, a transgression poses a threat to their relationship with the transgressor and more broadly their status as a valued group member <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4)</ref>. On the transgressor's side, committing a transgression may pose a threat to their moral self <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(5)</ref>, damage their relationship with the victim <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7)</ref>, and expose them to blame and even punishment from the victim or society <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(8)</ref>.</p><p>Given these costly consequences, it is then critical for the physical and mental well-being of both sides, their relationship, and the cohesion of the group and the functioning of society at large that the transgressor seeks reconciliation with the victim. Past research has identified two ways in which the transgressors react to the transgression and the victim (9-12). On the one hand, a transgressor could adopt an approach tendency, such as genuinely expressing guilt and remorse, offering apologies to and seeking forgiveness from the victim, and providing material and/or psychological compensation (13-16). Extant research in social psychology and affective science has shown that being responsible for an interpersonal transgression not only elicits guilt in the transgressor, but also leads the transgressor to adopt the approach tendency <ref type="bibr">(17-20, 16, 7)</ref>.</p><p>On the other hand, transgressors may adopt an avoidance tendency following a transgression because approach tendencies may come at some costs on the transgressors' side. For example, acknowledging one's own fault threatens one's belief in a moral self, which is associated with aversive feelings. Exposing oneself to the devaluations and negative reactive attitudes of the victim is embarrassing and uncomfortable <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(21)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(22)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(23)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(24)</ref>. Social contact with the victim also run the risk of inviting retribution from the victim in future interactions (25). For example, a study that manipulates the responsibility of the participants (i.e., the transgressors) in causing physical harm to another (i.e., the victim) shows that the participants would avoid direct eye contact with the victim during a virtual face-to-face meeting with the victim when the participants are fully responsible for the victim's harm; making eye contact with the victim elicits stronger emotional arousal in the transgressor <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(26)</ref>. The costs of approaching the victim may lead the transgressors to avoid the victim, such as escaping and hiding from the victim, denying the transgression, denying the full humanness of the victim, and even shifting blame to the victim <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(27)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(28)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(29)</ref>.</p><p>While past research has investigated the approach and avoidance tendencies of transgressors following transgression separately, these two behavioral tendencies or motivations need not be mutually exclusive. Indeed, some research has demonstrated that they can co-exist as two competing motivations that jointly determine how a transgressor reacts to the transgression and the victim. For example, <ref type="bibr">Amodio and colleagues (2007)</ref> observed opposite approach-avoidance motivations from the transgressors' electroencephalography activities in the early and late stages of social transgression (9), suggesting that transgression-induced approach and avoidance motivations may dynamically change over time. The temporal dynamics of approach and avoidance motivations reveal the underlying cognitive processes following social transgression.</p><p>For instance, the approach motivation may emerge rapidly, reflecting an intrinsic tendency to make amend and benefit the victim. Conversely, the avoidance motivation may emerge later after the transgressor is aware of the potential negative consequences of interacting with the victim, such as embarrassment and risks of retribution. This delayed emergence could be modulated by, for example, transgressor's responsibility in causing the interpersonal harm. The goal of the present study was to investigate whether the temporal prioritization between the two tendencies adjusts in accordance with the individual's moral and socio-affective states, such as the responsibility in causing interpersonal harm and the social emotions associated with it.</p><p>To address these questions, we utilize a decision-making framework to examine how the participants prioritize the processing of specific decision attributes that are respectively linked to the motivations of compensation and contact avoidance. We combined an established 113 interpersonal transgression task (16, 30) with mouse tracking technique and computational 114 modeling (31). In the task, we varied the levels of the transgressor's responsibility in causing the 115 victim's loss to create different social-affective states in the transgressor. To probe the 116 underlying transgressor's approach and avoidance motivations following a transgression, we 117 asked the participant to make two-attribute binary choices with each option containing the 118 amount of money used to compensate the victim (targeting approach motivation) and the 119 probability of having a face-to-face contact with the victim (targeting avoidance motivation).</p><p>Since mouse-tracking is a sensitive tool that provides a temporally precise measure of the dynamics of multiple decision components or attributes (for review, see (32)), we tracked the full dynamics of the decision process when the participants moved their mouse from the bottom center of thse screen to choose one of the options on the upper-left and upper-right corners of the screen.</p><p>Computational modeling was applied to disentangle the impact of each decision attribute on the momentary moving speed of the mouse cursor, which enabled us to pinpoint the temporal 128 dynamics of approach and avoidance motivations independently. We expected a temporal 129 prioritization of the processing of approach/compensation motivation relative to the processing 130 of avoidance/distancing motivation due to the prosocial nature of guilt. Therefore, the attribute of 131 monetary amount would have an earlier impact than that of the attribute of contact probability on 132 the participants' mouse movements. We also predicted that the conflict between the approach 133 and avoidance motivations would occur in the later stage of the decision when both motivations have accumulated strength in the process. We further predicted that such a temporal prioritization would be modulated by the transgressor's social-affective states. Specifically, we predicted that the transgressor's concerns about social contact increases when their responsibility in causing the victim's loss increased. As a result, the temporal processing of contact avoidance would be expedited and the processing of monetary compensation would be delayed when the concern of avoidance motivation increased relative to that of compensatory motivation. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>157</head><p>The interpersonal paradigm used to simulate social transgression 158</p><p>The task involves an interpersonal paradigm to induce different levels of guilt and embarrassment in the transgressor following an unintentional social transgression <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1a)</ref>.</p><p>On each trial, each Player A was paired with a Player B to collaborate on a visual search task. Either one failing the task would cost Player B of each pair, but not Player A, ten monetary units (M.U.). Player A's responsibility in causing Player B's monetary loss gradually increases from the condition when only Player B failed the task (partner-failed), to the condition when both players failed the task (both-failed), and then in the condition when only Player A failed the task (self-failed). The number of trials across the conditions was balanced by a control algorithm, without the participants' awareness (Supplementary Methods and supplementary <ref type="figure">Figure S2</ref>).</p><p>On the trials where Player B lost money, Player A was subsequently asked to choose between two options, each characterized by two decision attributes: the amount of monetary compensation to Player B (i.e., attribute ) and the probability of experiencing face-to-face interaction with Player B through a video camera later on that trial (i.e., attribute ) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1d</ref>).</p><p>The two options were marked as Option 1(with and ) and Option 2 (with and ) for subsequent data analysis; however, the participants were not aware of these labels as the left or right positions of the two options were randomized across trials. The difference in the offer values between the two options were marked as ≡ − and ≡ − and controlled by a self-adaptive algorithm to optimize the task efficiency in revealing the participant's preferences within limited numbers of trials <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1b</ref>; Supplementary Methods).</p><p>The social context was carefully designed to target Player A's approach motivation (e.g., 179</p><p>compensating Player B) and social avoidance motivation (e.g., avoiding being seen by Player B) with the two decision attributes, respectively (Methods). It is possible that Player A's monetary 181 preference and emotional reactions to face-to-face contact with Player B differ across individuals.</p><p>For example, altruistic compensation may not be desirable for all participants, as some may prefer their partner to be worse off financially (33, 34); similarly, video contact with the victim may not be aversive for all of the participants. The possible combinations of the valence of or (i.e., appetitive (+) or aversive (-)) results in four types of preference (i.e., + −, + +, − +, and − −), which was considered and well accommodated in the self-adaptive algorithm <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1c</ref>; Supplementary Methods).</p><p>To make a choice, Player A needed to move the mouse cursor from the bottom center of the screen to one of the options at the upper left and right corners of the screen <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1d</ref>; see details in Supplementaty Methods). We tracked Player A's mouse movement as they made their choices. Previous studies show that time pressure is important for motivating an individual to consider the importance and the prioritization of different decision factors <ref type="bibr">(35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36)</ref>. The Player A participants were asked to make their choices within varying time limits (see the distribution of time limits in the inset of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref>; see details in Supplementary Methods); otherwise, their choice would be determined by a computer algorithm. The participants were asked to rate their emotions at the end of each trial (guilt and embarrassment for Player A; anger and embarrassment for Player B, which were not reported here).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Self-reported emotions and final decisions 201</head><p>As a manipulation check, we first examined whether the social interaction paradigm successfully induced the social emotions as we expected. To this end, we carried out repeated-measures 203 ANOVA separately for guilt and embarrassment ratings. We found that the ratings of both guilt 204 and embarrassment significantly differed across conditions (guilt: F 2, 72 = 72.61, p &lt; 0.001; embarrassment: F 2, 72 = 26.23, p &lt; 0.001). Post-hoc paired t-test showed that both guilt and 206 embarrassment ratings were significantly higher when the participants were more responsible in 207 causing the partner's loss (guilt: self-failed &gt; both-failed: t 36 = 7.94, p &lt; 0.001; both-failed &gt; 208 partner-failed: t 36 = 6.09, p &lt; 0.001; embarrassment: self-failed &gt; both-failed: t 36 = 4.66, p &lt; 209 0.001; both-failed &gt; partner-failed: t 36 = 3.65, p &lt; 0.001) <ref type="figure">(Figures 2a and 2b)</ref>. These results confirmed the effectiveness of our paradigm in inducing the target emotions, suggesting that the social interaction contexts were engaging.</p><p>Further, because the emotion ratings were after the choice about compensation and video contact, the self-reported emotions may reflect how these behaviors influence participants' felt emotions. .20, p = .84) <ref type="figure">(Figure 2a)</ref>. In contrast, ratings of embarrassment were significantly higher after video contact (main effect: = 1.99, S.E. = .65, t 1246 = 3.07, p = .002; interaction with conditions: = -.32, S.E. = .27, t 2093 = -1.19, p = .23), but no such association was found between embarrassment ratings and the amount of money (main effect: = 082, S.E. = .07, t 684 = 1.17, p = .24; interaction with conditions: = -.041, S.E. = .029, t 2084 = -1.39, p = .16). These results demonstrated associations between the two emotions and the subsequent behaviors: the transgressor's feeling of guilt was alleviated after a higher amount of money compensated to the victim, while the feeling of embarrassment was intensified after the passive social contact.</p><p>However, it is important to note that in our current design, self-reported emotions were measured only as psychological consequences of social events (e.g., transgression, compensation, and video contact). We acknowledge that in complex, life-like social interactions such as our current task, it is unlikely that behavioral tendencies (e.g., compensation and contact avoidance) are solely driven by any one discrete emotion. Instead, it is possible that multiple cognitive affective 244 processes underlie a behavioral tendency. We hypothesized that as participants' perceived responsibility for interpersonal harm and their emotional reactions intensified, they would become more concerned about the embarrassing encounter during the video contact and/or a heightened heightened probability of being frowned upon. This would consequently shift their decision-making process, resulting in a rebalanced trade-off between compensation and avoidance in their choices. To test this, we examined how the participants weigh the attributes of monetary compensation (i.e., Δ ) and the probability of video contact (i.e., Δ ) in their decisions. Positive or negative decision weights indicate that the corresponding attribute is appetitive or aversive to the participants, respectively. Hierarchical both-failed: t = -.44, Cohen's D = -.07, p = .66). This pattern suggests the decision weight on benefiting the victim (i.e., monetary compensation) wanes as the concern about social contact increases (see <ref type="figure">Figure 2c</ref>). Since the collinearity between the estimated and was low 292 (supplementary <ref type="figure">Figure S7)</ref>, the trade-offs between the two decision weights reflect a competition between the two motivations within the participants, but not due to any restrictions during parameter estimation. This reveals a novel aspect of the transgressors' social responses following a transgression. Previous studies of guilt and compensation have consistently shown that transgressors' compensation or willingness to compensate increases as their responsibility in causing the victim's harm increases <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6,</ref><ref type="bibr">16,</ref><ref type="bibr">37)</ref>. However, unlike the present study and everyday social interactions, none of these studies has a social contact component in their experimental design. Therefore, they are not able to interrogate how the motives for benefiting the victim and avoiding social contact with the victim interact to determine the transgressor's response. To further investigate how the two motives evolve and interact over time, we examined the temporal dynamics of the processing of these two attributes based on the participants' mouse trajectories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Asynchronous processing of compensation and contact avoidance</head><p>The choice trajectories provide detailed information about how the cognitive processes </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>340</head><p>We further compared these dynamics across conditions and observed the shifting of dynamics 341 across conditions for both attributes. The ESTP of , was gradually delayed from the partnerfailed condition to the both-failed condition then to the self-failed condition ( <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1)</ref>  <ref type="table">Table    for</ref> a summary of statistics on the ESTPs and the corrected ESTPs across conditions).</p><p>Since , and , were regression weights to , they carried not only the information about the participants' preferences but also the mechanical features of mouse movement. Both of the , and , dynamics ramped up to a peak value around the time bin of 95 and were followed by a quick drop at the end of every time course <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Figure 3b)</ref>, which were aligned with the dynamics of average <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Figure 3a)</ref>. This was due to the mechanical nature of the movement 357 speed, which accelerated from the beginning of each trial to a peak and decelerated at the end of 358 each trial. To rule out the potential bias that the movement speed may introduce to the ESTP 359 distributions, we examined the dynamics of relative decision weights</p><p>, and , . Specifically, we obtain , and , by normalizing , and , with their summed magnitudes, i.e.,  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>).</p><p>Taken together, these results provide evidence that the processing of monetary compensation and contact avoidance is asynchronous. The participants' processing on monetary compensation was prioritized over contact avoidance across all conditions. However, as participants' motivation for contact avoidance relative to monetary compensation increased, the processing of contact avoidance was expedited and the processing of monetary compensation was delayed, suggesting that the processing adaptively prioritize these attributes to match the participants' changing needs under different conditions.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Neural circuit model predicts the curvatures of the competition dynamics</head><p>An alternative interpretation of the above the ESTPs results is that the temporal difference between and solely reflects the differences in the magnitude of decision weights instead of 409 asynchronous processing of the attributes. In other words, the decision weight with a larger magnitude could be detected earlier in time, appearing as the time asynchrony we observed in the ESTP distributions. To address this concern, we applied a neural circuit model of multi-attribute decision-making (38) to elucidate the impacts of magnitude and temporal asynchrony on the dynamics of the decision weights.</p><p>In this model, we assume two decision attributes, and , are integrated independently in the neural nodes of and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Figure 4a)</ref>. To test the impact of onset, we varied the onset of (i.e., ) so that the process on the attribute of p has no delay (i.e., synchronous, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 4b)</ref>, a large delay ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure  431</ref> 4c), or medium delay <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Figure 4d)</ref> relative to the onset of (i.e., ). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figures 4e-g</ref>   <ref type="figure">-j)</ref>. Importantly, time asynchrony impacts the fine-grained details of the dynamics. 437</p><p>When the integration of the attribute is delayed, the dynamics of , shows non-monotonic curvature in the late suppression when , rises <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Figures 4i and j)</ref>; in contrast, when the two attributes are integrated synchronously, the dynamics of , does not show such a late suppression even if the impact on its magnitude still exists <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Figure 4h)</ref>. The curvatures of the 441 late suppressions are different under different levels of time asynchrony. When has a large 442 delay relative to , the dynamics of , shows a quadratic curvature in the late suppression 443 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Figure 4i)</ref>; when has a medium delay relative to , the dynamics of , shows a kink of 444 decrease right after , rose <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Figure 4j)</ref>.</p><p>To compare the prediction of the neural circuit model with the empirical dynamics, we fitted the neural circuit model to the dynamics of relative weights ( , and , ) with two competing 448 hypotheses, namely whether the processing of the two attributes is asynchronous or synchronous 449 (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Methods)</ref>. Specifically, we took the similar approach as described above, 450 Taken together, the neural circuit model analysis teased apart the contributions of attribute magnitudes and temporal asynchrony to the dynamics of relative decision weights, suggesting that magnitude alone was not enough to result in the non-monotonic curvatures observed in our empirical data. The modeling results suggest an asynchronous rather than synchronous processing on the two attributes and corroborate the findings based on the analysis of the ESTP distributions, namely, the dynamics of contact avoidance arise later than that of the monetary compensation. Moreover, the time onset for contact avoidance were expedited and the time onset for compensation were delayed from both-failed condition to self-failed condition. asynchronous assumption, the circuit (dashed lines) captures well the rich and non-monotonic 508 dynamics in the empirical data (golden and blue lines indicating , and , , respectively, with shadows indicating the 95 C.I.) (l) The circuit model with the synchronous assumption captures worse the empirical dynamics than the asynchronous circuit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time-varying DDM reveals the shifting of asynchronous processing over conditions</head><p>To further dissociate the effects of condition on the onsets of decision attributes and the effects on the magnitude of the weights of the decision attributes, we applied a drift-diffusion model (DDM) to capture the onset of accumulation on each decision attribute while controlling for any difference induced by the drift rates of the attributes. To this end, we fit a time-varying drift diffusion model (tDDM), with a varying onset of accumulation on each decision attribute <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Figure 5a; cf. (39)</ref>). The model was applied to the reaction time and choice data but not to the mouse trajectories. The attributes of money (golden lines) and contact probability (blue lines)</p><p>were accumulated with independent drift rates and summed into an integrated decision signal (black line). Different from the implementation of most sequential sampling models, which do not assume temporal priorities on different decision attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(40)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(41)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(42)</ref>, the tDDM assumes the temporal onsets of the money attribute and the contact probability attribute can be asynchronous; it therefore includes a time asynchrony parameter ( ) to capture the relative onset time difference between these two attributes. Negative indicates the onset of money is later 526 than that of contact probability (illustrated in the two left panels in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Figure 5a</ref>) and positive 527 indicates the onset of money is earlier than that of contact probability (right panels in 528  <ref type="figure">Figure S8)</ref>. Results from tDDM showed that significantly differed across conditions (ANOVA: F 2,72 = 3.32, p = .042). Post-hoc test showed 533 that in the self-failed condition was more negative than in the both-failed and the 534 partner-failed conditions (self-failed -both-failed: t 36 = -2.10, p = .043, Cohen's D = -.45; self-failed -partner-failed: t 36 = -2.19, p = .035, Cohen's D = -.38; both-failed -partner-failed: : t 36 536 = .36, p = .72, Cohen's D = .06) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">(Figure 5b)</ref>, indicating that the onset of processing on contact avoidance relative to monetary compensation was expedited in the self-failed condition than in the other two conditions. Other parameters, including the drift rates, showed no significant differences across conditions (decision threshold: F 2,72 = .09, p = .91; bias: F 2,72 = 1.11, p = .33; non-decision time: F 2,72 =.66, p = .52; drift rate of money: F 2,72 = .24, p = .79; drift rate of contact probability: F 2,72 = 1.45, p = .24). This result further confirmed our findings that the processing of money and contact probability were asynchronous and the prioritization of the attributes varied as a function of the social interaction context. In addition, the fact that there was no difference in drift rate across conditions indicates that the difference in the final decision weights could be solely induced by the difference in the onset of attribute accumulation processes while the accumulation speed of each attribute was comparable. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The present study investigated the temporal dynamics of approach-avoidance behavioral conflict in social transgressors after they unintentionally harm a victim. By adopting a social transgression task, we induced different levels of guilt-related motivations in the participants and examined how they made tradeoffs between compensating the victim (i.e., the approach 560 motivation) and avoiding face-to-face interaction with the victim (i.e., the avoidance motivation). 561</p><p>Participants exhibited intensified competition between the motivations as guilt and 562 embarrassment levels increased. By analyzing the participants' choice trajectories, we revealed 563 that as participants' responsibility increased, the weight on contact avoidance increased and the 564 onset of its dynamics was expediated; at the same time, the weight on monetary compensation 565 decreased and the onset of its dynamic was delayed. Simulation from a neural circuit model and 566 data fitting using time-varying DDM confirmed that the processing of the two attributes is 567 asynchronous and temporally modulated by social-affective states. 568</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>569</head><p>The paradigm and the results of this study highlight the richness and complexity of the emotional and motivational states following interpersonal transgression. Traditional views in social psychology and emotion science portrait a rather "sunny" or positive picture of how people react (or ought to react) to interpersonal transgression -as soon as they realize the transgression has occurred, the transgressor would halt the damage, feel guilty, and make amendments or apologize to the victim <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7)</ref>. Part of the reason why most previous empirical evidence supports such a sunny view is that those studies predominantly examine what the participants would feel and how they may react in hypothetical scenarios, rather than what they actually feel and how they react in real-time social interactions. However, what ones think they should do and what ones actually do in social decision-making contexts differs in important ways, and they are associated with distinct neurocognitive processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(43)</ref>. One noticeable exception to the traditional views of guilt and transgression is <ref type="bibr">Amodio and colleagues (2007)</ref> who demonstrated that both an avoidance tendency (i.e., refraining from damaging) and an approach tendency (i.e., making compensation) co-exist in transgressors following an interpersonal transgression, and that these tendencies have distinct temporal dynamics (9). However, even in this study a critical aspect of real-world interpersonal transgressions was missing, namely face-to-face interaction between the transgressor and the victim. Both anecdotal and empirical evidence has shown that in a guilt state, the transgressor has a tendency to avoid or hide from confrontation with the victim (12, <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">44)</ref>. By adopting a measure of motivational forces with high temporal resolution (i.e., mouse-tracking), we are able to demonstrate that the two opposite tendencies do co-exist in real-life interactions, and that the increase in the strength of one (i.e., avoiding confrontation) suppresses the manifestation of the other (i.e., compensating the victim). The current findings have implications for our understanding of the complex, and sometimes dialectic, nature of the emotional and motivational reactions in interpersonal transgression and other social interactive contexts, e.g., the co-existence of gratitude and indebtedness in helping contexts (45). In conclusion, we demonstrate in a real-time social interaction paradigm that the compensatory and social-avoidance tendencies co-exist and compete in a transgressor's social choice following an interpersonal transgression. We uncover the dynamics of the participants' decision-making using mouse tracking and computational modeling, demonstrating that the individuals process the attributes of compensation and social avoidance asynchronously over time and the temporal profiles are flexibly modulated by their social-affective states. These results shed light on the dynamics of complex emotional and motivational processing following social transgression and provide general implications on the mechanism of interaction between motivations and their related decision attributes' processing during decision-making.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1a)</ref>. Participants assigned to the same role were instructed to sit on the same side of the computer room in separate compartments, shielded from view of the participants in a different role on the other side of the testing room (for a photo of the testing room arrangement, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1a</ref>). Video cameras (Logitech WebCam C270) were placed in front of each participant so that they could see the paired partner through real-time video at 651 designated time points during the experiment (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1a</ref> for the setup). Computers were connected via TCP-IP protocol using Matlab. Prior to the main task, all participants went through the same procedure for practicing the skills required in the main task (supplementary <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures    S1b-d)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>The main task. All participants were instructed in the same room with the same information on the main task. Each player was endowed with 90 Chinese Yuan (about 14 US dollars) for the game. All players were informed that Player B, but not Player A, could lose up to 1/3 of their entire endowments (i.e., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30</ref>  participants' task was to identify which of the four possibilities was the case for each trial, by 669 pressing one of four buttons, with two buttons on the keyboard ("Q" and "W") and the other two 670 buttons on the mouse (left and right click). Pressing the wrong buttons or not responding within 671 time constraints (see below) were counted as a failure. 672 When both were correct, the players saw "Pass" on the screen and proceeded to the next trial directly. When failure(s) occurred, Player A was asked to choose between two options presented at the top-left and top-right corners of the screen by moving the computer mouse from the bottom-center of the screen <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1d)</ref>. Each option contains a certain amount of monetary compensation to Player B and a probability of engaging in video contact between the two players later on at the end of the trial. The offer values were controlled by a self-adaptive algorithm (Supplementary Methods).</p><p>At the end of the trial, the participants were asked to rate the intensities of two emotions (i.e., guilt and embarrassment for Player A, anger and embarrassment for Player B) they experienced on the current trial from 0 to 10.</p><p>Free money. Instead of having Player A compensate Player B using Player A's own money, here 686 the money was from the experimenters. In this way, Player A's monetary self-interest would 687 therefore have no impact on their choice. Player A's decision would be a result of the tradeoff 688 between two motivations we were interested in this study, namely, compensating (approaching) 689 the victim and avoiding social contact with the victim. Admittedly, oftentimes in real-world 690 social situations, compensation to the victims comes at the cost of the transgressors. Delineating 691 how the transgressors' motivation for maximizing their self-interest is integrated with the 692 motivations for benefiting and avoiding the victim is beyond the scope of the current study and 693 calls for future research. 694</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Procedure and tasks. (a) After the random assignment of the roles in the beginning of the experiment (illustrated on the top), Player A and Player B were re-paired in each trial to go through the interactive task. The inset in the middle shows the four outcomes from the cooperative visual search task, and the inset on the left shows the empirical distribution of time pressure on Player A's binary choices. (b) Illustration of the self-adaptive algorithm to generate the values of the compensatory amount ( ) and contact probabilities ( ) in Option 1 ( , ) and Option 2( , ). The value differences between the two options ( ≡ − and ≡ − ) consist of two out-of-phase triangular waves as a function of . (c) The landscape of adaptation. The self-adaptive algorithm in b led to different landscapes of adaptation for different types of preferences. The balls and arrows illustrate the offer values (corresponding to the value indicated at the x-axis) and adaptation directions for each type of preference regarding the attribute m or p is appetitive (+) or aversive (-) (indicated on the title of each panel). Each type of preference converged to their specific area of offer set that would maximize the extraction of information about their preference. (d) Example screen of Player A's choice.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>To pinpoint this potential influence, we regressed the emotion ratings against the amount of money compensated in the current trial and the occurrence of video contact (1 = video contact occurred, 0 = no video contact). Other than the main effects of increased emotion ratings overconditions (guilt: = 2.60, S.E. = .30, t 92 = 8.70, p &lt; .001; embarrassment: = 1.25, S.E. = .25, t 142 = 5.03, p &lt; .001), linear mixed regressions revealed a double dissociation with respect to the impacts of monetary compensation and video contact on guilt and embarrassment ratings of Player A (conditions were coded as ordinal variables in the regressions, with partner-failed = 1, both-failed = 2, and self-failed = 3). For guilt, the main effect of the monetary compensation was insignificant ( = .031, S.E. = .073, t = .42, p = .68), whereas a significant interaction was found between the amount of money and the experimental conditions ( = -.065, S.E. = .030, 225 t 2076 = -2.13, p = .034). Participants' guilt ratings significantly decreased as the amount of 226 monetary compensation increased in self-failed and both-failed conditions but not so in the 227 partner-failed condition (self-failed: = -.17, S.E. = .054, t 58 = -3.12, p = .003; both-failed: = -.12, S.E. = .048, t 42 = -2.48, p = .017; partner-failed: = -.031, S.E. = .031, t 82 = -1.00, p = .32). 229 Guilt ratings were not significantly modulated by the occurrence of video contact (main effect: 230 = .72, S.E. = .65, t 1841 = 1.12, p = .26; interaction with conditions: = -.056, S.E. = .280, t 2070 = -</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>245 246Figure 2 .</head><label>2452</label><figDesc>Transgression-induced emotions and choice behavior. (a and b) Participants' selfreported guilt and embarrassment at the end of each trial. (c) and (d) The regression decision weights on monetary compensation ( , golden) and video contact probability ( , blue) estimated from the participants' binary choices. Colored dots indicate the random effects; black lines, squared dots, and whiskers indicate respectively the distributions, mean, and interquartile of the fixed effects.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>logistic regressions on participants' binary choices (Option 1 was coded as 1, Option 2 was coded as 0) showed that the fixed effects of participants' decision weights on monetary compensation ( ) were significantly positive across all conditions, indicating a consistent 265 preference for benefiting the victim (Figure 2c, envelope lines surrounding the golden dots 266 indicating the fixed effects of regressions; partner-failed: mean = 9.69, 95% C.I. = [5.49, 14.86]; both-failed: mean = 9.57, 95% C.I. = [5.04, 15.31]; self-failed: mean = 3.98, 95% C.I. = [2.20, 2686.19]). On the contrary, the fixed effects of decision weights on video contact probability ( ) were significantly negative in the both-failed and the self-failed conditions but not significantly different from 0 in the partner-failed condition. This pattern indicated that video contact with the victim was aversive to the participants when the participants were fully or partially responsible for the victim's loss, and had no impact on the participants' choice when the participants were not responsible for the victim's loss(Figure 2d,envelope lines surrounding the blue dots indicating the fixed effects of regressions; partner-failed: mean = -.02, 95% C.I. = [-.38, .33]; both-failed: mean = -1.15, 95% C.I. = [-1. 71, -.69]; self-failed: mean = -1.22, 95% C.I. = [-1.87, -.64]). These results suggest that the transgressor shows both compensation-seeking and contactavoidance tendencies after social transgression, confirming the hypothesis that the social contact avoidance motivation co-exists with the compensation motivation in the social transgressor.More interestingly, when we compared the difference in the decision weights across conditions (characterized by the estimated random effects; the golden and blue dots inFigures 2c and 2d), we found that was significantly lower in the self-failed condition than in the partner-failed and the both-failed conditions (self-failed &lt; partner-failed: t 36 = -4.06, Cohen's D = -.71, p &lt; .001; 284 self-failed &lt; both-failed: t 36 = -4.09, Cohen's D = -.66, p &lt; .001; no significant difference 285 between partner-failed and both-failed: t 36 = .01, Cohen's D = .00, p = .99). In contrast, was 286 more negative in the both-failed and self-failed conditions than in the partner-failed condition 287 (both-failed &lt; partner-failed: t 36 = -11.31, Cohen's D = -2.21, p &lt; .001; self-failed &lt; partner-288 failed: t 36 = -6.55, Cohen's D = -1.44, p &lt; .001; no significant difference between self-failed and 289</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>underlying decision-making unfold over time before the final decision is reached. The horizontal component of mouse movement velocity ( ) reflects a participant's momentary preference for an option relative to the other. Validation analysis confirmed that towards a higher value option parametrically tracked the value difference between the two options (supplementary Figure S4). Thus, we regressed the attribute values (i.e., Δ and Δ ) on over 100 time bins 311 equally distributed over the reaction time (RT) of each trial. The goal of this analysis is to reveal 312 the dynamics of momentary decision weights on monetary compensation ( , ) and video contact probability ( , ) during the decision-making process. Hierarchical linear regression showed that , ramped up to be significantly positive in the late stage of decision (around the 315 60 th time bin) across all conditions (golden lines in Figure 3b; asterisk above the shadow of 95% C.I. indicating significance after multi-comparison correction described in Supplementary Methods), suggesting that the participants' preferences for monetary compensation gradually built up during the courses of decisions across all conditions. In contrast, , drifted down to be significantly negative in the late stage of decision only in the both-failed and self-failed conditions but not in the partner-failed condition (blue lines in Figure 3b), indicating that contact avoidance emerged to be a behaviorally relevant concern only in the both-failed and selffailed conditions. The general pattern of dynamics was consistent with the decision weights from binary choices. To quantify the rising time of the dynamics, we calculated the earliest significant time point (ESTP) of each time series by bootstrapping (Supplementary Methods). ESTP indicates the earliest time point on a time series of the regression parameters that reaches statistical significance after multiple-comparison correction. Figure 3d illustrates the distributions of ESTP for , (golden) and , (blue) across conditions. These distributions showed that the ESTP of 330 , was earlier than , in the both-failed condition but show no significant difference from , 331 in the self-failed condition (both-failed condition: ESTP of , = 69.02 ± 6.06, ESTP of , = 89.27 ± 6.94, difference = -20.26 ± 9.20, 95% C.I. = [-30, -11]; self-failed condition: ESTP of , = 73.17 ± 6.10, ESTP of , = 75.96 ± 5.04, difference = -2.79 ± 7.98, 95% C.I. = [-15, 7]; partner-failed condition: ESTP of , = 56.22 ± 14.38, ESTP of , in the partner-failed condition was not compared because the , dynamics did not survive multiple-comparison 336 correction). These results suggest that the processing of monetary compensation arose earlier 337 than that of contact avoidance in the both-failed condition but such a temporal advantage was 338 diminished in the self-failed condition. 339</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. The delay from the partner-failed condition to the self-failed condition was significant (difference = 16.95 ± 15.84, 95% C.I. (one-tailed) =<ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref> 61]). In contrast, the ESTP of , was significantly expedited in the self-failed condition than in the both-failed condition (difference = -13.31 ± 8.61, 95% C.I.= [-22, -2]). Because the time scales were normalized within each condition, comparing ESTPs across conditions might be affected by the differences in reaction time across conditions. To address this concern, we made corrections and rescaled the ESTPs according to the mean reaction time of each condition. The conclusions still held with the rescaled ESTPs (see</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). , and , indicated the decision weights of one attribute relative to the other, therefore were free of the motor-related features on the time courses. The ESTPs bootstrapped from , and , resulted in the same conclusions as we obtained from , and , . The ESTPs of , were earlier than that of , in the bothfailed and self-failed conditions (both-failed condition: ESTP of , = 61.42 ± 5.06, ESTP of , = 88.50 ± 6.73, difference = -27.08 ± 8.44, 95% C.I. = [-34, -19]; self-failed condition: 367 ESTP of , = 67.22 ± 4.09, ESTP of , = 76.30 ± 4.94, difference = -9.08 ± 6.44, 95% C.I. = [-17, -3]); the temporal advantage of , relative to , in the self-failed condition was significantly smaller than in the both-failed condition (the 95% C.I.s above showed no 370 overlapping)(Figure 3e;Table 1). Comparing across conditions, the ESTPs of , were 371 delayed from partner-failed condition to both-failed condition and self-failed condition, and the ESTP of , were expedited from both-failed condition to self-failed condition (ESTP of,, both-failed -partner-failed: difference = 14.80 ± 19.01, 95% C.I. = [1, 60]; self-failed -partner-374 failed: difference = 20.60 ± 18.75, 95% C.I. = [8, 66]; ESTP of , , self-failed -both-failed: difference = -12.21 ± 8.43, 95% C.I. = [-20, -3]). The conclusions held after the corrections of the mean reaction time of each condition (results listed in</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>The temporal dynamics of decision weights and their ESTP distributions. (a) The temporal dynamics of averaged velocity ( ) over time bins. Shadows indicate 95% C.I. of . (b) The temporal dynamics of regression weights on monetary compensation ( , , golden) and contact probability ( , , blue) over the three conditions. Lines and shadows indicate the mean value and 95% C.I. of the fixed effects, respectively. Stars indicate statistical significance after multi-comparison correction. (c) The temporal dynamics of relative regression weights ( , , gold and , , blue) after controlling the magnitude of moving velocity. (d) The ESTP distributions of regression weights ( , , golden and , , blue). (e) The ESTP distributions of</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The inputs to the neural nodes are the difference in the values between Option 1 and Option 2 (i.e., and ) and the outputs are the integrated decision signals (i.e., and ). The two integrated signals then additively contribute to the 419 final decision value ( ) and guide behavioral responses. The relative decision weights , 420 and , are defined as the relative contributions of the integrated attribute values, i.e., and , to . At the end of the process, a positive leads to the choice of Option 1 and a negative leads to the choice of Option 2 (for details of the model, see Supplementary Methods). The temporal parameters and capture the time onsets when the attributes and start integrating, respectively. We tested the input magnitudes of and and the temporal 425 asynchrony between and to the predicted dynamics of , and , . 426 427 Figures 4b-d illustrate the temporal dynamics of the input values, and . To test the impact of magnitude, we varied the magnitude of (indicated by the shade of blue) and fixed the magnitude of .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>fixing the magnitude of at 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>and fitting the magnitude of to capture the participants' 451 weight on contact avoidance relative to compensation. The results show that the asynchronous circuit with one additional parameter in each condition (i.e., and estimated independently) 453 outperformed the synchronous circuit (i.e., and estimated as an equal value) in all three conditions (LL Asynchronous = -989.8, LL Synchronous = -1072.6; AIC Asynchronous = 2001.7, AIC Synchronous = 455 2161.1; BIC Asynchronous = 2042.1, BIC Synchronous = 2190.5). The model performance in each condition was visualized in Figures 4k (asynchronous circuit) and 4l (synchronous circuit). Specifically, in the partner-failed condition, where the weight on contact avoidance was not significant, the two models perform similarly (Partner-failed: left panels in Figures 4k and l, LL Asynchronous = -316.4, LL Synchronous = -331.3). However, in the both-failed and self-failed conditions when the contact avoidance is a more serious concern, the asynchronous circuit tracks much closely on the empirical dynamics (Both-failed: middle panels in Figures 4k and l, 462 LL Asynchronous = -313.8, LL Synchronous = -373.5, self-failed: right panels in Figures 4k and l, LL Asynchronous = -359.6, LL Synchronous = -367.7). Zooming in on these dynamics, we found that the asynchronous circuit captured the detailed pattern exceptionally well, particularly the nonmonotonic dynamics on , (dashed lines tracking golden lines in Figure 4k). In both the bothfailed and self-failed conditions, the , curves exhibited subsequent suppressions following 467 the rise of , (around time bin 77 in both-failed and time bin 62 in self-failed), due to the 468 asynchronous/delayed time onsets of relative to . In contrast, the non-monotonic dynamics was not observed in the synchronous circuit (dashed lines in Figure 4l). In addition, the 470 curvatures of the empirical dynamics were consistent with the model predictions. The empirical 471 dynamics of , showed quadratic curvature in the both-failed condition but demonstrated a 472 sudden drop in the self-failed condition, since a larger delay of processing relative to in the both-failed condition but a smaller delay of processing relative to in the self-failed condition. The time onsets estimated from the asynchronous circuit were consistent with the ESTPs results reported above, with the onsets of contact avoidance expedited and the onsets of compensation gradually delayed from partner-failed to self-failed condition (Partner-failed: = 44.2 , = 80.1; both-failed: = 53.8, = 77.3; self-failed: = 58.8, = 62.3). Interestingly, 479 the magnitudes of estimated from the asynchronous circuit were comparable between the both-failed condition and the self-failed condition (Partner-failed: -.20, both-failed: -.50, and self-failed: -.51), suggesting that the intensified final relative decision weight on contact avoidance in the self-failed condition might due to the time prioritization of this attribute. Other parameters estimated from the two models were reported in Supplementary Methods.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>The specification and results of the neural circuit model. (a) The neural circuit model gets input values of the two attributes (golden) and (blue) from Option 1 and Option 2. The values on different attributes are integrated into their corresponding neural nodes (golden) and (blue) with specific temporal delays and . The integrated values linearly 499 contribute to the final decision node (decision value) to guide choice behavior, with their relative 500 contribution notated as and . (b-d) The evolving of input value differences of each attribute ≡ − (golden) and ≡ − (blue) over time. Across the three panels, the magnitudes of were varied and the magnitude of was fixed; the onset of varied from no delay (synchronous) (b), to having a large delay (c), and medium delay (d) relative to the onset of . (e-g). The accumulated signals in and over time corresponding to the input settings in b-d. (h-j) The dynamics of relative decision weights , (golden) and , (blue) 506 corresponding to the integrated signals in e-g. (k) By fitting the circuit model with the 507</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 5a ).</head><label>5a</label><figDesc>Model comparison between the tDDM and a standard DDM without time 529 asynchrony (thus reducing one parameter) showed that tDDM fitted the data better than DDM 530 (LL tDDM = -13235.8, LL DDM = -13415.2; AIC tDDM = 27803.5, AIC DDM = 27940.4) (See posterior predictive check on model fitting in</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>The time varying DDM (tDDM) results. (a) Illustration of the tDDM hypothesis. The upper panels illustrate the time onset of monetary input ( , golden) and probability input ( , blue). The bottom panels illustrate the integrated decision signals ( ) over time. (b) The 551 fitted in the three critical conditions. Gray dots and envelopes indicate the fitted values 552 of individuals and the group-level distributions. Squared dots and whiskers indicate mean values 553 and S.E.s in each condition. 554</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Our results have general implications about the role of motivation in orchestrating the temporal dynamics of decision-making. Recent theoretical work in decision-making emphasizes the role of metacognitive processes in the real-time control of decision-making process, such as guiding attention to optimize information seeking(35,<ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">47)</ref> and exerting cognitive efforts to achieve better task performance<ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(48)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(49)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(50)</ref>. Prior research has demonstrated the critical role of motivation in distributing cognitive efforts in the processing of single decision attributes (48, 50-52).However, empirical evidence regarding how motivation impacts the temporal dynamics of processing on multiple decision attributes has been lacking. The current study fills this gap by directly manipulating the participant's motivational states in a social transgression context and examining the temporal dynamics of the processing of two decision attributes related to the participant's internal needs (i.e., monetary compensation to the victim and avoiding face-to-face interaction with the victim). Tracking the participant's locomotion as the end process of decision execution may reflect an integrated effect of motivation on the latent cognitive processes underlying attribute processing and decision-making, including information sampling on these attributes, retrieving long-term memory about the values of these attributes, comparing the differences between options, and trade-offs between attributes. These processes are generally considered as (part of) cognitive control in previous studies<ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(48)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(49)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(50)</ref>. We show here that the fluctuation in motivational state modifies the relative decision weights on attributes, which are also reflected in the temporal prioritization of the attributes processing. Our findings extend the close relationship between motivation and cognitive control on single decision attributes to the coordination of multiple attributes processing and highlight the adaptive function of motivation in the exertion of cognitive control.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Seventy-four right-handed college students participated in the experiment. Half of the participants (N = 37, age = 22.6±2.1, 19 females) played the role of transgressors (the role we focused on), and the other half played the role of victims. The sample size was determined by power analysis (G*Power 3)(53) on a within-subject design one-sample t-test, which showed that it requires at least 34 subjects to test the hypothesis on the temporal dynamic at α level 95% and power level 80% for a medium-level effect size (Cohen's d = .5) shown in a previous study using similar mouse-tracking methodologies (31). None of the participants reported a history of neurological or psychiatric illness. All the participants provided written informed consent before the experiment. Participants were paid based on their task performances (see details below). The experiment conformed to the Declaration of Helsinki and was approved by the Ethics Committee of the School of Psychological and Cognitive Sciences, Peking University. Procedure Role assignment and preparation. Participants in the same session, consisting of 4, 6, or 8 individuals of the same sex, met in a computer room before the experiment. Half of them were assigned as Player A and the other half as Player B depending on the role concealed in a folded label each participant drew</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>RMB, or 840 M.U.), if the players failed their task in all trials (for the actual performance of our participants, Player B earned 80.79 ± 1.01 RMB, with an individual min of 78.87 and maximum of 82.51, less than the fixed amount of 90 RMB that Player A earned). Most of the participants experienced 84 trials, except one session (4 pairs of participants) who experienced 68 -69 trials due to a technical error. In the visual search task, both players saw 20 bars of the same color, either blue or orange, scattered in the central area (500×500 pixels) of the screen, and were asked to search for a target bar with an orientation that was either vertical or horizontal among the other distractors with random orientations. The color of the stimuli and the orientation of the target bar result in four possible associations with responses: blue &amp; vertical, blue &amp; horizontal, orange &amp; vertical, and orange &amp; horizontal. The 668</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Statistics on the ESTPs of dynamic decision weights</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Condition</cell><cell>Mean ± S.D.</cell><cell>95% C.I.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">, − , Self</cell><cell>-2.79 ± 7.98</cell><cell>[-15, 7]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Both</cell><cell>-20.26 ± 9.20</cell><cell>[-30, -11]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>,</cell><cell cols="2">Self -Both Both -Partner 12.79 ± 15.73 4.16 ± 8.68</cell><cell>[-5, 16] [-1, 54]</cell></row><row><cell>Time bins</cell><cell cols="3">Self -Partner 16.95 ± 15.84 Self -Both -13.31 ± 8.61 -9.08 ± 6.44 , − , Self , Both -27.08 ± 8.44</cell><cell>[3, 61] [-22, -2] [-17, -3] [-34, -19]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>,</cell><cell cols="2">Self -Both Both -Partner 14.80 ± 19.01 5.79 ± 6.53</cell><cell>[-1, 12] [1, 60]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Self -Partner 20.60 ± 18.75</cell><cell>[8, 66]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>,</cell><cell>Self -Both</cell><cell>-12.21 ± 8.43</cell><cell>[-20, -3]</cell></row><row><cell>Reaction times</cell><cell>, , ,</cell><cell cols="2">Self -Both Both -Partner .24 ± .28 s .09 ± .15 s Self -Partner .33 ± .28 s Self -Both -.22 ± .16 s Self -Both .12 ± .12 s Both -Partner .27 ± .34 s Self -Partner .39 ± .33 s</cell><cell>[-.08, .30] [-.01, .97] [.08, 1.12] [-.38, -.02] [-.00, .23] [.03, 1.08] [.17, 1.20]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>,</cell><cell>Self -Both</cell><cell>-.20 ± .15 s</cell><cell>[-.34, -.04]</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">, and , across three conditions reached the same conclusions as from d.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Sensen Song for assistance in the data collection, Dr. Lusha Zhu, Dr. Kunlin Wei for their suggestions on data analysis. This work was supported by National Natural Science</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Confidential compensation and no communications during video contact. Video contact would 696</head><p>be triggered when the chosen probability was greater than a randomly generated value 697 (uniformly distributed between 0 and 100%), these two players would experience a 5 s long 698 virtual face-to-face contact through real-time video; otherwise, a blank screen would be presented to both players for 5 s. If face-to-face contact with the victim was enacted, both</p><p>Players were asked to keep a neutral facial expression and not to engage in communication using and social avoidance motivation (e.g., avoiding being seen by Player B).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hierarchical logistic regressions on participants' binary choices</head><p>We estimated participants' decision weights and on monetary compensation and contact probability from their binary choices by using logistic regression (Eq. 1), </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Estimation of the decision weight dynamics 726</head><p>We estimated the impact of each attribute on the participants' momentary preference by running 727 multiple regressions of the attributes' values on the participants' horizontal velocity ( ); the result would indicate the transient tendency of towards or away from the options,</p><p>The regressions were performed repetitively over 100 time bins, with t as the indicator of the 731 time bin. Because , and , estimated here carried not only information about preference but also the mechanical features of mouse movement velocity, e.g., acceleration in the beginning of a trial and deceleration at the end of a trial. To remove the motor effect and keep only decision- ; the obtained values indicate the decision weights on one attribute relative to the other.</p><p>Parameters were estimated using the Bayesian statistical inference method mentioned above.</p><p>Data from each condition and each time bin were estimated by a single hierarchical model, with all participants' data combined. The numbers of chains and iterations were set the same as above.</p><p>The model convergence for the estimated parameters was checked and reported in <ref type="figure">Supplementary Results (Figure S6</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing interests</head><p>None of the authors has conflicts of interests to declare.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data and code availability</head><p>The data and code presented in this work will be openly available upon publication in Mendeley Data at http://dio.org/10.17632/jcng3638wx.1</p><p>Foundation of China (71942001, 31630034). Bo Shen was supported by China Postdoctoral 757 Science Foundation (2018M642489).</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Morality in everyday life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hofmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wisneski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Skitka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">345</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1340" to="1343" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpersonal transgressions and psychological loss: Understanding moral repair as dyadic, reciprocal, and interactionist</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Woodyatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wenzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Okimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Thai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identity concerns following a severe relational transgression: the role of discovery method for the relational outcomes of infidelity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Afifi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Falato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Weiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Soc. Pers. Relatsh</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="308" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bridging diverging perspectives and repairing damaged relationships in the aftermath of workplace transgressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Okimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wenzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus. Ethics Q</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="473" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The essential moral self</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Strohminger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">131</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="171" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guilt: an interpersonal approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baumeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Stillwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Heatherton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">243</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral emotions and moral behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Tangney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stuewig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mashek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu. Rev. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="372" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guilt in response to blame from others</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Parkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Illingworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Emot</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1589" to="1614" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic model of guilt: implications for 778 motivation and self-regulation in the context of prejudice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Amodio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Devine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Harmon-Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="524" to="530" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Children&apos;s understanding of guilt and shame. Child 780 Dev</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stegge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Damhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">827</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compliance without pressure: The effect of guilt</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Freedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wallington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bless</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lickel, The approach and avoidance function of guilt and shame emotions: comparing reactions to self-caused and other-caused wrongdoing</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Motiv. Emot</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">785</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The strength of a remorseful heart: 787 psychological and neural basis of how apology emolliates reactive aggression and promotes 788 forgiveness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Beyens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The mutuality of social emotions: how the victim&apos;s reactive attitude 790 influences the transgressor&apos;s emotional responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">244</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">118631</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conciliatory gestures promote forgiveness and reduce anger in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mccullough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pedersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tabak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11211" to="11216" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The voice of conscience: neural bases of interpersonal guilt 795 and compensation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Cogn. Affect. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1150" to="1158" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affirmation, acknowledgment of in-group responsibility, group-based guilt, and support for reparative measures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Čehajić-Clancy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Effron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Halperin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Liberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Apology as aggression control: Its role in mediating appraisal of and response to harm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ohbuchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kameda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Agarie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="219" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Costly apology and self-punishment after an unintentional transgression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ohtsubo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Evol. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Group-based guilt and shame in the context of intergroup conflict: The role of beliefs and meta-beliefs about group malleability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Weiss-Klayman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hameiri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Halperin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preferred responses when honour is at stake: The role of cultural background, presence of others, and causality orientation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ceylan-Batur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Uskul</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Asian J. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="336" to="347" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From virility to virtue: the psychology of apology in honor cultures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Caluori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Öztürk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gelfand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2210324119</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of offering an apology: understanding the barriers to apologizing and how to overcome them</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Dir. Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="74" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sorry seems to be the hardest word: cultural differences in apologizing effectively</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shafa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Harinck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ellemers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="567" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revenge and forgiveness after 816 victimization: psychometric evaluation of a Dutch version of the TRIM intended for victims and offenders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gerlsma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lugtmeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Van Denderen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Keijser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7142" to="7154" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guilt in the eyes: Eye movement and physiological evidence for guilt-induced social avoidance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Duan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="128" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What do I care? Perceived ingroup responsibility and dehumanization as predictors of empathy felt for the victim group</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Čehajić</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>González</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Group Process. Intergroup Relat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="715" to="729" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dehumanization: an integrative review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Haslam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personal. Soc. Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="252" to="264" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guilt and guiltlessness: an integrative review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bègue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shankland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Personal. Psychol. Compass</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="440" to="457" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integration of error agency and representation of othersʼ pain in the anterior insula</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Koban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Corradi-Dell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Vuilleumier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Cogn. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="258" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dietary self-control is related to the speed with which attributes of healthfulness and tastiness are processed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hutcherson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="831" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How mouse-tracking can advance social cognitive 833 theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">P E</forename><surname>Stillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="543" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ring measure of social values: a computerized 835 procedure for assessing individual differences in information processing and social value 836 orientation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">W B G</forename><surname>Liebrand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Mcclintock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. J. Personal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social value orientation: theoretical and measurement 838 issues in the study of social preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">R O</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ackermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personal. Soc. Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards a neuroscience of active sampling and curiosity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gottlieb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="758" to="770" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An opportunity cost model of subjective effort and task performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kurzban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Duckworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Brain Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="661" to="679" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing neural correlates of context-dependent advantageous-and 844 disadvantageous-inequity aversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Excitatory-inhibitory tone shapes 846 decision strategies in a hierarchical neural network model of multi-attribute choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">W W</forename><surname>Pettine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Louie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X.-J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS 847 Comput. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1008791</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissociable mechanisms govern when and how strongly reward attributes affect decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Beharelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polanía</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative decision field theory: a dynamic connectionst model of decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Roe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="370" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The multiattribute linear ballistic accumulator model of context effects in multialternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="205" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loss aversion and inhibition in dynamical models of multialternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="757" to="769" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What we say and what we do: the relationship between real and hypothetical moral choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Feldmanhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approach and avoidance social motives and goals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Gable</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="222" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The hidden cost of receiving favors: A theory of indebtedness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>. 2020.02.03.926295</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Active inference and epistemic value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Friston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognitive computations for information search: confidence in control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>No Pagination Specified-No Pagination Specified</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivation and cognitive control: from behavior to neural mechanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Braver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu. Rev. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The expected value of control: an integrative theory of anterior cingulate cortex function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="240" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interactions of motivation and cognitive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Braver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">871</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of motivational influences on 873 cognitive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Parro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Christoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Hum. Brain Mapp</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5097" to="5111" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The mysterious motivational functions of mesolimbic dopamine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">J D</forename><surname>Salamone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Correa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">875</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="485" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Power 3: A flexible statistical power 877 analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Faul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Erdfelder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-G</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Buchner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Res. Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">878</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">RStan: the R interface to Stan</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stan</forename><surname>Development Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
