<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Evolution of human intelligence: Psychological Science for a Better World</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L Senarath</forename><surname>Dayathilake</surname></persName>
							<email>klsenarathdayathilake@yahoo.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Upamal</forename><surname>Karunaratne</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nishal</forename><surname>Paranagama</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L S</forename><surname>Kawya</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Prof</roleName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">Kenneth</forename><surname>Nicholls</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mahinda Rajapaksa</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Prof</roleName><forename type="middle">Carlo</forename><surname>Gotabaya Rajapaksa</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Fonseka</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Everyday</forename><forename type="middle">Happiness</forename><surname>Ann N Y</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Acad</forename><surname>Sci</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Human Well-being Science Program</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>177/1, Epitamulla Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>10100</postCode>
									<settlement>Kotte</settlement>
									<country key="LK">Sri Lanka</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Kaushalya Kurulugama, Sandaru Shamaindra Senarath, and Nieces -Ushara Dakshin Karunaratne, Nishali Paranagama, Mr</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<address>
									<addrLine>Cahn, Levy, Fernandez, &amp; Delorme</addrLine>
									<postCode>2017)</postCode>
									<settlement>Braboszcz</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Evolution of human intelligence: Psychological Science for a Better World</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0003-066x.51.2.77.ISSN0003-066X</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Clarke (late)</term>
					<term>Mr. H.B. Jayewardene (late)</term>
					<term>Mr. Douglas Perera</term>
					<term>Mr. Chula Fernando (late)</term>
					<term>Dr. Hashitha Mahen Dom bagahawatta</term>
					<term>Mr. Sanjeewa Wickramanayake</term>
					<term>Mrs. Probodhinee Marasingha</term>
					<term>(late) Mr. W.G SENARATH DAYATHILAKE</term>
					<term>K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE Buddhist meditation</term>
					<term>cognitive psychology</term>
					<term>consciousness</term>
					<term>decision making</term>
					<term>eightfold path</term>
					<term>two ultraquantum particles</term>
					<term>healthy mind viruses</term>
					<term>intelligence evolution</term>
					<term>life after death</term>
					<term>mind viruses</term>
					<term>nature and nurture</term>
					<term>grand delusions</term>
					<term>social well-being</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>What might be the fundamental psychology of intelligence naturally selected in biological evolution to minimize, prevent, and cure social and personal issues like war, crime, commit suicide, homicide, theft, drug addictions, and so on? How to achieve a higher level of well-being? I found a primary cognitive limiting factor called mind viruses (MV)(more than 3000) which regresses intelligence and well-being and makes the grand delusion: remedies are healthy mind viruses(HMV)(3000). Here, I show the disclosed core of early Buddhist teachings (on learning, training the mind, and behavior on the 8-fold psychological course psychologically &apos;program&apos; for better (intelligent) decisions. A theoretical 3D graph might represent the state of evolution of intelligence, nature, nurture, X-ultra quantum unique consciousness particle (X-UQUPC), and psychological well-being with the psychological time of a person. To this hypothesis, if the afterlife occurs, the natural selection of vacant zygote/early embryo neurons of the next life and their quality might depend on the finally evolved X-ultra quantum genomic particle of consciousness (X-UQGPC). Therefore, the quality, including the species of the new life and its nurture in the universe/s, depends on the quality of the finally evolved X-UQGPC. Such natural selection of a new nurturing environment for future (promising)life might be uncertain and, therefore, a high risk of finding a life-consciousness in great nature and nurture. However, there may be more mysterious issues to be solved in future research; therefore, the article might not discuss a theory of everything on the central theme.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE e need another debate, as behavioral decisions are independent doer 'soul' (volunteer in the brainmind system) or just occur-happen decisions/behaviors (without -/free-will/commander/doer in the brain-mind -system). This phenomenon occurs in the central nervous system, without the doer/soul/psyche in the brain-mind. <ref type="bibr">(Dayathilake, K.L. Senarath,1991)</ref>. Moreover, it might enjoy true happiness purely through brain-mind function and nurture. My recent studies suggest that X-UQCPG+ X-UQUPC makes a significant contribution but is not permanent (it might be reversibleregression-and evolve and might collapse one day). "Wegner summarizes some empirical evidence that may suggest that the perception of conscious control is open to modification (or even manipulation). Wegner observes that one event infers to have caused a second event when two requirements are:</p><p>1. The first event immediately precedes the second event, and 2. The first event is consistent with having caused the second event" <ref type="bibr" target="#b138">(Wegener, Daniel Merton (2002)</ref>.</p><p>However, some psychologists have shown that reducing a person's belief in free will make them less helpful and more aggressive <ref type="bibr">(Baumeister, RF;</ref><ref type="bibr">Masicampo, EJ;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dewall, CN (2009)</ref>. Because the subject might be losing a sense of self-efficacy. Caveats have, however, been identified in studying a subject's awareness of mental events in that the process of introspection itself may alter the experience. <ref type="bibr">(Susan Pockette, 2009)</ref>. My findings suggest that the eightfold path is a treatment for the evolution of intelligence treated by a higher intelligent teacher or teaching. Such teachings might not create such an issue, even though the disciples do not believe in the illusion of free will, as taught in the Buddhist teachings, and emphasize those are just causes and effects of interdependent arising facts". This theory is also called "Conditioned Genesis" or "Dependent Origination." <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Dayathilake, KL. Senarath, 2019, April)</ref> Fundamental insight of Buddhism is the SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE recognition of the fluctuating, impermanent nature of all phenomena that arise in dependence on preceding causes and contributing conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">(Nanamoli &amp; Bodhi, 1995)</ref> The actual causes of such well-being are rooted in a wholesome way of life, nurtured through the cultivation of mental balance, and come to fruition in the experience of wisdom and compassion. In this way, the pursuits of genuine well-being, understanding, and virtue come to be thoroughly integrated. Some researchers say that 'having a sense of free will would suggest that the subject is proactive or not shy of taking action. Having paranormal worldviews might result in the subject taking actions (e.g., based on astrological readings), even based on misconceptions. Illusions such as free will and paranormal beliefs might have been adaptive because they made the subjects more proactive" <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Mogi, 2014)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Thought experiment -1</head><p>Is there an X or third factor of the 3D graph as an X-UQCPG+ X-UGPC incorporeal? Such a center in mind exchanges information, as below: first, the external stimuli input to -sensorial, then the sensoria nerves impulses input to the brain; therefore after that decision makes result nerves impulses output toward the external environment as an observable/empirical behavior the support with X-UQGPC+ X-UQUPC and not just stimuli information input to the brain, and the brain decision-making as output nerve impulses as behaviors <ref type="bibr">(Dayathilake, K.L. Senarath, 2019-April)</ref>.</p><p>I suggest no identical act X-UQUPC that simultaneously functions anywhere in the universe/s. Even identical twins seem to be in the same environment but not entirely the same (they might be similar and have X-UQGPC but not X-UQUPC), at least in slightly different nurture. Performing a complete control psychological experiment on the nature versus nurture debate is complex. Many SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF <ref type="bibr">HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</ref> experiments suggest that life's minds and behaviors depend only on nature and nurture; there might also be a third factor as a center between the mind-brain link, as already mentioned. At the same time, there are such conscious phenomena <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Dayathilake, K.L. Senarath, 2019 April)</ref>, X-UQGPC+ X-UQUPC functions since it binds with matching and vacant zygotes until clinical death occurs.</p><p>This theory of mine might be helpful to find a solution to why you have only self-identity-soulbut not two or more in the universe/s. This why I suggest one more factor in addition to nature and nurture, as microparticle.</p><p>. Buddhist teachings emphasize that the evolution of life toward the optimum stage takes an extremely long time. However, the specific time duration is not precise until now; to my knowledge, somebody's text (to the Buddha's Enlightenment took many Kalpak-eon) says there are many Kalpa (eon). Therefore, while life (if) exists for such an extended period, the X-UQCPG might evolve extremely slowly; therefore, we might have suffered a massive number of years until the phenomena collapsed.</p><p>The Buddha has taught five fates deciding natural laws;</p><p>(1) Hereditary (Bija Niyama)</p><p>(2) Weather, climate (Uthu niyama)</p><p>(3) Results of previous decision/action/Volitions of the person; -'Volition is the most significant mental factor-out of seven-in generating Kamma since it is Volition that determines the ethical quality of the action. <ref type="bibr">(Bhikkhu Bodhi, 2003)</ref> (4) present decisions of the person (Citta niyama) (5) (other) natural laws (Dhamma niyama) SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE However, the Buddha has not emphasized divine-or/and astrological fate-dependent factors in human life. The elements perform the most rudimentary and essential cognitive functions, without which consciousness of an object would be utterly impossible. <ref type="bibr">(Bhikkhu Bodhi,2012)</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.0">Intelligence and psychological well-being</head><p>One of the essential factors of the successful evolution of intelligence (EI) might be psychological well-being (PWB) to my theory of intelligence. It defines that a person has confidence in harmful mind viruses not activated by using correct HMV treatments and preventable methods toward his/her and others' PWB.</p><p>A lower intelligent person with a relatively higher MV and a qualitatively higher level have a higher potential of disease-causing MV in others' minds. Most such persons appear healthy and happy (a result of some MV) and spread MV to others. However, more intelligent persons are associated with less intelligent persons and attempt to create a PWB society. We can consider two main groups of persons in two extremes struggling for supremacy. -Even though there are no clear margins/boundaries between differing with each primary group, but relative sense-;</p><p>(i) Negative EI is progressed toward a psychologically unhealthy society by said 'unhealthy fittest/s.' (They influence others' minds and functions directed by the behavior of MV).</p><p>(ii) Positive EI is progressed toward PWB society led by intelligent and healthy fittest/s. They influence others' minds and functions by use of their behavior of HMV.</p><p>I suggest that the central developmental mechanisms might be based on the following: (a) Practical knowledge of HMV. (including that they are interested in the The task for developing health and happiness) (b) Utilizing the potential and correct behavior to 'stimulate others' senses (e.g., by teachings and training while interpreting correct and precise scientific answers to problems such as why/how you should do, and when/where you must make these training/practice/decisions making against on SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE 16 particular MV to cure and preventions methods, etc.) by correct teachings, (etc.)the correct time to the correct person with particular MV by correct person or source (intelligent) (c) How do the quality and quantities of HMV or MV successfully develop in the two groups? <ref type="bibr">(d)</ref> To what extent has neurobiology developed in the two groups? (e) Hidden potential for the EI of the person or a group might evolve. Then, according to the personal potential of intelligence of the related person, create the present state of cognitive functions. In this process, his/her corresponding MV and HMV would be the primary causes of the cognition level. If he can fight against MV and gradually evolve his PWB, he might enjoy his present life; others will not find it difficult to reverse his development-regress.</p><p>I define human intelligence as the fundamental cognitive ability to solve problems practically with scientific creativity to optimize self and others' PWB. This theory explains with the newly discovered 8-fold path of early Buddhist teachings that humans' success and personal, global, and cosmic goals might not contradict real happiness comes from healthy cognitive function with less or no MV.</p><p>Internal cognitive processes (according to the 3D graph) in generally low intelligent persons do not think to behave logically or positively to/her and others PWB; they probably think they are healthy, happy, and very intelligent, too. Because of their psychology and the brain might not be well developed, or he/she has not been taught/trained well by a more intelligent person.</p><p>The 8-fold path might manifest the behavioral law of scientific ethics in the EI(evolution of intelligence). Because of this intellectual process:</p><p>(1) Personal-social PWB is unharmed.</p><p>(2) No personal and social contradictions.</p><p>(3) It might be a highly recommended efficient personal &amp; social-psychological development method.</p><p>(4) Not collapsing 'Law of society in general.</p><p>(5) Trades and professions, unharmful to society and sustainable development. <ref type="formula">6</ref>government budgetary allocations might decrease for arms and weapons. <ref type="formula">7</ref>This can increase funding for science and technology, health, education, etc.</p><p>(8) It is not harmful to the environment but protects, prevents, harms, and helps to develop it.</p><p>(Including rights of animals) (9). 'Less' or no struggle for PWB.</p><p>The most hidden primary goals of life are ways of finding happiness. MV are the limiting factors of genuine pleasure. There are two ancient Buddhist texts called Theragatha and Therigatha, full of the joyful utterances of Buddha's male and female disciples, who found peace and happiness through his teaching. King Kosala once told the Buddha, "Unlike many a disciple of other religious systems who look haggard, coarse, pale, emaciated and unprepossessing. (Buddha's) your disciples were joyful and glad, jubilant and exultant free from anxiety, enjoying the life, with faculties pleased living with a gazelle's mind (e.g., light-hearted) and peaceful" (The Buddha's teachings-3). The above lesson was not given as highly technical as in the Abhiddhamma by the Buddha to King Kosala, as the king was worldly, so in general terms.</p><p>SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</head><p>Suppose we activate correct decisions on MV, which are recorded in the unconscious mind, and resist absolute pleasure. Suppose we enable HMV finding and treatment giving by universal loving-kindness, compassion, sympathetic joy, etc. In that case, our deep unconscious mindrelated MV is destroyed gradually and releases more happiness. Since 2000, the field of positive psychology has expanded drastically in terms of scientific publications. It has produced many different views on the causes of happiness and the factors that correlate with happiness. <ref type="bibr">(Wallis, Claudia (2005)</ref>  <ref type="bibr">(Bolier, Linda;</ref><ref type="bibr">Haverman, Merel;</ref><ref type="bibr">Westerhof, Gerben J;</ref>  <ref type="formula">Marcus   2015</ref>Life satisfaction refers to your thoughts and feelings when you think about your life, which occasionally happens, including in well-being surveys. Happiness describes the feelings people have as they live their everyday life. I now try to avoid: Happiness and life satisfaction are not synonymous with Life" (Kahneman, D.) Another researcher says a particularly rigorous validation would be based on extra domain assays. Human g correlates with academic success, workplace success, health, and happiness. (Burkart, Schubiger, &amp; Schaik, 2016) Individuals who use reappraisal more in situations they perceive as low in controllability have greater well-being. <ref type="bibr">(Haines et al., 2016)</ref>. This might make more intellectual capability and efficiency of mind, brain biochemistry, biophysics, and psychology, which might be the reason to make the frontal lobe of actual Buddhist practitioners is more active. Appropriately engaging sources of appetitive motivation, characteristic of the higher left than right baseline levels of prefrontal activation, may encourage the experience of well-being. <ref type="bibr">(Urry et al., 2004)</ref> Psychological Dynamics of neural recruitment surrounding the spontaneous arising of thoughts in experienced mindfulness SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE practitioners. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Ellamil et al., 2016)</ref>. Buddha discovered that the nature of destroying MV by HMV might be an efficient way of developing a person of any age to create and maintain brain biochemistry-related biophysics of the brain-mind combination. Thus, Buddha might be the best and the only teacher who has found the correct programming of the human brain-mind destroys MV and gains psychological health and happiness.</p><p>Therefore, as a result, we can believe that the quest for pleasure may underpin every decision we make. It is summarized by (3) &amp; (4) fate facts; for example, the strength of our hate-related MV (jealousy, anger, etc.) decisions resist/and or decrease for short term/long term in the foundation of true pleasure. A model in which cognitive control, emotional regulation, and empathic concern mediate the effects of meditation on decision-making. This model provides insights into the mechanisms by which meditation affects the decision-making process <ref type="bibr" target="#b112">(Sun, Yao, Wei, &amp; Yu, 2015)</ref>. "Individuals who use reappraisal more in situations they perceive as low in controllability have greater well-being. These findings have important implications for theoretical models of emotion regulation and their clinical applications". <ref type="bibr">(Haines et al.,2016)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MV classification</head><p>Identifying what links the mind and brain has become a reality ( ). The brain is a remarkable computer. As a result, it has been possible to draw three remote yet conclusive qualitative parallels between the aspects of the mind in the highly complex human brain, physical matter, and 3 of the main MV. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>20</head><p>(1) The concept of desirable MV:</p><p>The attraction between matters (e.g., gravity, chemical bonds) is parallel to some of the mentally structured elemental psychological thoughts that one draws close to oneself or, in other words, the attempts made to gain long-term possession of stimuli., e.g., A person might desire to enjoy the beauty of his wife forever, children.</p><p>(2) The concept of hateful MV:</p><p>The repulsion between matters (e.g., electron to electron) is parallel, e.g., yearning to repel or destroy one who is your enemy/dislikes</p><p>(3) The concept of MV of delusional:</p><p>The stabilization between matter (e.g., plants in the solar system) or electrons in atoms can be parallel by one's attempts to maintain stimuli and carry on regardless, e.g., the effort to preserve the status of MV.</p><p>2.0 Some significant MV out of more than 3000 MV at Abhidhamma Pali canon is the book of analysis in the chapter on the small matters.</p><p>When somebody is, be a generator of excessive confidence that one's interpretation of the world is correct, leading to hallucinations <ref type="bibr">(Schmitt et al., 2006</ref> Some of these *MV may be required (lawfully) to some extent to make worldly or family life successful, e.g., sensual pleasure, but relative to the highest intelligent person/s teachings, those are always MV. Therefore, MV might define someone's relative position in the graph as psychobiological-delusional limiting factors that attempt to reverse well-being and intelligence level due to the negative evolution(regression) of nature, nurture, and the X-UGPC+ X-UQUPC.</p><p>However, such a person justifies that such MV is essential for a successful life. When an MV activates, another or more MVs might also arise as a chain or network. This MV is out of approximately 3000 MV analyzed in the advanced teaching of Buddha called Abhidhamma Canon's book of analysis (Buddha's teachings-4). It is Volition (Cetana) action; thus, I say, "O monks; for as soon as intention arises, one does the activity by the body (physique), speech, or mind." (The Buddha's teachings-5).</p><p>The fifty-two mental factors (Cetasika) are mental concomitants bound up with the simultaneously arising consciousness (Citta = vinnana) <ref type="bibr">(Nyanatiloka, 1980)</ref>. The consciousness state (Citta) continuously appears and vanishes while the variable of its level repeatedly vanishes in Buddhist teaching. In the Abhidhamma canon, three mains categorize a person/life-all phenomena of existence-eighty-nine of consciousness, fifty-two mental factors, and corporeality (Citta, cetasika, and rupa). One such consciousness moment (Cittakkhana) is said in the commentaries to be inconceivably short and to last no longer than the billionth of the time occupied by a flash of lightning <ref type="bibr">(Nyanatiloka, 1980)</ref>. Some research findings provide "preliminary evidence that prolonged meditation practice may modulate self-vs. other-related processing, accompanied by an increase in compassion." <ref type="bibr" target="#b123">(Trautwein, Naranjo, &amp; Schmidt, 2016</ref>  I suggest that the conscious brain-mind is also partially split, but with a ''central executive, the manager that manipulates and coordinates information stored in the buffers for problem-solving, planning, and organizing activities" <ref type="bibr" target="#b139">(Wickelgren 1997)</ref>. All mental state decisions have the mind as their forerunner, the brain-mind (central executive) is their chief, and they are mind-made. If one speaks or behaves with HMV (Kusala), happiness follows one as one's 'shadow.' (The Buddha's teachings-8). However, I suggest by the above statement (if done) by Buddha, it might be a method of ''programming'' the disciples' minds because, many times rejects the soul of a person by Buddha. Nevertheless, He might not mean that the forerunner-free will-independent soul. Research suggests that the PFC exerts top-down control that is hierarchically organized in the processes of selection control, decision control, and evaluation, and a hierarchical view of the top-down control of perceptual decision-making demonstrates the intimate links between perception and cognition and promises to bring deeper insight into each of these domains <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">(Rahnev, 2017)</ref>. The frontal lobe contains decision-making cells independent of any of the senses; such cells could form the basis for a central executive in the brain, an area in overall control of decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Merali 2008)</ref>.</p><p>Additionally, because of the eye and visible forms, a consciousness arises, and it is called visual consciousness; likewise, auditory, olfactory gustatory, and tactile -consciousness and because of the mind and mind-objects (ideas and thoughts) arises a consciousness, and it is called 'mental' consciousness (The Buddha's teachings-9). Therefore, the mind must be divided into functionally separate modules <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">(Penrose, 2001)</ref>. Consciousness depends on matter, sensation, perception, and mental formations. That cannot exist independently of them, and consciousness may exist having SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE an issue as its means, matter as its object, matter as its support, and seeking delight it may grow, increase and develop (The Buddha's teachings-10), etc.</p><p>There is no single measure of intelligence (Mackintosh, 1995)-only several different, independent abilities <ref type="bibr">(Gardner, 1985)</ref>. For self-study and training of the EI toward an optimum can be achieved by developing latent abilities, the eightfold path, which was set deeply during Buddhism's early period, may be one of the most suitable, efficient, and practical methods. It is relevant to consider the scientific background of the practical and theoretical contribution of the evolution of intelligence and study the quantitative and qualitative features embodied in the abstract of the 8-fold path (The Buddha's teachings-11) (as in-depth brain-mind teachings of training for the cure and prevention methods for 'any person at any time). I suggest these treatments are successful if teacher/s are 'psychologically reprogramming a low-level person by a higherlevel person of intelligent and well-being.' However, this summary of treatment explains, convincingly as a therapy, many places in different places, in addition, to forms in the Pali canon, according to the student or disciple's psychological level at the particular time and place.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Selection of intelligent decisions making creatively on healthier behavior:</head><p>e.g., Actions avoid destroying or injuring lives (list of highest rank beginning from intelligent human beings including parents and then all other beings), theft, and sexual misconduct. In addition, avoid using or giving dangerous drugs, e.g., the Gift of a meal, to an intelligent person without activating(or expecting anything from them, but purely generous intention) more MV in self (e.g., expecting more gain/profit), but as an act of entirely of your best with HMV. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Selection of intelligent decision-making toward 'healthier and happier with professional behavior:</head><p>Actions avoid trading, using, or producing arms, licker, dangerous drugs, poisons; trading animals or animal flesh, human beings; slaughtering, fishing, soldiering, deceit, betrayal soothsaying, trickery, usury, etc. (Preservation of health, rights, and duties of human beings, animals and minimization of environmental pollution)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Selection of intelligent decision-making toward healthier and happier communication:</head><p>Refrain <ref type="formula">(</ref> above for a sufficient length of time, according to the self-potential and minimize worldly greed and grief and while enjoying the whole process, selflessly)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6">Selection of intelligent decisions of 'healthier and happier ways;</head><p>The attention to the cognition of HMV to reach the four higher cognitive levels-states-(jhana), they might only remain tranquility, awareness, intellectual process, etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.7">Selection of intelligent decisions on well-being perspective:</head><p>(a) Meditate on selfless renunciation (freedom from sensual MV) as an MV-preventing method (b) Develop loving-kindness meditation self to others PWB.</p><p>Take possible decisions toward self and another's optimum well-being. (use prevention methods for hate-MV). "The combined with empirically supported treatments, such as cognitive-behavioral therapy, loving-kindness meditation LKM, and compassion meditation CM may provide potentially useful strategies for targeting a variety of different psychological problems that involve interpersonal processes, such as social anxiety, marital conflict, anger, and coping with the strains of long-term caregiving." (Hinton, 2012). The above meta-analytic review confirmed that LKM interventions could enhance positive emotions in daily life and that the ongoing practice of LKM could provide short-term positive emotions. Further analysis implied that (1) interventions focused on loving-kindness were more effective than interventions focused on compassion and (2) didactic SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE components were necessary, while more intensive meditation did not enhance the effect. However, the mechanisms of LKM on positive emotions are still unclear, and potential applicability limitations among people with different backgrounds should be considered in practice". <ref type="bibr" target="#b147">(Zeng, Chiu, Wang, Oei, &amp; Leung, 2015)</ref>. Despite these limitations, the current study provides some evidence that a reduced focus on the individual self and stronger self-other integration might be an underlying mechanism of prolonged meditative practice. Such a mechanism would have significant implications. First, it might at least partially explain the effects of meditation on mental health and well-being. Excessive self-focus and feelings of isolation are hallmarks of mental disorders such as depression. Practices such as mindfulness meditation and LKM are increasingly regarded as effective treatments for these conditions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b123">(Trautwein et al., 2016)</ref> No pharmacological interventions can be envisioned to be somewhat effective in maintaining and perhaps improving optimal levels of cognitive capabilities. Some NPCEs, such as sleep, meditation, exercise, music, and spirituality, are based on widely-accepted traditional habits. <ref type="bibr" target="#b91">(Sachdeva, Kumar, &amp; Anand, 2015</ref>) Meditate on (when self and others are not having had well-being state -suffering-) compassion. In a review, they integrate three evolutionary arguments that converge on the hypothesis that compassion evolved as a distinct affective experience whose primary function is facilitating cooperation and protecting the weak and those who suffer. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.8.">Intelligent decision-making of perception/judgment of causes and effects alias as</head><p>"scientific thinking" is rational on cause and effect whatever you do -to eliminate the suffering from MV, the importance of HMV, and treatments given to MV intelligently (not only for your issues but also for treating others). "It fits for you to be perplexed. Kalama, it fits for you to be in doubt. Doubt has arisen in you about a perplexing matter. Come Kalama. Do not go by oral tradition or the lineage of teaching or gossip or a collection of text or logic or by inferential reasoning or reasoned cogitation or the acceptance SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE of a view after pondering it or the seeming competence of a speaker, or because you think, 'The ascetic is our teacher.' However, when you know thoroughly, These things are for 'well-being', those things are disapproval; the Wise convicts these things. If undertaken (MV) and practiced, these things lead to harm and suffering, and then you should abandon those." <ref type="formula">(The Buddha</ref> Mirror neurons might function between I 1 and I 2 (I 1 might be the executive of cognitive brainmind areas or/and the mechanism of its operation, and I 2 might be the internal-psychological environment representing the natural external environment outside of the physique.**This idea origin 1991 when I was writing the first article on intelligence) (I 2 the symbolic image of the selfbody and outer world with the support of five physical senses. (K. L. Senarath <ref type="bibr">Dayathilake, 1991)</ref>.</p><p>A functional, psychological picture of your actual body is in external environment I 2 in which your SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE physical body and outer world (frames) reflect your 'inner world' in you. There may be a simple relationship of complex brain-mind phenomena-executive functions of brain-mind I 1 might be responsible for higher cognitive functions. However, their behaviors might become irrational when the primary or immature human has incredible difficulty, such as his close relation/friends' death.</p><p>Even in this twenty-first century, over the world. 'Elders are a time to time singing hymns/prayers/canticles, together which do not have clear or rational meaning-but with pleasant melody-, encode (such teachings collapsing sound mind) irrational beliefs into their children. (who do not have any knowledge of God/s at birth and have a primarily great rational mind) as actors by their faith and fear (imaginary belief-of God/s) and beliefs, they trust that they get rewards (1. mostly in the future&gt; 2. had in the religious -as mentioned in their religious books, etc. in past time &gt;3. Now -in the present-rewards are the lowest in their categorization; this is the most observable order of belief of getting tips from God/s) when they affect tremendous fear or suffering or unseen effect(that cannot explain to the related person clearly) influence supper natural force/s.</p><p>(1) Some of the neurons encoded by God/s notions might give some relief. (but it does not identify or solve the real problem rationally), but it does not depend directly on whether the belief is correct.</p><p>We do not scientifically observe such supernatural being/s yet. (K. L. Senarath <ref type="bibr">Dayathilake, 1991)</ref>. Senarath <ref type="bibr">Dayathilake, 1991)</ref> SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE I 1 &lt; --------&gt; I 2 It/s, you, S/he, They ---' your' sensory organs and neurons of muscles →your physical body and 'your' real external world (i.e., if 'X person scolds 'y' person, it first affects 'X mind-brain because 'y' person is a just image in ' X mind-brain even though 'y' is in the external environment. If 'X' person scolding 'y' is just a side effect of the mechanism in the mind-brain relative of 'X.' (an 'X experiencing a grand delusion of the external environmentincluding his own body with five sensory which beyond the mindbrain), and he thinks it is not an image in him,(the images of the external world is in his flesh of brain) but this a natural direct simultaneously a reaction to 'y'. The great delusion theory confirms that no one will ever grasp all the knowledge of the natural external world -environmentbut just an incomplete image in the mind-brain. The physical body includes the image of the grand delusion beyond the brain-mind. (which connects to the brain-mind via sensory organs). Therefore, no one obtains perfect knowledge about any external environment, idea/concept/theory. I call it an incomplete image in anyone's mind. So your thoughts initially deal with the delusional information in your brain-mind.NO one can simultaneously reach-perception the external environment.</p><p>Neuropsychology affects the in-person 'X' brain-mind (see diagram below). Due to unpleasant emotions/feelings, internal cognitive functions, and many MV, such as inner dialog/function with hateful MV, your image of 'Y' and its memories in 'X (brain-mind). That is, first of all, majorly harmful to 'X. Then, if X has taken action with MV, she/he/they, and it too(who are in the actual external environment). The Constitution of UNESCO states that since wars begin in the minds of men. It is in the minds of men that defenses of peace should lay. I suggest that the great barrier is the grand delusion in the mind of men. representation is a significant challenge that will require developing in conjunction with specific experimental paradigms and theoretical frameworks <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Destexhe &amp; Contreras, 2006)</ref>. Our environment can affect how our mind develops, but the relationship is complex <ref type="bibr">(Bloom, 2006)</ref>.</p><p>The free association may create efficient patterns of spontaneous brain activity from single cells to networks of well-selected, much-limited, well-focused high-amplitude gamma synchrony. The neural circuits in the brain that underlie our behaviors are well-suited for processing real-world or natural stimuli <ref type="bibr" target="#b102">(Sharpee et al., 2006</ref>). The prefrontal cortex shows relatively late structural and metabolic maturation. The prolonged phase of prefrontal cortical gain in the most intelligent region might afford an even more extended 'critical' period for the development of high-level cognitive cortical circuits <ref type="bibr" target="#b103">(Shaw et al., 2006)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5.0Mind-brain mechanism of EI in a 3D graph</head><p>According to graphs, nature and nurture have a more significant role in brain biology and cognitive functions. The cognitive abilities in common are the genetic origin (due to g), whereas the specific cognitive abilities' specific features are primarily environmental <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">(Plomin, 2001)</ref>. Therefore, the environment for PWB of society could manage. The processes of intelligence are universal <ref type="bibr" target="#b110">(Sternberg, 2004)</ref> and manifestations. Two other scholars highlight "five genetic findings special However, researchers found no "individual protein-altering variants reproducibly associated with extremely high intelligence. Thus, despite the power of sampling from the extremely high end of the distribution of intelligence, we conclude that these results primarily highlight the complex genetic architecture of intelligence". (Spain et al., 2015). Those who are not perfectly intelligent (according to my 3D graph and Buddhist psychology, entirely intelligent are the Buddha and Arahat's) persons might be 'actors,' e.g., people secretly may hate someone and desire to marry their wife. Therefore, they have a lifelong conflict with related MV. I agree that sexual desire and needs are natural and vital to some extent until s/he will destroy all MV-for example, better family life with a spouse. There is less conflict with healthy family life, earning wealth, and being generous. The conscious mind has a vital role in treating MV with HMV. There are theoretical possibilities of the qualitative and quantitatively different EI stages of some human beings, relative to each other, that we can predict. These +/-groups of individuals may be graphically represented in the 3-D 'graph' to show the three dependent factors' activity over time. with relatively more MV than D. Person H: Lacking in HMV and therefore very harmful to oneself and society. (E.g., Hitler) (E.g., even by a microwatt of external stimuli, might be enough for him/her to decide to react (when s/he has the facilities) even a nuclear bomb to destroy the world) Alternatively, it might help the origin of new species, as well (on the earth and so on) (according to previous birth stories of the Buddha, he had been born in several species. Buddha explains how hard it is to select a better partner with said qualities.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A+highest positive level &gt; B +positive level &gt; level C+positive level</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">EI and Decision-making</head><p>Reminders of money, relative to no money reminders, led to a reduced request for help and reduced helpfulness toward others <ref type="bibr" target="#b131">(Vohs et al., 2006)</ref>. Little is known about how the human brain limits the impact of selfish motives and implements fair behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Knoch 2006</ref> MV, such as increasingly (limitless desires) money-making MV, could create less generosity in people. Because it has combinations of some other MV, repelling or neglecting others' well-being, selfishness that does not like to share money with poor/helpless people, hate-related MV may also underlie the process. I think HMV, such (levels) as loving-kindness, compassion (etc.), sympathetic joy, and serenity, etc., good remedies might limit the specific level of selfish motives.</p><p>Many people are not aware of the importance of how/why they should practice the science of psychology, which enhances a better life. This may be a reason for the frontopolar cortex's <ref type="bibr">(FPC)</ref> capacity, which appears highly limited and suggests that the FPC is effective for protecting the execution of long-term mental plans from immediate environmental demands and for generating new, possibly more rewarding behavioral or cognitive sequences, rather than for complex decision-making and reasoning <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Koechin &amp; Hyafil 2007)</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Some Psychiatric Disorders and EI</head><p>We can hypothesize that psychiatrically abnormal people suffer due to multifactorial causes such as their genome, other psychiatrist physiological factors, external environmental facts( nurture), and deviated MV but not may due to X-UQCPG because X-UQCPG is only crucial and depending key and bond with the next life. If the new life's genome, nurture, and MV have such potential for disease, the particular person has to suffer. Here, I suppose and emphasize that nature and nurture might be direct and indirect causes for the particular person's MV versus HMV evolvement; then, the state and total impact of those MV and HMV in cognitive function may impact the evolvement of the brain and its genome. The complexity of MV also might impact disorders of particular patients, such as schizophrenia and manic depression. Symptoms such as paranoia, phobia, overestimating (self), irrationality, and a supportive environment with their intense imagination might make creativity possible. The genes that predispose people to schizophrenia and manic depression have been maintained in the gene pool by natural selection because of their beneficial effects in enhancing creativity, and out of a wide range of 'eminent people,' scientists had one of the lowest lifetime rates of mental disorder <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Nettle 2001</ref>). If we can manage compassionate thoughts, we can utilize that creativity to enhance a better world. A pilot study examined loving-kindness meditation (LKM) with 18 participants with schizophrenia-spectrum disorders and significant negative symptoms. The findings indicate that the intervention was feasible and associated with decreased negative symptoms and increased positive emotions. Psychological recovery <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Johnson et al. 2011</ref>) and mindfulness, meta-cognitive approaches, compassionate mind training, and method of levels are postulated to be useful adjuncts for CBT with psychotic patients. <ref type="bibr" target="#b115">(Tai &amp; Turkington 2009)</ref> However, it is also "unclear what particular role meditation may have: relapse prevention, motivational enhancement, or promotion of abstinence. Additionally, pharmacotherapy may have a role as an adjunct to meditation practice. No definitive statements can be made at this time, however, regarding meditation's place in the treatment of addictive disorders. Further research needs to be done in order to more properly and conclusively determine its benefits, mechanisms, and limitations" <ref type="bibr">(Dakwar &amp; Levin, 2009)</ref>. "Acutely ill psychiatric inpatients at a state hospital found the Headspace app easy to use; we are able to complete a series of meditations and felt the app helped with anxiety, sleep, and boredom on the unit. There were no instances of an increase in psychotic symptoms reported, and there were no episodes of aggression or violence noted in the Emotional self-awareness is the building block of the next fundamental of emotional intelligence: being able to shake off a bad mood (Goleman 1995). "Compassion," as one patient put it in an open letter to his doctor, "is not merely hand-holding; It is good medicine" <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Kramer 1993)</ref>. Perhaps the most powerful demonstration of the clinical power of emotional support, women with advanced breast cancer who went to weekly meetings with others survived twice as long as women with the same disease faced it on their own. <ref type="bibr" target="#b108">(Spiesel 1989)</ref> The strongest scientific link between emotions and heart disease is to anger (Goleman 1995). Experience may modulate gene expression, which leads to substantial behavioral differences. His study of 681 people who had suffered major depression for an average of eight years highlighted how significant early life events could be on later mental health. If you look at measures such as the loss of a parent through death, divorce, separation; abuse; or physical or sexual neglect, only one-third of patients had no trauma. Two-thirds suffered early life trauma; we have to consider this a risk factor (Goleman1995). Consciousness might be a product of the brain-mind and X-UNP+ XMPG SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE function, and this process might influence behaviors by MV and HMV. The human mind does not correctly explain the pleasure principle. To me, the quality and quantitative pleasure may explain more correctly by MV and HMV principles. The meaning of pleasure may be in different forms for different individuals. However, a healthy intellectual person's health pressure might only be reached by eightfold treatment(a great CBT).</p><p>Additionally, the superego is a simple moral expectation and an intelligent way of nature of psychology. The frontal collision of the superego is why hundreds of fundamental mechanisms of MV against HMV occur in the human brain. However, all of these treatments are successful only if cognitive functions of the brain remain 'normal' or psychiatrically, not highly abnormal. This kind of eccentric person can also be treated medicinally and with an 8-fold path for EI simultaneously.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">A few Buddhist psychological views &amp; EI</head><p>Psychology is not a new science; the Abhidhamma, the third division of Pali texts of Theravada.</p><p>The school contains a complete system of mind training based on analysis of consciousness taken to a degree not yet surpassed by the West <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Humphreys 1984)</ref>. Founding President of the Pali Text Society of London T.W. Rhys Davids. He said, "Buddhist or not Buddhist, I have examined every one of the great religious systems of the world, and in none of them have I found anything to surpass in beauty and comprehensiveness, the 8-fold path and the four noble truths of the Buddha".</p><p>Suppose the Buddhists and neuroscientists can put their heads together and figure it out. Now we can all wish to get a healthier world <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Barinaga 2003)</ref>. Not in the ordinary sense of words of 'desire,' 'hate,' and 'delusion,' but the classification of MV theory of technical teachings by Buddha and I SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE attempt to confirm the leading theory of this paper, also supported by Goleman's two books on emotional intelligence.</p><p>There is one torment when something permanent within oneself does not find (The Buddha's teachings-16). It means you may not find eternal, undecaying, and not suffering beings in the "universe. (In Buddhist teaching, those 12 sufferings are old age, sickness, death, association with unpleasant persons and conditions, separation from beloved persons and pleasant conditions, not getting what you desire, grief, lamentation, and distress) (according to modern physics confirm that there is no matter or energy is in permanent but always them impermanence). Even if you have a 'soul'-like identity, it will also face the natural laws of the universe/s. Whatever is of the nature of arising, all that is of the nature of cessation (Buddha's teachings-17). Buddha's teaching was in no way religion and not even metaphysical, and Buddhism is frequently described as atheistic, as it has no place for a supreme controller of the universe <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Davies 1990</ref>). Albert Einstein said, "If there is any religion that would cope with modern science, it would be Buddhism."</p><p>Many people have been misled regarding Buddhism as pessimistic <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(Rahula 1959)</ref>. breathing is one of the most important 'Buddhist exercises' to achieve higher mental levels by practicing the 8-fold path -like a meditation-. It may maintain a higher level of O2 for related brain active regions by breath supervision of the frontal cortex.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.0">Order and EI World</head><p>The evolution of intelligence in the world will be more favorable when the average number of 9. Even if he/she faces complex problems, should be patient, calm-full (not to be aggressive; which leads to violence, terrorism, crime, etc.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10.">Being constitutional</head><p>Furthermore, treat in an equal manner to every citizen, with pleasant speech (Not being cruel, hateful, in an unintelligent way). Fortunately, some scientists are now discussing and making a dialog for better world order in a psychological aspect. For example, the ten guidelines of Buddha mentioned above for leaders were valid according to five studies. They say that power increases hypocrisy, moralizing in reasoning, immorality in behavior, and exploring whether power increases moral hypocrisy (i.e., imposing strict moral standards on others but practicing less strict moral behavior oneself) (Joris et al., 2010). In addition, scholarly men for leaders are impartial.</p><p>However, history shows that impressive academics and impressive academic records do not guarantee good, impartial advice and caution <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">(Dallek 2009)</ref>. Therefore, psychological researchers are also dialoguing toward practical policy planning and implementation for leaders with scholarly organizations, which is essential. In short, academic advice should have genuine compassion toward humanity; therefore, impartially and intelligently convincing politicians are crucially needed. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.0">Eightfold Path &amp; EI</head><p>This theory emphasizes that a person's external world is imaginary and limited (any person at any time). When you are doing business with somebody else, always your brain's imaginary world makes dialog directly with visual/and auditory and three sensories of the particular person in your delusional world in you., etc. image in your brain similar to you are dreaming while awaking because of your great delusion (if it is lower level mean your insight-mindfulness irrelatively high, and you might observe delusion in you and think its just-primary result in your fleshy mind-brain link. Therefore not tend to get angry, aggressive to your mind images if do so the side effects of aggressive become as behaviors (externally observable). In theory, argue, your brain is <ref type="bibr">(almost)</ref> perfect <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Montague 2007)</ref>, but how/why you may severely deviate/could be deviated by the external world in you. It may be associated with your definition of cost, benefits, and economy. A decision is a commitment to a proposition or plan of action based on evidence and the expected costs and benefits associated with the outcome. The theoretical and experimental findings advance the understanding of decision-making regarding the highly flexible and cognitive acts of vacillation and self-correction <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Resulaj et al., 2009)</ref>. Those thoughts on economic decisions may depend on total MV vs. HMV results and neutral MV fluctuations in cognitive neural actions. Several quality studies on meditation suggest that a functional reorganization of brain activity patterns for focused attention and cognitive monitoring takes place with mental practice. Meditation-related neuroplasticity is crucially associated with a functional reorganization of activity patterns in the prefrontal cortex and insula <ref type="bibr">(Manna et al., 2010)</ref>. Systematic mental training in studying the human mind by revealing neural mechanisms that enable the brain to successfully represent target information <ref type="bibr" target="#b105">(Slagter et al., 2009)</ref>. Western psychological research on positive psychology and  <ref type="bibr">(Brown 2007)</ref>. I mean (according to some observations on well-meditating persons) that relatively highly evolved personal decisions always (even) take a risk for themselves to keep others' psychological well-being with great compassion.</p><p>Individuals who believe that moral character can change over time (incremental beliefs) are more trusted than their counterparts following an apology and trustworthy behavior than are individuals who believe that moral character cannot change (entity beliefs). A simple but powerful message can induce either entity or incremental beliefs about moral character . Even cockroaches develop psychological problems if they are denied a normal social life. Animals reared in solitude are less likely to explore new environments. <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Lihoreau et al., 2009)</ref>. A study shows that the 8-fold path emphasizes mindfulness communications of higher quality, which may cure many psychological problems. Primary care physicians report high levels of distress linked to burnout, attrition, and more inferior quality of care and participation in a mindful communication program, which was associated with short-term and sustained improvements in well-being and attitudes associated with patient-centered care. Because before-and-after designs limit inferences about intervention effects, these findings warrant randomized trials involving a variety of practicing physicians. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Krasner et al. 2009)</ref>. It may be valid in other jobs as well. For example, professional attitudes may shape or even change by good meditation according to 8-fold path guidelines toward a healthier world.</p><p>Minimal needs in the simple life of higher intelligence levels person not/less evolving on environmental pollution. Because "industrial societies pollute and it is possible that in the future SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE the new mutation rate could rise and these changes could go into reverse. For this reason, population monitoring of somatic mutations is required'' <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Morris, 1999)</ref>. Therefore, S/he might need fewer resources in the modern world. However, the priceless brain gives priority to better psychological health, self, and others, and cognitive functional well-being helps interact in many ways concerning physical health.</p><p>Recent researchers have found that meditation produces positive and demonstrable stress reduction effects on the brain and immune functions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b143">(Yang et al., 2009)</ref>. Compassion enhances the emotional and somatosensory brain representations of others' emotions, and this effect is modulated by expertise <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Lutz et al., 2009)</ref>. A study evaluated the effectiveness of mindfulnessbased cognitive therapy (MBCT) for individuals diagnosed with cancer. There were large and significant improvements in mindfulness (effect size [ES] = 0.55), depression (ES = 0.83), anxiety (ES = 0.59), and distress (ES = 0.53), as well as a trend for quality of life (ES = 0.30) for MBCT participants compared to those who had not received the training. These improvements represent clinically meaningful changes and provide evidence for the provision of MBCT within oncology settings <ref type="bibr">(Foley et al., 2010.)</ref> Additionally, the first empirical evidence is that the visual perception of people's symptoms may cause the immune system to respond more aggressively to infection. <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">(Schaller et al. 2010</ref>) Recent research has revealed that a wide range of morphological anomalies even those that are not symptoms of infectious diseasecan elicit emotional, cognitive, and behavioral responses that mimic those associated with the perception of disease symptoms <ref type="bibr">(Park et al., 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Park et al., , 2007</ref>. It shows a close relationship between mind-brain-body interactions and their importance. I suggest that we biologically evolved (billions of years). The natural greenish environment tremendously impacts the brain's interaction with sensory organs. That is why we may feel more comfortable and relaxed. This may be the main reason for the EI of Buddha's brain-mind mechanism in a very efficient way in a certain period without any environmental pollution. In other words, his good genomes might not deviate, especially in his mind-brain mechanism and when it evolves. According to the Pali Canon, the Buddha has not slept more than a few hours (after the Buddhahood), sleeping specifically (Niroda samapatti) other than worldly persons, but it never impacts his well-being. Therefore, meditation acutely improves psychomotor vigilance and may decrease sleep needs. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Kaul, Passafiume, Sargent, &amp; O'Hara, 2010)</ref>. On the other hand, deviation from interacting with nature may be a reason for developing many psychological </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.0">Educational Psychology &amp; EI</head><p>To every person, he is the most important. Therefore, is there a proper methodology to find 'self'</p><p>that could help achieve a better quality of life by strengthening the advanced psychological SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE education system? Even in diverse cultures, it could evolve through broad scientific dialog. We can observe much of the child population directly toward a rat race; in the present education system, they may (generally) deviate immensely from their psychological well-being. Now we know the unlimited desire MV for money, luxury life, etc., such targeting education could not make a healthy, happy, and kind person. Too much-unwanted information flows through the senses, and most of the time spent in the artificial environment may deviate from potential beneficial learning. Such as from modern <ref type="bibr">IT, devices, media, etc. (unsystematic)</ref> • Too much study workload</p><p>• Less sound sleep</p><p>• Less love, kindly touch simulations from parents, guardians, teachers, etc.</p><p>• In school environments, sound pollution, air pollution, etc., trends</p><p>• Hypocrisies of Teachers, leaders, parents, etc.</p><p>• The higher workload of teachers, parents, etc., again affects the child (aggressiveness, stress, restlessness)</p><p>• Fewer exercises/fewer sports/faster food/malnutrition/more soft drinks/drugs abuse/child sexual abuse/sex video/watching more TV programs, etc., might develop MV directly/indirectly • Therefore, the children's environment and education system should be psychologically healthy and more advanced toward their wellness. Education psychologists should be more active with other psychologists by searching, planning policy, and more research and developments on healthy education systems. Aspiring to the fulfillment of one's talents and abilities in the form of transcendent creative contributions will lead to high levels of personal satisfaction and selfactualization as well as unimaginable benefits to society. <ref type="bibr">(Subotnik, Olszewski-kubilius</ref> Worrell, 2016). Four meta-analyses yielded significant results; supplementing infants with longchain polyunsaturated fatty acids, enrolling children in early educational interventions, reading to children in an interactive manner, and sending children to preschool all raise the intelligence of young children. <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">(Protzko, Aronson, &amp; Blair, 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Enthusiastic knowledge searching, appreciating, and encouraging-unbiased questioning, curiosity, and creative thinking support-a rewarding system in education may create healthier, happy, and more creative persons. However, minimal harm through creativity on welfare should be managed and dialogued by scholars. Then, it could affect future leadership, media, and policymakers, even in the unbiased advanced scientific publication system, to eradicate many problems. Researchers suggest that as people win or lose more money, they are increasingly biased toward overestimating the emotional impact of these outcomes. Our modeling approach provides novel insight into how explicit feelings relate to choice. Such understanding is of theoretical importance and has practical implications for policymakers, economists, and clinicians, who often measure explicit feelings to predict choice <ref type="bibr">(Benjamin, Heffetz, Kimball, &amp; Rees-Jones, 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">, 2014</ref>. Other researchers "propose expanding on the traditional set of predictors by adding a third agency: intellectual curiosity. A series of path models based on a meta-analytically derived correlation matrix showed that (a) intelligence is the single most powerful predictor of academic performance; (b) the effects of intelligence on academic performance are not mediated by personality traits; (c) intelligence, conscientiousness (as a marker of effort) and typical intellectual engagement (as a marker of intellectual curiosity) are direct, correlated predictors of academic performance; and (d) the additive predictive effect of the personality traits of intellectual curiosity and rival effort influences intelligence. Our results highlight that a "hungry mind" is a core determinant of individual differences in academic achievement." (von Stumm, Hell, &amp; Chamorro-</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</formula><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE Premuzic, 2011) Action in the 8-fold path emphasizes the importance and universal responsibility, truth, and accuracy of the information you 'tell 'and how important that information is for your EI.</p><p>Recently, an editorial discussed that in the article "information overload," US National Academies makes recommendations for tackling the issue surrounding the era of petabyte science. The integrity data he or she produces (Campbell 2009). We do not need (even if they are scientific) all this information for a better life for (with higher EI) humankind. Even top scientific personalities can enjoy their well-being with society with essential and systematic scientific information. Here, I suggest psychologists could make outstanding leadership to eradicate the waste of billions or trillions of dollars and human hours of working toward avoiding harmful or unwanted duties that they engage in until death. We should compassionately and more open-mindedly study this problem toward the more prosperous inner world of the mind. According to this theory, EI shapes potential emotional intelligence as well. The 8-fold paths may shape even the body's better language; facial expressions are clues to others' emotions, communications, and aggressive action toward effective methods. In a broad sense, preventive education in the mind-brain development process by meditation should take place. A higher cognitive system can often influence our reaction to emotion-provoking events. An experienced meditator (i) aware of the treatments when he or others get aggressive, depressed, etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(ii)</head><p>In a short period, they might successfully recognize and react to whether they tend to harm emotions, actions, etc.</p><p>(iii) They might diagnose those emotions or thoughts as just a result of the internal mechanism of his brain-mind (if it is harmful). They feel it has an unpleasant 'taste' of those unhealthy emotions, thoughts, etc.  shows that people will likely support more enforcement measures if the crime described as a "beast" preys on a community. However, by telling them there is a "virus" infecting a city, they are more inclined to treat the problem with social reform (Gorlick, 2011).</p><p>They found that exposure to even a single metaphor can induce substantial differences in opinion about solving social problems: larger differences, for example, than preexisting differences in opinion between Democrats and Republicans. <ref type="bibr" target="#b121">(Thibodeau &amp; Boroditsky 2011)</ref> The treatment of anger is present in seven steps: (i) taking responsibility, (ii) becoming aware, (iii) understanding anger, (iv) reflection, (v) decision, (vi) relaxation, and (vii) opening the heart <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Leifer, 1999)</ref>. In my view treatment of anger with mindfulness of 1. Yes, I have this MV and activated (taking responsibility)</p><p>2. Aware/mindful of the (present) situation of mind (and body) -Becoming Aware.</p><p>3. Understanding Anger. (How/why/where it is happening. In the mind mechanism. It is unpleasantness, harmfulness.) Mainly it is our mind creating phenomena, etc.  <ref type="bibr">6</ref>. Relaxation: enjoy the challenge you face and how you faced it in the past-now it is just a memory. Therefore, I can now relax meaningfully. 7. By this self-study, mindfulness might enhance brain frontal area aggression and determine the process at an advanced level.</p><p>A consideration of the targets within emotion processing that is likely to be impacted by mindfulness . Recovery from an emotional challenge and increased tolerance of negative affect are both hallmarks of mental health. Mindfulness training (MT) has been shown to facilitate these outcomes, yet little is known about its mechanisms of action. The greater somatic recruitment observed in the MT group during evoked sadness was associated with decreased depression scores.</p><p>Restoring the balance between effective and sensory neural network-supporting conceptual and body-based representations of emotion could be one path through which mindfulness reduces vulnerability to dysphoric reactivity. (Farb et al. 2010)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>9.0Mind-brain Mechanism, Well-being, and EI</head><p>Even with the modern scientific substantial knowledge (millions of research publications we already have), we may be in the early stages-of such findings while facing (universal) psychological mysteries -challenges-problemsremain. It is difficult to predict when it will be entirely discovered without the support of other alternative advanced sources or hypotheses, such as (if there is a sense of scientific rationale)Buddhist teachings( or whatever other knowledge exists, but that information should be more reliable and no or fewer scientific contradictions in ). However, when studying his daily routine (only a few hours he used to sleep every day) and this small number, teaching in words is challenging. While going through 57 volumes of the remaining teaching of Buddhis should be one great(est) teacher who was behind the great(est) teachings ( good evidence), with less or no contradictions even without (or after little editing of the original meaning as we realized form.Such (much clear ) advanced psychology of his teachings might (probably give us, as psychologists, great resources. For example, no strong research finding confirms the great harmfulness of the (generally) human mind and behavior, which has been greatly discussed and used to evolve people during that period. lives by even one person may not be able to solve all these problems alone. However, I suggest these teachings might help solve many tremendous issues in brain-mind-evolving practical methods. In PubMed Central, I found more than 30400, and in Google Scholar, there are 1.4 million publications until June 29th, 2023, on meditation, some high-quality studies, and positive impact on minds and behaviors. For example, there is emerging evidence that mindfulness meditation might cause neuroplastic changes in the structure and function of brain regions involved in regulating attention, emotion, and self-awareness <ref type="bibr" target="#b119">(Tang, Hölzel, &amp; Posner, 2015)</ref>. While studying consciousness, there is no understanding of how neuron firing gives rise to intense personal sensations (Lane 2009). I suggest SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE that the brain-mind, combined with the third 'matter,' I call X -ultraquantum consciousness particle genome associated with X-UQUPC. (X-UQUPC -might neuro-ultra quantum-biophysical matter that is responsible for your unique consciousness identity), Furthermore, unfortunately, we could not find/it challenging to find technical terms-well defined scientific terms for some Theravada Abhidhamma (advanced Buddhist psychology in 7 volumes) terms. Apparently, some Buddhist psychological explanations look more advanced than modern psychology, and many are tally with modern psychological science (i.e., neurogenesis and neuroplasticity phenomena might help). While the neuroscientific study of meditation is still in its infancy, mainstream psychology, and cognitive neuroscience will arguably serve well by engaging in a more open but critical and rigorous examination of the findings from meditation studies. Such findings may help to determine the extent to which the adult brain is plastic or subject to change, identify the basic mechanisms that underlie process-specific learning, and lead to further exploration of cognitive-neural systems that are resilient to damage, amenable to reorganization and capable of improving the efficiency of processing through training or pharmacological treatment <ref type="bibr" target="#b107">(Slagter et al. 2011)</ref>. More generally, these findings support the idea that the nervous system is a continuously changing structure in which plasticity is an integral property and the obligatory consequence of not only sensory and motor processing but also more complex mental activities, such as focusing attention and metacognitive monitoring <ref type="bibr">(Buonomano and Merzenich, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Pascual-Leone et al., 2005)</ref>. Just as a specific physical exercise will produce selected changes in brain circuitry and performance <ref type="bibr">(Hillman et al., 2008)</ref>, a specific mental exercise will lead to selected changes in brain circuitry that can significantly affect information processing and behavior. <ref type="bibr" target="#b107">(Slagter et al. 2011)</ref> Brain regions associated with attention vary over the time of a meditation session and may differ between long-and short-term meditation practitioners. Vipassana meditation appears to be associated with SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE differences in attentional deployment, brain function, and cortical structures that may underlie meditation's long-term effects of decreased emotional reactivity, increased well-being and compassion and reported changes in self-experience <ref type="bibr">(Goleman, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b132">Wallace, 1999)</ref> and scientific <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Astin, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr">Cahn and Polich 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Farb et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b126">Travis et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b134">Wallace and Shapiro, 2006)</ref>. This knowledge could be the best way to create advanced psychotherapy for many psychiatric disorders. Much is still to be learned about the molecular basis of mental disorders <ref type="bibr">(Ross &amp; Margolis 2009)</ref>. Common polygenic variation contributes to the risk of schizophrenia and bipolar disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b102">(Purcell et al. 2009)</ref>. A journal editorial says that if clinical psychology in the US wants to remain viable and relevant in today's health systems, it must publicly embrace science. There is a moral imperative to turn psychology into a robust and valued science (Campbell 2009). If we change/make a better environment and stimulate and develop a hidden healthy program -the mind may make less/no interaction with genetic factors of complex disorders, and it may create better personalities. For example, schizophrenia is a complex disorder caused by both genetic and environmental factors and their interactions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b109">(Stefansson et al., 2009)</ref> Ongoing research and practice of cognitive behavior therapy (CBT) have led to emerging evidence of other important factors in schizophrenia, in addition to thought content and thinking styles <ref type="bibr" target="#b115">(Tai &amp;Turkington 2009)</ref>. These include the role of arousal <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Morrison &amp; Wells 2003)</ref>, emotion <ref type="bibr">(Freeman &amp; Garety 2005)</ref>, attachment and interpersonal issues <ref type="bibr">(Birchwood et al. 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">MacBeth et al. 2008)</ref>, loss and trauma <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Read et al. 2001)</ref>, self-esteem <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Barrowclough et al. 2003)</ref> and acceptance and self-to-self relating. <ref type="bibr">(Gilbert et al. 2001)</ref>. Increasing knowledge about the neurobiological effects of mindfulness-based cognitive therapy (MBCT) may foster the convergence of the biological and SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE psychological aspects of psychiatry and aid in the design of much-needed primary prevention studies in mood disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b145">(Young 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Engagement in compassion meditation may reduce stress-induced immune and behavioral responses, although future studies are required to determine whether individuals who engage in compassion meditation techniques are more likely to exhibit reduced stress reactivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(Pace et al., 2009)</ref>. Positive improvement in psychological well-being following mindfulness-based stress reduction was associated with increased natural killer cytolytic activity and decreased levels of creative protein. <ref type="bibr">(Fang et al. 2010)</ref> Happiness is also important for physical well-being, given that there are immune benefits to feeling happy and immune costs to feeling sad <ref type="bibr">(Cohen et al. 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr">Marshland et al. 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr">Rosenkranz et al. 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b100">Segerstrom &amp; Sephton 2010)</ref>. Health threats loom larger late in life, particularly from cancers and parasites <ref type="bibr">(World Health Organization 2009)</ref>. I suggest several conscious levels and their formation qualities, healthy to unhealthy connections with different brain areas in the diversity of human brains, changing with time. There are eightynine consciousness groups and fifty-two cognitive factors in the diversified 'brain-mind functions in Buddhist teachings. Although the adult brain was once seen as a rather static organ, it is now clear that the organization of brain circuitry is constantly changing as a function of experience or learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b107">(Slagter 2011)</ref>. Research has shown that the genetic risk for psychotic illnesses is linked, at least in part, to abnormal connections between different brain areas and that risk genes do not influence the strength of activation in various brain areas. Connectivity between some areas is either reduced or increased in risk gene carriers in a pattern reminiscent of that seen in patients <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Meyer, 2009)</ref> SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>69</head><p>A study discusses four metaphysical techniques for facilitating patient healing: 1) refocusing on the present, 2) reframing adversity, 3) practicing surrender, and 4) meditation. These approaches can be mutually integrated and complement psychological treatment in either the psychiatric or primary care setting, regardless of whether the patient has formal religious beliefs <ref type="bibr">(Sansone &amp; Sansone 2009)</ref>. I believe that the 8-fold path already has the above four techniques. A current study provided preliminary results about neurobiological and clinical changes related to Vipassana meditation (VM). Nonetheless, few publications are available, especially for clinical studies, and current products must be considered with caution. In the Theravada tradition alone, there are over fifty methods for developing mindfulness and forty for developing concentration, while in the Tibetan tradition, there are thousands of visualization meditations <ref type="bibr">(Goldstein, 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Further research is needed to answer critical questions about replications, self-selection, placebo, and long-term effects of VM. (Chiesa, 2010) Mindfulness-based stress reduction (MBSR) training in patients with a social anxiety disorder (SAD) may reduce emotional reactivity while enhancing emotion regulation. These changes might facilitate a reduction in SAD-related avoidance behaviors, clinical symptoms, and automatic emotional reactivity to negative self-beliefs in adults with SAD . Clinical psychology has focused primarily on diagnosing and treating mental diseases, and only recently has scientific attention turned to understanding and cultivating positive psychological health.</p><p>On the other hand, the early Buddhist tradition has focused since 538 BC might cultivating exceptional states of mental well-being and identifying and treating psychological problems <ref type="bibr" target="#b134">(Wallace &amp; Shapiro 2006)</ref>. In an analysis, a researcher says that good analytic listening requires one other quality: the capacity to decode or translate what we hear on the latent and metaphoric SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE level, which meditation does not do. This is a crucial weakness of meditation <ref type="bibr" target="#b90">(Rubin, 2009)</ref>. I think the 8-fold path-meditation-defines and broadly discusses IE and well-being and how mindfulness helps to scan hidden MV by HMV. According to another study, with greater numbers of patients and physicians choosing alternatives to traditional, medication-oriented treatment, meditation's clinical use and popularity have grown tremendously. The specific ways that meditation may be helpful for substance use disorders suggest new avenues for research <ref type="bibr">(Dakwar &amp; Levin 2009)</ref>. Correct meditation methods might give actual and potential happiness; there is no need to search for harmful substances to find them.</p><p>Furthermore, a loving and caring environment could be created through 8-fold paths-treatment methods-within the family and society. The results show the consistent and significant efficacy of relaxation training in reducing anxiety. This meta-analysis extends the existing literature through the facilitation of a better understanding of the variability and clinical significance of anxiety improvement after relaxation training <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Manzoni et al., 2008)</ref>. After five days of training, the IBMT group showed better regulation of the ANS by a ventral mid-frontal brain system than the relaxation group <ref type="bibr">(Tang et al. 2009)</ref>. A meditation workshop for GP well-being is practical, feasible, and appealing to GPs.</p><p>Quantitative feedback from the workshop indicates its potential as an effective mental health promotion and prevention strategy <ref type="bibr">(Manoch et al., 2009)</ref>. The new intervention activities were generally feasible to deliver, acceptable to participants, and perceived to yield positive benefits for family functioning and parent psychological well-being <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Duncan et al. 2009)</ref>, that mindfulness training can affect working memory capacity and enhance the ability of participants to talk about SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE past crises in a way that enables them to remain specific and yet not be overwhelmed. <ref type="bibr" target="#b140">(Williams 2010</ref>) In a web survey of Buddhists' religious practices and beliefs, Sixty-eight percent of respondents rated their health as very good or excellent. A one-point increase in the Buddhist Devoutness Index was associated with a 15% increase in the odds of being a nonsmoker and an 11% increase in the odds of being in good to excellent health <ref type="bibr">(Wist et al., 2010)</ref>. After four sessions of either meditation training or listening to a recorded book, participants with no prior meditation experience were assessed with measures of mood, verbal fluency, visual coding, and working memory. Both interventions were effective at improving mood, but only brief meditation training reduced fatigue and anxiety and increased mindfulness. Moreover, brief mindfulness training significantly improved visuospatial processing, working memory, and executive functioning. <ref type="bibr" target="#b146">(Zeidan et al., 2010)</ref> Meditation practice in the medical setting is proven to be an excellent adjunctive therapy for many illnesses and an essential and primary means of maintaining holistic health and wellness. Rather than being a fringe or marginal concept, meditation is now widely known and accepted as a beneficial mind-body practice by the general public and in the scientific community <ref type="bibr">(Fortney &amp; Taylor, 2010)</ref>. The application of cutting-edge technology toward understanding mindfulness -an "inner technology" -is elucidating new ways in which attention, awareness, acceptance, and compassion may promote optimal health -in mind, body, relationships, and spirit. <ref type="bibr">(Greeson 2009)</ref> Some findings suggest that long-term Vipassana meditation contributes to increased occipital gamma power-related long-term meditation expertise and enhanced sensory awareness (Cahn et al.2010); findings suggest meditation can decrease neurophysiologic processes' amplitude subserve attentional engagement elicited by unexpected and distracting stimuli. Consistent with SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE the aim of VM to reduce cognitive and emotional reactivity, the state effect of reduced P3a amplitude to distracting stimuli reflects decreased automated reactivity and evaluative processing of task-irrelevant attention-demanding stimuli <ref type="bibr">(Cahn &amp; Polich 2009)</ref>. We cannot live with skepticism alone; scientists have been too dogmatic about scientific truth, and sociologists have fostered too much skepticism-social scientists must now elect to put science back at the core of society. The prospect of a society that entirely rejects the values of science is too awful to contemplate <ref type="bibr">(Collins, 2009)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General discussion:</head><p>Moving psychological science might help understand humankind's (in general) 'good' potential genes and functions of the brain-mind -. Additionally, how it was or might deviate from 'artificial environmental facts' they face within a short period (in about -the last 100-150 years), after being in use for 3.5 billion years of the naturally selected environment on earth toward more psychological issues. When we discuss the pros and cons of the new era, deviated sustainably, natural environmental facts may collapse EI. (E.g., We have many 'new' 'senses stimulants.' 'Artificial' foods and drinks, the polluted air, light, and sounds we breathe.) New lifestyle, less exercise, relaxation, etc.; addictive drugs, cigarettes, alcohol availability addiction to video, audio, etc.) compassion, sympathetic joy such as good emotions, etc. Those might greatly impact directly or indirectly human brain physiology and psychology revolutionized environment changes within a short period(about 150 years) (suddenly) after being in a natural environment of 3.5 billion years of the period for similar species of human beings with similar genomes. Prince Siddhartha renounced worldly life after his son was born. Is this just a coincidence? I believe(after) he had completed his final biology evolutionary duty of reproduction; Thereby, his mind-brain liberated him from that limiting factor much more than other leading characters (religious or scholarly) until now. Because he might have less of a polluted environment, peacefull political background, a loving and beautiful wife since his early adulthood, proper natural (and best ) nutrition (to develop brain-mind well), physical and mental exercises in his luxurious life, as many as the association of intellect people, learned lots of disciplines since childhood truth searchers, religious practitioners, teachers, enough sports, no wars, conflicts, no sophisticated SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE technology of communications, simple, serene livelihood might enhance (nurtured) his mind and activities. Asia also has good potential for cognitive and intelligent people; there may be recent human evolution, and people are different at the level of their genes <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Lahn, 2006)</ref>. I suggest that the Buddha and many thousands of followers-even very young people, including children -might have many potential genes and cognition, even more genetically evolved human beings. In addition, they became monks, so their breeding became very low, and their gene pool (including the Buddhas) may have been wiped out of the world population and in the human genome. My suggestion as his last life in the universe/es by discontinuing the brain-mind link by collapsing or neutralizing (X-UQGPC+ X-UQUPC) death completing the Buddhahood as a (happiest beingmight in the universe) human being.</p><p>'Extrinsic" signals are likely responsible for generating a large spectrum of protein activities that support complex cognitive brain function. Moreover, consciousness, plasticity, and several molecular mechanisms that contribute to neuronal diversity and dynamic diversity are generated by experience, correct tuning of neurons, wiring, and generating diverse subtypes of neurons <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Muotri &amp; Gage, 2006)</ref>. Thus, several molecular mechanisms (and their related biophysics), neuronal diversity, and software for creative programming may significantly enhance the role of self-regulated switching in EI.</p><p>The problem of self-regulated switching solves digital computers, which are the most complex machines we have built. Nevertheless, regarding the flow of information through the brain, we know (only) that there are ways of biasing the flow by mechanisms such as neuron modulation or inhibition <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abbott, 2006)</ref>. The cognitive process biasing and inhibition mechanism could explain SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</p><p>6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE MV and HMV brain-mind switching more clearly. (e.g., desire-related MV bias money to gain by theft; a well-developed person's HMV-related program may bias prevent theft and even may bias generous) Diet and exercise affect our brains just as much as our bodies, with bad diets having several deleterious effects on memory and good diets bringing benefits. Exercise probably exerts its effect on the brain by altering energy metabolism <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">(Pinilla &amp; Nemerof, 2005)</ref>. The Buddha and his students' practice of going for alms door to door (teaching and training others simultaneously) might have helped to get balanced food for Buddha and monks. According to a study, Buddha had walked approximately five km per day of Buddha-hood (other monks)( never used vehicles, except one a boat ( according to literature) and encouraged them to go alms door to door. It might have helped them get many proteins-amino acids, vitamins, minerals, etc. simultaneously and good exercise to maintain their health. TM has been linked to reduced cardiovascular disease risk factors and, in controlled trials, has reduced blood pressure <ref type="bibr">(Schneider et al. 2005)</ref> and carotid artery atherosclerosis (Arias 2006), as reviewed by Walton and colleagues. While physics and mathematics may tell us how the universe began, they are not much used in predicting human behavior because there are far too many equations to solve (Hawking, 2010). Therefore, this was an attempt to identify the mechanism of cognitive functions, their social networks, the necessary intelligence factors, and their evolution in human beings. The most profound EI, which manifested itself in the human development of this planet, might have occurred during Buddha's time. In addition, the practical contributions of institutions such as the UNO, academic institutions, journals, scientists, and psychologists will be an excellent boon for minimizing personal and social problems humankind faces toward their optimum EI and PWB for a better world. None of the empirical or conceptual challenges (even) might strike us as fatal to the theory, so future research must assess the merit of 'our' ideas and how best to extend them. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Material &amp;Methods</head><p>A highly diverse ~45 personnel have been used for the research for over thirty years. The study employed both interview and observational methods; supplementary data were obtained from many personnel while day today's informal meetings through random observation and questioned them and many personalities depicted in electronic, nonelectronic media by freely observing their behaviors. Therefore, I have had to do some thought experiments, as well. The factors studied included personal environment, behavior, self-assessment of their cognitive functions, and introspection study of me even as the researcher. In addition, I have done a theoretical experiment to find a third factor and the correlation of nature, nurture, and X-third factor; What/how is its mechanism via the intelligence/well-being evolution (+/-)? I have gone through many research findings related to my research objective on Buddhist and modern psychology, neuroscience, fundamental physics, abstract unbiased studying of human endeavors, law, arts, politics, policymaking, economics, education, and philosophy. It hypothesizes that basic teachings found in early Buddhist teachings in Theravada tradition (which ~8 million words of information in Pali text society-Pali canon, the English versions) might provide us with means to find psychological solutions efficiently ways to these problems. This has plagued humankind for centuries; comparative studies of support with scientific evidence of current research findings have disclosed these facts on fundamental humanity's ever-suffering issues.  <ref type="bibr">Davidson, R.J. et al. (2003)</ref>. Alterations in brain and immune function produced by mindfulness meditation.Psychosom.Med.65, 564-570 <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Davidson, R.J., (2004)</ref>  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Ekaggata -one-pointednessJīvitindriya -life faculty (to this theory of mine, I suppose this function might occur with the X-UGPC+ X-UQPCin a brain-mind link as ultraquantum particles Manasikāraattention Buddhist psychology refers to the five aggregates of clinging (Pancha-upadanakkhanda), the five physical and mental factors that increase craving and clinging. They also explained that the five elements constitute and explain a sentient being's person and personality (In Rawson 991, 11. p) (The Pali canon SN 22 and Bodhi (2000), p. 80</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>physical objects (five of them are physical), brain, and mind (The Buddha's teachings -6). Sound happiness causes healthy psychological development; a sorrowful, melancholic, penitent, negative attitude can be harmful. Healthy satisfaction is one of the seven factors of enlightenment, the essential quality toward the optimum development of the brain and mind, as proclaimed by the Buddha. During the negative stages (levels in the 3D graph) of EI, the mental state-level-of consciousness, thoughts, and feelings of suffering increase, and the individual might feel as if time goes slower while entering the positive stages (levels), the passing of time (mentally) becomes standard. In the higher levels of EI, time is spent unhurriedly, in tranquility, happily and well satisfied, and might have time dilation too, and a more efficient brain-mind; therefore, I suggest that each person in different clock times might not similarly feel their psychological times, as well as different people, are in the similar environment might have had different psychological time even clock time similar. A person in the 'unconscious' sleeping ( when not dreamings) stages might not feel that time flows. In other words, no or less feeling of time past. Furthermore, in real suffering, people (or other beings) psychologically times might feel relatively slower time. If somebody has developed the optimum mind potential, he is free from all complexes and obsessions, the worries and troubles that torment others. His mental health is perfect; He does not repent the past or brood over the future; He lives mindfulness in the present (The Buddha's teachings-7). The authors state that the quiet ego, as a balanced self-identity, encompasses four principal features: (1) detached awareness; (2) interdependence; (3) compassion, involving acceptance, empathy, and a desire for the cultivation of happiness; and (4) growth, including a consideration of the development of the self and others(Bauer and Wayment, 2008)    </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a) from telling lies, including unscientific/irrational communication/illegal forms (b) from backbiting and slander and talk that may bring about hatred, enmity, disunity, and disharmony among individuals or groups of people (c) from harsh, rude, impolite, malicious, and abusive language and (d) from idle, useless, and foolish babble and gossip. In brief, preventing all actions of MV about (3.1), (3.2) &amp; (3.3) as above (but engaging in select creative decisions on healthy behavioral activities toward EI and PWB.) Prevent MV from entering fresh-new-forms (c) Development of prevailing-updating-HMV (d) Attempt to obtain new-updating HMV treatments. 3.5 -A study of causes and effects-Intelligent decision-making of mindfully of the present moment and awareness of the deliberative body, the cognitive and behavioral states toward 'healthier and happier by self-learning and training to be: (a) Mindfulness of 'the input sensorial information from the body,' 'output information from the brain to behavioral actions,' and 'the cognitive information input to the central mind by rest of cognitive functions from the brain'; (b) Mindfulness of emotions (c) Mindfulness of cognitive functions and decisions of the mind (d) Mindfulness of cognitive function, cognitions (the '8-fold path', the 'healthier and happier way of the "Psychology" of the causes and effects) Engage in true Mindfulness of (a), (b) &amp; (c)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(Goetz et al.,2010).First, meditation Increases Compassionate Responses to Suffering. Second, contemplative science has documented a plethora of intrapersonal benefits stemming from meditation, including increases in gray matter density, Hölzel, (B. K., Lazar, S. W., Gard, T., Schuman-Olivier, Z., etc. 2011) positive affect (Moyer, C. A., Donnelly, M. P. W., Anderson, J. C., Valek, etc. (2011) and improvement in various mental health outcomes. Hölzel, B. K., Lazar, S. W., Gard, T., etc. (2011). SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE (c) Meditation developing (your selfless joy when you observe others' well-being) on 'sympathetic joy.' (d) Meditation evolving and maintaining tranquility even when you;--have a 'gain' or 'loss.' -will be 'honored' or 'dishonored.' -will be 'praised' or 'blamed.' -are 'healthy and happiness' or while you are '12 kinds of suffering.'</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>I</head><label></label><figDesc>suggest this eightfold treatment methodology, great mental exercise, and training/meditational process to overcome your great delusion in your brain mind for better health and happiness. (And others who are in the objective external world) The facts of suffering compared with a disease, the origin of suffering from the cause of the disease, the facts of extinction of suffering from the cure of the disease, and the (8-fold path) of treatment as medicine. (The Buddha's teaching -11) There are attractive, logical, clear, and rarest lines on thinking more accurately-scientifically! By Buddha in Kalama sutta.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>'s teaching reference -12) Buddha had already opened windows on the unconscious brain-mind system by freely associating (by central mindfulness on the present moment and scanning the MV by intelligence and creating decisions with HMV treatment) with emotions, ideas, and memories of MV; (i) It is not 'Just' repression (to Freud, it is just repression) (ii) Clear, rational, and full of self-lovingkindness creative study (iii) You can ask yourself, 'What is happening now(in my mind')? (iv) Why is this happening(in my mind)? (v) What happens to my well-being if I do this(by me)? (vi) Understanding this process as just the problems created by my own brain-mind(my brain) (vii) So, if somebody needs well-being and as much as well-being for others, should they think, '</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>As I summarize above, (a) teamwork actions and reactions and thoroughly convincing the suffering person/s that s/he will /might get relief and rewards even after his/her death may relieve suffering to the related person. (b) However, gradually, your brain tries to overcome problems biologically due to evolution's natural selection process. (c) However, MV-related mechanisms may harm real happiness. (i.e., after the death of my father, I could misbehave freely)(K. L.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE to intelligence differences and important implications for its genetic architecture and gene-hunting expeditions. (i) The heritability of intelligence increases from approximately 20% in infancy to perhaps 80% in later adulthood. (ii) Intelligence captures genetic effects on diverse cognitive and learning abilities, which correlate phenotypically by approximately 0.30 on average but correlate genetically by approximately 0.60 or higher. (iii) Assortative mating is greater for intelligence (spouse correlations ~0.40) than for other behavioral traits such as personality and psychopathology (~0.10) or physical traits such as height and weight (~0.20). Assortative mating pumps additive genetic variance into the population every generation, contributing to intelligence's high narrow heritability (additive genetic variance). (iv) Unlike psychiatric disorders, intelligence is normally distributed with a positive end of exceptional performance, a model for 'positive genetics.' (v) Intelligence is associated with education and social class. It broadens the causal perspectives on how these three intercorrelated variables contribute to social mobility, and health, illness, and mortality difference". (Plomin &amp; Deary, 2014).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Of (X+ Y+Z+) 3D of the graph E-in minus level-state-&gt; F-in minus state &gt; Gin minus level-state-On the negative side of the 3D graph (X-Y-Z-) for three examples SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE Figure legend: -EI and well-being;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>For example, Person A: The conscious mind state has achieved the highest level of EI by destroying all MVs.Person B: The state of mind during EI is relatively unlikely to revert, but he still has a few MVs.Person D: Layperson or an ordinary person whose mind fluctuates toward +/-. Person E; Mind SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(O): The numbers of HMV and MV differences are zero (because the numbers are equal). When 'E' is in front of the "D," D presents positive external stimuli toward E. E is still (-) when "D" starts, remedies for "E," E's I 1 ------→ I 2 (if there is a potential in "E" to evolve more positive) gradually might reach positive (+), including his (E) 'virtual external environment' becomes a positive.Human cognitive functions have become a highly complex diversification like a Worldwide Web or network, and someone's total well-being of brain-mind neuropsychology might be its cognitive functions. The imagination or perception level of the external 'world' is dependent on your present potential cognitive intelligence and well-being.The Buddhist relativity theory of psychology is related to 'me.'i. 'you are -truly -there (your physical existence) ii. 'You are not there (you are just an imagination figure in my cognition system) iii. Cannot say 'you are 100% there' (because in my imaginary world, I do not have 100% correct /perfect knowledge about you) iv. Cannot say 'you are 0% there' (I may have even a little knowledge, e.g., at least you are a human…etc.) The present graph EI of a person when awake, intelligence fluctuates(between + andlevels) according to the potential level of brain -hardware &amp; psychological-software evolution of the particular person. II. It depends on the strength of the challenge he faces in a decision on PWB III. It depends on the quality and quantity of present decision-making against the challenge IV. It depends on his recent and past well-being level A person's decision-making depends on the related problem-solving total level of HMV and MV (i.e., lack of relevant knowledge and intelligence level to solve the problem, understanding the latent negative frames, etc.). 'Hateful' MV (i.e., risk-seeking to himself and others). MV can spreadif the problem positively praises profit rather than in a negative frame regarding expenses. The negative information has been deliberately hidden in self-MV or influenced by another party. Even for human being-related problems, not only money or just property, etc., this also applies. For example, analyzing hundreds of marriage proposals published in papers seems largely positive (i.e., when desirable MV is arousing information emphasize, etc.) or more zero negative frames of information ( less or not mentioned unattractive facts but incorrect facts) mentioned. So generally limits intelligent decisions by bounded selecting rational programs (delusional MV, etc.).Therefore, decision-making can also be programmed by external factors. Finally, unintelligible decisions result from the total influence of activating MV against HMV, the mind's hardware, and external informational stimuli.The human brain is more complex than a human-made computer and can wire itself up without blueprints or outside support. It might happen because of infinite frame forms of neuronal connectivity paths, MV, and HMV factors of the cognitive function' Mindfulness of breathing is one of the most essential 'Buddhist exercises' to achieve higher mental levels 8-fold path-treatment SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE -like meditations methods. It might also help maintain a higher level of O2 for related brain active regions by breathing supervision of the frontal cortex.5.1 Face and Mind in EIIs there a process in secret behind 'mind and face ' (human face)? It may be one of the universal intellectual searching and merit of the actions rewarded in the journey of the biological evolution of the earth (and might happen in other worlds-if there are living beings, like on earth -as well). It depends mainly on selecting suitable partners' extreme beauty and highest intelligence capacity chosen by the highest intellectual/or handsome ( might be crucial to selecting and transferring good genomes to the following species )(Dayathilake, 2020) of beings in biological evolution. (if reincarnations occurlife after death-) The highest intellectual beings (e.g., The Buddha teachings -15) in their previous birth, maybe the cutting edge or crucial point of human biological evolution on earth. Because they are searching for and selecting a partner of the highest beauty &amp; intelligence (with less MV), it might help create next-generation with more beautiful and intelligent beings.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>record".<ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Mistler, Ben-Zeev, Carpenter-Song, Brunette, &amp; Friedman, 2017)</ref>. Some psychological, practical methods in the 8-fold path treatments(is kind of Cognitive behavioral therapeutic method psychiatric patient or any other personal below level one in a 3-D graph) to all might utilize and emphasize how vital to improving emotion;(i) Emotional self-awareness (ii) Managing emotions (iii) Harnessing emotional productivity (iv) Empathy; reading emotions (v) Handling relationship on well-being for both parties(Goleman 1995)    </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>"Seeking satisfaction in the world, monks, I had pursued my way. That satisfaction in the world I found, in such a far satisfaction, existed in the world, and I have well perceived it by intelligence (The Buddha's teachings-18). However, Buddha's teachings have been recognized as the result of indepth psychological studies on well-being. Rare in this world enjoy freedom from mental illness even for one moment, except those free from MV-klesha (The Buddha's teachings-19). Natural meditators may pay careful attention to what they want to remember. Because: The prefrontal cortex is the brain region responsible for working memory (Selemon 1995), 'Mindfulness of SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>leadership(Political, Economic, Health &amp; Education, etc.)  total decisions are more positive on the well-being of world society. In this complex global mechanism, world psychologists have a significant role in minimizing the activation of MV/&amp; prevention of MV in the leadership as well as in the world population, making scientific dialog on why/how the importance of the well-being of each &amp; every person. In addition, it will prevent the selection of harmful future leadership with cruel, barbarian &amp; irrational minded-identification &amp; treating them early compassionately and teach them how/why they should treat humanity with loving-kindness. Tremendous and genuine leadership depicts clear decisions and acts on the ten critical qualities mentioned below taught by /less activated hateful thoughts (MV) (Should be full of loving-kindness toward humanity) 8. Not/less decide MV through their behaviors (all nonviolent decision does welfare for humans)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The natural environment may have a significant role in EI's psychological well-being. For example, I could observe (and assess the self &amp; others' personal experiences) a pleasant greenish environment with less pollution &amp; humans showing much relief, less aggressiveness, and better and healthy behaviors. Furthermore, research shows that walking in nature or viewing pictures of nature can improve directed attention abilities as measured with a backward digit-span task and the attention network task, thus validating attention restoration theory(Berman et al. 2008).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>disorders. The brain and body's latent genetic and psychological background might yearn for and need a natural environment as much as possible.Lack of natural interaction with (functional cognitive system) MV may enhance secondary gene expression toward psychiatric disorders. Such biological was evolutionally unfamiliar artificial stimuli, and information may deviate or develop to remain MV. For example, even when meditating, you may get angry or uneasy for the (at least)-short term-if someone makesSENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE continuous noise. On the other hand, if it is simple, straightforward, and natural psychological well-being needs a fulfilling lifestyle; the person finds relief and much happiness while avoiding and preventing MV from activating. According to Freund's theory and ours, it may have mathematical relationships (proportions) as below. Id MV Ego PSMV Some research evidence depicts 71-76 MV qualities. Violence as a form of entertainment has existed for centuries. Unfortunately, for catharsis theory, research shows that playing violent video games increases aggression<ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Anderson et al., 2010)</ref>. Even though the catharsis theory is false, belief in catharsis still influences angry people to play violent games. (Bushman &amp; Whitaker 2010). A Neuroscience research note on "the thief within," say, and primate research shows that I sometimes suggest it is also valid for the human MV concept. A drug that quiets cravings for alcohol may also soothe the urge to steal in kleptomaniacs.(Grant et al. 2009)  Monkeys like to know the size of rewards coming their way, and, in the brain, this desire is signaled by the same dopamine neurons that signal primitive rewards like sex and food(Bromberg-Martin &amp; Hikosaka   2009).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>person/s not so well developed and should treat them compassionately at every moment as much as possible: "From the Buddhist point of view, anger is a form of suffering because the angry individual suffers as well as his or her victims. The traditional Buddhist view suffers from three main mental factors (MVs): desire, aversion, and ignorance-the dynamics of anger are conceptualized by these three mental factors and the biology of anger and aggression. Recent research</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>its). I could sincerely state that I have never met or heard even Buddhist teachings (as Tripitaka in Pali text society has had nearly 8.5 million words of ) completely/broadly understood person/s are presently living in (including myself). On the other hand, such interpretations and translations most likely might not say what the Buddha meant by his original teaching. In my observation, the PTS volumes might not present all the lessons of the Buddha in his 45 Buddhahood. At the same time, divide the Pali words (approximately 4 million) of Tripitaka text in pali by the dates (16,425 days of Buddhahood's) average mention of the word he taught per day by very few (243 words per day</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Another burning problem is drug-seeking behavior (smoking and alcohol addiction) due to interconnected MV. Neurobiology may also deviate from the MV for drug-seeking behaviors even after addiction. Diversifying the brain-mind, infection methods with MV (I further suggest that 'scam,' 'malware,' 'hacking' might also impact the human mind and behaviors ''as'' in computer function) seem more present in such computers by other persons infected with higher MV.According to the WHO, we miss millions of precious lives from our global family yearly.Therefore, psychologists have a huge role in minimizing MV and creating a better world by compassionate teaching, training, and managing (and conducting research) the psychological evolution of humankind (since childhood). Although a variety of mechanisms likely contribute to these changes, the present demonstration that mindfulness training improves cognitive function and minimizes mind wandering suggests that enhanced intentional focus may be key to unlocking skills that were, until recently, viewed as immutable (Michael D. Mrazek, Michael S. Franklin, Dawa Tarchin Phillips, etc.-2013).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. J., and Wayment, H. A. (eds) (2008). "The psychology of the quiet ego," in Transcending Self-Interest: Psychological Explorations of the Quiet Ego, (Washington, DC: American Psychological Association), 7-19.DOI: 10.1037/11771-001   Baumeister, RF; Masicampo, EJ; Dewall, CN (2009). "Prosocial benefits of feeling free: disbelief in free will increases aggression and reduces helpfulness." Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin. 35(2): 260-68. doi:10.1177/0146167208327217. PMID 19141628. Benjamin, D. J., Heffetz, O., Kimball, M. S., &amp; Rees-Jones, A. (2014). Can marginal rates of substitution be inferred from happiness data? Evidence from residency choices. American Economic Review, 104, 3498-3528. doi:10.1257/aer.104.11.3498 Berridge KC, Kringelbach ML (May 2015). "Pleasure systems in the brain." Neuron. 86 (3): 646-664. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2015.02.018. PMC 4425246. PMID 25950633. Berman M G, John Jonides, and Stephen Kaplan (2008 Dec)The Cognitive Benefits of Interacting with Nature, Psychological Science;19(12):1207-12. Bhikkhu Bodhi (2003), A Comprehensive Manual of Abhidhamma, Pariyatti Publishing SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE Bhikkhu Bodhi 2012, Kindle Locations 2232-2234. Bodhi (2000a), p. 80, The Pali canon universally identifies that Vedanā involves the sensing or feeling of something as pleasant, unpleasant, or neutral (see, for instance, SN 22) Birchwood M, Meaden A, Trower P, Gilbert P, Plaistow J. (2000); The power and omnipotence of voices: subordination and entrapment by voices and significant others. Psychol Med. 30:337-344. Bloom, P., (2006) Changing's over minds. Nature 442, 27-28 Britta K. Ho¨lzel, James Carmody,3 Karleyton C. Evans, et al. (2010) Stress reduction correlates with structural changes in the amygdala SCAN (5),11-17 Bolier, Linda; Haverman, Merel; Westerhof, Gerben J; Riper, Heleen; Smit, Filip; Bohlmeijer, Ernst (8 February 2013). "Positive psychology interventions: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled studies." BMC Public Health. 13 (1): 119. doi:10.1186/1471-2458-13-119. PMC 3599475. PMID Cloninger CR(2006 June). The science of well-being: an integrated approach to mental health and its disorders World, Psychiatry.; 5(2): 71-76 Dakwar, E., &amp; Levin, F. R. (2009). The emerging role of meditation in addressing psychiatric illness, with a focus on substance use disorders. Harvard Review of Psychiatry, 17(4), 254-267. https://doi.org/10.1080/10673220903149135 Dakwar E, Levin FR. (2009). The emerging role of meditation in addressing psychiatric illness, with a focus on substance use disorders Harv Rev Psychiatry.;17(4):254-67 Davidson RJ. (2010 Feb) Empirical explorations of mindfulness: conceptual and methodological conundrums. Emotion; 10(1):8-11.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fell in challenges [facing others MV; loss, relation/s' death, etc.]    </figDesc><table><row><cell>SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</cell></row><row><cell>6/29/23 6/29/23 6/29/23 6/29/23 6/29/23 6/29/23</cell></row><row><cell>EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</cell></row><row><cell>). 103. Dislike seeing the enlightened person/disciples 144. Phobia of life after death in suffering worlds-including animal kingdom-164. Thoughts on the necessity of (justifying) MV 187. Search in more depressed visuals 57. 58. Activate behavioral MV 104. Dislike hearing/studying scientific knowledge of PWB 145. Anger on unhappiness 165. Thoughts on the necessity of idea development on MV 188. Search in more depressed sounds</cell></row><row><cell>36. Underestimation of self 59. Hateful talks 105. Hate when others get actions of HMV 146. The desire for sensual lust * 166. Hatred of thought of unpleasant scenes 189. Search in more depressed odor</cell></row><row><cell>37. 'I am the most honorable person,' etc. 60. Not helpful toward others PBW 106. Unmethodical/irrational attention on PWB 147. A wish to engage in sensual activities * 167. Hatred of thought of unpleasant odors 190. Search in more depressed taste</cell></row><row><cell>38. Soul is independent 61. The desire for selecting/supervising sense-organ stimulators 107. Not searching scientific paths to PWB 148. The willingness to romantic related luscious * 168. Hatred of thought of unpleasant sounds 191. Search in more depressing thoughts</cell></row><row><cell>39. Homicide thinks that s/he is a hero 62. Lack of knowledge of quality and quantity of food when you eat 108. telling what is not seen as if seen (lie) 149. The desire to engage in sensual activities 169. Hatred of thought of unpleasant tastes 192. Search in more depressed touches</cell></row><row><cell>40. Aggression on self (e.g., Suicide) or others 63. Not creative for EI 109. Telling what not heard as if heard (lie) 150. Impatience to engage in sensual activities 170. Hatred of thought of unpleasant touches 193 Intention of depressed visuals</cell></row><row><cell>41. Hidden hatred 64. Think that 'Relations are immortal.' 110. Telling what you did not feel as felt by sensual organs (lying) 151. Willingness to possess eternal body-beauty * 171. Hatred of thought of unpleasant Thoughts (ideas) 194. The intention of depressing sounds</cell></row><row><cell>42. Forget/do not help (to parents/teachers, etc.) 65. Deviation of behavioral HMV 111. Cognitively unknown facts told as if known (lying) 152. Discourage the development of HMV 172. Not interested in intelligent teacher/s 195. The intention of depressing odor</cell></row><row><cell>43. Jealousy of PWB/wealth 66. Deviation of understanding HMV 112. When you tell seen facts as not seen (lying on seen facts) 153. Not obtaining fresh HMV 173. Not interested in intelligent teachings 196. The intention of depressing tastes</cell></row><row><cell>44. Stinginess 67. Planning/deciding on sensuous (laypeople may require this to a certain extent) * 113. When you tell heard facts as unheard (lying) 154. Matricide 174. Not interested in intelligent training 197. The intention of a depressing thought</cell></row><row><cell>45. Trying to hide active MV 68. Pleasure derived from thoughts of homicide 114. Other sensual observed facts tell as unobserved (lying) 155. Patricide 175. Not interested in making decisions for his/her EI 198. The intention of depressing touches</cell></row><row><cell>46. Hide your MV [when] expect again 69. Pleasure derived from thoughts of sufferings others 115. Cognitively known facts tell as unknown facts (lying) 156. Create disunity among intellectuals 176. Engaging in illegal (which are inclined MV) professions 199. Taking alcohol/dangerous drugs</cell></row><row><cell>47. Unscientific/delusions on PWB 70. Enjoying of (unlawful) sensuous perception (Above 8 MV emphasizes the scientific importance of related HMV for modern scientists, law, 157. Kill the perfect intelligent ones 177. Excessive sleeping 200. Making/trading weapons</cell></row><row><cell>48. Desire for eternity 71. Enjoying of killing perception/s order, family, social issues, etc.) as well) 158. Injuring the Buddha 178. Vision stimulating for lust * 201. Gambling</cell></row><row><cell>49. Belief in an eternal/unchanging soul 72. Enjoying suffering perception 116. Phobia of illness Buddhist literature emphasized that the above 5 MV-activated persons in the highest risk group 179. Ear stimulating for lust * 202. Anti-hygienic attitudes</cell></row><row><cell>50. Disbelief in reincarnation 73. Memories arising out of factors of sensual (MV) 117. Phobia of political leaders are definitely reincarnation in the suffering world after death. (Buddhist text mentions the definite 180. Touch stimulating for lust * 203. Fear of death</cell></row><row><cell>51. Shameless to activate MV 74. Memories arising out of factors of enjoying killing 118. Phobia of thieves risk) 181 Search for more visual pleasure * 204. Fear of decay</cell></row><row><cell>52. Fearless to activate MV 75. Memories arising out of factors of others/or self-suffering thoughts 119. Phobia of fire 159. Phobia of personals in the suffering world 182. Search for more sound pleasure * 205. You help only for your relations' well-being</cell></row><row><cell>53. Unwillingness to get advice on PWB (even if needed) 76. Memories arising out of factors on depression 120. Phobia of water 160. Social phobia 183. Search in more odor pleasure* 206. Lusty stimulated by odors</cell></row><row><cell>54. When your friend/s is activating MV, you appreciate/encourage them 77. Theft (some more phobias 121 to 141) 161. Thoughts of the necessity of anger 184. Search in more touch feeling pleasure* 207. Lusty thoughts</cell></row><row><cell>55. 'Dishonesty' 78. Sexual misconduct 142. Phobia of doing lawful activities 162. Thoughts of the necessity of stinginess 185. Search for more taste pleasure* 208. Lusty taste</cell></row><row><cell>56. Unhealthy personal relationship 79. Killing others by manipulating others 143. Phobia of punishments 186. Search in more thoughts pleasure* Etc.</cell></row><row><cell>25 28</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>It may help to settle unsettling feelings or memories by well-planned voluntary mechanisms (…...?). Therefore, it may decline involuntary feelings or memories related to MV. In this mindfulness, MV scanning by HMV may decrease potential (e.g., sexually) aggressive drives. The unconscious mind may release happiness and (also) may underlie the creation of a 'new'-more effective HMV. Understanding the relation between network state dynamics and information</figDesc><table><row><cell>SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</cell></row><row><cell>6/29/23</cell></row><row><cell>EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). Some greed-related</figDesc><table><row><cell>SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</cell></row><row><cell>6/29/23</cell></row><row><cell>EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</cell></row><row><cell>48</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Buddhism has recently converged in emphasizing developing positive states, such as excellence and everyday happiness. Rorschach and tachistoscopic research on advanced meditators suggest that advanced meditators have gained unusual mastery over states of mind not yet documented in Western psychological research on positive psychology</figDesc><table><row><cell>SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</cell></row><row><cell>6/29/23</cell></row><row><cell>EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Making life worth living; neural correlates of well-being. Psychological Sci.15, SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE Dynamics of neural recruitment surrounding the spontaneous rise of thoughts in experienced ://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2016.04.034</figDesc><table><row><cell>mindfulness</cell><cell>practitioners.</cell><cell>NeuroImage,</cell><cell>136,</cell><cell>186-196.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Fang CY, Reibel DK, Longacre ML, Rosenzweig S, Campbell DE, Douglas SD(2010 May)</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Enhanced Psychosocial Well-Being Following Participation in a Mindfulness-Based Stress</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Reduction Program is Associated with Increased Natural Killer Cell Activity J Altern Complement</cell></row><row><cell>Med.; 16(5): 531-538</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>httpsFarb NA, Anderson AK, Mayberg H, Bean J, McKeon D, Segal ZV Minding one's emotions:</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 9, 58-65. (2008)    <p>Hinton, D. E. (2012). NIH Public Access, 31(7), 1126-1132.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Where are the switches on this thing?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abbott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">440</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1113" to="1114" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shibuya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ihori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Swing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sakamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Violent video game effects on aggression, empathy, and prosocial behavior in Eastern and Western countries: A meta-analytic review</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">136</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="173" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Changes of Mind in Decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arbora</forename><surname>Resulaj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roozbeh</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wolpert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">461</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress reduction through mindfulness meditation. Effects on psychological symptomatology, sense of control, and spiritual experiences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Astin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychother Psychosom</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Studying the well-trained mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Barinaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">302</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Self-esteem in schizophrenia: the relationship between self-evaluation, family attitudes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Barrowclough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Tarrier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Humphreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gregg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Andrews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">@</forename><surname>News</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Uw-Medison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1923" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dysfunction in the neural circuitry of the emotion-a possible prelude to violence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Putnam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">289</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="591" to="594" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Buddha&apos;s Brain: Neuroplasticity and Meditation (In the Spotlight)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Signal Processing Magazine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/MSP.2008.4431873</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/MSP.2008.4431873" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Scientist Looks at Buddhism. (The Book Guild Limited</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<pubPlace>Sussex</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Consciousness, life after death and evolution of intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Senarath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-04" />
			<publisher>PsyArxiv</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Philosophy: Basic Readings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>Routledge</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuronal computations with stochastic network states</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Destexhe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Contreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">314</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">85</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal and spatial dynamics of brain structure change during extensive learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Draganski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gaser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kempermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6314" to="6321" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Winners do not punish</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dreber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fudenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nowak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">452</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="348" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A pilot study to gauge the acceptability of a mindfulness-based, family-focused preventive intervention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Duncan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Coatsworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Prim PrevSep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="605" to="623" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-08-13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spending money on others promotes happiness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Aknin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">319</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1687" to="1688" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">) Color of pleasure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ekman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New Scientist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">44</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003-05-24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ellamil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C R</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pritchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Todd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Christoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cpr.2011.07.003.Loving-Kindness</idno>
		<ptr target="L.6/29/23EVOLUTIONOFHUMANINTELLIGENCEhttps://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2011.07.003.Loving-Kindness" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Humphreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Dictionary of Buddhism</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>The Buddhist Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Rawson</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental modules on the brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Johnson-Laird</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">389</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="577" to="578" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Penn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Fredrickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kring</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Catalino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brantley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mar 6 A pilot study of loving-kindness meditation for the negative symptoms of schizophrenia</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr Res</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thinking fast and slow</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joris</forename><surname>Lammers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Diederik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">'</forename><surname>Stapel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Galinsky Psychological Science</title>
		<editor>Kahneman, D. (n.d</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Meditation acutely improves psychomotor vigilance and may decrease sleep needs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kaul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Passafiume</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sargent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Hara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1186/1744-9081-6-47</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1186/1744-9081-6-47" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Functions: BBF</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">47</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Demising reciprocal fairness by disrupting the right prefrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">;</forename><surname>Knoch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Koechin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hyafil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decisions, decisions. Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">318</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="594" to="598" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neurobiology of addiction: a neurocircuitry analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Koob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Volkow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lancet Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="760" to="773" />
			<date type="published" when="2016-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A prescription for healing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Newsweek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Krasner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Beckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Suchman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Quill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAMA</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">302</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1284" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="1993-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brain, man, make waves with claims of recent human evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">314</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1871" to="1873" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Meditation experience is associated with increased cortical thickness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lane</forename><forename type="middle">N ; W W</forename><surname>Norton &amp; Co Lazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Life Ascending: The Ten Great Inventions of Evolution</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Buddhist conceptualization and treatment of anger</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Leifer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Clin Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="51" />
			<date type="published" when="1999-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lihoreau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Process</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The underlying anatomical correlates of long-term meditation: larger hippocampal and frontal volumes of gray matter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Luders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Toga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lepore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gaser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="672" to="680" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BOLD signal in insula is differentially related to cardiac function during compassion meditation in experts vs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Greischar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Perlman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">novices. Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1038" to="1084" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long-term meditators self-induce high-amplitude gamma synchrony during mental practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Greischar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rawlings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Recard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pro.Natl.Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16369</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention regulation and monitoring in meditation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Slagter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dunne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neurophenomenology: integrating subjective experience and brain dynamics in the neuroscience of consciousness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J.Conscious.Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The association between attachment style, social mentalities, and paranoid ideation: an analog study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Macbeth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schwannauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gumley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Psychother</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Insight into intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mackintohs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">377</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="581" to="582" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Do Simple Positive Activities Increase Well-Being?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lyubomirsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Layous</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0963721412469809</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0963721412469809" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE Medical</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Malenka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Nestler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>978-0-07-148127-4</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Molecular Neuropharmacology: A Foundation for Clinical Neuroscience</title>
		<editor>McGraw-Hill SENARATH DAYATHILAKE,K. .L.</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="148" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of focused attention and cognitive monitoring in meditation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Manna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Raffone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Perrucci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nardo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ferretti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tartaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Londei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Del</forename><surname>Gratta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Belardinelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Romani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain Res Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="201029" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using meditation for less stress and better wellbeing -A seminar for GPs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Manocha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Black</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Malhi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Seidler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Aus Fam Physician</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="454" to="462" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">:41Relaxation training for anxiety: a ten-year systematic review with meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Manzoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pagnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Castelnuovo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Molinari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bmc Psychiatry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-06-02" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Positive affect and immune function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Marsland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pressman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Psychoneuroimmunology, ed. R. Ader</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="79" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mechelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Crinion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Noppeney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Structural plasticity in the bilingual brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Proficiency in a second language and age at acquisition affect gray-matter density-Nature, 431, 757</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reincarnation can save Schrödinger&apos;s cat</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Merali</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">454</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">324</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">605</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mistler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ben-Zeev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Carpenter-Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Brunette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mobile Mindfulness Intervention on an Acute Psychiatric Unit: Feasibility and Acceptability Study</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2196/mental.7717</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2196/mental.7717" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JMIR Mental Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Free will and paranormal beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mogi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00281</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00281" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Your Brain is (almost) Perfect; How We Make Decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Montague</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognition across disorders: a comparison of patients with hallucinations, delusions, and panic disorder with nonpatients</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav Res Ther</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="256" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information and redundancy: key concepts in understanding the genetic control of health and intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medical Hypotheses</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1054/mehy.1998.0728</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1054/mehy.1998.0728" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generation of neuronal variability and complexity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Muotri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Gage</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">441</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1087" to="1093" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The middle-length discourses of the Buddha: A new translation of the Majjhima Nikaya. Boston: Wisdom Naynatiloka, 198°. Buddhist dictionary -The manual of Buddhist terms and Doctrines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nanamoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bodhi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>By Buddhist Publication Society</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Trans.</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Strong Imagination; Madness Creativity &amp; Human Nature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nettle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>Oxf. Uni. Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of Compassion Meditation of Neuroendocrine, Innate Immune and Behavioral Responses to Psychosocial Stress Park</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tww</forename><surname>Pace</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Nonverbal Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="87" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schaller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Crandrall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Evolution, and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pascual-Leone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Amedi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Fregni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Merabet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The plastic human brain cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="377" to="401" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Paulsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sejnowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr.Opin.Neurobiol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">172</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age effects on gray matter volume and attentional performance in Zen meditation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pagnoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cekic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurobiology of Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1623" to="1630" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Penrose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Scientific American</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pinilla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nemerof</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New Scientist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2005-11-26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The genetics of g in human and mouse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Plomin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Review-Neuro</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Genetics and intelligence differences: five special findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Plomin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Deary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/mp.2014.105</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/mp.2014.105" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Molecular Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="98" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="2014-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to Make a Young Child Smarter: Evidence From the Database of Raising Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Protzko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691612462585</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691612462585" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do clever brains age more slowly? Further exploration of a nun result</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Chetwynd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Malnnes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brit.Jour.Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Top-Down Control of Perceptual Decision Making by the Prefrontal Cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="464" to="469" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0963721417709807</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0963721417709807" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What the Buddha taught. 125 (The Gordon Fraser Gallery Ltd</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Rahula</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Raine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Buchsbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lacasse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biol.Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">495</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The contribution of early traumatic events to schizophrenia in some patients: a traumatic neurodevelopmental model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Perry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moskowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Connolly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="345" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Dallek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">458</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009-04-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Romo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Salinas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu.Rev.Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">107</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenkranz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dalton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Dolski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Ryff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affective style and in vivo response: Neurobehavioral mechanisms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kalin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Natl Acad Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11148" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deepening psychoanalytic listening: the marriage of Buddha and Freud</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am J Psychoanal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonpharmacological cognitive enhancers -Current perspectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sachdeva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Clinical and Diagnostic Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7860/JCDR/2015/13392.6186</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7860/JCDR/2015/13392.6186" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolutionary Theory, Historical Perspective, and Current Concepts Sansone RA, Sansone LA</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sam</forename><surname>Goldstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="31" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Dec) Psychotherapy: What&apos;s Metaphysical Got to Do With It? Psychiatry</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A randomized controlled trial of stress reduction in SENARATH DAYATHILAKE</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Alexander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Staggers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">African Americans were treated for hypertension for over one year</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am J Hypertens</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="88" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="2005-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mere Visual Perception of Other People&apos;s Disease Symptoms Facilitate a More Aggressive Immune Response</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schaller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gervais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">21</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schmitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Frodl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dresel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>La Fouge`re</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bottlender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Koutsouleris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Striatal Dopamine transporter availability is associated with a productive psychotic state in drugnaı ¨veschizophrenic patients, European Archives of Psychiatry and Clinical Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">256</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="121" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuronal reward and decision signals: from theories to data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1152/physrev.00023.2014</idno>
		<idno type="PMID">26109341</idno>
		<idno type="PMCID">PMC4491543</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physiological Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="853" to="951" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b100">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimistic expectancies and cell-mediated immunity: The role of positive effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Segerstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Sephton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="448" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b101">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b102">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Common polygenic variation contributes to the risk of schizophrenia and bipolar disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shaun</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Purcell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">460</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="936" to="942" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Nature</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b103">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intellectual ability and cortical development in children &amp; adolescents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">440</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="676" to="67" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b104">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Regional brain activation during meditation shows time and practice effects: an exploratory fMRI study Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Short</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Mu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Borckardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Newberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kozel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/ecam/nem163.Epub</idno>
		<ptr target="DOI:10.1093/ecam/nem163.Epub" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b105">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Slagter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Greischar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nieuwenhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theta phase synchrony SENARATH</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b106">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">conscious target perception: impact of intensive mental training</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1536" to="1585" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b107">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A genome-wide analysis of putative functional and exonic variation associated with extremely high intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Slagter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A ; | Article</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Pedroso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kadeva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Iacono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mcgue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/mp.2015.108</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/mp.2015.108" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Human NeuroscienceFebruary |</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Molecular Psychiatry</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b108">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of psychological treatment on survival of patients with metastatic breast cancer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Spiesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lancet</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8668</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b109">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Common variant conferring risk of schizophrenia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stefansson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">460</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009-08-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b110">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intelligence and culture: how culture shapes what intelligence means, and the implications for a science of well-being Phil</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sternberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E L</forename><surname>Grigorenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trans. R. Soc. Lond. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b111">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rethinking Giftedness and Gifted Education: A Proposed Direction Forward Based on Psychological Science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Subotnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Olszewski-Kubilius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Worrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1529100611418056</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1529100611418056" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b112">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Calm and smart? A selective review of meditation effects on decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b113">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neuroscience of movement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Pockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Susan Pockett; WP Banks</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b114">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Does Consciousness Cause Behavior</title>
		<idno>978-0-262- 51257-2</idno>
		<editor>Shaun Gallagher</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">19</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b115">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The evolution of cognitive behavior therapy for schizophrenia: current practice and recent developments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Turkington</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Schizophr Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="865" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-08-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Epub</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b116">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Senarath</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b117">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Central and autonomic nervous system interaction is altered by shortterm meditation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fan</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Natl Acad Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8865" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-05-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b118">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Short-term meditation training improves attention and self-regulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pro.Natl.Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17152" to="17156" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b119">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neuroscience of mindfulness meditation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y.-Y</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hölzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Posner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nrn3916</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3916" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b120">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Buddha&apos;s Teachings 1 to 19</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Pali canon of PTS</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Pali Text Society-London</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b121">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Metaphors We Think With: The Role of Metaphor in Reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thibodeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Boroditsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b122">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0016782</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16782</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b123">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Decentering the Self?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F.-M</forename><surname>Trautwein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Naranjo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Reduced Bias in Self vs</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b124">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Other-Related Processing in Long-Term Practitioners of Loving-Kindness Meditation</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2016.01785</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2016.01785" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b125">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b126">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological and physiological characteristics of a proposed object-referral/self-referral continuum of self-awareness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Travis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Arenander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dubois</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Conscious Cogn</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="401" to="420" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b127">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Urry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Nitschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Dolski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dalton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mueller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b128">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b129">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making a life worth living: Neural correlates of well-being</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.0956-7976.2004.00686.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0956-7976.2004.00686.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="372" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b130">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Varela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Lachaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Rodriguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Martinerie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat.Rev.Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">229</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b131">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Hungry Mind: Intellectual Curiosity Is the Third Pillar of Academic Performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Vohs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Goode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stumm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Chamorro-Premuzic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691611421204</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691611421204" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">314</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="574" to="588" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The psychological consequences of money Science</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b132">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Buddhist tradition of Samatha: Methods for refining and examining consciousness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wallace</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consciousness Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b133">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b134">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wallace</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mental balance and well-being: Building bridges between Buddhism and Western psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="690" to="701" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b135">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0003-066X</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b136">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudia</forename><surname>Wallis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>2011-02-07</idno>
		<title level="m">Science of Happiness: New Research on Mood</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-01-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b137">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Review of controlled research on the transcendental meditation program and cardiovascular disease. Risk factors, morbidity, and mortality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Walton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nidich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cardiol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="262" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="2004-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b138">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Illusion of Conscious Will (PDF)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Wegener</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Merton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>978-0- 262-23222-7</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b139">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Getting a grasp on working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Wickelgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">275</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1580" to="1582" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b140">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mindfulness and psychological process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2010-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b141">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Buddhists&apos; Religious and Health Practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wiist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>St George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wayment</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Relig Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-03-25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Epub ahead of print</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b142">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE WHO Statistical Information System (WHOSIS)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">. L</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.who.int/whosis.WorldHealthOrganization" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">20</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Available at</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b143">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of meditation on physical and mental health in junior college students: a quasi-experimental study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Nurs Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b144">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rongxiang Tang2, and Jarrod A. Lewis-Peacock3 1 Brief Mental Training Reorganizes Large-Scale Brain Network Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience | www.frontiersin.org 1</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">*</forename><surname>Yi-Yuan Tang1</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Tang1</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-02" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b145">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biologic effects of mindfulness meditation: growing insights into neurobiological aspects of the prevention of depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Psychiatry Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="82" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b146">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mindfulness meditation improves cognition: Evidence of brief mental training</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zeidan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Diamond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Goolkasian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Conscious</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="597" to="605" />
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b147">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of lovingkindness meditation on positive emotions: A meta-analytic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P K</forename><surname>Chiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P S</forename><surname>Oei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">Y K</forename><surname>Leung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01693</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01693" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b148">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">L. 6/29/23 EVOLUTION OF HUMAN INTELLIGENCE</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Senarath Dayathilake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
