<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Running head: JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY The Effect of Source Reliability and Information Credibility on Judgments of Information Quality in Intelligence Analysis</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Preprint Version</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Fordham University-New York City</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Megan</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
							<email>megan.kelly@princeton.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Defence Research and Development Canada-Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Waterloo</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Waterloo</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Budescu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Fordham University-New York City</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mandeep</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dhami</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Middlesex University-London</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
							<email>david.mandel@forces.gc.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Defence Research and Development Canada-Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Running head: JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY The Effect of Source Reliability and Information Credibility on Judgments of Information Quality in Intelligence Analysis</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Information quality</term>
					<term>Information credibility</term>
					<term>Source reliability</term>
					<term>Intelligence Analysis</term>
					<term>Information evaluation</term>
					<term>Decision-making under uncertainty</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The quality of information that informs decisions in expert domains such as law enforcement and national security often requires assessment based on metainformational attributes such as source reliability and information credibility. Across two experiments with intelligence analysts (n = 74) and non-experts (n = 175), participants rated the accuracy, informativeness, trustworthiness and usefulness of information varying in source reliability and information credibility. The latter two attributes were communicated using ratings from the Admiralty Code, an information evaluation system widely used in the defence and security domain since the 1940s. Ratings of accuracy, informativeness, and likelihood of use were elicited as repeated measures to examine intra-individual reliability. Across experiments, intra-individual reliability was higher when levels of source reliability and information credibility were consistent (i.e., both either high or low) compared to when they were inconsistent (i.e., one low and one high). Results also show that trustworthiness ratings were more dependent on source reliability than on information credibility. Finally, the likelihood of using information was consistently predicted by accuracy ratings and not by judged informativeness or trustworthiness. The current findings offer insights into the ability of experts and novices to reliably use information evaluation systems for structuring human judgments about intelligence.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>particularly important to understand in high-stakes contexts such as defence and national security where intelligence professionals routinely evaluate information quality to inform critical and highly influential decisions.</p><p>The evaluation of information quality is an important precursor to making intelligence assessments that support defence and national security decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Carter, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Irwin &amp; Mandel, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">NATO, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet, 1975)</ref>. To facilitate effective information evaluation, raw intelligence (e.g., communications from informants or intercepted electronic signals) is often accompanied by explicit meta-informational attributes that provide information about the information or raw intelligence-for example, the reliability of the intelligence source. Despite the routine occurrence of judging information quality, it is unclear how information quality judgments are influenced by the consistency (or inconsistency) among the available meta-informational attributes. In the present work, we aim to better understand the various assessments made in response to two key meta-informational attributes, source reliability and information credibility, based on a widely implemented information evaluation system used in intelligence analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Information Evaluation Processes</head><p>Formal information evaluation in the intelligence and national security domain often employs the Admiralty Code or NATO System, which was developed by the British Admiralty's Naval Intelligence Division during World War II <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Hanson, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Irwin &amp; Mandel, 2019)</ref>. The North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) joint intelligence doctrine (among other organizations; <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Hanson, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Miron et al., 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr">United States</ref> Department of the Army, 1951) use the Admiralty Code for evaluating the quality of raw intelligence which is often unverified, incomplete, and/or prone to inaccuracies or biases. The Admiralty Code uses a 6 × 6 alphanumeric rating system which requires the evaluation of source reliability and information credibility independently from one another. See <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> for standards (updated NATO AJP-2.1, NATO 2016). In applying the Admiralty Code, source reliability has been linked to the confidence in the information source provided past performance levels <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Irwin &amp; Mandel, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">McDowell, 2009)</ref>. For additional context, an older standard for the Admiralty Code detailed that source reliability could range from a source that "has proved unworthy of any confidence" ('E': unreliable) to a source that is "tried and trusted" and "depended upon with confidence" ('A': completely reliable; <ref type="bibr">NATO STANAG 2511;</ref><ref type="bibr">NATO, 2003)</ref>.</p><p>The standards imply that source reliability can only be judged for sources that have been used in the past. Thus, if a source is completely novel, it is designated as "reliability cannot be judged" ('F'). In general, source reliability can be thought of as the confidence associated with a source's long-term success in providing quality information <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Irwin &amp; Mandel, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">McDowell, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">NATO, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet, 1975)</ref>.</p><p>In contrast to source reliability, the information credibility scale of the Admiralty Code refers to the probability that the information being evaluated is true. The earlier standards outlined that information credibility can range from information that "positively contradicts previously reported information" or "conflicts with the established pattern of an intelligence target in a marked degree" ('5': improbable) to information that "originates from another source than the already existing information on the same subject" ('1': confirmed by other sources; <ref type="bibr">NATO STANAG 2511;</ref><ref type="bibr">NATO, 2003)</ref>. Notably, completely novel information that "provides no basis for comparison with any known behavior pattern of a target" is classified as "truth cannot be judged" <ref type="bibr">('6';</ref><ref type="bibr">NATO STANAG 2511;</ref><ref type="bibr">NATO, 2003)</ref>. Generally, then, information credibility is based on the degree to which the information seems true, with a key factor in determining truth being confirmation from other independent sources (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Irwin &amp; Mandel, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">NATO, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet, 1975)</ref>.</p><p>Once the information has been "encoded" with the alphanumeric designations for source reliability and information credibility independently, the information and codes are communicated for subsequent interpretation ("decoding"), often by an intelligence analyst who is distinct from the encoding process. For example, if information from a source judged as "Completely Reliable" is perceived by the encoding party as "Possibly</p><p>True" in information credibility, the information would be communicated with the alphanumeric designation of "A3" for subsequent decoding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Challenges with Applying the Admiralty Code</head><p>Despite the wide practice of the Admiralty Code, challenges with using the Admiralty Code to assess and communicate information quality are evident. For example, when assigning (i.e., encoding) the alphanumeric codes, analysts or operators most often assign codes that fall along the diagonal such that source reliability and information credibility align perfectly in ordinal position (i.e., assigned codes of A1, B2, C3, etc.; <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Baker, 1968)</ref>. That is, encoders do not tend to assign inconsistent metainformational attributes such as high source reliability and low information credibility, or vice versa. Relatedly, encoders may use source reliability as a cue for information credibility and not vice versa <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Miron et al., 1978)</ref>.</p><p>These findings indicate that analysts may not be assigning source reliability and information credibility classifications independently from one another despite the instruction within the Admiralty Code to do so <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Mandel et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet, 1975</ref>).</p><p>Nevertheless, national intelligence communities commonly advise that intelligence assessments, which do share dependencies, be given independently from one another.</p><p>For instance, the Office of Director of National Intelligence advises that analysts assign probability and confidence assessments independently, even though probabilities do, in fact, put boundaries on confidence levels. For instance, an event that is judged to have a 99% chance of occurring can have at most an upper bound of 100% on a confidence interval around the estimate. Such a small room for error would be inconsistent with expressing "low confidence". Therefore, the guidance from the intelligence community that such a probability could be coupled with low confidence is ill advised, and recent research shows that analysts and non-experts alike do treat probability and confidence as related constructs . Similarly, it is unclear whether information evaluators are capable of treating source reliability and information credibility as fully independent, even if such guidance were prescriptively valid.</p><p>The research discussed thus far has focused on the unreliability of the encoding processes of the Admiralty code. However, further ambiguity in applying the Admiralty Code may be evident during the decoding process in which analysts use such metainformation to weigh the raw intelligence they receive. This issue is the focus of the current work. In past research, <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet (1975)</ref> compared the consistency of Admiralty Code interpretations across two separate tasks in US army captains. In the first task, participants selected which of two camps were more likely to be attacked provided the camps differed in source reliability and/or information credibility (e.g., Camp X: A3 vs.</p><p>Camp Y: C1). In the second task, participants assigned the probability of event likelihood for each of the alphanumeric codes involving A-E source reliability and 1-5 information credibility. If A3 was judged as more likely than C1 in the first task, and if probabilities x and y were assigned to A3 and C3, respectively, in the second task, then responses between tasks were considered consistent if x &gt; y, ambiguous if x = y, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet (1975)</ref> found that across two different tasks, response consistency was lower than expected: consistency was ambiguous or inconsistent for one-third of the cases and the vast majority of participants were inconsistent at least some of the time. These findings suggest that, at an intra-individual level, users of the Admiralty Code interpret the same meta-information inconsistently. This poses issues for downstream intelligence analysis (i.e., use of that information in making intelligence assessments) and is compatible with the idea that intelligence processes that aim to support analysts' judgments may inadvertently amplify noise (or unreliability) due to undetected ambiguities or algorithmic imprecision in how those processes should be executed <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Chang et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Mandel, 2020)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">inconsistent if x &lt; y.</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consistency among Meta-information</head><p>Multiple intelligence processes intended to facilitate formal structure in analysis procedures and increase intelligence accountability have exhibited unreliability <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Chang et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Karvetski &amp; Mandel, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Marcoci et al., 2015</ref>. For instance, in the Admiralty Code, the consistency or reliability within individuals' interpretations of the alphanumeric codes could depend on whether the meta-informational attributes of source reliability and information credibility are consistent with one another. We sought to examine how the reliability within individuals' assessments might be influenced by the agreement among source reliability and information credibility (e.g., both high source reliability and high information credibility versus high source reliability and low information credibility).</p><p>While the influence of consistency between the source reliability and information credibility on information assessment is under-explored in the context of the Admiralty Code, work in other domains suggests attribute consistency is an important factor in effective or reliable use of attributes. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Slovic (1966)</ref> examined how the use of attributes in judgments depended on attribute consistency and found that both attributes contributed to judgments if both of them agreed, but that only one of these attributes were used when they disagreed. In a similar vein, <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Miyazaki et al. (2005)</ref> tested the effect of consistency in two product attributes on the price-quality relationship for a product and found that two positive attributes (e.g., strong brand, strong warranty)</p><p>led to a clear price-quality relation for the product. When a product had both a positive attribute and a negative attribute, consumers tended to focus on the negative attribute during evaluation. Thus, individuals may opt to favor one attribute over the other in the case of disagreement. Individuals may also resort to "averaging" the attributes when receiving inconsistent information (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Lichtenstein et al., 1975</ref>).</p><p>In the current context of the Admiralty Code, <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref> examined whether consistency in the levels of source reliability and information credibility affected intra-individual reliability (i.e., test-retest) in ratings of information accuracy. They found that intra-individual reliability was directly related to attribute consistency. If attribute consistency was high (as in A1 or E5 ratings) reliability was significantly better than if attribute consistency was low (as in A5 or E1 ratings). These findings suggest that individuals may experience increased difficulty in assigning reliable judgments when presented with inconsistent attributes compared to consistent ones.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Present Research</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 10</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of Attribute Consistency on Intra-individual Reliability</head><p>A central aim of the current work was to further examine the relation between intra-individual reliability in information quality ratings and the level of meta-informational attribute consistency. Critically, we aimed to do so with improved statistical power by collecting larger samples than those in earlier work. Across two experiments, we elicited information quality ratings in response to varying levels of source reliability and information credibility. Crossing levels of source reliability and information credibility allowed for the key manipulation of attribute consistency such that information presented to individuals was either of low, medium, or high attribute consistency.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Batini &amp; Scannapieco, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Eppler &amp; Wittig, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Stvilia et al., 2007)</ref>, its trustworthiness <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Batini &amp; Scannapieco, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Nurse et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Stvilia et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr">Tan, 2007)</ref>, and the receiver's intention to use the information <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Batini &amp; Scannapieco, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Huang et al., 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Madnick et al., 2009)</ref>.</p><p>Based on the earlier work, we expected that intra-individual reliability will be positively related to the consistency of meta-information. We tested this hypothesis across three measures (i.e., accuracy, informativeness, and likelihood of use) which were assessed in two blocks in a repeated measures design (a fourth measure of trustworthiness was only collected at one time point). We thus extended the previous work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref>  </p><formula xml:id="formula_1">SAE = |p1 -p2| / Max [p1, p2, 100 -p1, 100 -p2].</formula><p>With such a measure, the SAE is a proportion of the maximum amount that it could theoretically be. A potential issue arises with this scoring rule, however.</p><p>Because SAE is a proportion of maximum possible difference, this approach can cause the disproportionate reduction of SAE near the endpoints of the scale, as the denominator depends on the observed values (i.e., <ref type="bibr">Max [p1,</ref><ref type="bibr">p2,</ref>).</p><p>Therefore, the incongruity effect on reliability observed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref> might have, at least in part, been a result of the particular choice of scoring rule. Critically, in the present research, we use a scoring rule that avoids this potential conflation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of Meta-information on Information Quality</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 12</head><p>While we expect general positive effects of source reliability and information credibility across indices of information quality as found by <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref>, another key aim in the current work was to examine how information quality measures might be differentially affected by source reliability and information credibility given previous mixed findings. <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref> proposed that information accuracy and information credibility both directly refer to characteristics of the information being evaluated,</p><p>whereas source reliability indirectly describes that information because it refers instead to the source (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Lemercier, 2014)</ref>. This proposal was indirectly supported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet (1975)</ref>, who found greater weighting of information credibility than source reliability on likelihood judgments. However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref> did not find evidence of unequal weighting of these two factors on judgments of information accuracy. In contrast, <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet (1975)</ref> found that participants' event likelihood estimates depended more strongly on information credibility than source reliability. That said, estimates</p><p>were not a direct measure of information quality in <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet (1975)</ref> as they were in <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref>, and this difference might account for the ostensible inconsistency.</p><p>It remains plausible that other quality indices encourage differential weighting. For example, given the well-documented relation between source and trustworthiness (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bertino &amp; Lim, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Dai et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gil &amp; Artz, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Nurse et al., 2011)</ref>, an assessor might weigh source reliability heavier than information credibility when assessing the trustworthiness of the information. We extended the previous work to test for differential effects of source reliability and information credibility on four indices of information quality (i.e., accuracy, informativeness, trustworthiness, and usefulness).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predictors of Likelihood of Information Use</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 13</head><p>Finally, the intent to use information represents an ultimately consequential aspect of information quality. Evaluating information quality will affect whether the analyst or consumer uses the information. Therefore, a final aim of the present research was to examine whether the rated probability of using information characterized by a particular meta-informational profile was influenced by the other information-quality measures (i.e., accuracy, informativeness, and trustworthiness). Accordingly, we assessed the relative influence of those measures across differing meta-informational profiles in an exploratory manner.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Participants were 74 intelligence analysts (n = 52 Canadian; n = 22 UK) who participated remotely using a Qualtrics survey link distributed by their managers.</p><p>Participation was voluntary, anonymous, and there was no remuneration. Sixty-two percent of the sample indicated being familiar with the source-reliability and informationcredibility scales. Demographic information was available from 45.9% of participants, (the demographics for some analysts were not reported to protect their identities). Of those reporting this information, 23.5% reported as female and the age range was 21 to 60 years (M = 35.06, SD = 9.45). The reported highest level of education attained was high school or equivalent for 5.9%, trade school (non-military) for 11.8%, undergraduate for 52.9%, and graduate for 29.4%. Fifty-three percent stated that they were civilian and 47% reported being military (all participants responded).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design</head><p>The experiment was a mixed design with one between-subjects factor (item set) and three within-subjects factors (information quality measure, source reliability, information credibility). Specifically, participants were randomly assigned to one of two experimental stimuli conditions (item set 1, item set 2; explained further below). Each participant provided ratings for each information quality measure (i.e., accuracy, informativeness, likelihood of use, and trustworthiness) as a function of both source reliability (low, medium, high), and information credibility (low, medium, high). In addition, given the varying levels of source reliability and information credibility, the attribute consistency between source reliability and information credibility also varied within-subjects. Specifically, the consistency in the levels of source reliability and information credibility could be low consistency (e.g., low source reliability and high information credibility), medium consistency (e.g., low source reliability, medium information credibility), or high consistency (e.g., low source reliability, low information credibility). As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>, both item sets included the same low-and highattribute consistency items (A5, E1; A1, E5), but different medium-attribute consistency items (Set 1: A3, C1; Set 2: C5, E3). trustworthiness, and prevalence. Next, they were shown the source-reliability and information-credibility scales, followed by an annotated sample question (see in supplementary materials).</p><p>Before advancing to the experimental task, participants had to pass two screening questions. First, they were asked to select the highest source reliability rating from a set of four: "Reliability cannot be judged (F)," "Not Usually Reliable (D)," "Fairly Reliable (C)," and "Usually Reliable (B)." Participants who provided an incorrect response were prompted to review the scales and try again. Those who failed on their second attempt were automatically screened out of the experiment. This process was repeated with a question asking participants to select the lowest information credibility rating from a set of four: "Doubtful (4)," "Possibly True (3)," "Improbable (5)," and "Completely credible (1)."</p><p>The experimental task comprised four blocks of questions about information quality. Within each block, participants were shown the six pieces of information corresponding to the condition they were randomly allocated to (i.e., Set 1 or Set 2), one at a time and in random order. For each item, participants responded to two of five questions about information quality below (determined by the block) using 100-point sliders with a starting position of 50:</p><p>1. Use: "How likely would you be to use a piece of information with this combination of reliability and credibility ratings in your analysis?" 1 [0 = Extremely unlikely, 100 = 1 For the participants in the condition that had item set 1 and question order 1, the item was actually stated unintentionally as "How likely would you be to include a piece of information with this combination of reliability and credibility ratings in your analysis?" instead.</p><p>5. Prevalence: "How likely is it to encounter a piece of information with this combination of reliability and credibility ratings?" [0 = Extremely unlikely, 100 =</p><p>Extremely likely] 2</p><p>The information quality questions were posed to participants as follows: Block 1 elicited accuracy and likelihood of use judgments; Block 2 elicited trustworthiness and informativeness judgments; Block 3 elicited prevalence and likelihood of use judgments;</p><p>and Block 4 elicited informativeness and accuracy judgments. For half of the participants, question order was reversed within blocks (e.g., Block 1: likelihood of use, then accuracy; Block 2: informativeness, then trustworthiness). Note that responses to the accuracy, informativeness, and likelihood of use questions were elicited twice during the experiment, allowing for a measure of intra-individual reliability. Between blocks, a buffer printed in capital letters and italics stated, "Note: the questions you will be asked are changing. Please read them carefully!" Participants provided 48 responses total (i.e., 4 blocks × 6 items × 2 questions). Following the experimental task, participants completed brief tasks unrelated to the current research. Finally, all participants indicated their familiarity with the rating scales, provided basic demographic information, and were debriefed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>Analyses were conducted using R version 4.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bakeman, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Olejnik &amp; Algina, 2003)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of Meta-information on Information Quality</head><p>We examined the influences of source reliability and information credibility on ratings using a 2 (Source Reliability: low, high) × 2 (Information Credibility: low, high) × 2 (Set: 1, 2) × 4 (Measure: use, accuracy, informativeness, trustworthiness) mixed ANOVA wherein item set was the only between-participants factor.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> shows, the interaction effects reflect variations in the degree of the observed effects but not in the direction of those effects. In all cases, higher source reliability and information credibility was associated with higher information quality ratings. 3 To explore whether source reliability and information credibility differed from one another in their influence on each information quality measure, we compared three pairs of items that were complementary in terms of high/low source reliability and low/high information credibility. For example, A5 (highest source reliability and lowest information credibility) was compared to E1 (lowest source reliability and highest information credibility). The same was performed for A3 versus C1 (observations from item set 1), and C5 versus E3 (observations from item set 2). information accuracy were significantly higher for E1 than A5, indicating that information credibility was weighted more heavily than source reliability [t(73) = 2.30, p = .024, d = 0.27]. However, the comparisons between A3 and C1 and C5 and E3 showed no such significant effect for accuracy ratings [ts &lt; 1, ps &gt; .599]. In fact, when comparing within item pairs (A5 vs. E1, A3 vs. C1, C5 vs. E3) in their ratings for probability of using information and degree of informativeness, there was no evidence of a significant difference. The exception to this was trustworthiness ratings, such that, in all three comparisons, the item with higher source reliability had higher ratings compared to the item with higher information credibility. That is, A5 was rated significantly more trustworthy than E1, A3 was rated significantly more trustworthy than C1, and C5 significantly more trustworthy than E3. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of Attribute Consistency on Intra-individual Reliability</head><p>To examine the effect of attribute consistency on intra-individual reliability, we computed an intra-individual reliability index using the standardized absolute error (SAE) between the first and second ratings of each question type asked twice (i.e., accuracy, use, informativeness). We did this as a function of item set and attribute consistency level. Letting p1 and p2 refer to the ratings elicited at test and retest, respectively:</p><p>If p2 ≤ p1:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">SAE = |p1 -p2| / p1</formula><p>If p2 &gt; p1:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">SAE = |p1 -p2| / (100 -p1)</formula><p>In other words, the normalizing factor was always the distance from the initial probability estimate to the limit that was in the direction of the second probability estimate. Thus, lower SAE indicates higher intra-individual reliability (a score of 0 conveys perfect reliability). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We conducted a 3 (Consistency: low, medium, high) × 3</p><p>(Measure: accuracy, informativeness, use) × 2 (Set: 1, 2) mixed ANOVA on SAE. There was a significant main effect of consistency [F(2, 144) = 10.48, p = .001, ηG 2 = .06] such that the higher the consistency, the lower SAE (i.e., the higher the intra-individual reliability). No other main or interaction effects were statistically significant [Fs &lt; 1.74, ps</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">&gt; .170].</formula><p>We further conducted polynomial contrasts for the main effect of consistency.</p><p>These analyses aimed to provide further insights into the relation between SAE as a function of attribute consistency by treating the level of attribute consistency as ordered (from low to high) and enabled us to test whether the relation of SAE by consistency level followed a linear or quadratic (or neither) function. We did this collapsing across the factors of item set and measure as there were no interactions between them and consistency.</p><p>The linear effect of consistency was significant such that as consistency  38, p = .001]. The correlation between mean SAE at for low and high levels of consistency was not significant [t(72) = 1.90, r = .22, p = .062].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 26</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predictors of Likelihood of Information Use</head><p>We regressed participants' ratings of likelihood of information use on their ratings of perceived information accuracy, informativeness, and trustworthiness for each of the four items common to Sets 1 and 2 (i.e., A1, A5, E1, and E5. Each of the four models was significant. <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 4</ref> shows the overall model statistics for the four models and the statistics for each parameter in the four models. 6 Across stimuli, accuracy ratings significantly predicted likelihood of use ratings. Additionally, when source reliability was low and information credibility was high, informativeness ratings significantly predicted likelihood of use ratings. No other relations were significant. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In Experiment 1, we replicated the positive effect of meta-informational attribute consistency between source reliability and information credibility on the reliability of analyst ratings of information accuracy shown by <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref>. Indeed, the present research demonstrated this effect in a much larger sample of intelligence analysts and across multiple indices of information quality. We also replicated the positive effects of source reliability and information credibility on ratings of information quality from previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Mandel et al., 2023)</ref>. Extending earlier work, we examined the differential weighting of source reliability and information credibility in information quality ratings and found consistent evidence only for trustworthiness ratings as more strongly influenced by source reliability than information credibility. Finally, we explored whether intent to use the information was predicted by the other indices of information quality and found that likelihood of use ratings was predicted by accuracy and not informativeness or trustworthiness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 28</head><p>In Experiment 2, we sought to examine whether the findings observed in Experiment 1 are specific to professional intelligence analysts who may have received training in information evaluation methods or whether those with little or no prior experience in information evaluation methods would show similar findings. While we do not presume that the Admiralty code itself is relevant for use in the general population, the generalizability of findings across expert and non-expert samples would indicate that general cognitive processes underlie the results. In contrast, if such findings from expert populations do not generalize to non-expert samples, it might suggest that responding in these information systems is driven by analyst training. Finally, testing the generalizability of the results from expert analysts to non-experts could be relevant for better understanding the application of systems analogous to the Admiralty Code to other areas of specialization, such as education and training, given the broad utility of properly assessing information provided meta-informational attributes such as source reliability or information credibility (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Hanson, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>We also extended Experiment 1 (and earlier work by <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. 2023</ref>  <ref type="bibr">(Erceg &amp; Bubic, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Piazza &amp; Sousa, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Shenhav et al., 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Pennycook et al., 2016</ref>. Specifically, we include the intuitive response rate and accuracy rate each in an analysis of intra-individual reliability in quality measures (i.e., those collected at two time points; accuracy, informativeness, and likelihood of use). for 21.1%, Undergraduate for 37.7%, and Graduate-Masters for 4.6% with one participant not reporting. All participants stated that they were 'civilian' and 13.1%</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>reported prior familiarity with the source reliability or information credibility scales. 7</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design, Materials, and Procedure</head><p>The design was the same as in Experiment 1 and the materials and procedure were also the same as Experiment 1 with one exception. Specifically, all participants also completed the CRT after the core task of the experiment before responding do basic demographic questions and debriefing. Two participants did not complete the CRT and were excluded from analyses involving the CRT scores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>The intuitiveness and accuracy scorings of the CRT items were performed based on earlier work such that the intuitive responses were coded with '1' with other response types coded as '0' and such that, for accuracy, correct responses were coded with '1' and incorrect responses with '0' <ref type="bibr">(Erceg &amp; Bubic, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Piazza &amp; Sousa, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Shenhav et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">cf. Pennycook et al., 2016)</ref>. Analyses were conducted in R and Greenhouse-Geisser corrected degrees of freedom and p values are reported where applicable for the within-participant factors. Analyses were not preregistered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of Meta-information on Information Quality</head><p>We examined the influences of source reliability and information credibility on ratings using a 2 (Source Reliability) × 2 (Information Credibility) × 2 (Set) × 4 (Measure) mixed ANOVA with set as the only between-participants factor. There were significant main effects of source reliability [F(1, 173) = 393.52, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .27] and information credibility [F(1, 173) = 398.41, p&lt; .001, ηG 2 = .26], such that ratings were higher when source reliability and information credibility were higher. As in Experiment 1, there were also significant interactions between source reliability and measure <ref type="bibr">[F(2.53, 437</ref>.74) = 6.84, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 &lt; .01] such that the positive effect of high source reliability (vs. low source reliability) was the largest for trustworthiness ratings and the smallest for informativeness ratings. There was also an interaction between information credibility and measure <ref type="bibr">[F(2.82, 487</ref>.33) = 3.73, p = .011, ηG 2 &lt; .01] such that the positive effect of high information credibility (vs. low information credibility) was largest for accuracy ratings and smallest for trustworthiness ratings, which was also seen in Experiment 1.</p><p>An interaction between source reliability and information credibility [F(1, 173) = 32.72, p</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 31</head><p>&lt; .001, ηG 2 = .01] revealed that the positive effect of information credibility was larger for a high-reliability source than a low one, like in Experiment 1. The interaction effects reflect variations in the degree of the observed effects but not in the direction of those effects such that higher source reliability and information credibility was associated with higher information quality ratings. No other effects or interactions were statistically significant <ref type="bibr">[Fs &lt; 1.62,</ref><ref type="bibr">ps &gt; .129]</ref>.  To examine the differential influences of source reliability and information credibility on the separate dependent measures, we compared three pairs of items that were complementary in terms of high/low source reliability and low/high information credibility as in Experiment 1 (i.e., A5-E1, A3-C1 and C5 E3). <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 5</ref> presents the results of these paired comparisons for each dependent variable. Comparing within the item pairs (A5 vs. E1, A3 vs. C1, C5 vs. E3), there was no evidence of any significant differences in ratings of accuracy, informativeness or likelihood of use [ts ≤ 1.26, ps ≥ .096, ds ≤ 0.13. The exception to this was trustworthiness ratings such that, in two out of three comparisons (A5-E1 and C5-E3), the item with higher source reliability had higher ratings compared to the item with higher information credibility. However, A3 was not rated significantly more trustworthy than C1, though it is in the numerically consistent direction as the other comparisons with A5 having the numerically higher trustworthiness rating. As in Experiment 1, we examined the effect of attribute consistency on intraindividual reliability as a function of set and consistency. Thus, we conducted a 3</p><p>(Consistency: low, medium, high) × 3 (Measure: accuracy, informativeness, use) × 2 (Set: 1, 2) mixed ANOVA on SAE with set as the only between-participants factor. We found significant main effects of attribute consistency [F(1.85, 319.59) = 24.40, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .03] such that the higher the consistency, the lower the SAE (i.e., the higher the intra-individual reliability). There was also a significant main effect of measure <ref type="bibr">[F(2, 346)</ref> = 3.41, p = .034, ηG 2 &lt; .01] such that SAE was highest for accuracy ratings and lowest for informativeness ratings. The interaction between item set and measure was also significant [F(2, 346) = 5.24, p = .006, ηG 2 &lt; .01] such that use and accuracy SAEs were numerically greater in Set 2 than in Set 1, while informativeness SAE was numerically greater in Set 1 than in Set 2. No other main or interaction effects were statistically significant [Fs &lt; 1.80, ps &gt; .160].</p><p>We conducted polynomial contrasts for the main effect of consistency collapsed across item set and measure, as in Experiment 1. Again, this was to explore SAE as a  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predictors of Likelihood of Information Use</head><p>We regressed participants' ratings of likelihood of information use on their ratings of perceived information accuracy, informativeness and trustworthiness for each of the four items common to Sets 1 and 2 (i.e., A1, A5, E1, and E5). Each of the four models was significant. <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 6</ref> shows the overall model statistics for the four models and the</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 37</head><p>statistics for each parameter in the four models. 9 Across all stimuli, accuracy ratings significantly predicted likelihood of information use ratings, and informativeness ratings predicted likelihood of use ratings in all cases except when both source reliability and information credibility were high. The fit of the models was much higher in the two reliable cases. Finally, when source reliability and information credibility were both low, trustworthiness ratings also predicted likelihood of use ratings. Note. SR = source reliability; IC = information credibility. Bold p values are statistically significant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In Experiment 2, we replicated and extended the key findings of Experiment 1 and earlier work. Specifically, we, again, found a positive effect of meta-informational attribute consistency between source reliability and information credibility on reliability of ratings of information accuracy, also replicating <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref>. As in Experiment 1, we extended previous work by demonstrating this effect across multiple indices of information quality. Novel from Experiment 1, we did so in a non-expert sample and analyzed the relation between intra-individual reliability with intuitive and accurate responding on the CRT (finding no compelling evidence for a correlation).</p><p>In addition, we replicated the robust positive effects of source reliability and information credibility on information quality ratings from both Experiment 1 and <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref>. Similar to Experiment 1, we found evidence only for trustworthiness ratings as more strongly determined by source reliability than by information credibility when examining differential influences of source reliability versus information credibility across information quality ratings. Finally, when testing whether the intent to use information was predicted by other information quality indices, we found likelihood of information use ratings were predicted by accuracy ratings, as in Experiment 1. However, we also found some evidence that likelihood of information use ratings was predicted by informativeness ratings (although not when source reliability and information credibility were both high) -only when source reliability and information credibility were both low did we find a clear effect of trustworthiness on likelihood of use ratings. Thus, this latter result appears to be bounded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Expert assessments require disparate sources of information, and information naturally varies in quality for many reasons. Accordingly, information is often encoded with meta-informational attributes cueing information quality <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Irwin &amp; Mandel, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Those attributes, however, may conflict with each other and if they do, the inferences that people draw from them about information quality may become less reliable, as earlier work suggests <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Lichtenstein et al., 1975;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Slovic, 1966)</ref>.</p><p>Across two experiments, we observed that the intra-individual reliability of information quality judgments was directly related to the consistency between levels of source reliability and information credibility. These findings conceptually replicate those of <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mandel et al. (2023)</ref>  The relation between meta-informational attribute consistency and judgment reliability could reflect uncertainty in how individuals think they should assess inconsistent information, more generally. Although we did not collect direct measures of uncertainty, a plausible hypothesis is that the more uncertain individuals are in their responding, the more varied their responses will be upon retesting. Future work could examine participants' confidence levels or response times when tasked with mapping meta-information of varying degrees of inconsistency onto information quality measures.</p><p>Exploration of the confidence-reliability relation would appear to be supported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Koriat's (2024)</ref> recent suggestion that one's confidence level in a given response reflects the general replicability of that response. That is, we would expect levels of uncertainty or confidence level in one's rating of information quality to also be predictive of the reliability or consistency within ratings.</p><p>Our findings also extend the earlier work by testing how the meta-informational attributes of source reliability and information credibility might be differentially weighted when considering each information quality measure. Only trustworthiness ratings differentially weighted these attributes, giving more weight to source reliability. The lack of evidence for unequal weighting of source reliability and information credibility for other information quality measures raises prescriptive questions. Given that information credibility directly pertains to the information quality, whereas source reliability is an indirect indicator, one might have expected the former to be weighted more heavily, and some might argue that it should. Perhaps in a more naturalistic setting, reasoning for differential weighting between source reliability and information accuracy might be salient in response to key contextual information at that time. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet (1975)</ref> presented participants with plausible raw intelligence and found that information credibility (or "accuracy" in their version) was weighted more heavily than source reliability when judging event likelihood. <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Samet's (1975)</ref> inclusion of plausible raw intelligence could have introduced additional contextual interactions not present in the current work. The current findings suggest that "all else being equal", source reliability and information credibility are also treated "equal" when judging certain aspects of information quality and that this is true of experts and non-experts alike.</p><p>A final question we addressed was whether accuracy, informativeness, and/or trustworthiness predicted intent to use that information (i.e., the rated probability of using that information) given that, in practice, intent to use the information is arguably most consequential in terms of information quality indices. That is, if an analyst decides not to use the information, it cannot influence the analyst's substantive assessment.</p><p>Across both experiments, accuracy ratings significantly predicted likelihood of use regardless of the levels of source reliability or information credibility (low vs. high). The other indices of information quality did not consistently predict likelihood of use ratings across experiments-although in Experiment 2, there was some evidence that informativeness also predicted likelihood of use. While information quality indices might be similarly affected by source reliability and information credibility, these results suggest that accuracy, in particular, is predictive of one's intention to use the information. Thus, accuracy appears to be an essential factor in opting whether to use information and earlier works focusing on eliciting accuracy judgments likely indirectly capture the likelihood of using information. These findings suggest that it may therefore be beneficial to focus on methods for reliably assessing information accuracy, and that intelligence doctrine might do well to be explicit about the connection between judged information accuracy and decision-making regarding information use or disuse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Constraints on generality</head><p>Like in any research, there are limits to generality. In the current work, we examined a single information evaluation system and, for experimental control, did not incorporate contextual information along with the meta-informational attributes that would typically accompany the alphanumeric coding in day-to-day administration. This could potentially affect the generality of the present findings. We are also aware that being an experienced intelligence analyst does not necessarily imply one is also an expert in applying the Admiralty Code to effectively manage complex situations. Indeed, this could explain why performance was similar across the two samples (of experts and novices). Future work could focus on isolating a particularly expert sample (e.g., human</p><p>intelligence analysts who interact with such meta-information on a regular basis), though collecting an adequately powered sample of such individuals is nontrivial.</p><p>Despite the points we raise above, the generality of the current findings is expected to be higher than in previous relevant work for three main reasons. First, the task that participants completed was based on a real-world information evaluation system (the Admiralty Code) which has been in use for the better half of a century and across many domains including intelligence and national security. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Transparency and openness:</head><p>The data, analyses code, and supplementary materials for Experiments 1 and 2 are all available at https://bit.ly/3TCq5WE.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. Annotated Sample Question</head><p>Below is a sample question page.</p><p>As you can see, you will be presented with the header portion of a fictitious intelligence report, where only the source reliability and information credibility have remained visible.</p><p>You must then answer each question (typically two per page) by moving the slider under each question until it reflects your answer to that question.</p><p>The slider covers the probability scale expressed in percentage ratings, from 0-100. As you move the slider it will show you the exact numerical value from 0 to 100 associated with the slider position. Select the value that best represents your response, then move on to the next question. Once both questions are answered, click on the red arrow icon at the bottom right corner of the page to proceed.</p><p>The two sample questions below ask you to estimate likelihoods. In the context of the first (top) question in the example:</p><p>The value 0 means you are absolutely unlikely to use a piece of information with this rating combination.</p><p>The value 50 means you're absolutely uncertain you would use it.</p><p>The value 100 means you're absolutely likely to use a piece of information with this rating combination.</p><p>The same general rule applies to using sliders to express your responses to each question throughout the study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. Supplementary Figures</head><p>Experiment 1: Information Quality by SR, IC, and IQM <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S1</ref>.</p><p>Grand mean information quality as a function of source reliability (SR) and information credibility (IC) in Experiment 1 as a function of information quality measure (IQM). Error bars represent 95% bootstrap bias corrected and accelerated CIs using 10,000 samples.</p><p>Experiment 1: Mean SAE by Consistency, Set, and IQM <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure S3</ref>. Mean SAE by consistency, set, and information quality measure (IQM) in Experiment 1. Error bars are bias corrected and accelerated 95% confidence intervals using 10,000 bootstrap samples.</p><p>Experiment 2: Mean SAE by Consistency, Set, and IQM <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure S4</ref>. Mean SAE by consistency, set, and information quality measure (IQM) in Experiment 2. Error bars are bias corrected and accelerated 95% confidence intervals using 10,000 bootstrap samples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. Predictors of Expected Information Use -Excluding Influential Points</head><p>Experiment 1: Influential observations removed <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table S2</ref>.</p><p>Models fitted for each stimulus and predictor of use ratings in Experiment 1 without influential observations</p><p>Note. SR = source reliability; IC = information credibility. Bold p values are statistically significant. Influential points were determined by plots of Cook's distance and leverage using influence_plot from the reglass package <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Petrie, 2020)</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimulus and predictor</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of Meta-information on Information Quality</head><p>We examined the influences of source reliability and information credibility on ratings using a 2 (Source Reliability: low, high) × 2 (Information Credibility: low, high) × 2 (Set: 1, 2) × 5 (Measure: use, accuracy, informativeness, trustworthiness, prevalence) mixed ANOVA wherein item set was the only between-participants factor. There were main effects of source reliability [F(1, 72) = 422.94, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .35] and information credibility [F(1, 72) = 392.69, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .31] such that ratings were higher when source reliability and information credibility were higher. There was also a main effect of information quality measure [F(3.05, 219.75) = 3.86, p = .005, ηG 2 = .01] such that ratings were lowest for prevalence and highest for informativeness. There was a significant interaction between source reliability and measure [F(2.55, 183.93) = 71.37, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .13] such that the positive effect of high source reliability (vs. low source reliability) on ratings was largest for trustworthiness rand smallest for prevalence. There was also an interaction between information credibility and measure <ref type="bibr">[F(2.95, 212.11) =</ref> 78.06, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .14] such that the positive effect of high information credibility (vs. low information credibility) on ratings was largest for accuracy and smallest for prevalence. Finally, source reliability and information credibility also interacted [F(1, 72) = 27.34, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .02] such that the positive effect of information credibility was significantly larger for a high reliability source than a low one. No other effects or interactions were statistically significant [Fs &lt; 1.48, ps &gt; .228].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 66</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of Meta-information on Information Quality</head><p>We examined the influences of source reliability and information credibility on ratings using a 2 (Source Reliability) × 2 (Information Credibility) × 2 (Set) × 5 (Measure) mixed ANOVA with set as the only between-participants factor. There were significant main effects of source reliability [F(1, 173) = 389.45, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .21] and information credibility [F(1, 173) = 372.12, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .20], such that ratings were higher when source reliability and information credibility were higher. There were also significant interactions between source reliability and measure [F(3.01, 520.47) = 28.20, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .02] such that the positive effect of high source reliability (vs. low source reliability) on ratings was largest for trustworthiness ratings and smallest for prevalence. There was also an interaction between information credibility and measure <ref type="bibr">[F(3.35, 578</ref>.81) = 34.58, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .03] such that the positive effect of high information credibility (vs. low information credibility) on ratings was largest for accuracy and smallest for prevalence. Finally, an interaction between source reliability and information credibility [F(1, 173) = 41.62, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .01] revealed that the positive effect of information credibility was larger for a high-reliability source than a low one. No other effects or interactions were statistically significant [Fs &lt; 1.16, ps &gt; .320].</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>: "How likely is a piece of information with this combination of reliability and credibility ratings to be accurate?" [0 = Extremely unlikely, 100 = Extremely likely] 3. Informativeness: "How informative would a piece of information with this combination of reliability and credibility ratings be?" [0 = Not at all informative, 100 = Extremely informative] 4. Trustworthiness: "How trustworthy do you think a piece of information with this combination of reliability and credibility ratings would be?" [0 = Not at all trustworthy, 100 = Extremely trustworthy]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Mean information quality rating (i.e., averaged across accuracy, informativeness, trustworthiness and likelihood of use) as a function of source reliability and information credibility in Experiment 1. Error bars represent 95% bootstrap bias corrected and accelerated CIs using 10,000 samples.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>increased, error in reliability (SAE) decreased [estimate = -0.08, SE = 0.02, t(146) = 4.48, p &lt; .001]. The quadratic effect was not significant [estimate = -0.02, SE = 0.03, t(146) = 0.84, p = .398]. Figure 2 presents mean SAE and 95% bootstrap confidence intervals according to each level of attribute consistency within each item set for Experiment 1 and depicts how accuracy, informativeness, and likelihood of use ratings were well approximated by the linear effect of attribute consistency in the case of each item set. 5</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Mean standardized absolute error (SAE) by consistency and set in Experiment 1. Error bars are bias corrected and accelerated 95% bootstrap CIs using 10,000 samples. To examine the relation between an individual's mean SAE across levels of consistency, we conducted three separate correlations (i) the mean SAE at low consistency with the mean SAE at medium consistency, (ii) the mean SAE at medium consistency with the mean SAE at high consistency, and (iii) the mean SAE at low consistency with the mean SAE at high consistency. Mean SAEs correlated positively between low and medium levels of consistency [t(72) = 4.25, r = .45, p &lt; .001], and correlated positively between medium and high levels of consistency [t(72) = 3.50, r = .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>) by exploring how potentially relevant individual differences in cognition may influence the reliability of individuals' responses. Specifically, individuals who are more likely answer intuitively--or less likely to answer accurately--might be less reliable or reflective in their responses, particularly as attribute consistency decreases. We provide a test of this general idea by considering both the intuitive response rate and overall accuracy on the Cognitive Reflection Task (CRT; Frederick, 2005) as proximate indicators of less reflective responding</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Experiment 2 was approved by Defence Research and Development Canada Human Research Ethics Committee. Data was collected from 175 participants using Qualtrics Panels. Participants were sampled from Canada and the US and were required to have English as their first language. They were prohibited from completing the experiment on a smartphone. The sample was 62.9% female and sample age ranged from of 18 to 60 years (M = 40.26, SD = 12.84). The highest level of education attained reported was high school or equivalent for 36.0%, trade school (non-military)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3presents the mean values across the information quality measures (i.e., accuracy, informativeness, trustworthiness and likelihood of use) as a function of source reliability and information credibility (see the supplementary materials for the analogous figures disaggregated by measure).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Mean information quality rating (i.e., averaged across accuracy, informativeness, trustworthiness and likelihood of use) as a function of source reliability JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 32 and information credibility in Experiment 2. Error bars are bias corrected and accelerated 95% bootstrap CIs using 10,000 samples.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>function of attribute consistency by treating the level of attribute consistency as ordered JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 35 (from low to high). More specifically, this analysis permitted a test of whether the relation between SAE and attribute consistency level was linear or quadratic (or neither or both). The linear effect of consistency was significant such that as consistency increased, SAE decreased [estimate = -0.10, SE = 0.02, t(348) = 6.89, p &lt;.001]. The quadratic effect was not significant [estimate = -0.03, SE = 0.03, t(348) = 1.07, p = .284]. Figure 4 presents mean SAE and 95% bootstrap confidence intervals according to each level of consistency within each set for Experiment 2 and depicts how accuracy, informativeness, and likelihood of use ratings were well approximated by the linear effect of attribute consistency in the case of each item set. 8</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Mean standardized absolute error (SAE) as a function of consistency and set in Experiment 2. Error bars are bias corrected and accelerated 95% bootstrap CIs using 10,000 samples. Like in Experiment 1, we examined the correlations between mean SAE and levels of consistency within participants. That is, we conducted three separate correlations as follows: (i) the mean SAE at low consistency with the mean SAE at medium consistency, (ii) the mean SAE at medium consistency with the mean SAE at high consistency, and (iii) the mean SAE at low consistency with the mean SAE at high consistency. In all three cases, the mean SAEs correlated positively between the two levels of consistency. Specifically, mean SAEs correlated positively between low and medium levels of consistency [t(173) = 7.73, r = .51, p &lt; .001], correlated positively between medium and high levels of consistency [t(173) = 4.21, r = .30, p &lt; .001], and correlated positively between low and high levels of consistency [t(173) = 3.24, r = .24, p = .001].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and extend that work in multiple respects. First, we showed that the effect of attribute consistency on judged information quality extends to multiple indices of quality including not only information accuracy (which Mandel et al. examined), but also the information's judged informativeness and likelihood of being used. Second, we observed similar consistency-reliability results among professional analysts (Experiment 1) and non-experts (Experiment 2), suggesting that both groups judge similarly despite differing in formal intelligence training, including with respect to the Admiralty Code. Third, reliability estimates tended to correlate across levels of attribute consistency in both experiments. Taken together, the aforementioned findings suggest that there are stable individual differences in the ability to fuse information from multiple attributes. Future work could examine the impact of other potentially relevant individual differences (e.g., need for cognition, conscientiousness) as well as the promise of more structured judgment elicitation methods on the assessment of information quality. For instance, Irwin and Mandel (2019) outlined a list of questions that analysts might routinely ask themselves when conducting information evaluation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Second, Experiment 2 was specifically designed as a generalizability test (i.e., from an expert sample to a non-expert sample) comprising a large sample collected from a general online pool and the results across experiments were similar in their qualitative results. Third, where possible, samples were diverse in their demographics including sex, age, educational attainment, and expertise (i.e., professional analysts in Experiment 1, general online sample in Experiment 2).ImplicationsIn light of the current findings, we might recommend considering how to reduce ambiguity during application of the Admiralty Code. Inconsistent attributes such as those explored in the context of the current work contribute ambiguity to the intelligence production process and, thus, pose several risks to subsequent communication of intelligence assessments (e.g., presence of Russian military forces in Transnistria, Moldova in 6 months) and decision-making (e.g., NATO response to increased Russian forces in Transnistria). One potential way to reduce ambiguity in the Admiralty Code (particularly in response to the unreliability in responses during inconsistent levels of source reliability and information credibility) might be an evidence-based ranking system that considers, together, the combinations across both dimensions. While each source reliability and information credibility dimension are to be assigned independently, the combination of both attributes could yield a consistent ranking of the information. For example,<ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Icard (2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Icard ( , 2024</ref> proposes a 3 (Honesty of Source: Honest vs. Imprecise vs.Dishonest) × 3 (Truth of Content: True vs. Indeterminate vs. False) matrix wherein the nine categorizations are qualitatively ranked. The effectiveness of this and alternative proposals could inform next-generation models for information evaluation. Further research is needed to determine the feasibility and performance of such models, along with other potential points of improvement within intelligence practices.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 . NATO AJP-2.1 Source Reliability and Information Credibility Scales Reliability of the collection capability Credibility of the information</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>A Completely reliable</cell><cell>1 Completely credible</cell></row><row><cell>B Usually reliable</cell><cell>2 Probably true</cell></row><row><cell>C Fairly reliable</cell><cell>3 Possibly true</cell></row><row><cell>D Not usually reliable</cell><cell>4 Doubtful</cell></row><row><cell>E Unreliable</cell><cell>5 Improbable</cell></row><row><cell>F Reliability cannot be judged</cell><cell>6 Truth cannot be judged</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Item rated from Code</cell><cell>Set</cell><cell>Source Reliability (SR): A-E</cell><cell>Information Credibility (IC): 1-5</cell><cell>SR-IC attribute Consistency</cell></row><row><cell>A1</cell><cell>1 and 2</cell><cell>High (A)</cell><cell>High (1)</cell><cell>High</cell></row><row><cell>E5</cell><cell>1 and 2</cell><cell>Low (E)</cell><cell>Low (5)</cell><cell>High</cell></row><row><cell>A5</cell><cell>1 and 2</cell><cell>High (A)</cell><cell>Low (5)</cell><cell>Low</cell></row><row><cell>E1</cell><cell>1 and 2</cell><cell>Low (E)</cell><cell>High (1)</cell><cell>Low</cell></row></table><note>Item characteristics by set in Experiments 1 and 2Human Research Ethics Committee. At the start of the experiment, participants were informed that they would be judging pieces of information classified as TOP SECRET along different dimensions, including accuracy, likelihood of use, informativeness,</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3.1. For the relevant withinparticipants variables for analysis of variance or covariance (ANOVA or ANCOVA, respectively) ("ez"; Lawrence, 2016), Greenhouse-Geisser corrected degrees of freedom and p values are reported where applicable (i.e., whenever Mauchly's test for sphericity was significant). For any regression analyses conducted ("stats" package; R</figDesc><table><row><cell>Core Team, 2023), multicollinearity, heteroscedasticity and normality of residuals were</cell></row><row><cell>all checked using the vif ("car" package; Fox &amp; Weisberg, 2019), bptest ("lmtest"</cell></row><row><cell>package; Zeileis &amp; Hothorn, 2002) and qqnorm ("stats" package; R Core Team, 2023)</cell></row><row><cell>functions respectively. Effect sizes from ANOVAs are generalized eta squared, ηG 2 ,</cell></row><row><cell>which is more comparable across within-and between-participant designs and are</cell></row><row><cell>expected to be smaller than partial eta squared in repeated-measures designs with</cell></row><row><cell>multiple factors</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>There were main effects of source reliability [F(1, 72) = 562.06, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .51] and information credibility [F(1, 72) = 490.91, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .48] such that ratings were higher when source reliability and information credibility were higher. There was also a main effect of information quality measure [F(2.60, 187.33) = 4.43, p = .005, ηG 2 = .01] such that ratings were lowest for the accuracy measure and highest for informativeness. There was a significant interaction between source reliability and measure [F(2.58, 186.03) = 23.64, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .04] such that the positive effect of high source reliability (vs. lowJUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 19source reliability) on ratings was largest for trustworthiness and smallest for informativeness. There was also an interaction between information credibility and measure[F(2.68, 192.91) = 15.38, p &lt; .001, ηG 2 = .03] such that the positive effect of high information credibility on ratings (vs. low information credibility) was largest for accuracy and smallest for trustworthiness. Finally, source reliability and information credibility also interacted [F(1, 72) = 30.43, p = .001, ηG 2 = .03] such that the positive effect of information credibility was significantly larger for a high reliability source than a low one. No other effects or interactions were statistically significant [Fs &lt; 1.55, ps &gt;</figDesc><table /><note>.216]. Importantly, as</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>presents the results of these paired comparisons for each dependent variable. Comparing A5 and E1, ratings for JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY | 21</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 3 . Effect of source-reliability/information-credibility trade-offs on mean information quality measures in Experiment 1.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Stimuli pair and measure</cell><cell>Mean (SD)</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>df</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>Cohen's d</cell></row><row><cell>A5 -E1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Accuracy</cell><cell>MA5 = 39.11 (24.15) ME1 = 49.07 (23.76)</cell><cell>2.30*</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>.024</cell><cell>0.27</cell></row><row><cell>Use</cell><cell>MA5 = 42.55 (24.77) ME1 = 45.42 (24.75)</cell><cell>0.79</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>.430</cell><cell>0.09</cell></row><row><cell>Informativeness</cell><cell>MA5 = 47.36 (23.92) ME1 = 52.12 (21.86)</cell><cell>1.38</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>.172</cell><cell>0.16</cell></row><row><cell>Trustworthiness</cell><cell>MA5 = 60.76 (23.85) ME1 = 35.53 (24.04)</cell><cell>6.17***</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell><cell>0.72</cell></row><row><cell>A3 -C1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Accuracy</cell><cell>MA3 = 67.51 (15.73) MC1 = 66.49 (15.52)</cell><cell>0.41</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>.677</cell><cell>0.07</cell></row><row><cell>Use</cell><cell>MA3 = 71.83 (16.71) MC1 = 67.77 (17.46)</cell><cell>1.61</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>.117</cell><cell>0.27</cell></row><row><cell>Informativeness</cell><cell>MA3 = 70.26 (11.62) MC1 = 68.91 (10.04)</cell><cell>0.54</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>.596</cell><cell>0.09</cell></row><row><cell>Trustworthiness</cell><cell>MA3 = 77.11 (11.55) MC1 = 65.77 (14.44)</cell><cell>3.77**</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>.001</cell><cell>0.64</cell></row><row><cell>C5 -E3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Accuracy</cell><cell>MC5 = 32.15 (17.18) ME3 = 33.05 (13.61)</cell><cell>0.27</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>.786</cell><cell>0.04</cell></row><row><cell>Use</cell><cell>MC5 = 38.03 (21.21) ME3 = 34.39 (21.68)</cell><cell>1.09</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>.282</cell><cell>0.17</cell></row><row><cell>Informativeness</cell><cell>MC5 = 40.00 (19.15) ME3 = 42.21 (20.84)</cell><cell>0.66</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>.511</cell><cell>0.11</cell></row><row><cell>Trustworthiness</cell><cell>MC5 = 41.72 (16.40) ME3 = 27.59 (17.34)</cell><cell>4.19**</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>&lt; .001</cell><cell>0.67</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 4 . Models fitted for each stimulus and predictor of use likelihood ratings for Experiment70) = 23.10, p &lt; .001, R 2 Adj. = .48</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Stimulus, Model fit, and predictor</cell><cell>b</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>β</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>p</cell></row><row><cell>A1 (high SR, high IC):</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">F(3, Accuracy 0.80</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>6.77</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Informativeness -0.13</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>-0.11</cell><cell>1.27</cell><cell>.208</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Trustworthiness 0.13</cell><cell>0.22</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell>0.57</cell><cell>.573</cell></row><row><cell>A5 (high SR, low IC):</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>F(3, 70) = 14.0, p &lt; .001, R 2</cell><cell>Adj. = .35</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Accuracy 0.50</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>0.48</cell><cell>4.59</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Informativeness 0.15</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell>1.45</cell><cell>.151</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Trustworthiness 0.17</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>0.17</cell><cell>1.60</cell><cell>.113</cell></row><row><cell>E1 (low SR, high IC):</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>F(3, 70) = 14.0, p &lt; .001, R 2</cell><cell>Adj. = .35</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 5 . Effect of source-reliability/information-credibility trade-offs on mean information quality measures in Experiment 2</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Stimuli pair and measure</cell><cell>Mean (SD)</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>df</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>Cohen's d</cell></row><row><cell>A5 -E1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Accuracy</cell><cell>MA5 = 50.64 (27.89) ME1 = 52.62 (27.81)</cell><cell>0.69</cell><cell>174</cell><cell>.490</cell><cell>0.05</cell></row><row><cell>Use</cell><cell>MA5 = 47.98 (27.65) ME1 = 48.47 (28.46)</cell><cell>0.20</cell><cell>174</cell><cell>.844</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>Informativeness</cell><cell>MA5 = 48.62 (28.29) ME1 = 53.18 (28.92)</cell><cell>1.67</cell><cell>174</cell><cell>.096</cell><cell>0.13</cell></row><row><cell>Trustworthiness</cell><cell>MA5 = 57.04 (28.75) ME1 = 45.95 (29.09)</cell><cell>3.71</cell><cell>174</cell><cell>&lt; .001</cell><cell>0.28</cell></row><row><cell>A3 -C1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Accuracy</cell><cell>MA3 = 68.45 (18.07) MC1 = 66.70 (18.07)</cell><cell>0.73</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>.469</cell><cell>0.08</cell></row><row><cell>Use</cell><cell>MA3 = 68.08 (18.90) MC1 = 65.36 (18.65)</cell><cell>1.06</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>.292</cell><cell>0.11</cell></row><row><cell>Informativeness</cell><cell>MA3 = 69.01 (19.34) MC1 = 69.64 (18.52)</cell><cell>0.27</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>.791</cell><cell>0.03</cell></row><row><cell>Trustworthiness</cell><cell>MA3 = 69.76 (20.15) MC1 = 66.44 (18.99)</cell><cell>1.26</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>.210</cell><cell>0.13</cell></row><row><cell>C5 -E3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Accuracy</cell><cell>MC5 = 42.29 (25.08) ME3 = 41.53 (24.78)</cell><cell>0.28</cell><cell>86</cell><cell>.781</cell><cell>0.03</cell></row><row><cell>Use</cell><cell>MC5 = 38.94 (25.92) ME3 = 37.83 (25.81)</cell><cell>0.41</cell><cell>86</cell><cell>.682</cell><cell>0.04</cell></row><row><cell>Informativeness</cell><cell>MC5 = 43.40 (26.89) ME3 = 44.94 (27.51)</cell><cell>0.63</cell><cell>86</cell><cell>.531</cell><cell>0.07</cell></row><row><cell>Trustworthiness</cell><cell cols="2">MC5 = 47.23 (24.21) ME3 = 35.15 (27.38) 4.31</cell><cell>86</cell><cell>&lt; .001</cell><cell>0.46</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 6 . Models fitted for each stimulus and predictor of use likelihood ratings in Experiment</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Stimulus, model fit, and predictor</cell><cell>B</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>β</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>p</cell></row><row><cell>A1 (high SR, high IC):</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">F(3, 171) = 161.5, p &lt; .001, R 2</cell><cell>Adj. = .73</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Accuracy 0.78</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>0.77</cell><cell>16.53</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Informativeness 0.04</cell><cell>0.06</cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell>0.74</cell><cell>.463</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Trustworthiness 0.05</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>0.66</cell><cell>.510</cell></row><row><cell>A5 (high SR, low IC):</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>F(3, 171) = 23.8, p &lt; .001, R 2</cell><cell cols="2">Adj. = .28</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Accuracy 0.35</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.34</cell><cell>4.78</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Informativeness 0.31</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.31</cell><cell>4.82</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Trustworthiness 0.03</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>0.41</cell><cell>.681</cell></row><row><cell>E1 (low SR, high IC):</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>F(3, 171) = 16.8, p &lt; .001, R 2</cell><cell cols="2">Adj. = .21</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Accuracy 0.29</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.29</cell><cell>3.96</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Informativeness 0.24</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.24</cell><cell>3.29</cell><cell>.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Trustworthiness 0.10</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>.210</cell></row><row><cell>E5 (low SR, low IC):</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">F(3, 171) = 154.9, p &lt; .001, R 2</cell><cell>Adj. = .73</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Accuracy 0.67</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>0.65</cell><cell>12.62</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Informativeness -0.18</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>-0.18</cell><cell>2.36</cell><cell>.020</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Trustworthiness 0.41</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.41</cell><cell>5.21</cell><cell>&lt;.001</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Although we collected prevalence ratings (see question wordings below), we opted to exclude prevalence as a dependent measure of interest because, upon reflection, we did not consider it to be an indicator of information quality-a key focus in our investigation. Therefore, prevalence ratings results are not discussed, although they are available in the Supplementary Materials for the relevant key main analyses (the results were qualitatively the same).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">The supplementary materials present figures analogous toFigure 1that are disaggregated by dependent measure.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Note that extreme values of 100 or 0 for ratings were adjusted to 99 and 1, respectively, to avoid undefined values.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">The analogous means and 95% CIs as a function of dependent measure are presented in the supplementary materials</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Results were qualitatively the same when excluding potentially influential observations and participants with potentially influential observations (identified with influence_plot() from the regclass package; Petrie, 2020), see analogous results for these analyses in the Supplementary Materials.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">The rate of prior familiarity might be inflated if participants interpreted prior familiarity as experience with similar constructs in other studies (i.e., not prior familiarity with the NATO Admiralty Code specifically).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">The analogous means and 95% CIs as a function of dependent measure are presented in the supplementary materials.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">Results were qualitatively the same when excluding potentially influential observations and participants with potentially influential observations (identified with influence_plot() from the regclass package; Petrie, 2020), see analogous results for these analyses in the Supplementary Materials.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments:</head><p>We thank Daniel Irwin for his research assistance. This research also contributes to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization System Analysis and Studies Panel Research Task Group on Anticipatory Intelligence for Superior Decision-Making (SAS-189), co-chaired by the last author and including national representation from the second and third authors.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Competing interests: None declared. Remember: Although the questions may appear repetitive, we are changing the intelligence report header data regularly. Please ensure you scrutinize the header data for each intelligence report you see before answering each question. <ref type="table">Table  Table S1</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. ANOVA</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis of Variance for the Effects of Source Reliability (SR) and Information</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Certitude judgments in an operational environment (Technical Research Note</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mckendry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mace</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="0200" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>US Army Research Institute for Behavioral and Social Sciences</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/e463552004-001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/e463552004-001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recommended effect size statistics for repeated measures designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bakeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03192707</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03192707" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Data and information quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Batini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Scannapieco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-24106-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-24106-7" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cham, Switzerland</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Assuring Data Trustworthiness -Concepts and Research Challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bertino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-642-15546-8_1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-15546-8_1" />
		<editor>Jonker, W., Petković, M.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Secure Data Management</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of testimonial inconsistencies and eyewitness confidence on mock-juror judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Brewer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Burke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="364" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1015380522722</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1015380522722" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Law Enforcement Intelligence: A Guide for State, Local, and Tribal Law Enforcement Agencies, Second Edition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Office of Community Oriented Policing Services</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Washington, DC; U.S. Department of Justice</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Restructuring structured analytic techniques in intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Berdini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02684527.2017.1400230</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02684527.2017.1400230" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Intelligence and National Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY |</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Approach to Evaluate Data Trustworthiness Based on Data Provenance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bertino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kantarcioglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Jonker, W., Petković, M.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-540-85259-9_6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-85259-9_6" />
		<title level="m">Secure Data Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conceptualizing Information Quality: A Review of Information Quality Frameworks from the Last Ten Years</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Eppler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wittig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://mitiq.mit.edu/iciq/Documents/IQ%20Conference%202000/Papers/ConceptIQaReviewofIQFramework.pdf" />
		<title level="m">Conference on Information Quality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="91" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">One test, five scoring procedures: different ways of approaching the cognitive reflection test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Erceg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bubić</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/20445911.2016.1278004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/20445911.2016.1278004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An R Companion to Applied Regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Weisberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://socialsciences.mcmaster.ca/jfox/Books/Companion/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Third edition. Sage publications</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive reflection and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Frederick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1257/089533005775196732</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1257/089533005775196732" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards content trust of web resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Gil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Artz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Web Semantics: Science, Services and Agents on the World Wide Web</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.websem.2007.09.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.websem.2007.09.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The admiralty code: a cognitive tool for self-directed learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://mail.ijlter.org/index.php/ijlter/article/view/494/234" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Learning, Teaching and Educational Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY |</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An analysis-of-variance model for the assessment of configural cue utilization in clinical judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rorer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0025665</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0025665" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quality Information and Knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K.-T</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New Jersey</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Facts versus Interpretations in Intelligence: A Descriptive Taxonomy for Information Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Icard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/q8avs</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/q8avs" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Intellectica, Cognition and Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Dynamic Logic for Information Evaluation in Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Icard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.4627928</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4627928" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">SSRN Preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Communicating uncertainty in national security intelligence: Expert and non-expert interpretations of and preferences for verbal and numeric formats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Risk Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="943" to="957" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving information evaluation for intelligence production</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Intelligence and National Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="525" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02684527.2019.1569343</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02684527.2019.1569343" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cue utilization in communication of emotion in music performance: Relating performance to perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Juslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0096-1523.26.6.1797</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0096-1523.26.6.1797" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1797</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JUDGMENTS OF INFORMATION QUALITY |</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coherence of probability judgments from uncertain evidence: Does ACH help?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Karvetski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1930297500008159</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1930297500008159" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="939" to="958" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do humans optimally integrate stereo and texture information for judgments of surface slant?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Knill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Vision Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2539" to="2558" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0042-6989</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0042-6989" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="458" to="467" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective Confidence as a Monitor of the Replicability of the Response</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Koriat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/17456916231224387</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/17456916231224387" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
			<publisher>Advance Online Publication</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When is the averaging effect present in auditor judgments?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lambert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Peytcheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Contemporary Accounting Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="296" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1911-3846.12512</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1911-3846.12512" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ideal-observer models of cue integration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Banks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Knill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sensory cue integration</title>
		<editor>J. Trommershauser, K., Kording, &amp; M. Landy</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developmental changes in the primacy of facial cues for emotion recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Leitzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Pollak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0040067</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0040067" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">ez: Easy Analysis and Visualization of Factorial Experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=ez" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 4.4-0</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Fundamentals of Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Lemercier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781118899151.ch3JUDGMENTSOFINFORMATIONQUALITY|50</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118899151.ch3JUDGMENTSOFINFORMATIONQUALITY|50" />
		<editor>P. Capet &amp; T. Delavallade</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="100" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Information Evaluation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cue utilization in a numerical prediction task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lichtenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Earle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0096-1523.1.1.77</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0096-1523.1.1.77" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Assessing components of judgments in an operational setting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lusk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Time pressure and stress in human judgment and decision making</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4757-6846-6_20</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4757-6846-6_20" />
		<editor>Svenson &amp; A. J. Maule</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview and framework for data and information quality research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Madnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1515693.1516680</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1515693.1516680" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Data and Information Quality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The occasional maverick of analytic tradecraft</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02684527.2020.1723830</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02684527.2020.1723830" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Intelligence and National Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="443" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Meta-informational cue inconsistency and judgment of information accuracy: Spotlight on intelligence analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dhami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Budescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.2307</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.2307" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Better together: Reliable application of the post-9/11 and post-Iraq US intelligence tradecraft standards requires collective analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Marcoci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Burgman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kruger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Silver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mcbride</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Thorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fraser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wintle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Fidler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vercammen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.02634</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.02634" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Marcoci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vercammen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Burgman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02684527.2018.1546265JUDGMENTSOFINFORMATIONQUALITY|51</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02684527.2018.1546265JUDGMENTSOFINFORMATIONQUALITY|51" />
		<title level="m">ODNI as an analytic ombudsman: is Intelligence Community Directive 203 up to the task? Intelligence and National Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="224" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Strategic intelligence: A handbook for practitioners, managers, and users (rev</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcdowell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>The Scarecrow Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The structure of combat intelligence ratings (technical paper 286). US Army Research Institute for Behavioral and Social Sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Miron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Patten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Halpin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.21236/ADA060321</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.21236/ADA060321" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of multiple extrinsic cues on quality perceptions: A matter of consistency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Miyazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Grewal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Goodstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1086/429606</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1086/429606" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="153" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of cue integration in human navigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nardini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bedford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Braddick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="689" to="693" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cub.2008.04.021</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2008.04.021" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Allied joint doctrine for intelligence procedures (NATO AJP-2.1, edition B, version 1)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>NATO Standardization Office</publisher>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Standardization agreement 2511-Intelligence reports (NATO STANAG 2511</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>NATO Standardization Agency</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R C</forename><surname>Nurse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Rahman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Creese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Goldsmith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lamberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information Quality and Trustworthiness: A Topical State-of-the-Art Review</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The International Conference on Computer Applications and Network Security (ICCANS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">67536</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized eta and omega squared statistics: measures of effect size for some common research designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Olejnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Algina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/1082-989X.8.4.434JUDGMENTSOFINFORMATIONQUALITY|52</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/1082-989X.8.4.434JUDGMENTSOFINFORMATIONQUALITY|52" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="447" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Is the cognitive reflection test a measure of both reflection and intuition? Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cheyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Koehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fugelsang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-015-0576-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-015-0576-1" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="348" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Regclass: Tools for an Introductory Class in Regression and Modeling. R package version 1.6</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Petrie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=regclass" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Religiosity, political orientation, and consequentialist moral thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Piazza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sousa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychological and Personality Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="334" to="342" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1948550613492826</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1948550613492826" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.R-project.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<pubPlace>Vienna, Austria</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantitative interpretation of two qualitative scales used to rate military intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Samet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Factors</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="192" to="202" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/001872087501700210</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/001872087501700210" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Divine intuition: cognitive style influences belief in God</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0025391</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0025391" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">141</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">423</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cue-consistency and cue-utilization in judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1420883</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/1420883" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="434" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for information quality assessment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stvilia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gasser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Twidale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/asi.20652JUDGMENTSOFINFORMATIONQUALITY|53</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.20652JUDGMENTSOFINFORMATIONQUALITY|53" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American society for information science and technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1720" to="1733" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Field Manual FM 30-5, Combat Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1951" />
			<pubPlace>Washington, DC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>United States Department of the Army</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of country-of-origin cues on consumer judgments in multi-cue situations: a covariance analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liefeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Heslop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF02726002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02726002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of The Academy of Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cue integration: A common framework for social cognition and physical perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="296" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691613475454</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691613475454" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diagnostic Checking in Regression Relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zeileis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hothorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/doc/Rnews/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">R News</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
