<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Acute isolation is associated with increased reward responsiveness in human adolescents</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tomova</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Cardiff University Brain Research Imaging Centre (CUBRIC)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cardiff</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Towner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Cognitive Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Centre for Human Brain Health</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Birmingham</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Birmingham</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute for Mental Health</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Birmingham</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Birmingham</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Centre for Developmental Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Birmingham</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Birmingham</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Departement d&apos;Etudes Cognitive</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ecole Normale Superieure</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire de Neurosciences Cognitives et Computationnelles</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Institut National de la Santé et de la Recherche Médicale</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S-J</forename><surname>Blakemore</surname></persName>
							<email>sjblakemore@psychol.cam.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Cognitive Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff8">
								<orgName type="institution">Reward High Low</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>0 2 4 6 8</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Acute isolation is associated with increased reward responsiveness in human adolescents</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Social connection, a basic human need, is particularly important during adolescence. How a lack of connection impacts adolescent behaviour is unclear. To address this question, we employed experimental short-term isolation with and without access to virtual social interactions (iso total; iso with media; order counterbalanced, both compared to a separate baseline session). We assessed how isolation impacts self-reported loneliness, reward seeking and reward learning in adolescents (N=40) aged 16-19 years. Self-reported state loneliness increased as a function of duration of isolation. When participants had access to virtual interactions, they self-reported less state loneliness during isolation. Isolation was associated with faster decisions to exert effort for rewards and improved reward learning. These effects were stronger in participants who reported higher state loneliness following isolation. We used fMRI to explore neural predictors of sensitivity to isolation and found that participants with lower neural reward sensitivity signals in the occipital cortex at baseline showed stronger effects of isolation. These results demonstrate that, in adolescents, isolation is associated with higher reward responsiveness, a key driver of motivation and decision-making. 1. Screening: Online Questionnaire Reward tasks: EBDM task, RL task (counterbalanced) EBDM task</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Social connection is a basic human need <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> . However, we are not always able to obtain the kind of social contact that satisfies our social needs. Reports on chronic loneliness, the subjectively perceived lack of social connection 1 , have shown that, across the world, adolescents are one of the age groups most affected by increasing levels of chronic loneliness <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> (although there is some heterogeneity in findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> ). Over the past two decades, longitudinal research has revealed associations between adolescent chronic loneliness and depression <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref> and drug use <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> . However, the direction of causality is unclear, and bi-directional effects between chronic loneliness and mental ill health have been reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9</ref> . Experimental designs studying how modulations of state loneliness relate to changes in outcome measures enable a better understanding of causality, but such approaches have so far been limited to isolation studies in animal models. These studies have consistently shown that isolating adolescent animals primarily affects dopaminergic brain reward circuits and alters reward seeking and reward learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18</ref> . It is unclear to what extent these findings can be translated to human adolescents.</p><p>In addition to reporting high levels of chronic loneliness, young people also report more social media use than other age groups <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19</ref> . It has been proposed that there might be a connection between the use of virtual social interactions and chronic loneliness <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref> , while others have proposed that virtual social interactions might be a potential remedy for rising isolation and chronic loneliness <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> .</p><p>Here, we employed an experimental approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25</ref> using social isolation of up to four hours in human adolescents to induce subjective feelings of state loneliness and assess how they are associated with changes in reward processing <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">(Figure 1</ref>). Participants first underwent a baseline session without any isolation during which we measured reward seeking and reward learning.</p><p>Subsequently, participants underwent two isolation sessions (order counterbalanced across participants): a total isolation session (iso total), which involved isolation from any real-life and virtual social interactions, and an isolation session in which participants were isolated from inperson social interactions but had access to virtual social interactions via phone and/or other devices, using any platform they wanted (iso with media).</p><p>This design allowed us to compare the effects between two tightly controlled and counterbalanced experimental sessions (iso total; iso with media), which differed only in the amount of social interactions participants had, while keeping other factors (such as spending time alone in a room) constant (see methods section for details on procedures), and to compare the effects of both types of isolation to a baseline unaffected by experience of isolation. Finally, we sought to explore whether trait neural reward sensitivity predicted individual differences in sensitivity to isolation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>At baseline and during each isolation session, participants self-reported their feelings of state loneliness and underwent a reward seeking task and a reward learning task. During the baseline session, participants also underwent functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) to provide a measure of neural reward sensitivity, which was used in preliminary analyses testing for predictors of individual differences in sensitivity to isolation. All procedures, methods and hypotheses were preregistered on the Open Science Framework (https://osf.io/kbgsv; Appendix: Planned analyses and deviations from the preregistration in the Supplementary Information (SI) describes any deviations from the preregistration).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FIGURE 1 Overview of the experimental procedure</head><p>Left panel: Order of sessions. Individuals first completed an online screening questionnaire to assess eligibility and social connectedness. Eligible participants completed the baseline session, during which they underwent an MRI scan (fMRI with a monetary incentive delay (MID) task). MID task: Participants were presented with a star indicating how much they could win on a given trial. Subsequently, they were asked to press a button as fast as possible after seeing a white square appear. Participants then saw a screen indicating how much (from 0 -£5) they had won on that trial.</p><p>Following the scan, participants carried out the reward tasks (right panel). Participants were then invited to two isolation sessions (iso total, iso with media; order counterbalanced). At the end of each of the three sessions, participants carried out the reward tasks. Right panel: Timelines of example trials for each reward task. Effort-based decision making (EBDM) task: On each trial, participants were first shown a screen that listed details for the current trial (level of effort (hard, easy), reward (high (4 points), low (1 point)) and context (social, nature)) and were asked whether they wanted to complete the trial. We measured response time (RT) while participants decided if they wanted to complete the trial. If they chose yes, they saw a bar that they were required to pump up in 10 s (amount of effort required was calibrated to each participant's maximum effort levels assessed at the start of the task in each session) and, if they were successful, they saw a screen indicating how much they had won (1 or 4 points) and depicting images of social interactions or nature landscapes, depending on context (low reward = 1 image; high reward = 4 images).</p><p>Reward Learning (RL) task: Participants were presented with two slot machines and asked to choose one. After they</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FIGURE 2 Effects of isolation on state loneliness and mood.</head><p>Changes in self-reported state loneliness (left) and positive mood (right) over time during isolation. Dark green = iso total session; turquoise = iso with media session. The boxplots indicate the median (black centre line), mean (white circle), the interquartile range (IQR; box) and the 1.5 x IQR minima and maxima (whiskers). The black rhombi indicate outliers (values outside of 1.5 x IQR). The dashed lines across the plots indicate the mean (white) and median (grey) ratings during baseline and their 95% confidence interval (grey area). The insert regression plots on the right side of each panel show regression lines for each session and their 95% confidence interval (shaded area). * indicates p &lt; 0.001.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Adolescents show increased reward seeking following isolation</head><p>To measure reward seeking, we used an effort-based decision making (EBDM) task with three factors: reward (high/low), effort (high/low) and context (social/non-social). Response times (RTs) while participants chose whether or not to undergo an effortful task have previously been shown to be indicative of strength of preference <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28</ref> and were here used as the main measure of reward seeking as choice data showed very low variability (see methods for details). There was a 4-way interaction (b=-0.70, t=-2.13, CI=-1.35,-0.06, P=0.034; <ref type="table">Supplementary Table 1</ref>) between session (baseline, iso total, iso with media), reward (high, low), context (social, non-social) and effort (high, low) on RTs in the EBDM task (the time it took participants to decide to accept a trial).</p><p>Loneliness  Duration of isolation (h) Pairwise comparisons (Bonferroni corrected p&lt;0.0063 (0.05/8)) showed that participants were significantly faster in deciding to undergo trials in the iso total session compared with baseline when rewards were high (all p-values&lt;=0.005, range Cohen's d=0. <ref type="bibr">65-0.87)</ref>; see <ref type="bibr">Figure 3</ref>, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Supplementary Figure 1</ref> and Supplementary Table for full results). Mean RTs for low reward conditions were only faster in the iso total compared to baseline session when effort was low and only in the social context (t(27)=3.5, P=0.002, d=0.74; all other p-values were above the Bonferroni corrected level of 0.0063). This indicates that, following total isolation, participants were specifically faster in trials where rewards were high instead of showing generally decreased RTs across all conditions.</p><p>Note that the number of trials from which RTs were calculated was lower in the low reward conditions because participants decided to carry out fewer low reward trials. None of the RTs in the iso with media session were significantly different from baseline (all ps&gt;0.008).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FIGURE 3 Effects of isolation on reward seeking.</head><p>Violin plots depict response times (RTs) during the reward seeking (EBDM) task for high effort trials in each session plotted separately for high rewards (green) and low rewards (grey) averaged across contexts (social, non-social). The</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RT (s)</head><p>baseline iso total iso w media 8 violin plots illustrate the distribution of the data, the long-dashed lines indicate the median, the short-dashed lines the interquartile range with individual data points shown overlayed. * indicates Bonferroni-corrected p &lt; 0.0063.</p><p>We performed sensitivity analyses to assess whether order effects or gender might have contributed to changes in RTs between sessions and whether self-report state measures collected during the sessions (i.e., state loneliness, boredom, mood, social craving and state anxiety)</p><p>interacted with the effects of session on reward seeking (details in SI). We found no evidence that order effects were driving the main result of decreased RTs to high rewards after total isolation. Sensitivity analyses also showed no effects of gender on these results. We found that higher loneliness was associated with faster RTs in the EBDM task across all three sessions (baseline, iso total and iso media). Higher boredom and lower positive mood during both isolation sessions were also associated with faster RTs in the EBDM task (details in SI).</p><p>To further interrogate the driving factors underlying the changes in RTs in the EBDM task between sessions, we explored whether the difference in self-reported state loneliness between the two isolation sessions (i.e., the difference between iso total and iso with media in the state loneliness ratings after 3 hours of isolation) correlated with a difference in reward seeking (RTs in high reward, high effort trials, assessed separately for each context (social, nonsocial; Bonferroni corrected p&lt;0.025 (0.05/2)). We found a correlation between difference in state loneliness and difference in RTs in the social context (r(38)=-0.452; p=0.003; <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>) but not in the non-social context (r(38)=-0.030; p=0.851; <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>). Thus, participants who showed a larger difference in state loneliness between the two isolation sessions also showed more social reward seeking. We found no such effect for boredom or mood (all p-values&gt;0.025).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FIGURE Correlations between change in self-reported state loneliness and change in RTs in the EBDM task.</head><p>Scatter plots depict the difference between iso total and iso with media in self-reported state loneliness levels (after three hours of isolation) and RTs during the EBDM task for high reward, high effort trials separately for the social and non-social context. The scatter plots illustrate the negative correlation between difference in state loneliness and difference in RTs in the EBDM task in the social context and show individual data points and regression lines indicating the linear fit and the shaded areas depicting the 95% confidence interval. The plots show that a stronger increase in state loneliness in the iso total compared to iso with media session was associated with a larger decrease in RTs in the task for the social context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Adolescents show increased reward learning following isolation</head><p>We used a probabilistic reinforcement and reversal learning (RL) task <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29</ref> to measure how isolation affects the ability to learn stimulus-reinforcement associations, and to reverse them, based on probabilistic feedback. Feedback was given either via social cues (facial expressions) or non-social cues (symbols). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>10</head><p>Data analysis involved: first, assessing behavioural performance on the task; second, comparing three different models and selecting the model with the best fit to the data; third, assessing whether parameters estimated by the winning model (learning rates and inverse temperature) differed between sessions (baseline, iso total and iso with media) and feedback (social, nonsocial); and finally, assessing whether self-report measures collected during isolation interacted with effects of isolation on reward learning.</p><p>We assessed the following behavioural performance measures during each phase of the task ( <ref type="figure">Figure 5A</ref>): accuracy (quantified as the proportion of correct responses), perseverative errors (quantified as two or more consecutive errors following a reversal <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">30</ref> ) and RTs (because we had a time limit for responding (1s), hence making fast responding advantageous). We tested effects of session (baseline, iso total, iso with media), feedback (social, non-social) and phase (1, 2, 3, 4) on accuracy and RTs (see methods for details). Participants showed overall faster RTs with increasing phase number (b=-0.02, t=-2.15, CI=-0.03,-0.001, P=0.032). An effect of session suggesting participants were faster in the iso total session compared to baseline (b=-0.06, t=-2.0, CI=-0.11,-0.001, P=0.046) did not remain significant after a sensitivity analysis removing an outlier in the data. We did not find effects of session, feedback type or phase on accuracy (all p-values&gt;0.10; <ref type="figure">Figure 5B</ref>).</p><p>We then analysed accuracy and RTs from only acquisition (phase 1) to assess the effects of session and feedback type on reward learning (outside of reversal learning). We found that participants had faster RTs in the iso total session compared to baseline (b=-0.06, t=-2.69, CI=-0.10,-0.02, P=0.008), across feedback type. The results did not change after removing the outlier in the iso with media session (as seen in <ref type="figure">Figure 5C</ref>; with outlier removed (b=-0.06, t=-3.08, CI=-0.10,-0.02, P=0.002)). We found no effects on accuracy (all p-values&gt;0.2). Finally, we analysed perseverative errors from each reversal phase (phases 2-4). Because these data were binary (0 = no perseverative error; 1 = a perseverative error was made during that phase), we conducted nonparametric</p><p>Wilcoxon signed rank tests between sessions for each of the 3 phases (Bonferroni corrected p&lt;0.017 (0.05/3)).</p><p>We found that participants showed lower perseverative errors in the iso total session compared to the iso with media session (z=-2.48, p=0.013; compared to baseline: z=-1.71, p=0.088) in phase 2</p><p>(first reversal phase; <ref type="figure">Figure 5D</ref>). We found no difference between sessions in perseverative errors for phases 3 and 4 (all p-values&gt;0.06).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FIGURE 5 Effects of isolation on reward learning -behavioural indices.</head><p>A. The structure of the task. Feedback was given with an 80:20 reward ratio; green blocks indicate high reward (80%) and red blocks low reward (20%). Which stimulus was rewarded was reversed every 7 trials generating 4 phases of the task. B. Average accuracy over the whole task across social and non-social blocks shown for each session (baseline, As a next step, we employed computational modelling to uncover the latent learning process that could capture participants' behaviour. We compared model fits between three reversal learning models. We fit models to the overall data across all sessions (baseline, iso total, iso with media) and feedback (social, non-social) to capture the within-subject design structure. Three models were compared: (i) a reward-punishment model 31 (RP), which is based on the classic Rescorla-Wagner model of conditioning <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32</ref> , but expanded with separate learning rates for win and non-win trials 33 ;</p><p>(ii) an experience-weighted attraction model 34 (EWA), which is also based on the Rescorla-Wagner model, but includes a stickiness parameter that captures perseveration bias. This model also includes an 'experience' weight parameter that decouples acquisition and reversal; (iii) a fictitious update model 35 (FU), which is an approximation to the Hidden Markov Model formulation 36 but further extended to include an update rule for the unchosen option <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">37</ref> . The model is expanded with separate learning rates for positive prediction errors (learning_pos; outcome better than expected) and negative prediction errors (learning_neg; outcome worse than expected) <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">33</ref> .</p><p>All models were estimated and compared under the hierarchical Bayesian analysis framework .</p><p>We found that the FU model showed the best fitting results controlling for model complexity (see methods and <ref type="table">Supplementary Table 4</ref>). We then assessed and validated the model fit of the FU model by running posterior predictive checks and parameter recovery (see methods for details).</p><p>Parameter recovery was successful, and the model predictions captured the data well ( <ref type="figure">Supplementary Figure 3)</ref>.</p><p>As a next step, we extracted the population-level mean posterior distributions of each parameter estimated by the model: learning rates (learning_pos and learning_neg) and inverse temperature (beta; a measure of exploration). To compare the posterior distributions between the different cases (i.e., the combination of each session (baseline, iso total, iso with media) and feedback (social, nonsocial)), we then calculated the pairwise difference distributions for each parameter and each case. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> depicts the mean posterior distributions for each model parameter ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6A</ref>) and the difference distributions for each case and each parameter ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6B</ref>). We then calculated the posterior probability of a nonzero difference between each case. We used the Savage-Dickey density ratio <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38</ref> to perform hierarchical Bayesian hypothesis testing (see methods for details). This generates a Bayes factor for each pairwise comparison expressing the likelihood of the observed data occurring under the alternative hypothesis (i.e., that the difference between cases is non-zero).</p><p>A Bayes factor of 1 represents equal support for null and alternative hypothesis (inconclusive), while a BF10&lt;3 is weak, BF10&gt;3 is moderate and BF10&gt;10 is strong evidence for the alternative hypothesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40</ref> . Learning_pos rates. There was a 90% probability for a higher learning rate from social feedback (BF10=3.29) and 93% probability for higher learning from non-social feedback (BF10=3.66) in the iso total compared to baseline session. Learning_neg rates. There was a 96% probability for a higher learning rate from social feedback in the iso total compared to baseline session (BF10=5.30) and a 99% probability for a higher learning rate from social feedback in the iso with media compared to baseline session (BF10=20.40).</p><p>Of note, confirming previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29</ref> , learning rates from positive prediction errors were overall higher compared to learning rates from negative prediction errors.</p><p>Beta. There was a 88% probability for a higher beta (indicating less exploration) for social feedback (BF10=7.29) and a 86% probability for a higher beta for non-social feedback (BF10=4. <ref type="bibr" target="#b98">98)</ref> in the iso total compared to baseline session. Beta was also higher in the iso with media compared to baseline session (social:100% probability, BF10=45.33; non-social: 96% probability, BF10=16.0). In addition, beta was lower in the iso total compared to the iso with media session (social: 97% probability, BF10=20.92; non-social: 78% probability, BF10=4.98).  Beta (0-10)</p><p>iso w media iso total baseline iso w media iso total baseline   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Difference score</head><p>To interpret the parameter results more meaningfully, we used simulations to assess the optimal learning rate and inverse temperature for our specific task environment (see methods for details).</p><p>As expected 41 for a short task (28 trials per block) with frequent changes of reward contingencies (every 7 trials), a high learning rate (indicating stronger reliance on more recent outcomes for value updating) was optimal ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Supplementary Figure 2)</ref>. Thus, for the current task, frequently updating reward contingencies was associated with better performance.</p><p>For beta (inverse temperature), values &gt; 3 were shown to be optimal. Note that participants in our task showed overall lower beta values, indicating relatively high exploration ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6A</ref>), with most values ranging between 0.5-2 across sessions.</p><p>We performed sensitivity analyses to assess whether order effects or gender effects might have contributed to changes in performance between sessions and whether self-reported state variables collected during the sessions (i.e., state loneliness, boredom, mood, social craving and state anxiety) interacted with the effects of session on reward learning (see SI). We did not use model parameters for these analyses because such two-step approaches combining hierarchical Bayesian models with frequentist follow-up analyses were shown to systematically underestimate variance resulting in a bias towards the alternative hypothesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38</ref> . Instead, we used performance measures (RTs, accuracy and perseverative errors; see SI). While we found that overall females showed higher accuracy in the RL task, we found no evidence that gender interacted with session or that order effects were driving the results. We found that higher loneliness in the iso total session was associated with faster RTs in response to social feedback in the RL task and that better mood was associated with faster RTs in the social context in the iso with media session (see SI for details). Analogous to the EBDM task, we explored whether the difference in self-reported state loneliness between the two isolation sessions correlated with a difference in reward learning (see methods for details). We used individual-level parameters (learning_pos, learning_neg) for this analysis as past work has shown that correlation analyses are not affected by the two-step approach bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">42</ref> . We assessed this separately for each feedback type in each measure (social, nonsocial; Bonferroni corrected p&lt;0.025 (0.05/2)).</p><p>We found a correlation between difference in state loneliness and difference in learning_neg rates from social feedback (r(38)=0.384; p=0.0145; <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>) but not from non-social feedback (r(38)=0.222; p=0.169; <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>). Thus, participants who showed a larger difference in state loneliness between the two isolation sessions also showed higher reward learning from negative social feedback. We found no such effect for boredom or mood (all p-values&gt;0.031).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social Feedback</head><p>Non-social Feedback Scatter plots depict the difference between iso total and iso with media in self-reported state loneliness levels (after three hours of isolation) and Learning_neg rates from the RL task separately for Learning_neg rates from social and non-social feedback. The scatter plots illustrate the negative correlation between difference in state loneliness and difference in learning_neg rates in the social context and show individual data points and regression lines indicating the linear fit and the shaded areas depicting the 95% confidence interval. The plots show that a stronger increase in state loneliness in the iso total compared to iso with media session was associated with a larger increase in learning_neg rates from social feedback.</p><p>For both tasks, we also explored whether pre-existing trait anxiety, depression scores and chronic loneliness interacted with the effects of isolation. We found that participants who reported higher chronic loneliness showed stronger effects of social isolation on RTs in the social context trials in the EBDM task (b=-0.07, t=-2.58, CI=-0.12,-0.02, P=0.011; details in SI).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preliminary evidence that neural reward sensitivity at baseline predicts effect of isolation on reward seeking</head><p>Each participant underwent an fMRI scan at baseline, during which they carried out four runs of a monetary incentive delay (MID) task. This task is commonly used to study activity in the neural reward system <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">43</ref> . <ref type="figure">Figure 8A</ref> shows the group level results from the task (contrast high-reward &gt; no-reward anticipation), which revealed activity in reward-related regions, as expected 43 .</p><p>Our preregistered analyses comprised two measures of individual 'neural reward sensitivity': a univariate measure for which we extracted the mean activity for the contrast high-reward &gt; no-reward anticipation for each participant; and a multivariate measure, which was the prediction accuracy of a classifier trained to classify neural patterns of high rewards from no rewards during the anticipation phase (see methods for details).</p><p>We assessed both the univariate and multivariate measures of neural reward sensitivity in a priori selected regions of interest (ROIs), which have been consistently activated during anticipation of rewards <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">43</ref> . These regions included: the ventral striatum (VS), midbrain (MB), amygdala (AMY), anterior insula (AI), occipital cortex (OC), thalamus (TH) and supplementary motor area (SMA).</p><p>We then tested whether neural reward sensitivity correlated with reward seeking (RTs from the high reward / high effort conditions in the EBDM task; mean across social and non-social contexts)</p><p>and reward learning (accuracy and RTs in the RL task) in the isolation session. We calculated separate correlations for each ROI for each measure of neural reward sensitivity (univariate and multivariate; 14 tests in total) and report results as significant at p&lt;0.003 (0.05/14).</p><p>Univariate neural reward sensitivity in the OC showed a significant correlation with RTs in the EBDM task in the iso total session (r(38)=0.54, p&lt;0.001; <ref type="figure">Figure 8B</ref>). This association was not present at baseline (r(38)=-0.12, p=0.465; correlations differed significantly from each other:</p><p>z=2.08, p=0.038), suggesting that neural reward sensitivity specifically predicted reward seeking following isolation rather than general reward seeking. Multivariate neural reward sensitivity did not predict reward seeking in the iso total session for any of the ROIs (all p-values&gt;0.30). between neural reward signals and RTs in the EBDM task in the baseline (blue) and iso total (pink) session.</p><p>Neural reward sensitivity (univariate or multivariate) did not predict performance in the reward learning task for any of the ROIs (all p-values&gt;0.03).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In adolescents aged 16-19 years, short-term social isolation was associated with an increase in reward responsiveness measured in two different tasks. First, we found that, even after a relatively short period of isolation (between 3.5 and 4 hours), participants reported feeling lonelier at the end of the isolation period than they did at the beginning. This was true following both total isolation and, to a lesser extent, isolation in which participants were able to interact with others virtually.</p><p>Second, the results from the effort-based decision making (EBDM) task showed that total isolation (but not isolation with virtual social interactions) was associated with faster RTs when participants were deciding whether or not to undergo an effortful task for high rewards, which is indicative of increased reward seeking . Third, the results from the reward learning (RL) task revealed that total isolation (but not isolation with virtual social interactions) was associated with an increase in reward learning from positive feedback. Isolation was also associated with an increase in reward learning from negative social feedback and lower exploration (for both isolation sessions). Our findings are partially consistent with results from animal models, which have shown that social isolation in adolescence increases reward responsiveness <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18</ref> . In animals, social isolation increases responsiveness to social rewards 45 , seeking of food or drug rewards and risk of developing addictions <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">46</ref> . Our findings suggest that there is a similar effect of increased responsiveness to rewards immediately following total isolation in human adolescents.</p><p>While we found stronger reward responsiveness to social rewards following total isolation in both reward tasks, we also found evidence for increased reward seeking for non-social rewards and increased reward learning from positive feedback, following total isolation. This is in line with findings from animal research showing higher reward seeking following isolation in the non-social domain as well <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">46</ref> .</p><p>We found that individuals who reported higher state loneliness during isolation also showed stronger reward responsiveness for social rewards in both tasks. Specifically, the difference in subjective feelings of state loneliness between the two isolation sessions (which were two highly controlled active conditions) predicted the difference in reward seeking in the social context of the EBDM task and the difference in learning rates from negative social feedback in the RL task. Thus, individuals who reported higher state loneliness also showed stronger social reward responsiveness following total isolation. We did not observe such an effect for changes in mood or boredom.</p><p>The current results therefore suggest that there is a strong relationship between state loneliness and reward responsiveness. However, we cannot rule out that the observed effects might have been partially driven by other (unmeasured) variables, such as general arousal, which could be assessed in future studies.</p><p>The finding that total isolation was associated with higher reward learning is contrary to results from animal studies. Animal studies have found that isolation leads to perseveration to initially learned reward-outcome associations following reversals <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">48</ref> . In contrast, in our study, adolescents constantly updated associations between cues and rewards throughout the task, particularly in response to social feedback, and showed fewer perseverative errors following total isolation. Thus, our results suggest that, following total isolation, adolescents placed more weight on each instance of feedback they received to guide their behaviour, especially when that feedback was social. In everyday life, such a behaviour might lead to an overemphasizing of irrelevant features 41 .</p><p>Participants reported feeling lonelier at the end of the total isolation period than they did at the beginning and, interestingly, this was also true when adolescents had access to virtual social interactions during isolation. However, the increase in self-reported state loneliness was higher following total isolation. In contrast, positive mood decreased to a similar extent in both isolation sessions. Whether virtual social interactions fulfil social needs is debated <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20</ref> and some findings suggest the contrary, that is, that virtual social interactions can increase loneliness <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20</ref> . The current study showed that during isolation with social interactions participants self-reported lower feelings of state loneliness compared to total isolation. Thus, our findings provide support for the potential of social media to fulfil social needs.</p><p>In line with this, in the iso with media session, adolescents showed no significant difference in reward seeking (in the EBDM task), or reward learning from positive prediction errors (in the RL task), compared with baseline.</p><p>However, learning rates from negative prediction errors for social feedback were higher in both isolation sessions compared to baseline. This suggests that, following isolation (with and without access to social media), participants placed more weight on each instance of negative social feedback they received to guide their behaviour. We also found that inverse temperature was higher (indicating less exploration) in the iso with media session, especially on social feedback trials. Although lower exploration is thought to be adaptive in reinforcement learning tasks, higher exploration can also be adaptive in very dynamic environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">49</ref> . Indeed, participants showed higher perseverative errors in the iso with media session compared to iso total (but not compared to baseline).</p><p>These findings could be driven by general effects of virtual interactions on attention or motivation.</p><p>However, exploration (in line with learning_neg rates) was more strongly affected on social feedback trials suggests a possible alternative explanation. A substantial number of participants (18 out of 40; 45%) reported spending more than 50% of their isolation time participating in virtual social interactions. Behaviour on social media platforms was shown to conform to the principles of reward learning: users space their posts to maximize the average rate of accrued social rewards, considering both the effort cost of posting and the opportunity cost of inaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">50</ref> . Thus, a period of intense engagement in virtual social interactions might alter the reinforcing nature of other social cues, resulting in altered exploration towards such cues. However, this interpretation is speculative, and the findings require replication and further specification.</p><p>We found preliminary evidence that neural reward sensitivity in the occipital cortex measured at baseline predicted individual differences in the effects of isolation on reward seeking: adolescents with lower neural reward sensitivity in the occipital cortex at baseline showed increased reward seeking in the EBDM task after total isolation compared to baseline. Conceptually, low responsiveness to rewards has been linked to anhedonia and might represent a marker for stronger sensitivity to stressors <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[52]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[53]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[54]</ref> . Our findings suggest that lower neural responsivity to rewards might be indicative of higher sensitivity to the stress of isolation. The occipital cortex has been identified in meta-analyses as one of the core brain regions consistently activated during reward anticipation in the MID task <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">43</ref> and in other monetary reward tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">55</ref> . Given that the high reward and no reward condition did not differ visually in the MID task, except for the number presented inside the star ("0" in the no reward condition and "5" in the high reward condition), the measured activity might The present study raises key questions for future research. First, the neural processes underlying isolation-induced changes during reward seeking and reward learning remain to be explored.</p><p>While increased activity in reward circuitry has been consistently shown in animal model studies of adolescent isolation <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18</ref> , direct experimental assessment of reward circuit activity following isolation in humans would provide further evidence of isolation-induced increases in reward responsiveness.</p><p>Second, whether our experimental findings can be translated to the effects of real During adolescence, brain reward circuits undergo critical remodeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">59</ref> . The domain of reward processing is of particular importance due to its powerful effects on behaviour <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">60</ref> and mental health <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">61</ref> . The present study suggests that brief durations of social isolation alter core components <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">60</ref> of reward processing (i.e., reward seeking and reward learning) in human adolescents. Our findings indicate that real-life isolation (such as during a pandemic or when used as punishment in schools) might result in two key changes in adolescent behaviour. First, real-life isolation might result in higher seeking of rewards, such as food or recreational drugs. Second, the stronger reliance on each instance of feedback during reward learning following isolation suggests that real-life isolation might lead to an increased sensitivity to positive and negative feedback -especially social feedback -in adolescence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We collected data from 42 participants; 2 participants were unable to complete all experimental sessions, leaving 40 complete datasets (mean age = 17.1; std = 0.9; 22 female). Participants were recruited through online advertisements and flyers. The study description indicated that we were interested in studying how different forms of spending time alone (with or without access to virtual interactions) affects adolescent cognition. Interested individuals completed a screening questionnaire to assess eligibility for the study (questionnaire data was collected using Qualtrics  <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">65</ref> , which we adapted to number of close friends to simplify the question for our adolescent sample); and (b) Number of social interactions in the past month: counting face-to-face and virtual social interactions that were primarily social in nature (i.e., excluding professional interactions, like talking to a doctor, teacher, or hairdresser). We excluded participants who reported fewer than two close friends and fewer than 10 social interactions in one month (which is ~7 standard deviations below the previously reported means for adolescents for both measures <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">64</ref> ). The exclusion thresholds for the social network size measures were lower than previously reported 25 because data for this study was collected during the COVID-19 pandemic, which required social distancing and therefore lower levels of social connectedness were expected throughout the population.</p><p>All experimental procedures were approved by the Psychology Research Ethics Committee at University of Cambridge, UK. Participants signed a consent form describing all experimental procedures before participating in the study. Each participant was compensated with up to £127</p><p>(minimum payment for each participant was £107) for participating in three sessions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental procedures</head><p>Each participant underwent three experimental sessions, separated by at least 24 hours. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 1</ref> shows an overview of the experimental procedures. Each participant first completed a baseline session which included MRI scanning and the behavioural tasks (see Behavioural: Reward tasks for details). Following the baseline session, participants were invited to two isolation sessions (order counterbalanced). One session included up to 4 hours of total social isolation (iso total)</p><p>during which participants had no access to any social interactions (real-life or virtual); another session included up to 4 hours of social isolation with access to virtual social interactions (iso with media). All behavioural testing and the isolation periods took place in the same room, meaning that participants were able to start the tasks immediately following isolation.</p><p>Following the methods of Tomova et al. 2020 <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25</ref> , we sought to experimentally induce the subjective experience of state loneliness in adolescent participants. Re-analysing state loneliness ratings from a subset of 18-24-year-old participants from Tomova et al. 2020 and pilot measures in two 16year-olds (Ntotal = 21) showed that two hours of isolation resulted in increased self-reported state loneliness in this age group. We therefore reduced the duration of isolation in this study compared with Tomova et al. 2020. The minimal duration of each isolation session was set to 3h 30min and the maximal duration was 4 hours. We randomly assigned an added duration of 0-30 mins of isolation time to each session (in steps of 5 mins, separately for each session), so that participants were not able to predict the precise end of the isolation period in either session. The average isolation duration was similar between sessions (iso total: m=3h 46 mins, std=11.2 mins; iso with media: m=3h 47 mins, std=10.0; t(39)=0.30, p=0.765). All participants underwent all three experimental sessions (baseline, iso total and iso with media). Each participant was pseudorandomly assigned to one order, with the restriction that baseline was always first and that each order was approximately equally likely in the full sample. This design allowed us to compare effects of both types of isolation to a baseline unaffected by experience of isolation, and to compare effects of being totally isolated to being isolated with access to virtual interactions, while keeping other factors (such as spending time physically alone in a room) constant.</p><p>Note that in this study power calculations were made for within-subject effects of isolation (see also preregistration) and between-subject analyses (i.e., analyses on the predictors of individual differences in sensitivity to isolation) should be interpreted as preliminary.</p><p>During the iso total session, participants had access to a variety of non-social activities (such as games, puzzles, sudoku, books, drawing/writing supplies). We also encouraged participants to bring activities that they would like to occupy themselves with during the isolation. Examples of what participants chose to bring with them included school homework, a jewellery making kit, art materials and nail polish.</p><p>As we aimed to keep all social interactions during this session to a minimum, participants were given extensive instructions about the isolation procedures and the subsequent behavioural paradigms before starting social isolation. Participants gave their phones and laptops to the experimenter and were guided to a room containing an armchair, a desk and an office chair, and a fridge with a selection of food and beverages. The room had a roof window, which allowed day light to enter the room but kept participants from seeing other people outside the building.</p><p>Participants remained in that room for the duration of the isolation and the subsequent behavioural testing. Participants were told that they could spend the isolation time however they wanted with the restriction that they should fill out the questionnaire every hour and should avoid sleeping during isolation. Participants were reminded to fill out the questionnaires via an alarm sound that went off every hour during isolation and at the end of isolation, indicating to participants that they should start the behavioural tasks. Participants were provided with a desk computer (with parental controls enabled), allowing them to visit only our Slack channel (an online messenger software (www.slack.com)) and the webpage containing our online questionnaires. Messaging in Slack was restricted to emergencies (that is, in case participants ran into problems that required assistance from the research team during isolation). During isolation and the subsequent behavioural testing, we monitored participants via a live camera, which allowed a researcher to check in on the participant without interacting with them. The camera only provided a live stream of the participant in the room to the experimenter and did not store any recordings of participants. Participants were informed about the camera in an information sheet they received before agreeing to participate in the experiment. Participants completed an online questionnaire (see Questionnaires for details) every hour during the social isolation period. The behavioural testing was started immediately after the social isolation. Participants first filled out questionnaires and then started the behavioural tasks, which they started themselves (i.e., there was no interaction with the experimenter between the end of isolation and the beginning of the behavioural testing). After the session, a member of the research team chatted with the participants about their experiences during isolation and made sure participants were not feeling troubled.</p><p>Procedures during the iso with media session were the same as in the iso total session, except that participants could bring any electronic device with them into the room and were told they could use them as much as they wanted. sequence was used to collect T1-weighted structural images in 224 interleaved sagittal slices with 0.7-mm isotropic voxels (FOV: 224 mm). We also collected a field map (phase-difference B0 estimation; echo time 1 (TE1) = 1.11 ms, echo time 2 (TE2) = 3.06 ms) to control for spatial distortions, which are particularly problematic with ultra-high field scanning <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">66</ref> . Furthermore, DTI images were acquired with a scanning protocol of 90 1.4 mm-thick contiguous axial slices with an in-plane resolution of 1.4 × 1.4 mm providing full brain coverage. DTI data are outside the scope of this manuscript and will be described in a separate paper. During acquisition of the anatomical images (~7 min in total), participants underwent a practice run of the MID task (see "MID task" for details). (small loss trials), -5 (large loss trials)). Following the cue, participants saw a white circle on the screen presented for a jittered time interval (range 1.5-4 s, mean 2.5 s) briefly followed by a white square, which was presented for 100 ms and then the circle again. Participants' task was to press a button as fast as possible when they saw the square. Following their response, participants were presented with feedback revealing whether they won (or avoided a loss) or not on that trial (presented for 500 ms). At the end of each trial participants saw a fixation cross for a jittered time interval (range 2-6 s, mean 3.5 s) before the next trial began. The task was adaptive and the time window for how fast participants needed to respond narrowed or widened depending on their response times during the task to ensure that participants won on most (~80%) of the trials (to keep the task rewarding) but also that the task was not too easy (to keep participants engaged).</p><p>Participants underwent a practice run of the task during the anatomical MP2RAGE scan, and the data from this run was used to calibrate the initial response window for the MID task. We report exploratory analyses assessing interactions between individual differences in trait anxiety and depression, in addition to measures of chronic loneliness (UCLA loneliness scale 27 ) collected during the online screening, and the effects of our experimental manipulations in the SI.</p><p>Measures of self-reported state loneliness (0-100), social craving (0-100), boredom (0-100) and current affect (using the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule (PANAS 70 ) were also acquired at the beginning of the baseline session. In addition, participants were asked whether they drink alcohol and whether they vape (at least once per month). If yes, participants were asked to rate their current urge to drink alcohol and to vape on a scale from (0) not at all to (100) extremely. In accordance with the University COVID-19 risk assessment, participants who reported that they smoke were excluded from participation, and therefore we did not ask about craving in the domain of smoking. Because only 55% of our participants (N = 22) reported that they drank alcohol at all, and only two participants reported that they vaped, there was not sufficient power to assess effects of isolation on alcohol or vape craving.</p><p>Isolation sessions. Following each isolation session (iso with media and iso total), immediately before participants started the behavioural tasks, we assessed state anxiety and craving for alcohol and vaping. In addition, participants self-reported state loneliness, social craving, boredom and current affect at the beginning of each isolation session (T0) and then after every hour of isolation for 3 hours (T1, T2, T3), followed by a final rating at the end of isolation (T4; 3 hours 30 min to 4</p><p>hours of isolation, varying between participants). Effects of isolation on state anxiety are reported in the SI.</p><p>All statistical analyses using self-report questionnaires were conducted on measures taken after 3 hours (T3) of isolation. This allowed us to capture participants' affective state after a substantial period of isolation but before they knew it was over. Plots including state loneliness and mood ratings at the final time point (T4) are shown in <ref type="figure">Supplementary Figure 5</ref>, and statistics using these time points are included in the SI. Note that the general results remain the same regardless of whether T3 or T4 ratings were used. Boredom measures were used in exploratory analyses to assess whether self-reported boredom interacted with the effects of isolation (see SI).</p><p>After the iso with media session, participants completed a questionnaire which asked them to report how much they engaged in virtual social interactions during the session (percentage of time spent engaging in virtual social interactions during session (0-100%)). We also asked participants to indicate which method(s) (texting/messaging, voice calls, video calls, commenting/posting, gaming, other) and platform(s) (Instagram, Facebook, Facebook messenger, Snapchat, TikTok, Twitter, WhatsApp, other) they mostly used for their virtual social interactions during the session.</p><p>Participants were asked to list whom they interacted with virtually (i.e., friends, family, acquaintances, romantic partner, other). Participants could select multiple options and, if they selected "other", they were asked to specify.</p><p>Participants self-reported that, on average, they spent 47% of their time engaging in virtual social interactions during the iso with media session (std=28%; range=5-100%). Most participants (35 out of 40) engaged with virtual social interactions more than 20% of iso with media session and 18 out of 40 participants (45%) spent more than 50% of the session engaging in virtual social interactions. We asked participants what they used for connecting with others (multiple selections possible) and the majority of participants reported using instant messaging (37 out of 40). Some participants reported posting (9) and a small number reported engaging in voice calls (3), video calls (2) or gaming <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3)</ref>. Participants mainly used Snapchat <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(28)</ref>, Instagram <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(27)</ref> and WhatsApp <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(23)</ref> to connect with others, followed by TikTok <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10)</ref>, Twitter (3), Discord (3) and</p><p>Facebook/Facebook Messenger <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref>. The majority of participants connected virtually with friends <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(38)</ref>, followed by family <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(19)</ref>, romantic partners <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(13)</ref> and acquaintances (4).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Behavioural: Reward tasks</head><p>We used two computerized behavioural tasks to measure reward responsiveness in two domains (i.e., reward seeking and reward learning) at baseline and at the end of the two isolation sessions (iso total and iso with media).</p><p>Reward seeking. We used an effort-based decision making (EBDM) task, which was an adapted version of the Effort Expenditure for Rewards Task (EEfRT 71 ). In our adapted version, we manipulated and orthogonalized reward and effort. Participants were presented with a series of trials with different combinations of high rewards and low rewards for successfully completing "hard tasks" and "easy tasks". First, participants underwent two calibration trials in which the task measured their maximum effort (the maximum number of button presses performed in 10 s using their index finger). Based on this, "hard task" trials required participants to make 80% of the maximal button presses they managed in 10 s to succeed. "Easy task" trials required participants to make 40% of the maximal button presses they managed in 10 s to succeed. Rewards earned could be either 1 point (low reward) or 4 points (high reward) and participants were presented with combinations of required effort (hard/easy) and potential rewards (high/low) on each trial before deciding whether they wanted to perform that trial's task. Points were converted into monetary value at the end of each session.</p><p>In addition, we added the element of context (nature vs social low effort -high reward; high effort -low reward; low effort -low reward, each in either a nature or social context, with 6 trials per condition (48 trials in total), which were presented in random order.</p><p>Participants had to indicate whether or not they wanted to play each trial. There was no time restriction for participants' decisions. If participants completed the trial successfully (i.e., pumped up the bar within the time limit), they saw the social or nature pictures described above. Pictures were presented for 8 s together with the number of points participants won. After each trial, a fixation cross was presented for 0.5 s.</p><p>Reward Learning. The ability to learn stimulus-reinforcement associations and to reverse them based on probabilistic feedback was measured using a probabilistic reinforcement and reversal learning task <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">73,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">74</ref> . In the present task, participants were shown two slot machines and asked to choose between them to obtain a reward. One slot machine was rewarded 80% of the time; the other was rewarded 20% of the time. Participants needed to learn from feedback through trial and error which slot machine was rewarded more often. After 7 trials, the reward contingencies switched and participants needed to learn the new reward contingencies. Feedback was given via symbols (non-social feedback) and facial expressions (social feedback) in two counterbalanced blocks (28 trials per block, in total 56 trials). Rewards (positive feedback) were represented by either a plus symbol (+; non-social) or a smiling face (social), while the absence of a reward (negative feedback) was represented by a zero symbol (0; non-social) or a neutral face (social).</p><p>The two facial pictures (smiling and neutral) were generated by averaging facial pictures of Caucasian young adults. To do this, we used happy and neutral faces from the Averaged Karolinska Directed Emotional Faces set <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">75</ref> . We averaged the female and male faces for each emotion (happy and neutral) rendering them ambiguous as to gender. Photoshop was used to create the averages. We cropped the images to remove the background/hair and display the face only.</p><p>Facial pictures were displayed in black and white to match the non-social feedback. Participants were given 1 s to respond on each trial and then received feedback for 0.5 s. A fixation cross was presented for 0.5 s between each trial.</p><p>Counterbalancing: There were three pairs of stimuli used -the 'fruits' within the slot machines. Which side each fruit in the pair was displayed on was randomized at each session. Whether or not the first 'correct' response was on the left or the right side was randomized within each session.</p><p>Whether the social or nonsocial feedback came first was randomized within each session. The practice trials had separate stimuli that were not used in the rest of the experiment.</p><p>Participants also underwent three other tasks during the experiment (a go-no go task, a peer influence task and a threat learning task and (see full description of experimental procedures here:</p><p>https://osf.io/kbgsv). The order of the tasks was counterbalanced between participants with the exception that the threat learning task was always presented after the reward tasks reported here, so that there would be no effect of threat exposure on reward processing. Results from the other behavioural tasks will be reported elsewhere.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analysis</head><p>Reward Seeking. Response times (RTs) on each trial in the EBDM task were compared for the following conditions (non-social or social): high effort -high reward; low effort -high reward;</p><p>high effort -low reward; low effort -low reward (8 conditions in total). Response times (RTs) to choose whether to undergo an effortful task have been shown to be indicative of strength of preference <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28</ref> and here were used as the main measure of reward seeking due to the low variance in participants' choice data. More specifically, many participants chose to play almost every trial in the task (73% of all trials were played) with 28 out of 120 sessions (40 participants, each having 3 sessions; 23% of all data) having no variance at all (i.e., participants played every single trial in that session). This effect was similar across sessions (i.e., from a total of 28 sessions in which participants played every trial, 10 were from baseline sessions, 9 from iso total sessions and 9 from iso with media sessions) but the amount of affected sessions per participants differed (i.e., 6</p><p>participants played all trials in all sessions, 2 participants played all trials in two sessions and 6 participants played all trials in one of their sessions). Data with zero variance holds no information.</p><p>Because we were primarily interested in comparing effects between sessions, one session with zero variance effectively compromised our ability to analyse data for that participant (as we would not be able to compare effects of the other sessions to that session). This means that effectively 42 sessions (14 participants x sessions) were affected by this issue (35% of the data). We therefore decided to not analyse choice data and instead focus assessments on RTs when deciding to play a trial and how those differed between sessions (baseline, iso total, and iso with media) in our main analysis.</p><p>We used mixed effects models to investigate fixed effects of session, context, reward and effort on RTs (for trials in which participants decided to do the effortful task. Subject was included as a random effect (allowing intercepts and slopes to vary between participants 76 ). Baseline was the reference session in the model. Calibration (i.e., the number of button presses participants managed at the beginning of each session from which hard and easy tasks were calculated) was added as a control variable in the model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The command was:</head><p>fitlme(Data,'RT~(session*effort*reward*context)+(Calibration)+(session*effort*reward*context |subjectID)').</p><p>Reward Learning. Data analysis involved, first, assessing behavioural performance on the task.</p><p>We assessed three behavioural measures for the RL task: First, we assessed accuracy, which was quantified as the proportion of correct responses during each phase of the task ((phase 1 = acquisition, phase 2 = reversal_1 (reward contingencies flipped), phase 3 = reversal_2 (reward contingencies same as in acquisition), and phase 4 = reversal_3 (reward contingencies flipped again)); Fig6A). Second, we assessed perseverative errors, which were quantified as two or more consecutive errors following reversal (following methods of Crawley et al. 2020 <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">30</ref> ). In each phase, for phases 2-4 (excluding phase 1 because no rule had been learned yet), we assessed whether participants made a perseverative error (PE) or not (coded as 0 (no PE) or 1 (a PE was made)).</p><p>And third, we assessed response times (RTs) for making choices during the task. Because our version of the task included a time limit for responding (1s), hence making fast responding advantageous, we also assessed RTs for making choices during each phase of the task. <ref type="figure">Fig. 6</ref> shows all behavioural indices.</p><p>We tested effects of session (baseline, iso total, iso with media), feedback type (social, non-social) and phase (1, 2, 3, 4) on accuracy and RTs using mixed effects models. Subject was included as a random effect (allowing intercepts and slopes to vary between participants 76 ). Baseline was the reference session in the model.</p><p>The command was: fitlme(Data,'outcome~(session*feedback type * phase) + (session* feedback type * phase) |subjectID)').</p><p>We then analysed behavioural data (accuracy and RTs) from only acquisition (phase 1) to assess the effects of session and feedback type on reward learning (outside of reversal learning). The command was the same as for the full model but with phase as a predictor removed. Finally, we analysed perseverative errors from each reversal phase (phases 2-4). Because these data were binary, we calculated nonparametric Wilcoxon signed rank tests between sessions for each of the 3 phases (we report results for each phase as significant at Bonferroni corrected p&lt;0.017 (0.05/3)).</p><p>Following the analysis of performance data, participants' choices from the RL task were analysed using a computational reinforcement learning and decision-making model for probabilistic reversal learning tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">73</ref> .</p><p>To assess learning during the task, we first extracted the trial-by-trial responses for each participant, then employed a computational reinforcement learning model for probabilistic reversal learning using a hierarchical Bayesian modelling approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">73</ref> to estimate the learning rates for each participant.</p><p>For the group level means and standard deviations we used normal distributions; see <ref type="bibr">Ahn</ref>  </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">V !,# = $ V !,#$% + η &amp;'( (O #$% − V !,#$% ), if O #$% &gt; 0 V !,#$% + η )&amp;'( (O #$% − V !,#$% ), if O #$% &lt; 0<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Where, η rew is the learning rate for rewards and η nrew is the learning rate for non-rewards; O is the outcome received. In this model, only the chosen stimulus value is updated. V c,t is the value of choice c on trial t. O &gt; 0 indicates a win and O &lt; 0 indicates no win.</p><p>(ii) An experience-weighted attraction model 34 , which includes an "experience" weight parameter that decouples acquisition and reversal by allowing the balance between past experience and new information to increasingly tip in favour of past experience:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">n !,# = n !,#$% × ρ + 1 (2) V !,# = (V !,#$% × φ × n !,#$% + O #$% ) n !,# ⁄<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Where, n c,t is the "experience weight" of the chosen stimulus on trial t, which is updated on every trial using the experience decay factor r. V c,t is the value of choice c on trial t for outcome O received in response to that choice, and φ is the decay factor for the previous payoffs. In this model, φ is equivalent to the inverse of the learning rate in Rescorla-Wagner models.</p><p>(iii) A fictitious update model <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35</ref> , which includes an update rule for the unchosen option considering the knowledge individuals gain about the unchosen option, here with separate learning rates for positive and negative prediction errors.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">V !,# = 7 V !,#$% + η &amp;'( 8O #$% − V !,#$% 9, ifO #$% &gt; 0 V !,#$% + η )&amp;'( 8O #$% − V !,#$% 9, ifO #$% &lt; 0 (4) V )!,# = 7 V )!,#$% + η )&amp;'( 8−O #$% − V )!,#$% 9, ifO #$% &gt; 0 V )!,#$% + η &amp;'( 8−O #$% − V )!,#$% 9, ifO #$% &lt; 0<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Where the value V of both the chosen c and unchosen nc stimulus are updated with the actual prediction error and the counterfactual prediction error per trial t, respectively. O is the outcome received. The learning rate η, which is divided into η rew (learning rate for rewards; learning_pos) and η nrew (learning rate for non-rewards; learning_neg) evidences the magnitude of the value update affected by both positive and negative prediction errors.</p><p>Model fitting. For all models, a softmax choice function was used to compute the action probability</p><p>given the action values. On each trial t, the action probability of choosing option A (over B) was defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">p(A) = % %* ' !"($ % ! $ ' )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Where β is the inverse temperature parameter that governs the stochasticity of the choice, computed using inverse logit transfer. Higher β values denote decisions driven by relative value whereas lower β values denote more choice stochasticity.</p><p>Parameter estimation was performed with hierarchical Bayesian analysis using Stan language in R via modified scripts from the hBayesDM package <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">73</ref> . Posterior inference was performed using R-hat values of all models were lower than 1.05 suggesting MCMC samples were well mixed and converged to stationary distributions.</p><p>The models were fitted on all data combined from each session (baseline, iso total and iso with media) and feedback (social, non-social). To take the full advantage of the hierarchical Bayesian approach, we fit models to the overall data across all conditions rather than to separate data from each condition to better capture the within-subject design structure and to avoid overestimation of differences among conditions. Specifically, we constructed a design matrix of effect coding to reflect differences among sessions and conditions:</p><p>Here, the first three rows depicted non-social feedback, and the last three rows depicted social feedback; columns were used to describe the difference of sessions with respect to the baseline session. For example, the second column indicated the difference between iso_media and baseline for non-social feedback. As a result, row summaries indicated the actual parameters for the combinations between sessions and feedback. For example, the second row indicated the parameter in the iso_media condition (e.g., Xiso_media = Xbaseline + Xiso_media_diff). All other rows and columns followed the same rule. This design matrix was applied to all model parameters in each candidate model under a single overall hierarchical fitting framework.</p><p>Model comparison. Comparison of model fit was assessed using Bayesian bootstrap and model averaging, whereby log-likelihoods for each model were evaluated at the posterior simulations and a weight obtained for each model. We compared Bayesian model weights between models (higher weights denoting better model fit) using two model weight metrics: Bayesian stacking of means and Pseudo Bayesian Model Averaging <ref type="bibr" target="#b78">78</ref> . We found that model fit was best for the fictitious update (FU) model (Supplementary <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>).</p><p>Following model selection, we compared the posterior distributions of the group level parameters (learning_pos, learning_neg and beta) for each of the six cases (i.e., the combination of session (baseline, iso total and iso with media) and feedback (social, non-social): baseline-social, baselinenonsocial, iso total-social, iso total-nonsocial, iso with media-social and iso with media-nonsocial).</p><p>We use the Savage-Dickey method <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38</ref> to perform hierarchical Bayesian hypothesis testing which generates a Bayes factor for each pairwise comparison. The Bayes factor is obtained by comparing each difference distribution to a prior distribution that expresses the expectation about the effect size of the pairwise difference δ = (μ2−μ1)/τ, where μ1,2 are the means of the conditions to be compared and τ is the group level standard deviation. The null hypothesis specifies that δ = 0, indicating no difference between the conditions. The real difference distributions are then compared to this prior distribution for each case. Specifically, because the null hypothesis is δ = 0, the Bayes factor is described as the prior density at δ = 0 divided by the posterior density at δ = 0.</p><p>Simulations. Whether a certain difference in parameters indicates "better" or "worse" behaviour can be heavily dependent on the task design and the values of the other relevant model parameters . We therefore used data simulations to identify the optimal learning parameters for the present task environment to help with interpretation of the results. The parameter combinations were taken from a grid spanned by the learning rate (h; minimum value/maximum value/steps = 0/1/60) and "inverse temperature b" (0/20/60). Each of these virtual participants then completed 28 trials corresponding to the actual number of trials in our task for each feedback (social, nonsocial) in each session (baseline, iso total, iso with media) with a reward schedule of 80:20. For each virtual participant, we then calculated the percentage of correct choices as the percentage of choices for the option that was associated with a higher probability for a reward. To reduce random noise due to the finite number of samples, we smoothed the resulting images with a gaussian filter (std = 2). We identified the optimal learning rate and inverse temperature as the values that resulted in the highest choice accuracy (average of 10 highest accuracy scores in the simulations; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Fig. S2</ref>).</p><p>Posterior predictive checks. We simulated data from the fictious update model and assessed how well it represented real participants' choice data by comparing the two on the single-subject and group mean level. <ref type="figure">Supplementary Figure 3A</ref>-B shows the results from the posterior predictive checks.</p><p>Parameter recovery. We also ran parameter recovery to assess whether the fitting procedure is giving meaningful and identifiable parameter values <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">79,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">80</ref> . Posterior group-level mean and standard deviation were extracted as the "ground truth" for each parameter from their posterior distributions, and then used for generating n = 40 individual level parameters to simulate data.</p><p>Simulated data was generated from the FU model and the model was then fit to the simulated data.</p><p>The posterior group-level distribution from each recovered parameter was compared to the ground truth to evaluate parameter recovery <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">81</ref> . Parameters are considered well recovered if the ground truth is within the 95% highest density interval (HDI) of the posterior distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">82</ref> , which was the case for all parameters. Thus, parameter recovery was overall successful for all parameters (see Supplementary <ref type="figure">Figure 3C</ref>-E for the recovered parameter posterior distributions compared against the ground truth for each parameter).</p><p>Data analysis and visualization for the reward tasks was implemented in Python (version: 3.7)</p><p>using Jupyter notebooks (using packages Pandas, NumPy and Seaborn), RStudio and</p><p>Matlab2020a.</p><p>Correlations between reward tasks and state loneliness. First, we calculated the difference in state loneliness ratings after 3 hours of isolation between iso total and iso with media. For the EBDM task, we calculated the difference in RTs for high reward and high effort trials between the iso total and iso with media session. We then calculated a Pearson correlation for each context (social and non-social) to assess if the change scores between loneliness and reward seeking were correlated. For the reward learning task, we calculated a similar analysis for the two learning rates (learning_pos and learning_neg). For each parameter, we calculated change scores between the iso total and iso with media session and then calculated Pearson correlations for each feedback (social, non-social) to assess if the change scores between loneliness and reward learning were correlated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MRI Data Analysis</head><p>Preprocessing. Preprocessing was performed as preregistered on OSF using the same pipeline as Tomova et al. 2020 <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25</ref> (except for the MP2RAGE processing described below). We used nipy and nipype 83 open source preprocessing pipelines for fMRI data. First, the heudiconv python application was used to convert data into the NIFTI image file format using dcm2niix, and then to organize that data into a BIDS-formatted directory structure. fMRIprep 84 was used to minimally preprocess the anatomical and functional data (using default settings but including susceptibility distortion correction using fieldmaps (see below).</p><p>Because we collected fMRI data on 7T and used an MP2RAGE sequence, which is not a format that is currently supported by fMRIprep, we first processed the MP2RAGE data so it could be used by fMRIprep. To this end, we applied an offline reconstruction method using in-house code that reconstructs a phase-sensitive inversion recovery (PSIR) image from MP2RAGE scans (nifti files).</p><p>The PSIR file was then added as a T1 file into fMRIprep to be processed and was treated as a T1</p><p>anatomical scan in fMRIprep.</p><p>Using fMRIprep, we skull-stripped anatomical images: the atlas-based ANTS program <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">85</ref> was used first and then skull-stripping was refined using information from FreeSurfer surfaces after reconstruction was completed <ref type="bibr" target="#b86">86</ref> . We used the FMRIB Software Library (FSL) FAST program <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">87</ref> for brain tissue segmentation. Images were spatially normalized to MNI-space using ANTS (using the multiscale, mutual-information based, nonlinear registration scheme). Brain masks, tissue segmentation and FreeSurfer surfaces were visually inspected for quality control. We used phasedifference B0 estimation 88 for susceptibility distortion correction.</p><p>A reference image for each run was generated from the input BOLD timeseries. We created a functional brain mask using a combination of FSL, ANTS, AFNI and nilearn tools 89 . FSL's MCFLIRT program <ref type="bibr" target="#b90">90</ref> was used to estimate and correct for head motion, which generated a coregistered BOLD series and motion-based confound regressors. Any run containing a framewise displacement greater than 0.4 mm on more than 25% of the total frames was excluded from additional analyses. Additional confound regressors were generated, including other measures of motion (framewise displacement and DVARS and anatomical CompCor timeseries derived from cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) and white matter tissue segments. FreeSurfer's program "bbregister" <ref type="bibr" target="#b92">92</ref> was used to align the reference image of each run with the anatomical image. The timepoint-tofunctional reference transformation, the functional reference to anatomical transformation, and the anatomical-to-MNI transformation were concatenated into a single transformation and used to transform each functional timeseries into MNI template space.</p><p>We used FSL's SUSAN tool <ref type="bibr" target="#b93">93</ref> for spatial smoothing with a 6 mm smoothing kernel. The tool uses segmentation boundaries to avoid smoothing across tissue types. We used MRIQC, an open-source quality assurance software tool <ref type="bibr" target="#b94">94</ref> , to generate additional reports which display Image Quality Metrics (IQMs).</p><p>Functional MRI Data Modelling. We used the nipype framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b83">83</ref> to conduct the analyses. For run-level analyses, we assessed the preprocessed timeseries with algorithms from the Artifact Removal Toolbox (ART) to identify frames within each run that had an abnormal amount of motion (0.4 mm of total displacement, or an intensity spike greater than 3 standard deviations from mean).</p><p>Based on these criteria we had to remove one run from one participant which showed a framewise displacement (FD) of 0.42. All other runs were within the movement limit (mean FD across subjects, across runs = 0.165, std = 0.056, range = 0.082 -0.327). The design matrix included boxcars for the experimental conditions convolved with a double-gamma hemodynamic response function (HRF), and nuisance regressors representing frame-wise motion, the anatomical CompCor regressors derived from white matter and CSF, as well as impulse regressors for volumes identified by ART. A high-pass filter was applied to the design matrix and the smoothed data. We evaluated the model using FSL's FILM <ref type="bibr" target="#b95">95</ref> . Subject-level contrast maps were generated using FSL's FLAME 95 in mixed-effects mode.</p><p>ROIs in MID task. To analyse the functional data from the MID task, we applied whole brain analyses and region of interest (ROI) analyses. Whole brain data was used to generate group-level contrasts for the high reward vs no reward conditions to assess whether the resulting group-level brain activation was in line with expected activation for this contrast <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">43</ref> . For the ROI analyses, we included regions that have been consistently activated during reward anticipation in an Activation</p><p>Likelihood Estimation meta-analysis of 50 fMRI studies using the MID task (Oldham 2018 43 ).</p><p>These regions comprised: the ventral striatum (VS), midbrain (MB), amygdala (AMY), anterior insula (AI), occipital cortex (OC), thalamus (TH) and supplementary motor area (SMA). ROIs were created using the Harvard-Oxford cortical and subcortical probabilistic anatomical atlases;</p><p>included in FSL. We were not able to find an anatomical mask for the anterior insula and therefore created ROIs based on peak activation locations reported in Oldham 2018 (left AI: -40 14 -8; right AI: 34 24 -2). We drew 5 mm spheres around these peak coordinates and created a binary mask combining left and right AI.</p><p>Quantifying neural reward sensitivity.</p><p>Univariate. We extracted mean activation from the contrast high reward &gt; no reward during the anticipation phase of the MID task as a measure of univariate neural reward sensitivity from each ROI (7 ROIs in total).</p><p>Multivariate. Multivariate analyses can detect differences between conditions with higher sensitivity than conventional univariate analyses . We therefore also employed a multivariate measure of neural reward sensitivity by quantifying the similarity of the multivariate spatial patterns of activity between high reward versus no reward during the anticipation phase of the MID task from each ROI. Multivariate classification accuracy here can be seen as an indication of the amount of information about a variable of interest available in the BOLD signal <ref type="bibr" target="#b97">97,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b98">98</ref> , such that individual differences in classification accuracy indicate neural reward sensitivity in the multivariate domain. However, differences between multivariate and univariate tests do not afford conclusions about the nature or dimensionality of the neural signal (as both can also stem from the same source 96 ). Thus, here, these measures were used to assess the same concept (i.e., neural reward sensitivity) and we corrected for multiple comparisons across the different measures. For each ROI, we extracted the β values from the generalized linear model (that is, the amplitude of the fit HRF) of the response to the two conditions of interest (high reward, no reward) for each trial in each run (28 trials per condition per run × 4 runs) resulting in 112 β values for each voxel.</p><p>Responses were extracted from all voxels in the anatomically identified ROIs in each participant (see ROIs in MID task for ROI definition). No additional feature selection was applied. All multivariate analyses were conducted with the PyMVPA 99 toolbox in Python (http://www.pymvpa.org) and Matlab 2020a. We first trained a machine learning algorithm to decode neural patterns of high reward vs. no reward for each subject within each ROI. We used a 4-fold linear support vector machine (SVM; using linear kernel) classification for which we trained the classifier on 3 of the runs from the MID task while one run was left out for testing. We did this 4 times (4-folds) so that each run was a testing data set on one of the folds. We then averaged classification accuracies from each fold to create a measure of classification accuracy for each ROI for each participant. To obtain confidence intervals of the mean classification accuracy for each ROI, we used bootstrapping. We generated 1,000 datasets randomly by sampling with replacement from the classification accuracies for each ROI across participants using Matlab's bootci function.</p><p>First, we tested whether these classification accuracies for each ROI across participants were significantly above chance, indicating the ability to decode high reward vs no reward representations in that ROI. While the selected ROIs were chosen based on highly consistent univariate responsiveness to the MID task across different studies, they might not necessarily also represent reward anticipation in the multivariate domain. For hypothesis testing at the group level, we used a permutation analysis following the methods in Stelzer et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b100">100</ref> (also described in Tomova et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25</ref> ). This nonparametric approach does not depend on assumptions about the distribution of classification accuracies <ref type="bibr" target="#b100">100,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b101">101</ref> . To generate a null distribution from the data, we followed the steps described in Stelzer et al., which we summarize below. We shuffled the condition labels randomly during training within each run, and then used the same 4-fold cross-validation approach as in the original analysis to obtain prediction accuracies for each fold, which we then averaged to create a measure of classification accuracy for each ROI for each participant. We performed this permutation analysis 100 times per participant (thus creating 100 random permutations), resulting in 100 accuracy values per participant. To create a null distribution at the group level, we then randomly drew one of the 100 accuracy values for each participant and calculated a mean across participants. This procedure was repeated 10 5 times for each ROI, creating the null distributions for each ROI. We calculated the probability P of obtaining a mean accuracy value in the null distributions that is equal to or higher than the true mean from the analyses. Following Stelzer et al., we rejected the null hypothesis of no group-level decoding if P &lt; 0.001.</p><p>We were able to decode high reward vs no reward representations in all of our We used the classification accuracy obtained from each participant from the SVM classification as a measure of multivariate neural reward sensitivity for subsequent analyses.</p><p>For both measures of neural reward sensitivity (univariate and multivariate), we used Pearson correlations to test for an association between neural reward sensitivity and measures of reward seeking (RTs from the high reward / high effort conditions (mean across nature and social contexts)</p><p>in the EBDM task) and reward learning (learning_pos rates in the RL task) in the isolation session.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>∆ 80 ∆</head><label>80</label><figDesc>Loneliness (Iso total -Iso w media) ∆ RT (Iso total -Iso w media) Loneliness (Iso total -Iso w media)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>FIGURE</head><label></label><figDesc>Effects of isolation on reward learning -model results. A. Population-level mean posterior distributions of learning rates from positive prediction errors (learning_pos), learning rates from negative prediction errors (learning_neg) and inverse temperature (beta) for each session for each feedback type. The violin plots illustrate the posterior distributions for the population-level mean effects of the different conditions. The posterior distributions consist of 12,000 samples combined from four Monte Carlo Markov chains. The boxplots illustrate the interquartile range (IQR; box) and the centre lines signify medians. The whiskers extend from the hinge to at most 1.5 times the interquartile range. B. Difference in population-level mean posterior distributions for each pair of sessions (i.e., difference in iso total -baseline, iso with media -baseline and iso totaliso with media). Plots show the distributions for each feedback type (social, non-social). Rows show the difference distributions for each parameter (learning_pos rates, learning_neg rates and beta). The histograms depict the density of difference scores; the red dashed line indicates zero (no difference). The Bayes Factor in support of the alternative hypothesis (BF10) is shown for each pairwise comparison. BF10&gt;3 can be considered as meaningful evidence in support of the alternative hypothesis (i.e., that posterior distributions are different from zero meaning there is a difference between the sessions in this comparison).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>∆∆ 2 FIGURE</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Loneliness (Iso total -Iso w media) Loneliness (Iso total -Iso w media) Correlations between change in self-reported state loneliness and change in reward learning from negative feedback.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>FIGURE</head><label></label><figDesc>Neural reward sensitivity predicts effects of isolation on reward seeking. (a) Univariate group level activity family-wise error (FWE) corrected at the voxel level (p&lt;0.05) for the contrast High Reward &gt; No Reward during the anticipation phase of the MID task. (b) Brain reward signals predicting reward seeking in the EBDM after isolation (iso total) but not at baseline for univariate neural reward signals in occipital cortex. Plots depict individual data points, regression lines and confidence intervals (standard errors of the estimate)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>represent a neural signal of visual attention 56 towards cues predicting rewards. Thus, individual differences in such attention signals to rewards might represent the neural mechanism underlying the contribution of the occipital cortex to the behavioural change.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Subsequently, we collected</head><label></label><figDesc>functional data during four runs of the MID task. Each functional run consisted of 250 volumes with 96 T2*-weighted echo planar slices (TR = 1500 ms, TE = 25 ms, FOV = 192 mm, 128 x 128 matrix, yielding a voxel size of 1.5 x 1.5 x 1.5 mm 3 ) acquired as a partial-head volume in an anteroposterior phase-encoding direction using interleaved slices. The MID task took approximately 25 mins in total. Functional MRI: Neural Reward Sensitivity Using functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI), we measured blood-oxygen-leveldependent (BOLD) signal at a single voxel in successive scans (a voxel time-series) in response to anticipating rewards of different magnitudes during a monetary incentive delay (MID 67 ) task. The MID task is a well-established task used to study neural correlates of reward anticipation (i.e., winning money) and was used here as a marker of neural reward sensitivity. During the task, participants were able to win either £0.2 (small win) or £5 (large win), or lose £-0.2 (small loss),or £-5 (large loss). On some trials, participants did not win or lose any money, which served as control trials. On each trial, participants were first presented with a cue indicating whether they could win or lose money on that trial. The cue was a yellow star with the amount of the possible win (or loss) written inside (i.e., 0 (control trials), 0.2 (small win trials), 5 (large win trials), -0.2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>QuestionnairesBaseline.</head><label></label><figDesc>At the beginning of the behavioural testing in the baseline session, participants completed self-report questionnaires assessing trait and state anxiety (the State Trait Anxiety Index (STAI 68 )) and depression (the Center for Epidemiological Studies Depression (CES-D) scale) 69 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Pair 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Cherries &amp; Grapes Pair 2: Watermelon &amp; Banana Pair 3: Lemon &amp; Kiwi Participants were assigned an order (A,B,C). If A, they saw Pair 1 in their first session (baseline), Pair 2 in their second session, and Pair 3 in their third session. If order B, they saw Pair 2 in their first session (baseline), Pair 3 in their second session, and Pair 1 in their third session. If order C, they saw Pair 3 in their first session (baseline), Pair 1 in their second session, and Pair 2 in their third session.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Markov</head><label></label><figDesc>Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling using the mode of the posterior distribution as the summary parameter for individual participants. Four MCMC chains were used, with 1000 postwarmup iterations per chain, resulting in 4000 valid MCMC posterior samples. Model convergence was assessed by examining R-hat values, an index of the convergence of the chains 77 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>B Difference: iso total -iso w media Difference: iso total -baseline</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Difference: iso w media -baseline</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2 4 6 8 10 Density</cell><cell cols="4">BF 10 = 3.66 BF 10 = 3.29</cell><cell></cell><cell>BF 10 = 2.63 BF 10 = 1.24</cell><cell>BF 10 = 1.29 BF 10 = 1.05</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">-0.3 0</cell><cell cols="2">-0.2 -0.1</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.1 0.2 0.3</cell><cell>0.4</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">BF 10 = 1.58 BF 10 = 5.30</cell><cell></cell><cell>BF 10 = 1.98 BF 10 = 20.4</cell><cell>BF 10 = 1.53 BF 10 = 1.95</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="5">2 BF 10 = 4.98 BF 10 = 7.29 3</cell><cell></cell><cell>BF 10 = 16.0 BF 10 = 45.33</cell><cell>BF 10 = 4.98 BF 10 = 20.92</cell></row><row><cell>Social</cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Non-social</cell><cell cols="2">-1 0</cell><cell cols="2">-0.5 -0.75</cell><cell cols="3">0 -0.25 0.25</cell><cell>0.5</cell><cell>0.75</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Difference score</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The social homeostasis model suggests that prolonged engagement of mechanisms intended for short-term adaptation to state loneliness can cause pathological states during chronic loneliness<ref type="bibr" target="#b58">58</ref> . Prolonged increases in reward responsiveness during chronic loneliness might ultimately result in imbalances of the reward system, increasing proneness to developing compulsive behaviours, or a blunting of reward system activity. Indeed, longitudinal studies in humans consistently link chronic loneliness to depression and substance use<ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> . Here, there was an interaction between chronic and state loneliness on reward seeking: participants who reported higher pre-existing chronic loneliness showed stronger effects of isolation on reward seeking when</figDesc><table /><note>-life chronic loneliness is unknown. Chronic and state loneliness can have opposite effects on social behaviour .rewards were presented in social contexts. Further assessment of the relationship between state and chronic loneliness should address fundamental questions concerning the nature, origins and interrelations between loneliness and mental health problems in adolescence. Whether the observed effects are specific to adolescents or would also be observed in other age groups remains to be explored. As our study does not allow any inferences about age specificity or developmental differences, future studies including different age groups would provide insight into age-related effects of social isolation.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). This was based on a previous study showing that adolescents enjoy looking at pictures depicting social content more than looking at pictures of landscapes<ref type="bibr" target="#b72">72</ref> . The picture stimuli used in the present study were taken from Andrews et al. 2019. After successfully performing a trial, participants saw a message indicating how much they won (1 point or 4 points depending on the reward value of that trial) and pictures of landscapes (nature context; e.g., pleasant pictures of mountains, beaches, rivers, etc.) or social pictures (social context; e.g., pleasant pictures of people hugging, laughing together, etc.). Participants either saw 1 picture or 4 pictures, corresponding to the number of points they earned in that trial (i.e., 1 picture for 1 point and 4 pictures for 4 points). This allowed us to measure the extent to which effort-based decision-making was modulated by reward and whether isolation selectively enhanced reward seeking in social vs non-social contexts. In total, there were 8 conditions: high effort -high reward;</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>et al. 2017 for more details on model specification and parameter declaration 73 . To select a model that best captured the behaviour of participants, we first compared model fits between three different reversal learning models on the data from each session. Each model employs the Rescorla-Wagner value update rule 32 but differs in terms of how information is integrated. The Rescorla-Wagner update rule assumes that individuals assign and update internal stimulus value signals based on the prediction error, i.e., the mismatch between outcome (received</figDesc><table><row><cell>reward/punishment following choice of this stimulus) and prediction (expected value of choosing</cell></row><row><cell>this stimulus). The following models were compared:</cell></row><row><cell>(i) A reward-punishment model 31 , which expands the classic Rescorla-Wagner model of</cell></row><row><cell>conditioning 32 with separate learning rates for reward and punishment trials, here treating non-</cell></row><row><cell>wins as punishments:</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>selected ROIs: VS (mean accuracy=0.568, bootstrapped CI=0.540,0.594, P&lt;0.001); MB (mean accuracy=0.551, bootstrapped CI=0.525,0.582, P&lt;0.001); OC (mean accuracy=0.579, bootstrapped CI=0.552,0.606, P&lt;0.001); AI (mean accuracy=0.545, bootstrapped CI=0.521,0.573, P&lt;0.001); TH (mean accuracy=0.560, bootstrapped CI=0.534,0.592, P&lt;0.001); SMA (mean accuracy= 0.568, bootstrapped CI=0.536,0.601, P&lt;0.001); AMY (mean accuracy=0.506, bootstrapped CI=0.482, 0.534, P&lt;0.001).</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We calculated separate correlations for each ROI for each measure of neural reward sensitivity (univariate and multivariate; 14 tests in total) and report results as significant at p &lt; 0.003 (0.05/14)). ROI data analysis and visualization was implemented in Python (version: 3.7) using Jupyter notebooks (using packages PyMVPA, SciPy, Pandas, NumPy and Seaborn) and</p><p>Matlab2020a.</p><p>All statistical tests reported were performed two-tailed.</p><p>Data availability: All de-identified neuroimaging data will be publicly available on https://openneuro.org. Behavioural data will be publicly available on the open science framework (OSF). For peer-review we created a view-only link to access to the data: https://osf.io/2m9xs/?view_only=8f2e2a1cac8e489b95425b183f404611 . Author contributions: L.T. and S-J.B. designed the study with input from E.T. and K.T.; L.T., E.T. and K.T. collected the data; L.T. analysed the data with support from S-J.B., S.P., L.Z. and E.T. L.T. wrote the manuscript and all authors provided feedback on the final version.</p><p>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolutionary mechanisms for loneliness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Cacioppo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cacioppo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Boomsma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Emot</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The need to belong: desire for interpersonal attachments as a fundamental human motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baumeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Leary</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="497" to="529" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Less in-person social interaction with peers among US adolescents in the 21st century and links to loneliness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Twenge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Spitzberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Soc. Pers. Relatsh</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1892" to="1913" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Worldwide increases in adolescent loneliness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Twenge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Adolesc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="269" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Who Feels Lonely? The Results of the World&apos;s Largest Loneliness Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hammond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/articles/2yzhfv4DvqVp5nZyxBD8G23/who-feels-lonely-the-results-of-the-world-s-largest-loneliness-study" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Stability and Change of Loneliness Across the Life Span: A Meta-Analysis of Longitudinal Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Freuding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Möbius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Horn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Neyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personal. Soc. Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Peer-related loneliness across early to late adolescence: normative trends, intra-individual trajectories, and links with depressive symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Ladd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ettekal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Adolesc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1269" to="1282" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trajectories of loneliness during childhood and adolescence: Predictors and health outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Qualter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Adolesc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1283" to="1293" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Peer crowd affiliation and internalizing distress in childhood and adolescence: a longitudinal follow-back study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Prinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>La Greca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Res. Adolesc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adolescent Loneliness and Health in Early Adulthood</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Goosby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bellatorre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Walsemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cheadle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sociol. Inq</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceived social isolation, evolutionary fitness and health outcomes: a lifespan approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hawkley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Capitanio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philos. Trans. Biol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">370</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patterns, predictors, and outcome of the trajectories of depressive symptoms from adolescence to adulthood</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Essau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>De La Torre-Luque</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lewinsohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rohde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Depress. Anxiety</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The correlation between loneliness and substance use proclivity in child and adolescent substance users</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kayaoğlu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Okanlı</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Budak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Aslanoğlu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Subst. Use</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="70" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">More Depressive Symptoms, Alcohol and Drug Consumption: Increase in Mental Health Symptoms Among University Students After One Year of the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dogan-Sander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kohls</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Baldofski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Rummel-Kluge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Longitudinal within-and between-person associations of substance use, social influences, and loneliness among adolescents and emerging adults who use drugs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bonar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Addict. Res. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="262" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factors related to substance use among adolescents from six low-and middle-income countries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ozeylem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>De La Torre-Luque</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Essau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Addict. Behav. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social deprivation of neonatal, adolescent, and adult rats has distinct neurochemical and behavioral consequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Crit. Rev. Neurobiol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of early life stress on reward processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Novick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Psychiatr. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="103" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bayindir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Paisley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Digital vs Traditional Media Consumption. globalwebindex vol. Trend Repo</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loneliness and Social Internet Use: Pathways to Reconnection in a Digital World</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nowland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Necka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Cacioppo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspect Psychol Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="70" to="87" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internet paradox. A social technology that reduces social involvement and psychological well-being?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kraut</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1017" to="1031" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sociability</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Interpersonal Relations, and the Internet:Reconciling Conflicting Findings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="420" to="435" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Text Messaging, and Adolescent Social Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alison</forename><surname>Bryant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sanders-Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Smallwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Iming</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Comput.-Mediat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="577" to="592" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preadolescents&apos; and adolescents&apos; online communication and their closeness to friends</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Valkenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dev Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="277" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Acute social isolation causes midbrain craving responses similar to hunger</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomova</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Takahashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Saxe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1597" to="1605" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reliability and validity of the Danish version of the UCLA Loneliness Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lasgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personal. Individ. Differ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1359" to="1366" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">UCLA Loneliness Scale (Version 3): reliability, validity, and factor structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Assess</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revealed strength of preference: Inference from response times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Konovalov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgm. Decis. Mak</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="394" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confirmation bias in human reinforcement learning: Evidence from counterfactual feedback processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lefebvre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kilford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-J</forename><surname>Blakemore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Comput</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1005684</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling flexible behavior in childhood to adulthood shows agedependent learning mechanisms and less optimal learning in autism in each age group</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Crawley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3000908</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissociable effects of dopamine and serotonin on reversal learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">E M</forename><surname>Den Ouden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1090" to="1100" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of Pavlovian conditioning: Variations in the effectiveness of reinforcement and nonreinforcement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rescorla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Res. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">99</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The computational roots of positivity and confirmation biases in reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palminteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="607" to="621" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experience-weighted Attraction Learning in Normal Form Games</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hua Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="827" to="874" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining a role for ventromedial prefrontal cortex in encoding action-based value signals during reward-related decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gläscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Hampton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cereb. Cortex N. Y. N</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="483" to="495" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of the ventromedial prefrontal cortex in abstract state-based inference during decision making in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Hampton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bossaerts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O'doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8360" to="8367" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contributions of the amygdala to reward expectancy and choice signals in human prefrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Hampton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Adolphs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tyszka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="555" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the importance of avoiding shortcuts in applying cognitive models to hierarchical data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Matzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Res. Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1614" to="1631" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The JASP guidelines for conducting and reporting a Bayesian analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Van Doorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychon. Bull. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="826" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wetzels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bayesian analysis. Encycl. Clin. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using reinforcement learning models in social neuroscience: frameworks, pitfalls and suggestions of best practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lengersdorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mikus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gläscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lamm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Cogn. Affect. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="695" to="707" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How hierarchical models improve point estimates of model parameters at the individual level</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Katahira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Math. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The anticipation and outcome phases of reward and loss processing: A neuroimaging meta-analysis of the monetary incentive delay task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Oldham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Hum. Brain Mapp</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3398" to="3418" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Representation of Effort in Decision-Making and Motor Control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shadmehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1929" to="1934" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dorsal Raphe Dopamine Neurons Represent the Experience of Social Isolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">164</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="617" to="631" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Early social isolation in male Long-Evans rats alters both appetitive and consummatory behaviors expressed during operant ethanol selfadministration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mccool</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chappell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Alcohol. Clin. Exp. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="282" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Isolation rearing effects on probabilistic learning and cognitive flexibility in rats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Amitai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Affect. Behav. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="406" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Double dissociation of social and environmental stimulation on spatial learning and reversal learning in rats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">C A</forename><surname>Schrijver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Pallier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Würbel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Brain Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">152</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="314" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement learning across development: What insights can we draw from a decade of research?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Nussenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hartley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dev. Cogn. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">100733</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational reward learning account of social media engagement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lindström</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1311</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Homeostatic Regulation of Energetic Arousal During Acute Social Isolation: Evidence From the Lab and the Field</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Stijovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="537" to="551" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">THE PSYCHOBIOLOGY OF DEPRESSION AND RESILIENCE TO STRESS: Implications for</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Southwick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vythilingam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Charney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu Rev Clin Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="291" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bidirectional Associations Between Stress and Reward Processing in Children and Adolescents: A Longitudinal Neuroimaging Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Vidal-Ribas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biol. Psychiatry Cogn. Neurosci. Neuroimaging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="893" to="901" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ventral striatum reactivity to reward and recent life stress interact to predict positive affect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Nikolova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogdan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brigidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hariri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biol. Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="157" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brain activations associated with anticipation and delivery of monetary reward: A systematic review and meta-analysis of fMRI studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jauhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">255292</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Activity in primary visual cortex predicts performance in a visual detection task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ress</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Backus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Heeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="940" to="945" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chapter Three -Loneliness in the Modern Age: An Evolutionary Theory of Loneliness (ETL)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Cacioppo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cacioppo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="197" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural mechanisms of social homeostasis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tye</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1457</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Social Neuroscience Perspective on Adolescent Risk-Taking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Steinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dev Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="78" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing reward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Berridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="507" to="513" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of adolescent social experiences on behavior and neural circuits implicated in mental illnesses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Burke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mccormick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lukkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="280" to="300" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The REDCap consortium: Building an international community of software platform partners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Biomed. Inform</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103208</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The latent structure of loneliness: testing competing factor models of the UCLA loneliness scale in a large adolescent sample</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shevlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The social network-network: size is predicted by brain structure and function in the amygdala and paralimbic regions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Von</forename><surname>Der Heide</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Vyas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Olson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Cogn. Affect. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1962" to="1972" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The development of an instrument to measure social support</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Norbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lindsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carrieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nurs Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="264" to="269" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spatial distortion correction and crystal identification for MRIcompatible position-sensitive avalanche photodiode-based PET scanners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Chaudhari</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Nucl. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="549" to="556" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FMRI visualization of brain activity during a monetary incentive delay task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Knutson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Westdorp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kaiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hommer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">State-trait anxiety inventory for adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Spielberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The CES-D scale: A self-report depression scale for research in the general population</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Radloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Psychol. Meas</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="385" to="401" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development and validation of brief measures of positive and negative affect: the PANAS scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tellegen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1063</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Worth the &apos;EEfRT&apos;? The effort expenditure for rewards task as an objective measure of motivation and anhedonia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Treadway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Buckholtz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Schwartzman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Lambert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Zald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6598</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of social preference on academic diligence in adolescence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Andrews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Foulkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Griffin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Blakemore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">R. Soc. Open Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">190165</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revealing Neurocomputational Mechanisms of Reinforcement Learning and Decision-Making With the hBayesDM Package</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W.-Y</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Haines</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Separating probability and reversal learning in a novel Probabilistic Reversal Learning task for mice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Metha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Behav. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">270</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Averaged Karolinska Directed Emotional Faces -AKDEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lundqvist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Litton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Random effects structure for confirmatory hypothesis testing: Keep it maximal</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Barr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Scheepers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tily</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Mem Lang</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference from Iterative Simulation Using Multiple Sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Stat. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="472" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Stacking to Average Bayesian Predictive Distributions (with Discussion)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bayesian Anal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="917" to="1007" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ten simple rules for the computational modeling of behavioral data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How the Level of Reward Awareness Changes the Computational and Electrophysiological Signatures of Reinforcement Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M C</forename><surname>Correa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10338" to="10348" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical Bayesian parameter estimation for cumulative prospect theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nilsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Math. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rejecting or Accepting Parameter Values in Bayesian Estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Methods Pract. Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="270" to="280" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nipype: A Flexible, Lightweight and Extensible Neuroimaging Data Processing Framework in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Gorgolewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Neuroinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">fMRIPrep: a robust preprocessing pipeline for functional MRI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Esteban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Large-scale evaluation of ANTs and FreeSurfer cortical thickness measurements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tustison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="166" to="179" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cortical surface-based analysis. I. Segmentation and surface reconstruction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fischl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Sereno</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="194" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Segmentation of brain MR images through a hidden Markov random field model and the expectation-maximization algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Med. Imaging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Correction for geometric distortion in echo planar images from B0 field variations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Jezzard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Balaban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Magn. Reson. Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abraham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine Learning for Neuroimaging with Scikit-Learn. Frontiers in Neuroinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved optimization for the robust and accurate linear registration and motion correction of brain images</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jenkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bannister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="825" to="841" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A component based noise correction method (CompCor) for BOLD and perfusion based fMRI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Behzadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Restom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accurate and robust brain image alignment using boundary-based registration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Greve</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fischl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SUSAN-A New Approach to Low Level Image Processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Comput. Vis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MRIQC: Advancing the automatic prediction of image quality in MRI from unseen sites</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Esteban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">184661</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jenkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Beckmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E J</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Woolrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Fsl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="782" to="790" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What do differences between multi-voxel and univariate analysis mean? How subject-, voxel-, and trial-level variance impact fMRI analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="271" to="283" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Less Is More: Expectation Sharpens Representations in the Primary Visual Cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F M</forename><surname>Jehee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>De Lange</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention improves encoding of task-relevant features in the human visual cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F M</forename><surname>Jehee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8210" to="8219" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PyMVPA: a Python Toolbox for Multivariate Pattern Analysis of fMRI Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hanke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b100">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical inference and multiple testing correction in classification-based multi-voxel pattern analysis (MVPA): random permutations and cluster size control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stelzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="82" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b101">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valid population inference for informationbased imaging: From the second-level t-test to prevalence inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Allefeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Görgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-D</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">141</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
