<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Double Responding: A New Constraint for Models of Speeded Decision Making</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
							<email>nathan.j.evans@uon.edu.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gilles</forename><surname>Dutilh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Clinical Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Basel Hospital</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric-Jan</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Han</forename><forename type="middle">L J</forename><surname>Van Der Maas</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Double Responding: A New Constraint for Models of Speeded Decision Making</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Evidence accumulation models -Model mimicry -Double responding -Response time models</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Evidence accumulation models (EAMs) have become the dominant models of speeded decision making, which are able to decompose choices and response times into cognitive parameters that drive the decision process. Several models within the EAM framework contain fundamentally di↵erent ideas of how the decision making process operates, though previous assessments have found that these models display a high level of mimicry, which has hindered the ability of researchers to contrast these di↵erent theoretical viewpoints. Our study introduces a neglected phenomenon that we term &quot;double responding&quot;, which can help to further constrain these models. We show that double responding produces several interesting benchmarks, and that the predictions of di↵erent EAMs can be distinguished in standard experiment paradigms when they are constrained to account for the choice response time distributions and double responding behaviour in unison. Our findings suggest that lateral inhibition (e.g., the leaky-competing accumulator) provides models with a universal ability to make accurate predictions for these data. Furthermore, only models containing feed-forward inhibition (e.g., the di↵usion model) performed poorly under both of our proposed extensions of the standard EAM framework to double responding, suggesting a general inability of feed-forward inhibition to accurately predict these data. We believe that our study provides an important step forward in further constraining models of speeded decision making, though additional research on double responding is required before broad conclusions are made about which models provide the best explanation of the underlying decision-making process.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Understanding how humans make decisions has been a topic of great theoretical and applied interest within psychology, neuroscience, and economics, ranging from decisions as simple as what direction a cloud of dots is moving towards <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Pilly &amp; Seitz, 2009)</ref>, to decisions as complex as what risks to take in life or death situations <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">(Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1981)</ref>. The area of speeded decision making attempts to use quick, simple decisions to better understand the fundamental parts of the decision process. These tasks usually involve paradigms where participants make large numbers of quick decisions to simple stimuli and tasks (for examples, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Ratcli↵ &amp; Rouder, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Van Ravenzwaaij, Dutilh, &amp; Wagenmakers, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Evans, Rae, Bushmakin, Rubin, &amp; Brown, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dutilh et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Evans, Bennett, &amp; Brown, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Evans &amp; Hawkins, 2019)</ref>, and researchers are most commonly interested in the response given for each decision and the time taken to respond, with response speed and accuracy often known to trade o↵ with one another (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Luce, 1986)</ref>.</p><p>Evidence accumulation models (EAMs; <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Stone, 1960;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Laming, 1968;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Ratcli↵, 1978)</ref> have become the dominant models of speeded decision making, which are able to decompose the variables of response time and response choice into cognitive parameters that drive the decision process. Specifically, EAMs propose that evidence accumulates for each alternative at some rate (known as the "drift rate") until one alternative reaches some level of evidence (known as the "threshold") where a response is triggered. Several different models have been developed within the EAM framework that di↵er in the specifics of the proposed process, such as whether competition occurs between alternatives in accumulation (i.e., inhibition; <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Ratcli↵, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001</ref>), whether evidence decays over time <ref type="bibr">(i.e., leakage;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Busemeyer &amp; Townsend, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001)</ref>, and how these specific parts of the process might operate (e.g., lateral inhibition <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001]</ref> vs. feed-forward inhibition <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[Ratcli↵, 1978]</ref>). Importantly, each of these models reflect fundamentally di↵erent ideas of how the decision making process operates, with theoretically distinct components <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Teodorescu &amp; Usher, 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Despite the theoretical di↵erences between the models of speeded decision making, previous assessments have found that the models display a high level of mimicry: that is, that the predictions of the models can be di cult to distinguish from one another <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Ditterich, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Donkin, Brown, Heathcote, &amp; Wagenmakers, 2011)</ref>. Specifically, each of these models have been designed to account for several benchmark choice response time phenomena <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Ratcli↵, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Ratcli↵ &amp; Rouder, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Ratcli↵ &amp; Tuerlinckx, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brown &amp; Heathcote, 2008)</ref>, and in the majority of cases make accurate predictions about the choice response time distributions. Crucially, the joint success of these models in explaining empirical data -due to their mimicry in choice response time data from standard experimental paradigms -has "hinder[ed] the use of models as instruments for testing theories" <ref type="bibr">(Teodorescu &amp; Usher, 2013, p.2)</ref>, with researchers suggesting that they "cannot decide among competitive models that have the ability to mimic one" as "small di↵erences in data may rank order them di↵erently" <ref type="bibr">(Leite &amp; Ratcli↵, 2010, p.264)</ref>. One of the key goals of our study is to introduce a neglected phenomenon, "double responding" (explained in more detail below), which can help to further constrain these models. We show that double responding produces several interesting benchmarks, and that the predictions of di↵erent EAMs can be distinguished when they are constrained to account for the choice response time distributions and double responding behaviour in unison (without the need for novel experimental paradigms, such as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Teodorescu &amp; Usher, 2013)</ref>, with models that contain lateral inhibition generally making the most accurate predictions. However, this distinguishability did somewhat depend on the assumption about how double responses are triggered, with models that do not contain any inhibition providing almost equally accurate predictions as models that contain lateral inhibition under an alternative definition of the double responding process. However, these predictions were always distinguishable from models with feed-forward inhibition -such as the well-known di↵usion model <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Ratcli↵, 1978</ref>) -which universally failed to provide accurate predictions for these data.</p><p>Previous research within speeded decision making has been largely focused on only the variables of response choice (i.e., accuracy) and response time. However, the number of variables that could potentially be measured within rapid decision making is limitless, and attempting to measure and understand these variables can further our understanding of the decision making process. For example, another variable that has been previously investigated is choice confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b78">(Vickers &amp; Lee, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Ratcli↵ &amp; Starns, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pleskac &amp; Busemeyer, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Ratcli↵ &amp; Starns, 2013)</ref>, where researchers are not only interested in what choice a person makes, but also how confident they are in that choice. Several interesting phenomena have been found within the choice confidence literature, such as the "hard-easy e↵ect" <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Gigerenzer, Ho↵rage, &amp; Kleinbölting, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Rahnev &amp; Denison, 2018)</ref>, where participants tend to be over-confident when the task is hard, and underconfident when the task is easy. Interest in confidence has resulted in the development of models to explain these phenomena, which attempt to account for both response time and confidence, and mostly involve extensions of the standard EAM framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Ratcli↵ &amp; Starns, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pleskac &amp; Busemeyer, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Ratcli↵ &amp; Starns, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Moran, Teodorescu, &amp; Usher, 2015)</ref>. However, choice confidence has some limitations that prevent it from being a focus in "standard" rapid decision making investigations, as it requires the use of altered paradigms where participants are able to give a range of responses based on their confidence level, and there is no universal agreement on the best ways to make and model these measurements (e.g., one-stage <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[Ratcli↵ &amp; Starns, 2009</ref> vs. two-stage <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">[Van Zandt &amp; Maldonado-Molina, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pleskac &amp; Busemeyer, 2010]</ref>).</p><p>Although some additional variables require altered paradigms to measure, this is not necessarily the case for all potential variables of interest. One variable that can be easily measured within standard decision making paradigms is what we term "double responding"</p><p>(also see "error correcting responses"; <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Rabbitt &amp; Rodgers, 1977)</ref>, where after making a response in a speeded decision making task, participants make a second rapid response for another alternative. For example, in the classic two-alternative-forced-choice (2AFC) random dot motion task, where a participant has to decide whether a cloud of dots is moving towards the left or right of the screen, the participant may respond "left", but then straight afterwards also respond "right". This second "right" response is what we would term a "double response", and can be thought of as a "spillover" of information from the decision-making process. More specifically, in the context of EAMs, double responses reflect situations where di↵erent competing response alternatives each accumulate enough evidence to trigger a response in quick succession, where the evidence accumulation process continues despite a response having already been triggered for one alternative (i.e., the "spillover"). Double-responding provides additional information beyond response choice and response time on how the brain processes evidence in decision-making, which could be fundamental to better understanding the decision-making process as a whole; however, despite double responding being anecdotally observed, it is rarely studied.</p><p>One exception are the studies of Rabbit and colleagues <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Rabbitt, 1968;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Rabbitt &amp; Rodgers, 1977;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Rabbitt, 2002)</ref>, who assessed participants' "error correcting responses" (i.e., a subset of double responses where the initial response was an error), finding that these occurred regardless of whether or not participants were instructed to make them, and that these responses were substantially quicker than other responses used to signify an error.</p><p>Another similar area of investigation has been two-stage confidence judgments, where participants make an initial response in favour of an alternative, and then a second response for their level of confidence in their choice. In paradigms where the second confidence judgment allows participants to show greater confidence for the alternative that was not previously selected, researchers have attempted to model this change in preference in some cases <ref type="bibr">(see Van Zandt &amp; Maldonado-Molina, 2004</ref> for "response reversals", though note that their investigation did not model the choice response time distributions). However, these studies have focused on testing the ability of the models to explain the possibility of a change in preference based on the confidence calculation, and have not attempted to use this additional source of information to better understand the decision-making process as a whole. One other similar area of investigation has been "partial errors", where the motor movements of participants are recorded using electromyography (EMG), allowing researchers to detect trials where participants make initial movements towards the error response alternative, which they inhibit before making a response and then respond to correctly <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Coles, Gratton, Bashore, Eriksen, &amp; Donchin, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Burle, Spieser, Servant, &amp; Hasbroucq, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Servant, White, Montagnini, &amp; Burle, 2015)</ref>. Although these partial errors have mostly been assessed at a descriptive level, <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Servant et al. (2015)</ref> also performed simulations to compare the mean partial error latency observed in their flanker data to the predictions of EAMs variants adapted to conflict tasks. However, these simulations were only based on a single set of parameter values -those that provided the best fit to the regular choice response time distributions -and therefore, did not attempt to jointly assess partial errors and the choice response time distributions. Importantly, the assessment of double responding does not require altered experimental paradigms, psychophysiological data, or the large number of response alternatives used in many of the error correction studies of Rabbitt and colleagues, and is simply additional information that can be measured within any standard decision making task of interest.</p><p>From a theoretical perspective, double responding appears to fit within the broader "change of mind" literature, where researchers are interested in how people change their preferences during and/or after decisions. Initially, Rabbitt and colleagues <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Rabbitt, 1966</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Rabbitt, , 1967</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Rabbitt, , 1968</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Rabbitt, , 1969</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Rabbitt &amp; Rodgers, 1977;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Rabbitt, Cumming, &amp; Vyas, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Rabbitt &amp; Vyas, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Maylor &amp; Rabbitt, 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Rabbitt, 2002)</ref> were interested in people's ability to detect and correct errors, and how errors e↵ected subsequent responses (e.g., post-error slowing; <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Rabbitt, 1969)</ref>. Specifically, Rabbitt and colleagues found that people were able to detect most of their errors by making an "error detecting" response that was separate from other task responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Rabbitt et al., 1978)</ref>, though error detection was improved <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Rabbitt, 2002)</ref> and faster <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Rabbitt, 1968</ref>) when participants were required to "correct" their error by making the responses that they should have made (i.e., error correcting responses), and that these correcting responses were less e↵ected by reductions in the amount of time allowed for error detections to be made <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Rabbitt, 2002)</ref>. Post-error responses were also found to be faster when they were identical to the error correcting response, suggesting that post-error slowing may be due to a conflict between a desire to correct the previous response and to make the correct response to the current stimulus <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Rabbitt &amp; Rodgers, 1977;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Vickers &amp; Lee, 2000)</ref>. Recent research has taken neural approaches to assessing post-error behaviour <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Falkenstein, Hohnsbein, Hoormann, &amp; Blanke, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Yeung, Botvinick, &amp; Cohen, 2004)</ref>, and has had a greater focus on how people change their mind during a decision, using movement-based response mechanisms (e.g., hand/arm movement, a joystick, or electromyographic measurement) to assess how people change from favouring one alternative to another. Interestingly, people have been found to show changes of mind both in tasks that are intentionally designed with conflicting information <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Hasbroucq, Burle, Akamatsu, Vidal, &amp; Possamai, 2001)</ref>, as well as tasks that simply require sampling information from a noisy stimulus <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Resulaj, Kiani, Wolpert, &amp; Shadlen, 2009)</ref>. Furthermore, research into saccade-based response paradigms, which are common in research with macaque monkeys, has found that both humans and macaque monkeys display corrective saccades on some proportion of trials after making a saccade for the incorrect response <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Becker &amp; Jürgens, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Colby &amp; Goldberg, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Andersen &amp; Buneo, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Murthy et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Camalier et al., 2007)</ref>. All of these phenomena appear to show a common theoretical underpinning to double responding, where after an initial error participants either make another response, change the motor action of the current response, or alter their decision making on the subsequent trial.</p><p>Importantly, the additional information contained within double responding may provide critical constraint to distinguish between the di↵erent potential dynamics of the decision-making process. As discussed above, most EAMs can provide a good account of the choice response time distributions for most standard tasks (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Ratcli↵ &amp; Rouder, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brown &amp; Heathcote, 2008)</ref>, forcing researchers to extend these models to new paradigms to distinguish between their predictions <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Tsetsos, Gao, McClelland, &amp; Usher, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Teodorescu &amp; Usher, 2013)</ref>. However, another route to distinguish between models is constraining them to account for more sources of data, making it more di cult to accurately account for all sources of data. For example, accounting for the mean response time is a much easier task for models than accounting for the shape of the response time distribution, and therefore, accounting for the entire response time distribution can more clearly distinguish between models than accounting for only mean response times <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Luce, 1986)</ref>. Double responding provides an additional source of information about the decision-making process, serving as a behavioural manifestation of a spillover of information accumulation from the initial decision. EAMs also o↵er a somewhat natural extension to double responses, where evidence continues to accumulate after a response is made (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Rabbitt &amp; Vyas, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr">Busemeyer, 2010 for empirical validation of this idea, and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Maldonado-Molina, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Merkle &amp; Van Zandt, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pleskac &amp; Busemeyer, 2010</ref> for modelling frameworks that have used this "continued accumulation" assumption), and a double response is triggered if the evidence for the other alternative reaches the threshold. Therefore, double responses appear to provide a theoretically reasonable additional constraint for EAMs, which may provide a greater understanding of the dynamics of the decision-making process by distinguishing between the predictions of di↵erent models, which each represent a theoretically distinct decision process.</p><p>Our study aims to introduce double responding as a source of additional constraint for models of decision making, with double responding providing additional information about the complete decision-making process. As discussed above, double responding can be measured in standard decision making tasks, and can be easily recorded and analysed with little extra e↵ort from the experimenter. Our study assesses implicit double responding behaviour, where participants are not directly instructed to make a second response, and the observed double responses can be thought of as a motor output resulting from a spillover of information from the decision-making process. Our primary reason for choosing implicit double responding behaviour over explicit double responding behaviour (i.e., where participants are directly instructed that they are allowed to make a second response) is due to our desire to make inferences that are generalizable to regular 2AFC tasks, and that informing participants that they are able to change their responses may alter how they respond initially. For example, if participants are made aware that they can correct their errors for a fixed amount of time after their initial response, then they may become less cautious in their initial responding compared to situations when they are not provided with this information (see also interference e↵ects in decision-making tasks that involve initial responses; <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Kvam, Pleskac, Yu, &amp; Busemeyer, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Yearsley &amp; Pothos, 2016)</ref>. However, we believe that the assessment of explicit double responding behaviour is also an important avenue for future research, and we discuss the potential strengths and limitations of both implicit and explicit double responding in the discussion section.</p><p>More specifically, we aim to make two key contributions that showcase how double responding can further our understanding of the decision-making process. First, our study provides some general assessments on summary statistics relating to double responding, in order to gain a better understanding of when double responding occurs, and create potential qualitative benchmarks for models of decision-making to meet. Second, our study uses double responding to assess and compare di↵erent EAMs of decision making, in order to see which models are able to naturally account for this additional source of data within their framework, and therefore, which model provides the most accurate account of the dynamics of the decision-making process.</p><p>Experiment 1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Dutilh, Vandekerckhove, Tuerlinckx, &amp; Wagenmakers, 2009)</ref> Our first experiment uses the data from <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dutilh et al. (2009)</ref>, who aimed to understand how the latent components of the decision process -as formalized in the di↵usion model <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Ratcli↵, 1978)</ref> -changed across practice. Specifically, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dutilh et al. (2009)</ref> collected 25 blocks of trials from each participant, fitting the di↵usion model to each of these blocks to assess which parameters changed over practice, and the manner in which they changed.</p><p>Although double responding was recorded within this experiment, the focus of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dutilh et al. (2009)</ref> was purely on the response time and choice of each trial (and the di↵usion model parameters estimated from them), and double responding was not mentioned within their article. We believe that this data set provides a particularly good starting point for assessing double responding as it contained a large number of trials per participants (10,000), allowing for a detailed assessment of double responding even if their occurrence is quite rare. Furthermore, as discussed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Smith and Little (2018)</ref>, experimental designs with a large number of trials per participant provide a powerful design for making inferences about individuals, and each participant can be considered a replicate for the inference. Full details of the experimental setup can be found in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dutilh et al. (2009)</ref>, though we provide a brief outline below Method Experiment Details. Four native Dutch speakers each completed 10,000 trials of a lexical decision task, where participants were presented with a letter string on each trial and had to identify, via button press, whether or not the letter string was a (Dutch) word (i.e., "word" or "nonword"). Speed emphasis was used as a between-subjects manipulation, with participants either being told to focus on responding quickly, even if it meant decreases in accuracy (2 participants), or responding accurately, even if it took a little longer (2 participants). Once participants had made an initial response any additional responses were recorded for the following 250ms, as this was the minimum possible amount of time between trials. We defined "double responses" as being a response after the initial response for the opposite alternative, meaning that second responses for the original response were not considered. For example, in the lexical decision task, a double response would be if a participant initially responded that a letter string was a "nonword", but then less than 250ms after this response also responded "word".</p><p>Theoretical Models. In addition to basic assessments of double responses, we also extended a series of decision making models to incorporate this phenomenon. Specifically, all models were defined within the evidence accumulation framework, where evidence accumulates for each decision alternative until a threshold level of evidence is reached for one response, and the response is triggered. To incorporate double responding into the models, we assumed that the evidence continues to accumulate for each alternative after the initial response, which is in line with previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Rabbitt &amp; Vyas, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pleskac &amp; Busemeyer, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Resulaj et al., 2009)</ref>, as well as one of the potential verbal explanations proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Rabbitt and Vyas (1981)</ref> for the occurrence of error correcting responses. If the threshold of level of evidence is reached for the alternative that was not the initial response (i.e., the losing alternative) within 250ms (i.e., the amount of time available for double responses in the task), we assumed that this caused a second response to be triggered, resulting in a "double response" occurring. A diagram of this process can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. In this example, the orange accumulator reaches the threshold first, triggering a response. B: A diagram of our extension from the standard decision process to the double responding process, where the evidence continues to accumulate after a decision is triggered. The orange and green accumulators are replaced by red and blue accumulators, respectively, after the initial decision is made, for clarity on when the double responding process begins. In this example, the blue accumulator reaches the threshold after the initial orange response, triggering a double response for the green/blue alternative. C: Another example of a decision process that would result in a double response, where the orange/red alternative remains above the threshold. D: An example of a decision process that would not result in a double response.</p><p>We defined a "tree" of 9 models to test, based on the inclusion or exclusion of a series of components that are commonly included in EAMs: feed-forward inhibition <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Ratcli↵, 1978)</ref>, lateral inhibition <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">(Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001)</ref>, and leakage <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Busemeyer &amp; Townsend, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Ratcli↵ &amp; Smith, 2004)</ref>. Our most basic model was a stochastic di↵usion process with only a drift rate for each alternative, a threshold level of evidence, a random uniform distribution of starting evidence, and some time dedicated to non-decision processes 1 . This is commonly known as the "racing di↵usion model" <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Tillman &amp; Logan, 2017)</ref>, where the continuous evidence accumulation for alternative i can be formally written as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">dx i = [v i ] dt + [ i ✏] p dt (1)</formula><p>where x i is the evidence for alternative i, v i is the drift rate for alternative i, ✏ is a random variable from the univariate (i.e., independent noise between accumulators) standard normal distribution that provides the within-trial noise, i is the scale of the within-trial noise for alternative i, and t is time.</p><p>From this base model, we added either feed-forward inhibition, lateral inhibition, or leakage parameter to the base model, to create an additional 3 models. Feed-forward inhibition reduces future evidence accumulation based on the accumulation rates of the other alternatives, and can be formally written as an extension of the base model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">dx i = [v i n X j6 =i v j ] dt + [ i ✏ n X j6 =i j ✏] p dt (2)</formula><p>where is a parameter that controls the amount of inhibition, and n is the number of response alternatives. Note that the feed-forward inhibition is applied to both the drift rate and the within-trial noise (in both Equations 2 and 5), meaning that the noise processes of the di↵erent accumulators have a perfect negative correlation with one another. We also created a restricted feed-forward inhibition model with fixed at 1, which is mathematically equivalent to the di↵usion model <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bogacz, Brown, Moehlis, Holmes, &amp; Cohen, 2006)</ref>.</p><p>Lateral inhibition reduces future evidence accumulation based on the previously accumulated evidence for the other alternatives, and can be formally written as an extension of the base model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">dx i = [v i n X j6 =i x j ] dt + [ i ✏] p dt<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Leakage reduces the accumulated evidence for an alternative, and can be formally written as an extension of the base model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">dx i = [v i x i ] dt + [ i ✏] p dt (4)</formula><p>where is the leakage rate.</p><p>From here, we added leakage to each potential type of inhibition, creating another 3 models, giving 8 in total. The feed-forward inhibition model with leakage was defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">dx i = [v i x i n X j6 =i v j ] dt + [ i ✏ n X j6 =i j ✏] p dt<label>(5)</label></formula><p>and again, we created a restricted feed-forward inhibition model with fixed at 1 and leakage, which is equivalent to the Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Busemeyer &amp; Townsend, 1993)</ref>. The lateral inhibition model with leakage was defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">dx i = [v i x i N X j6 =i x j ] dt + [ i ✏] p dt<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Lastly, we added an evidence truncation at 0 (i.e., evidence cannot be negative) to the lateral inhibition with leakage model, which gave a final model that reflected the leakycompeting accumulator (LCA; <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001</ref>). The full tree of models can be seen in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>, and code for all models can be found on OSF (https://osf.io/7jmb2/).  <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Ratcli↵, 1978)</ref> Fixed at 1</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">LI X Leak X FFI + Leak X X OU (Busemeyer &amp; Townsend, 1993) Fixed at 1 X LI + Leak X X LCA (Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001) X X X</formula><p>Note that for the model fitting process we excluded trials with extremely fast response times (&lt; 250ms; used in both Experiment 1 and Experiment 2), as these responses are likely too fast to be the result of the regular decision process. All models were fit using Bayesian parameter estimation, where we estimated the posterior distributions using Di↵erential Evolution Markov chain Monte Carlo <ref type="bibr">(DE-MCMC;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Ter Braak, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Turner, Sederberg, Brown, &amp; Steyvers, 2013)</ref>, as this appeared to provide a superior method for traversing the complex likelihood space than regular maximum likelihood estimation fitting. However, as our current study is mostly interested in the broad, qualitative predictions of the models, comparisons between models were largely made using 1,000,000 simulated predictions from the models using the posterior sample that had the highest probability of the data given the parameters (i.e., P (D|✓), which is the maximum likelihood estimate under the assumption that the priors are su ciently broad to include the maximum likelihood estimate), rather than formal model selection metrics that involve the entire posterior distribution. To ensure robustness, the highest P (D|✓) (i.e., maximum likelihood) was determined by fitting each model 5 independent times (to minimize the potential influence of local maxima), obtaining the 50 highest P (D|✓) samples from each independent fit and averaging over 50 pseudo-likelihood estimates for each of these samples (to minimize the potential influence of simulation noise), and taking the sample (out of all 250 samples across the 5 fits) with the highest averaged P (D|✓). However, as we discuss below, we also include a complementary quantitative comparison using the Bayesian information criterion (BIC; <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Schwarz, 1978)</ref>, which uses the same method as above to find the maximum likelihood estimate.</p><p>Specifically, we assessed the ability of the models to account for the empirical data using defective cumulative density function (CDF) plots, plotting the empirical response time distributions for correct and incorrect responses against the model predicted distributions.</p><p>An example of a CDF plot can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, which displays the RDM predictions for participant S1 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dutilh et al. (2009)</ref> when jointly fitting choice response time distributions and double response proportions. The dots display the defective cumulative density function for the empirical response time distributions, with di↵erent dots displaying di↵erent quantiles of the distributions (reflected by the y-axis), and the crosses with joining lines display the defective cumulative density function for the model predictions.</p><p>Green dots/crosses/lines indicate correct initial responses, whereas red dots/crosses/lines indicate incorrect initial responses. The double response proportions are positioned at x = 0, with their position on the y-axis indicating the number of double responses after correct (green) and incorrect (red) initial responses, for the empirical data (dots) and model predictions (crosses). A close match between the dots and the crosses indicate an accurate account of the data, and greater discrepancies between the dots and crosses indicate greater misfit. As can be seen, there is a large amount of misfit for the predictions of the RDM, with the RDM predicting response time distributions with greater variance than the empirical data (crosses cover more of the x-axis than the dots), a higher accuracy than the empirical data (the final green cross finishes above the final green dot on the y-axis), and a higher proportion of double responses than the empirical data (crosses at x = 0 are higher on the y-axis than the dots). As our current study is mostly interested in the broad, qualitative predictions of the models, and how they compare to the empirical data, our comparisons are mostly based upon the visual fit and misfit of each model within the CDF plots <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Navarro, 2019)</ref>. However, to ensure that our inferences were not biased by our choices in which qualitative trends to assess <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Evans, 2019c)</ref>, we also provide a comparison between the models using BIC, which has been found to provide similar inferences to Bayes factors with uninformative priors in many situations <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Evans, 2019a)</ref>. times for the initial response) and double response proportions for correct (green; P(DR|C) in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>) and error (red; P(DR|E) in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>) initial responses. The x-axis displays the response times, and the y-axis displays the response proportions, with the double response proportions placed at 0 on the x-axis, to avoid confusion with the standard choice response time distributions. This format continues throughout CDF plots in subsequent figures.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • 0<label>.</label></formula><p>As the likelihood functions for most of our extended models are unknown, we used probability density approximation to obtain the likelihood function for the models <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Turner &amp; Sederberg, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Holmes, 2015)</ref>, which approximates the likelihood function using simulations from the model with a density kernel approximation. Specifically, for the two-choice task of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dutilh et al. (2009)</ref>, the probability of an initial response occurring at time t for alternative i followed by a double response for other alternative j was given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">f i (t) ⇥ F DR j (t DR max )<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where f (t) is the probability density function of the model for the initial response,</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">F DR (t)</formula><p>is the cumulative density function of the model for the double response (i.e., conditioned on an initial response having already been made, with t DR = 0 being the initial response), and t DR max is the maximum time available for a double response after an initial response, which in this experiment was 250ms. When assessing the double response times, the probability of an initial response occurring at time t for alternative i followed by a double response at time t DR for alternative j was given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">f i (t) ⇥ f DR j (t DR )<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where f DR (t) is the probability density function of the model for the double response. The probability of an initial response occurring at time t for alternative i followed by no double response was given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">f i (t) ⇥ S DR j (t DR max )<label>(9)</label></formula><p>where S DR (t) is the survivor density function of the model for the double response. Importantly, this means that the models are not only constrained by the occurrence of a double response, but also the lack of occurrence of a double response, as models will be punished for both predicting too many, or too few, double responses. All models were simulated using Euler's method (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Brown, Ratcli↵, &amp; Smith, 2006</ref>) with a time-step of 5ms, through the simulation method and framework of <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Evans (2019b)</ref>, and the density kernels for the PDA were created using 10,000 simulated trials each.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Assessment of Empirical Trends. To begin, we provide some descriptive assessments of the performance of all four participants, and in particular, their double responding tendencies. These data can be seen in Rather, our aim is to provide a complete description of the trends in this sample of data for interested readers (similar to previous studies that evaluate EAMs based on a small number of participants; e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Ratcli↵ &amp; Rouder, 1998)</ref>, and then assess whether these trends are also present in Experiment 2, which uses a within-subjects manipulation of emphasis and a greater number of participants.</p><p>As can be seen, the participants who completed the experiment under speed emphasis (columns 1 and 2) have faster mean response times and lower proportions of correct responses than the participants who completed the experiment under accuracy emphasis (columns 3 and 4), which suggests that the emphasis instructions were adhered to. Interestingly, those under accuracy emphasis made very few double responses, whereas those in the speed condition made relatively more double responses. However, in all cases the number of double responses is relatively small, occurring on under 2.6% of trials at most. Double responses also very rarely occurred after correct responses, but occurred relatively more often after error responses (i.e., after up to 12.75% of errors). In addition, those in the speed condition were more likely to make a double response after an error, suggesting that the greater number of double responses in the speed condition were a result of more than just the greater number of errors made. However, this did not appear to be due to responses being faster under speed emphasis, as the trial response time and whether a double response was made showed little relation to one another (and in general, more double responses occurred after slower responses). Lastly, double responses did not appear to occur more often at certain parts of the experiment, nor did they appear to show any clear first order autocorrelation. To gain some further insight on double responses, we also provide some descriptive assessments of the double response time (DRT) distributions for the two participants who made a large number of double responses (i.e., the two participants under speed emphasis). These distributions can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>, where both participants appear to show quite similar trends in their distributions. Interestingly, the DRT distributions appear to resemble the RT distributions of standard responses, showing a positive skew. The ma-jority of double responses occur very rapidly after the initial response, suggesting that they serve as quick, almost identically timed, "corrections" (i.e., mostly following error responses), though continue in smaller amounts out until the deadline. Another interesting question involving response time distributions is whether the initial responses on trials with double responses appear to be similar to those on regular trials, or whether the responses preceding double responses appear to be due to some other process (e.g., fast guessing; <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Vandekerckhove, Tuerlinckx, &amp; Lee, 2008)</ref>, which may be part of the reason for the additional response occurring afterwards. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> plots the standard response time distributions for trials with and without double responses for each of the two participants above. As can be seen, there does not appear to be any clear qualitative di↵erence between response times before double responses and those without double responses, and trials with double responses do not appear to have initial responses that are fast guesses.   distributions for trials that did have double responses following them. In general, these distributions seem to be fairly similar to one another, suggesting that double responses aren't clearly due to a non-standard decision process occurring during these trials.</p><p>Assessment of Theoretical Models. To begin assessing our tree of models in their ability to account for these data, we fit the models to the standard choice response time distributions of each participant. Although this is not the main question of interest, this provided an important baseline assessment, as all models should be able to provide a good account of these data. As suspected, all models provided a good account of the choice response time distributions, showing minor misfit at most (Figures 5 and 6). We also compared the models in their ability to account for only (i.e., ignoring the response time distributions) the double response proportions ( <ref type="figure">Figures 5 and 6</ref>). All models appear to provide a quantitatively accurate account of the double response proportions, though this is probably not surprising as each model contains at least 5 parameters and is only being fit to 2 data points (i.e., the proportions of double responses after corrects and errors), meaning that fitting to purely the double response proportions is likely not adequate to properly constrain these models.</p><p>Response Time Response Time</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •</formula><p>Response Proportion Response Proportion S1 S2 <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. CDF plots of the empirical and model predicted response time distributions and double response proportions for correct and error initial responses (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description). Di↵erent sub-plots show the fits of di↵erent models, with the naming conventions given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. The figure contains the fits -performed separately for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., allowing di↵erent parameter values for each type of data)</p><p>-for the two participants in the speed emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (S1), and the right half being the other (S2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Time</head><p>Response Time</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">• • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •</formula><p>Response Proportion Response Proportion A1 A2 <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description) -performed separately for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., allowing di↵erent parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the accuracy emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (A1), and the right half being the other (A2).</p><p>Next, we fit the models jointly to the choice response time distributions and the double response proportions, in order to provide greater constraint on the models and hopefully better distinguish between their predictions (see Equations 7, 8, and 9 in the Theoretical Models section for a complete explanation of how the joint fits were performed).</p><p>These fits can be seen in Figures 7 and 8, and seem to provide large distinctions between the models. Firstly, all models appear to provide a poorer account of both the response time distributions and double responses when fit jointly compared to when fit separately, suggesting that using double responses as an additional constraint provides a more di cult test for the models. Secondly, the models seem to be most clearly distinguished in their ability to account for the data by their type of inhibition implemented. The models with no inhibition (i.e., RDM, Leak) appear to provide the worst account of the data, greatly overpredicting the accuracy and later response time quantiles, as well as the double responses.</p><p>The models with feed-forward inhibition, regardless of whether the feed-forward inhibition was included as a free parameter (i.e. FFI, FFI + Leak) or fixed at 1 (i.e., DM, OU), provide a better account of the data, with an improvement in fit to the response time distributions and a closer prediction of the double response proportions. In general, the free parameter feed-forward inhibition appears to capture the response time distributions slightly better than the fixed feed-forward inhibition models, though not by a large amount.</p><p>Lastly, the models with lateral inhibition (i.e., LI, LI + Leak, LCA) appear to clearly provide the best account of the data, fitting the response time distributions at least as well as the feed-forward inhibition models, while also providing a better account of the double response proportions. The BIC values in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> appear to provide quantitative confirmation of these qualitative di↵erences in predictions, with the models that contain lateral inhibition strongly outperforming all other models on BIC. At an absolute level, the fit of the lateral inhibition models all appear to provide an accurate account of the data, and most importantly, provide accurate predictions for the double response proportions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Time Response Time</head><formula xml:id="formula_14">• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •</formula><p>Response Proportion Response Proportion S1 S2 <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description) -performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the speed emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (S1), and the right half being the other (S2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Time</head><p>Response Time</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">• • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• • • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •••• • • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •</formula><p>Response Proportion Response Proportion A1 A2 <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description) -performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the accuracy emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (A1), and the right half being the other (A2). We also assessed how well the models could account for the double response time distributions, for the two participants with a large number of double responses. <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref> displays the ability of the models to account for these data without the additional constraint of the response time distributions. All models provide an accurate account of the double response proportions, as with the fits to only the double response proportions. However, when looking at how well the models predict the double response time distributions (i.e., the di↵erent quantiles), the data show a tight clustering of early quantiles, which indicates a positively skewed distribution (as shown before in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>). However, all models predict fairly evenly spaced quantiles, which indicates a distribution with equal mass throughout (i.e., a uniform distribution). Therefore, all of these models appear to have some problems with accounting for the double response time distributions. In addition, this problem only appears to worsen when fit to the choice response time and double response time distributions jointly. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref> only plots the fits to the double response time distributions from these joint fits, as the fits to the choice response time distributions remained fairly similar to those from the double response proportions. Interestingly, although the independent models still predict a fairly uniform distribution, they now greatly miss on the proportions. In addition, all other models appear to predict distributions with either a uniform distribution or with a negative skew, which is inconsistent with the empirical data (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 11</ref> for a visual comparison between the probability density functions of the empirical data and the LCA predictions). Therefore, although the lateral inhibition models appear to provide a good account of double response proportions, even when being jointly constrained by the choice response time distributions, no model appears to be able to account for the shape of the double response time distributions. S1 S2</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">• • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • •• • •• ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • •</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion Response Proportion</head><p>Response Time</p><p>Response Time <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description) of the empirical and model predicted double response time distributions for correct and error initial responses. The x-axis displays the double response times, and the y-axis displays the double response proportions. Di↵erent sub-plots show the fits of di↵erent models, with the naming conventions given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. The figure contains the fits -performed separately for the response time distributions and the double response time distributions (i.e., allowing di↵erent parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the speed emphasis condition in Experiment 1 (left half: S1; right half: S2).</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">• • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • • • • • • ••• ••• • • • • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • ••• •• • •• •• ••• • • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• • • • ••• ••• ••• •• ••• • • • 0.00 0.10 0.20 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • ••• • •• • •• • • ••• ••• •</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion Response Proportion</head><p>Response Time</p><p>Response Time S2 S1 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description) of the empirical and model predicted double response time distributions for correct and error initial responses, based on fits that were performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response time distributions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the speed emphasis condition in Experiment 1 (left half: S1; right half: S2). Other details about the figure can be found in the caption for Data LCA <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 11</ref>. Probability density function (PDF) plots of the double response time distributions after error responses for the two participants (di↵erent plots) in the speed emphasis condition of Experiment 1. Blue lines plot the empirical data, and red lines plot the predictions of the LCA when jointly fit to the response time distributions and the double response time distributions (i.e., the PDF equivalent of the CDF plots in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref> for the LCA). As can be seen, the empirical data show a positive skew in the double response time distributions, whereas the LCA predicts more uniform distributions.</p><p>Why does lateral inhibition help in accounting for double responding?. In our assessment of the di↵erent theoretical models of speeded decision-making, only the models with lateral inhibition were able to provide an accurate joint account of the choice response time distributions and the double response proportions. Importantly, the choice response time distributions alone were unable to qualitatively distinguish between these models, meaning that the additional constraint provided by the double response proportions created this distinction. However, our previous analyses only provided limited insight into why lateral inhibition helped in accounting for the double response proportions (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Evans, 2019c;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Evans &amp; Servant, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Crüwell, Stefan, &amp; Evans, 2019</ref> for discussions on the importance of which and why in model assessment), with the only insight being that models without lateral inhibition provided a large over-prediction for the double response proportions, particularly for trials where an error was made for the initial response.</p><p>In order to provide further insight into why models with lateral inhibition were able to provide a superior account of double responding behaviour, we plotted the accumulation process predicted for the correct and error accumulators (green and red lines, respectively) by each model after an initial error, separated by whether or not a double response was made. Specifically, for each model we simulated the evidence accumulation process of 100,000 trials for 250ms each using the best fitting set of parameters for each participant.</p><p>We then separated the accumulation processes based on whether (1) the initial response was correct or an error, and (2) whether a double response was made, and averaged over accumulation processes within each category. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 12</ref> displays these averaged accumulation processes for initial error responses -using the best fitting set of parameters for participant S1, with the other participants shown in the Supplementary Materials -for three models:</p><p>Leak, OU, and LCA. These models each contain a leakage component, though di↵er in their type of inhibition, using no inhibition, feed-forward inhibition fixed at 1, and freely estimated lateral inhibition, respectively.</p><p>As can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 12</ref>, there appear to be clear di↵erences in the accumulation trajectories after an error for each model. First and foremost, OU shows a qualitatively di↵erent pattern to the other two models, which may explain its large over-prediction of double responses following errors. On both trials with and without a double response, the correct response accumulator starts a long -and similar -distance from the threshold.</p><p>For the 18.3% of trials that result in a double response, the average accumulation for the correct response alternative quickly accumulates towards the threshold, reaching it at approximately 200ms; well before the double response deadline. The 81.7% of trials without a double response show the same pattern, though with a slower average accumulation that does not reach the threshold before the double response deadline. Intuitively, one might assume that the OU (and the di↵usion model) would predict a very small number of double responses due to the feed-forward inhibition during the initial response, as the correct accumulator would have to travel a long distance to reach the threshold before the double response deadline. However, the distance that the correct accumulator is required to travel to reach the threshold appears to be quite small relative to its much larger drift rate. Furthermore, feed-forward inhibition only reduces future evidence accumulation based on the accumulation rates of the other alternatives, and contains no inhibition based on previously accumulated evidence for the other alternatives. Therefore, the initially high evidence for the error alternative does little to stop the correct alternative from quickly accumulating evidence after the initial response, which also results in the error alternative quickly losing evidence due to the feed-forward inhibition.</p><p>In contrast, the pattern of accumulation between Leak and LCA appear to be much closer to one another, showing many similarities. For both models, trials with a double response have a noticeably higher amount of initial evidence for the correct response alternative than trials without a double response, suggesting that the distance between the correct and error accumulators when the initial response occurs plays a large role in whether a double response occurs. The major di↵erence between the models in their patterns of accumulation appears to be how often the correct accumulator is close to the error accumulator after the initial response, and how quickly the correct accumulator is able to accumulate after the initial error response. For LCA, in 92.1% of trials the correct accumulator starts a reasonable distance below the error accumulator, and due to the lateral inhibition between accumulators, the accumulation for the correct accumulator is suppressed, resulting in the correct accumulator (on average) decreasing in evidence over this accumulation period. On the other 7.9% of trials the correct accumulator starts closer to the error accumulator, meaning that the lateral inhibition provides less suppression of the correct accumulator and more suppression of the error accumulator, resulting in the correct accumulator slowly accumulating evidence and moving beyond the threshold, while the error accumulator decreases in evidence over this time. In contrast, for Leak the correct accumulator is able to accumulate evidence in all cases, and does so more quickly than in the case of the LCA. This is a result of Leak not containing lateral inhibition, meaning that the initially higher accumulated evidence for the error alternative is not able to suppress accumulation for the correct alternative. In 61.7% of cases the correct accumulator starts close enough to the threshold to cross it before the double response deadline, and only starts far enough away from the threshold on 38.3% of trials to avoid crossing it.</p><p>These patterns of accumulation appear to provide a fairly clear and intuitive explanation for why lateral inhibition is able to help in accurately predicting double responses, as these models are able to avoid over-predicting this trend through the suppression of evidence accumulation for the correct response alternative. An alternative definition for how double responses are triggered. The primary goal of our study was to introduce double responding as a new constraint for EAMs, which required extending the standard EAM framework to incorporate double responses. Our definition in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> attempted to provide the most natural extension of the standard EAM framework, with accumulation continuing after the initial decision, and a double response being triggered by the other accumulator hitting the threshold. However, our definition is only one of a large number of possibilities, and the choice of extension could potentially influence the conclusions regarding which model provides the best account of these data. Although we believe that it would be infeasible to implement all possible extensions within our current study, here we implement another simple definition that we believe is theoretically sensible, which can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 13</ref>. This definition -which we term the "alternative definition" -is based on the potential proposal that double responding should not occur in cases where the evidence for the initial response is still higher than for the other alternative, and therefore, double responses should only occur when the initial response has dropped below the threshold. Furthermore, based on the predicted evidence accumulation plots in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 12</ref>, this definition may potentially greatly help models without inhibition, as these models provide a large over-prediction of double response proportions, though in many of these cases the evidence for the initial response never drops back below the threshold. Specifically, the alternative definition is identical to the "primary definition"</p><p>in every aspect except one: in the alternative definition a double response is only triggered if both (1) the accumulated evidence for the other alternative reaches the threshold, and</p><p>(2) the accumulated evidence for the initial response alternative drops below the threshold.</p><p>This di↵erence can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures 1C and 13C</ref>, which results in a double response under the primary definition, but does not under the alternative definition. Furthermore, our standard definitions of the di↵erent models only allowed for between-trial variability in the starting amount of evidence for each accumulator. However, two additional between-trial variability parameters are often included in EAMs, as they are able to capture certain benchmark phenomena often observed in empirical data: between-trial variability in drift rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Ratcli↵, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brown &amp; Heathcote, 2008)</ref>, and between-trial variability in non-decision time <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Ratcli↵ &amp; Tuerlinckx, 2002)</ref>. Importantly, these betweentrial variability parameters provide the models with greater flexibility, which may allow them to capture additional trends, and even potentially the pattern of double responding.</p><p>Here we also implement each of the models including all three between-trial variability parameters. <ref type="figure">Figures 7 and 8)</ref> provide the results of Experiment 1 with the alternative definition for how double responses are triggered and the inclusion of all three between-trial variability parameters. Note that we only include the fits with both the alternative definition and the between-trial variability parameters here, as changing either one of these factors separately did not result in any qualitatively di↵erent conclusions about the data, and these separate fits can be seen in the Supplementary Materials. As can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures 14 and 15</ref>, the combination of all three types of between trial variability parameters and the alternative definition of double responding greatly improves the ability of the models without inhibition to account for double responding, with the RDM and Leak models providing a qualitatively similar fit to the models with lateral inhibition for participants S1 and S2, which is also reflected in the RDM outperforming all other models on BIC for these participants <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">(Table 4)</ref>. The models without inhibition also provide an improved account of participants A1 and A2, though they (1) still appear to be qualitatively inferior to the models with lateral inhibition, and (2) provide this improved account at the expense of being able to account for the tails of the error choice response time distributions, with both of these issues being reflected in the lateral inhibition models outperforming the models without inhibition on BIC <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">(Table 4)</ref>. Therefore, based on the participants in the accuracy emphasis condition, the models with lateral inhibition still appear to provide an overall superior account of double responding, though this is only a slight advantage when jointly considering all three between-trial variability parameters and this alternative definition of double responding. Furthermore, it should be noted that the models with forced feed-forward inhibition (i.e., the DM and OU) remain inferior to all other models, and the models with freely estimated feed-forward inhibition only show an improvement when (1) the models without inhibition also show an improvement, and (2) their estimated amount of feed-forward inhibition (i.e., FFI and FFI + Leak) is approximately zero, meaning that they essentially reduce to a model without inhibition. Response Time <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 14</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figures 14 and 15 (equivalent to</head><p>-performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the speed emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (S1), and the right half being the other (S2). These fits were performed using the alternative definition of double responding and all three between-trial variability parameters. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion</head><p>Response Time Response Time <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 15</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description)</p><p>-performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the speed emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (A1), and the right half being the other (A2). These fits were performed using the alternative definition of double responding and all three between-trial variability parameters. ing was recorded within this experiment, the focus of <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Dutilh et al. (2013)</ref> was purely on the response time and choice of each trial (and the di↵usion model parameters estimated from them), and double responding was not mentioned within their article. We believe that this data set provides a suitable follow-up to Experiment 1 for our assessment of double responding, as it contains a within-subjects manipulation of task emphasis, which was suggested to influence double responding in Experiment 1. In addition, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Dutilh et al. (2013)</ref> contains a larger number of participants (15 young adults) than Experiment 1, though at the expense of a smaller number of trials per person. Full details of the experimental setup can be found in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Dutilh et al. (2013)</ref>, though we provide a brief outline below. Also note that we only assess the data from the young participants within our study, as our interest is not in how double responding is influenced by aging.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Fifteen participants each completed two sessions of a random dot motion task <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Pilly &amp; Seitz, 2009)</ref>, where participants were presented with a cloud of moving dots during each trial and had to identify, via button press, whether the cloud of dots was generally moving towards the left or the right of screen. Each session went for 1 hour and was performed under either speed or accuracy emphasis, meaning that the number of trials completed di↵ered between participants. The range of the number of trials completed in the speed emphasis condition was 102-923, and the range in the accuracy emphasis was 22-440. Double responses were defined in the same manner as the previous experiment.</p><p>All models were extended and fit in the same manner as the previous experiment. To model the di↵erent emphasis conditions for each person, all parameters were constrained to have the same value for both emphases, apart from threshold <ref type="bibr">(Dutilh et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Rae, Heathcote, Donkin, Averell, &amp; Brown, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Voss, Rothermund, &amp; Voss, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Lerche &amp; Voss, 2019)</ref>, drift rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Rae et al., 2014)</ref>, and non-decision time <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">(Voss et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Lerche &amp; Voss, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Rae et al., 2014)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>To begin, we provide the same descriptive assessments as Experiment 1 for each participant, for each emphasis condition <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">(Tables 5 and 6</ref>). As with Experiment 1, the emphasis manipulation appeared to be e↵ective, with participants being faster and less accurate when under speed emphasis. Again, very few double responses were made (the most being 2.73% of trials in the speed condition), though the number of double responses was much greater in the speed condition than the accuracy condition. In addition, in the speed condition double responses occurred much more frequently after error responses than correct responses, again suggesting that these double responses are mostly "corrective" (i.e., following error responses).  <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Summary statistics for the participants in Experiment 2 for the accuracy emphasis condition. Di↵erent columns provide di↵erent pieces of information, and di↵erent rows provide the information for di↵erent subjects. Abbreviations can be found in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>. We fit the models jointly to the choice response time distributions and the double response proportions, which can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 16</ref>. As with Experiment 1, the joint fits appear to clearly distinguish between the models, and provide similar results to Experiment 1. Once again, the type of inhibition in the model appears to be the decisive factor, with independent models vastly over-predicting the number of double responses, feed-forward inhibition models improving upon the independent models, and lateral inhibition models providing the best account of double responses. These findings are also supported by the BIC analysis <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">(Table 7)</ref>, with lateral inhibition models outperforming all other models for all participants. There also appears to be a tradeo↵ within the feed-forward inhibition models in accounting for the double responses and the response time distributions; the more-constrained di↵usion model provides a closer account of double responding than the less constrained feed-forward inhibition model, though this is at the expense of providing a poorer fit to the response time distributions. The independent models also provide a poor fit to both the double responses and the response time distributions, suggesting that to capture the response time distributions properly the independent models would have had to provide an even poorer account of double responding. These findings place a further emphasis on the importance of fitting the response time distributions and double responses jointly, as models can provide a poor account of the standard response time and choice data to more closely account for the double responses. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion Response Proportion</head><p>Response Time Response Time <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 16</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description)</p><p>-performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data), for the speed (left) and accuracy (right) conditions of Experiment 2. The data of each participant was fit separately to obtain the observed and predicted response time quantiles and response proportions, with these quantiles and proportions then then averaged over participants to create these groupaveraged CDF plots. However, as in Experiment 1, when considering both the alternative definition for how double responses are triggered and all three between-trial variability parameters, the models without inhibition provide much more accurate predictions about these data. These results can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 17</ref>, with the corresponding BIC analysis in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 8</ref>. As can be seen, both the models without inhibition and the models with lateral inhibition provide an accurate account of the choice response time distributions, with only a slight -and similar -over-prediction for the proportion of double responses in each condition.</p><p>However, unlike in Experiment 1 where the models with lateral inhibition were still superior for the participants in the accuracy emphasis condition, both models appear to have nearly identical accuracy in their predictions. This is also supported by the BIC analysis, where models without inhibition outperform other models for 8/15 participants, models with lateral inhibition outperform other models for 7/15 participants, and for all participants the BICs between these classes of models are quite similar. Similar to Experiment 1, models with forced feed-forward inhibition (i.e., the DM and OU) remain inferior to all other models, providing (1) a poorer account of the choice response time distributions, (2) a greater over-prediction of the double response proportions, and (3) never outperform the other models on BIC for any participant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion</head><p>Speed</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • Accuracy • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LCA • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 OU • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • ••• 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 LI + Leak • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion</head><p>Response Time Response Time <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 17</ref>. CDF plots (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for a more detailed description)</p><p>-performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data), for the speed (left) and accuracy (right) conditions of Experiment 2. The data of each participant was fit separately to obtain the observed and predicted response time quantiles and response proportions, with these quantiles and proportions then then averaged over participants to create these groupaveraged CDF plots. These fits were performed using the alternative definition of double responding and all three between-trial variability parameters. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Our study proposed double responding as a new constraint for models of decisionmaking, which allows for a better understanding of the dynamics of the complete decisionmaking process by separating the predictions of di↵erent theoretical models of decisionmaking. Previous studies within the decision making literature have mostly focused on response time and choice, as these two variables are able to provide insights into the decision making process using computational models <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Ratcli↵, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Ratcli↵ &amp; Rouder, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brown &amp; Heathcote, 2008)</ref>. Although other phenomena have also been explored in some studies (e.g., choice confidence; <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Ratcli↵ &amp; Starns, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pleskac &amp; Busemeyer, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Ratcli↵ &amp; Starns, 2013)</ref>, measuring these phenomena often require an alteration of the experimental paradigm, and prevents their assessment in "standard" decision making paradigms. Here, we suggest that double responding may be an interesting phenomenon for researchers to attempt to explain in addition to response times and choice, which can be collected as part of any standard experimental paradigm. We found that double responses are quite rare, mostly appear to be corrective (i.e., correcting previous errors; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Rabbitt &amp; Rodgers, 1977</ref> for more details about "error correcting responses"), and that they occur proportionally more after errors when participants were performing an experiment under speed emphasis than accuracy emphasis. When assessing the shape of the double response time distributions in the two participants who provided a sizable number of double responses, we found the distributions to display the positive skew found in standard response time distributions. These three observations could serve as benchmarks for theories that wish to provide a more comprehensive explanation of decision making by integrating double responses into their framework.</p><p>Importantly, we showed that double responding can be used to further constrain di↵erent models of decision making, and that lateral inhibition is required to explain the complete decision making process. As most studies within the decision making literature only focus on response time and choice, the prominent models of decision making -evidence accumulation models (EAMs; <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Stone, 1960;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Laming, 1968;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Ratcli↵, 1978)</ref> -have been designed to account for these response time and choice phenomena, resulting in the models being di cult to distinguish in standard paradigms (though see <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Teodorescu &amp; Usher, 2013</ref> for an example of an experimental test between EAMs). We provided a natural extension of 9 variants of EAMs to double responding, where evidence continued to accumulate for the alternatives after the initial decision had been made, and a double response was triggered if the opposing alternative reached the threshold. Under our primary definition for how double responses are triggered within the EAM framework, where any instance of the accumulated evidence for the other response alternative reaching the decision threshold triggered a double response, models with lateral inhibition -where the future evidence accumulation for an alternative is reduced based on the previously accumulated evidence for the other alternatives -provided the best account of double responding, suggesting that they occur quite rarely, whereas all model variants predicted that they occurred in large quantities. However, when simultaneously considering an alternative definition -where a double response can only be triggered if the evidence for the initial response alternative has also dropped below the threshold -and between trial variability in drift rate, threshold, and non-decision time, models without inhibition were also able to correctly predict the small quantities of double responses. Therefore, although models with lateral inhibition provided accurate predictions under all definitions, models without inhibition showed that they can also capture these trends under certain circumstances. Furthermore, the models with feedforward inhibition fixed at 1 -such as the popular di↵usion model <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Ratcli↵, 1978)</ref> -were unable to provide an accurate account of these data under any definition. Importantly, these distinctions could only be made when the models were forced to account for response time, response choice, and double responses simultaneously; when fitting only the double responses, all models provided a good account of the data. This places further emphasis on the importance of constraining models of additional sources of data, rather than just di↵erent sources of data, as important distinctions can often be made based on their joint predictions.</p><p>However, we wish to note that the aim of our study was only to distinguish between and compare di↵erent theories of speeded decision-making, and that our study does not have implications for the measurement properties of EAMs. Importantly, one of the most common uses of EAMs is as "measurement tools" of the decision-making process, where researchers use EAMs to estimate the latent parameters of the decision-making process -such as drift rate and threshold -and make inferences about how they vary across experimental conditions and/or groups <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Crüwell et al., 2019)</ref>. Having measurement tools that are theoretically accurate is important, as inaccuracies in the theoretical underpinning of the measurement tools may make the parameters estimated from them meaningless. However, we believe that the importance of having reliable measurement tools cannot be overstated, as having unreliable measurement tools (e.g., models with identifiable parameters) will guarantee inaccurate estimates and conclusions. Therefore, although our study suggested that models with lateral inhibition may be theoretically superior to models with feedforward inhibition for 2AFC tasks, models with lateral inhibition may be a questionable choice for use as measurement tools, as previous research has suggested that these models contain identifiability problems <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Miletić, Turner, Forstmann, &amp; van Maanen, 2017)</ref>.</p><p>Therefore, we again wish to reiterate that researchers should not use the results of our study to guide which EAMs they choose to use as measurement tools. However, we believe that an interesting avenue for future research would be to assess whether double responses -or other additional sources of data -are able to provide adequate constraint to allow models with lateral inhibition to have identifiable parameters, and whether including double responses as a constraint in models that are already identifiable leads to changes in parameter estimates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implicit or explicit double responding?</head><p>As briefly discussed at the end of our introduction, our study assessed implicit double responding behaviour, where participants are not directly instructed to make a second response. The observed double responses from an implicit paradigm can be thought of as a spillover of information from the decision-making process, which results in a second motor output for the other alternative. However, an alternate way to assess double responding would be through explicit double responding behaviour, where participants are directly instructed that they are allowed to make a second response. The observed double responses from an explicit paradigm can be thought of as a combination of the previously outlined spillover of information from the decision-making process -as these implicit double responses would still occur under direct instruction -and intentional corrections of errors, where participants make a second response knowing that the task allows for them to correct their errors. Importantly, when studying double responding, researchers must choose whether to assess implicit or explicit double responses, which may provide very di↵erent measurements of double responding behaviour. Here, we provide a discussion of the advantages and disadvantages of assessing each type of double responding behaviour, as well as how our choice of implicit double responding over explicit double responding may have impacted our results.</p><p>Implicit double responding provides an easy-to-implement measurement of double responding behaviour. Researchers do not need to change their existing speeded decisionmaking tasks, as the only specific requirement is that researchers record any responses that participants make between the initial response and the following trial. Importantly, implicit double responding ensures that participants do not alter their behaviour from a standard speeded decision-making tasks, as they are unaware that their second responses are being recorded, and therefore, cannot adjust their decision strategy accordingly. This equivalence provides a clear generalization for the findings of implicit double responding assessments to standard speeded decision-making tasks, as participants should be performing both tasks in the same manner. However, the key limitation of implicit double responding is that participants may intentionally avoid making double responses. For example, as participants are not aware that their second responses are being recorded, they may directly attempt to suppress their natural instinct to make a second response in some situations, as making a second response may impair their ability to prepare for the next trial. This would lead to an underestimation of implicit double responding behaviour, as only information spillovers that participants fail to inhibit would result in a double response being observed.</p><p>Explicit double responding provides a clear solution to the key limitation of implicit double responding. As participants are instead directly instructed that they are allowed to make a second response whenever they believe that their initial response was incorrect, participants would be unlikely to attempt to suppress second responses, as the suppression of these responses would result in a poorer performance in the task. Explicit double responding behaviour would consist of both implicit double responses, as these would not be suppressed, and purposeful corrections of perceived errors, in accordance with the instructions of the task. However, the key limitation of explicit double responding is that informing participants that they are able to correct their initial errors may alter how they complete the task. For example, as participants are aware that their initial response does not need to be their final response, they may adopt a less cautious strategy in their initial responses than they would normally, as they believe that they will be able to correct many of the errors that they make from being overly urgent in their initial responses.</p><p>Any change in strategy between standard decision-making tasks and the explicit double responding paradigm would decrease the generalizability for the findings of explicit double responding assessments to standard speeded decision-making tasks, making the assessment of double responding less useful in understanding the decision process more generally.</p><p>As discussed above, implicit and explicit double responding behaviour each have their own unique advantages and limitations, and therefore, we do not wish to make any claims about which type of double responding behaviour researchers should assess. Furthermore, our choice of implicit double responding behaviour is not intended as an endorsement of implicit double responding over explicit double responding, and was based upon (1) our desire to keep our results as generalizable as possible to standard speeded decision-making tasks, and (2) the availability of existing implicit double responding data. However, we believe that future research may be able to provide a solution to this problem through careful experimentation. Specifically, as the primary concern regarding explicit double responding is that participants' initial responses may be influenced by their knowledge that they can correct their initial response with a second response, experimentally establishing that introducing this information does not alter participants' initial responding behaviour would help to mitigate these concerns. However, finding a set of instructions that are able to convey this information, while also restricting participants' freedom to change how they perform the task, may prove challenging. Beyond informing participants of their ability to correct their errors through secondary responses, these instructions could also attempt to restrict participants' ability to rely on second responses by informing participants that they (1) should avoid relying on the secondary responses, (2) will only be partially correct when correcting an initial error, (3) are only allowed a certain number of corrections and must use them wisely, or (4) will only be able to correct their errors on a certain proportion of randomly selected trials. However, given that previous research has suggested that instructing participants to make multiple responses can alter their decision-making behaviour <ref type="bibr" target="#b83">(Yearsley &amp; Pothos, 2016)</ref>, even in the case of perceptual decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Kvam et al., 2015</ref>), it may not be possible to instruct participants to make secondary responses in a way that does not also influence their initial responding behaviour.</p><p>One important point that we wish to address is how our choice of implicit double responding over explicit double responding may have influenced our results and conclusions.</p><p>As discussed above, implicit double responding paradigms will only consist of involuntary second responses that involve some spillover of information from the decision-making process, where explicit double responding paradigms will consist of both implicit double responses and purposeful corrections of initial errors. Importantly, this means that the proportion of double responses should always be higher for explicit double responding paradigms than implicit double responding paradigms, as explicit double responding paradigms will consist of both implicit and explicit double responding behaviour. In our study, models with lateral inhibition provided the best account of empirical data from two experiments, primarily due to all other models providing a large over-estimation of the double response proportion, particularly when participants were instructed to perform the tasks with an emphasis on accurate responding. However, as the use of an explicit double responding paradigm should theoretically result in a higher proportion of double responses than an implicit double responding paradigm, our choice of implicit double responding may have led to the small proportion of double responses that most models were unable to capture, and an explicit double responding paradigm may have led to a larger proportion of double responses that would have provided less distinction between the models. However, it should be noted that although explicit double responding should increase the proportion of double responses, this increase may not be enough to change our results. Furthermore, as our study focused on the joint predictions of the models for both the initial choice response time distributions and double responding proportions, and as the explicit double responding paradigm may change how participants behave for the initial response, changing to explicit double responding may also alter the observed initial choice response time distributions, meaning that the models may still di↵er in their joint predictions. Although we believe that our choice of implicit double responding behaviour was sensible, and that our results and conclusions have potentially meaningful implications for our understanding of the decision-making process, we believe that the potential di↵erences between implicit and explicit double responding behaviour further motivates both (1) the assessment of explicit double responding behaviour, and (2) an investigation into how to inform participants of their ability to make a second, corrective response without altering how they behave for initial responses. It should also be noted that our 250ms double response deadline may not be adequate time to allow participants to make purposeful corrections of perceived errors, and that researchers who use explicit double responding paradigms may wish to implement longer deadlines.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Future directions related to double responding</head><p>We believe that the introduction of double responding as an additional constraint for models of speeded decision-making provides many potential avenues for future research, and we attempt to discuss some of these possibilities here. skew. Therefore, future research could aim to create new variants of EAMs that may be able to meet these benchmarks. Furthermore, we would again like to note that our study is the first to use double responding as an additional constraint for models of speeded decision-making, and therefore, we do not believe that it would be appropriate for our study to provide broad conclusions about which models of decision-making are superior to others. However, we believe that the general success of lateral inhibition within our study, in combination with previous experimental tests favouring lateral inhibition <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Teodorescu &amp; Usher, 2013)</ref>, shows a growing body of evidence for the importance of lateral inhibition in speeded decision-making.</p><p>Another important point of consideration is that our extensions of EAMs to double responding are only two of a large number of possibilities. Our primary choice of extension was based on trying to provide the most natural extension of the standard EAM framework, with accumulation continuing after the initial decision, and a double response being triggered by the other accumulator hitting the threshold. Our alternative extension was based on the potential proposal that double responding should not occur in cases where the evidence for the initial response is still higher than for the other alternative, requiring the additional condition that the initial response alternative has dropped below the threshold.</p><p>However, there are many other sensible and simple extensions that could be implemented, which could lead to di↵erent, and potentially better, accounts of double responding. For example, one could suggest that double responses might purely be due to a change in which accumulator has the greatest share in evidence, meaning that a double response would be triggered if the evidence for the losing alternative were to go above the evidence for the winning alternative after the initial decision. Furthermore, previous research has suggested that the level of lateral inhibition may increase after a decision is made <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bronfman et al., 2015)</ref>, meaning that allowing greater levels -or in the case of the independent models with the alternative definition, some lateral inhibition -during the double responding process may further improve the ability of these models to account for double response times and proportions. Alternatively, our assumption that double responses are the result of changes in the decision process may be incorrect, and instead double responding may result from motor errors where participants give the wrong response (i.e., press the wrong button), which they attempt to quickly correct following their initial response. We believe that our study has provided an important initial comparison between di↵erent EAMs in how well they can account for double responding, showing that double responding can be used to help distinguish between di↵erent EAMs, and future research should aim to compare other possible extensions of EAMs to double responding.</p><p>More generally, we believe that our study displays the importance of tightly constraining cognitive models, and how this can be done using additional sources of data.</p><p>However, it should be noted that these additional sources of data should be theoretically sensible, as the use of theoretically unrelated data (i.e., data produced by a di↵erence psychological process) may result in misleading conclusions. We believe that double responding provides a theoretically sensible constraint for models of speeded decision-making, as EAMs can be naturally extended to capture these data, but that future research should attempt to find further, and tougher, constraints for these models. For example, future research could perform a similar comparison to our study, though using partial errors measured through EMG recordings <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Coles et al., 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Servant et al., 2015)</ref> as the additional constraint. Moreover, future studies could potentially combine multiple constraints, providing an even tougher test for models of speeded decision-making. For example, the combination of choice response time distributions, double responses, and partial errors provide information about the decision process from before, during, and after the initial response, and therefore, would likely provide an extremely tough constraint for EAMs.</p><p>Aside from the potential to further constrain models of decision making, double responding also provides an interesting avenue of theoretical research in better understanding why people change their mind. Previous studies have assessed change of mind in a variety of di↵erent ways, both assessing how people's behaviour changes after making an error (e.g., error correcting responses, post-error slowing), and how people's preferences change of mind during a decision e↵ects their motor output (e.g., joystick movement, EMG).</p><p>Although some models currently exist that involve change of mind, such as the di↵usionbased models of conflict tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(White, Servant, &amp; Logan, 2018)</ref>, these models are still only constrained by the standard data of response time and choice, and are only intended for specific types of tasks (i.e., conflict tasks). Therefore, we believe that double responding provides an interesting avenue to better understand why people change their mind, which can be used to extend decision making models to explain these post-decision changes in mind. There are also several other common experimental manipulations that may be able to provide more double responding benchmarks for decision making models to explain, such as di culty manipulations (e.g., do double responses occur proportionally more often after errors on easy trials, or errors on hard trials?), response bias manipulation (e.g., do double responses happen more often after people respond in favour of the initial bias alternative?), or manipulations that place a stronger emphasis on fast responding (e.g., do double responses happen more often as more emphasis is placed on fast responding) such as deadline paradigms (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Evans, Hawkins, &amp; Brown, 2020)</ref>. Moreover, future research may benefits from exploring individual di↵erences in double responding, in order to understand why some people may be more likely to double respond than others. This may involve attempting to relate double responding behaviour to other constructs (e.g., personality traits), or to the parameters of EAMs (e.g., threshold) estimated from the standard choice response time distributions. Finally, double responding could be used as an additional source of constraint in the application of EAMs to theoretical and applied problems, such as assessing the robustness of selective influence manipulations (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Dutilh et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>We believe that each of these potential research questions provide informative directions for future research involving double responding, which may help to further our understanding of speeded decision-making and changes of mind.</p><p>Post-error evidence accumulation process in Experiment 1</p><p>In the results for Experiment 1, we attempt to provide some insight into why lateral inhibition is able to help in accounting for double responding behaviour by plotting the predicted evidence accumulation process for three models (Leak, OU, and LCA). To avoid redundancy, we only plotted these trajectories for participant S1, as all participants provide the same overall conclusion on why lateral inhibition is helpful in capturing double responses. For completeness, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures SM1, SM2</ref>, and SM3 display the trajectories for participants S2, A1, and A2, respectively.    It should also be noted that for S2, the predictions of the models without inhibition become about as good as those with lateral inhibition (which are both superior to those with feedforward inhibition), as reflected in the RDM outperforming the lateral inhibition models for S2 in BIC <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table SM1</ref>), suggesting that the lateral inhibition models are no longer superior for this subject. However, the lateral inhibition models remain qualitatively (Figures SM4 and SM5) and quantitatively <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table SM1</ref>) superior to all other models for participants S1, A1, and A2, meaning that our general pattern of results appears to hold even under the alternative definition. This is further supported by the results for Experiment 2 based on the alternative definition -which can be seen in <ref type="figure">Figure SM6</ref> and provides the same comparisons as the main text <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 12</ref> -where the models with lateral inhibition clearly qualitatively outperform all other models, and are favoured by 12/15 participants on BIC <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table SM2</ref>). However, it should be noted that the RDM now outperforms the 1 For the DM and OU, where feed-forward inhibition is fixed to 1, and therefore, evidence for one alternative is evidence against the other alternative, it is a necessity. lateral inhibition models in 3/15 participants on BIC, which is better than the 0/15 in the primary definition in the main text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Time</head><p>Response Proportion S1 Response Time <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure SM4</ref>. CDF plots performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the speed emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (S1), and the right half being the other (S2).</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 RDM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 DM • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• • 0.0 0.5 1.0 1.5 0.0 0.4 0.8 FFI • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •• •</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion A1</head><p>• </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion</head><p>Response Time Response Time <ref type="figure">Figure SM5</ref>. CDF plots performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data) -for the two participants in the accuracy emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (A1), and the right half being the other (A2).  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table SM1</ref>: BIC values for all 9 models (columns) for each of the 4 participants (rows) in Experiment 1. The best model for each participant is in bold within the table. Note that BIC is on the deviance scale, and therefore, smaller values indicate better performance. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion</head><p>Response Time Response Time <ref type="figure">Figure SM6</ref>. CDF plots performed jointly for the response time distributions and the double response proportions (i.e., the same parameter values for each type of data), for the speed <ref type="bibr">(left)</ref> and accuracy (right) conditions of Experiment 2. The data of each participant was fit separately to obtain the observed and predicted response time quantiles and response proportions, with these quantiles and proportions then then averaged over participants to create these group-averaged CDF plots.  Results when only considering all between-trial variability parameters Here, we provide the results for Experiment 1 when only considering all three between-trial variability parameters, without the alternative definition for how double responses are triggered. <ref type="figure">Figures SM7 and SM8</ref> provide the same comparisons as the main text <ref type="figure">Figures 7 and 8</ref>. As can be seen, the inclusion of these additional between-trial variability parameters does not change the overall inferences from Experiment 1, as the qualitative pattern of results remains the same (see also  Response Time <ref type="figure">Figure SM7</ref>. CDF plots for the two participants in the speed emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (S1), and the right half being the other (S2). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response Proportion</head><p>Response Time Response Time <ref type="figure">Figure SM8</ref>. CDF plots for the two participants in the accuracy emphasis condition in Experiment 1, with the left half of the figure being one participant (A1), and the right half being the other</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A: A diagram of the typical decision process proposed within evidence accumulation models, with di↵erent decision alternatives represented by the orange and green accumulation lines.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Cumulative density function (CDF) plot of the empirical (dots) and racing di↵usion model (RDM) predicted (lines and crosses) standard response time distributions (i.e., response</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Double response time distributions for the two participants (di↵erent histograms) in the speed emphasis condition of Experiment 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Response time distributions for the two participants (columns) in the speed emphasis condition of Experiment 1. The top row displays the response time distributions for trials that did not have double responses following them, and the bottom row displays the response time</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 12 .</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Predicted evidence accumulation processes following errors for the Leak (top), OU (middle), and LCA (bottom) models based on the best fitting parameters for participant S1. The x-axis displays the time from the initial response, up until the double response time limit of 0.25 seconds, and the y-axis displays the accumulated evidence, starting at the finishing evidence at the initial response. The green line displays the evidence for the correct response alternative, and the red line displays the evidence for the error response alternative, with the latter being the initial response. The straight black line displays the response threshold. The left panel displays accumulation processes that result in double responses (though the accumulation continues beyond the threshold for this plot), and the right panel displays accumulation processes that do not result in double responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 13 .</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Our alternative definition for how the standard EAM framework may extend to double responses. A: As in Figure 1. B: As in Figure 1. C: An example of a decision process that would not result in a double response, as the orange/red alternative remains above the threshold. D: As in Figure 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Firstly, although models with lateral inhibition were able to provide an accurate account of the joint response time/choice/double response data under both potential definitions of how double responses are triggered, their account of double responding was not perfect. Specifically, the lateral inhibition models still over-predicted the number of double responses that occurred -especially in Experiment 2and this was also true of the models without inhibition under the alternative definition for how double responses are triggered. In addition, no model -including the lateral inhibition models -predicted the positive skew present in the double response time distributions, with all models predicting either uniform distributions or distributions with a slight negative</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure SM1 .</head><label>SM1</label><figDesc>Predicted evidence accumulation processes following errors for the Leak (top), OU (middle), and LCA (bottom) models based on the best fitting parameters for participant S2. The x-axis displays the time from the initial response, up until the double response time limit of 0.25 seconds, and the y-axis displays the accumulated evidence, starting at the finishing evidence at the initial response. The green line displays the evidence for the correct response alternative, and the red line displays the evidence for the error response alternative, with the latter being the initial response. The left panel displays accumulation processes that result in double responses (though the accumulation continues beyond the threshold for this plot), and the right panel displays accumulation processes that do not result in double responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure SM2 .</head><label>SM2</label><figDesc>Predicted evidence accumulation processes following errors for the Leak (top), OU (middle), and LCA (bottom) models based on the best fitting parameters for participant A1. The x-axis displays the time from the initial response, up until the double response time limit of 0.25 seconds, and the y-axis displays the accumulated evidence, starting at the finishing evidence at the initial response. The green line displays the evidence for the correct response alternative, and the red line displays the evidence for the error response alternative, with the latter being the initial response. The left panel displays accumulation processes that result in double responses (though the accumulation continues beyond the threshold for this plot), and the right panel displays accumulation processes that do not result in double responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head>Figure SM3 .</head><label>SM3</label><figDesc>Predicted evidence accumulation processes following errors for the Leak (top), OU (middle), and LCA (bottom) models based on the best fitting parameters for participant A2. The x-axis displays the time from the initial response, up until the double response time limit of 0.25 seconds, and the y-axis displays the accumulated evidence, starting at the finishing evidence at the initial response. The green line displays the evidence for the correct response alternative, and the red line displays the evidence for the error response alternative, with the latter being the initial response. The left panel displays accumulation processes that result in double responses (though the accumulation continues beyond the threshold for this plot), and the right panel displays accumulation processes that do not result in double responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Results when only considering the alternative definition for how double responses are triggered Here, we provide the results for Experiment 1 when only considering the alternative definition for how double responses are triggered, without the inclusion of between-trial variability in drift rate and non-decision time.Figures SM4 and SM5provide the same comparisons as the main text Figures 7 and 8. For the models with lateral and feedforward inhibition, the results are near-identical to those in the main text. This probably not surprising given the evidence accumulation processes shown in main textFigure 11and supplementaryFigures SM1, SM2, and SM3, as the evidence for the initial response alternative generally dropped below the threshold in these models even under the primary definition 1 . However, the models without inhibition (RDM and Leak) show a large improvement, providing much less of an over-prediction of the double response proportions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">: The 9 models included within our assessment of double responding, and the components</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">beyond the base model that they included. Models are presented in the same order as in the</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">main text. Within the table and subsequent results figures, we use abbreviations for the racing</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">di↵usion model (RDM), feed-forward inhibition (FFI), the di↵usion model (DM), lateral inhibition</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">(LI), leakage (Leak), the Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process (OU), and the leaky-competing accumulator</cell></row><row><cell>(LCA).</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>Lateral Inhibition Feed-forward Inhibition Leakage Truncation at 0</cell></row><row><cell>RDM (Tillman &amp; Logan, 2017)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>FFI</cell><cell>X</cell></row><row><cell>DM</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>, where the columns give the di↵erent</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Summary statistics for the participants in Experiment 1. Di↵erent rows provide di↵erent pieces of information, and di↵erent columns provide the information for di↵erent subjects. Within</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">the table and subsequent tables, we use abbreviations for emphasis Emph, the total number of</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">trials (N trials ), mean response time (MRT), probability of X (P(X )), correct responses (C), error</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">responses (E), double responses (DR), correlation between X and Y (cor(X,Y )), trial number (t).</cell></row><row><cell>Sub</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>Emph</cell><cell cols="2">speed speed</cell><cell cols="2">accuracy accuracy</cell></row><row><cell>N trials</cell><cell cols="3">10,000 10,000 10,000</cell><cell>10,000</cell></row><row><cell>MRT</cell><cell cols="3">0.4348 0.4933 0.5678</cell><cell>0.5296</cell></row><row><cell>P(C)</cell><cell cols="3">0.7344 0.8252 0.948</cell><cell>0.9286</cell></row><row><cell>P(DR)</cell><cell cols="3">0.0191 0.0255 0.0003</cell><cell>0.0007</cell></row><row><cell>P(DR|C)</cell><cell cols="3">0.0037 0.0039 0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>P(DR|E)</cell><cell cols="3">0.0617 0.1276 0.0058</cell><cell>0.0098</cell></row><row><cell>P(C|DR)</cell><cell cols="3">0.1414 0.1255 0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>cor(DR,RT)</cell><cell cols="3">0.0359 0.0163 -0.0134</cell><cell>0.0023</cell></row><row><cell>cor(DR,t)</cell><cell cols="3">0.0371 -0.0354 0.0167</cell><cell>0.0107</cell></row><row><cell>P(DR t |DR t 1 )</cell><cell cols="3">0.0209 0.0118 0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>P(DR t |¬DR t 1 )</cell><cell cols="3">0.0191 0.0259 0.0003</cell><cell>0.0007</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>BIC values for all 9 models (rows) for each of the 4 participants (columns) in Experiment 1. The best model for each participant is in bold within the table. Note that BIC is on the deviance scale, and therefore, smaller values indicate better performance.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>RDM</cell><cell>1944.67</cell><cell>-3747.48</cell><cell>-7835.96</cell><cell>-5530.23</cell></row><row><cell>Leak</cell><cell>2011.84</cell><cell>-3943.15</cell><cell>-9238.01</cell><cell>-7312.79</cell></row><row><cell>DM</cell><cell>-5221.05</cell><cell>-9515.55</cell><cell>-11286.49</cell><cell>-10005.30</cell></row><row><cell>OU</cell><cell>-5199.89</cell><cell>-9499.34</cell><cell>-11268.55</cell><cell>-10021.70</cell></row><row><cell>FFI</cell><cell>-5342.49</cell><cell>-10145.67</cell><cell>-11271.22</cell><cell>-10006.08</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">FFI + Leak -5320.17</cell><cell>-10133.59</cell><cell>-11346.34</cell><cell>-10026.88</cell></row><row><cell>LI</cell><cell cols="3">-7421.07 -12144.46 -11816.74</cell><cell>-10338.38</cell></row><row><cell>LI + Leak</cell><cell>-7384.60</cell><cell>-12113.00</cell><cell>-11945.07</cell><cell>-10403.72</cell></row><row><cell>LCA</cell><cell cols="4">-7445.44 -12143.49 -11952.44 -10446.06</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>BIC values for all 9 models (rows) for each of the 4 participants (columns) in Experiment 1, using the alternative definition of double responding and all three between-trial variability parameters. The best model for each participant is in bold within the table. Note that BIC is on the deviance scale, and therefore, smaller values indicate better performance.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>RDM</cell><cell cols="3">-8409.98 -13259.74 -11610.48</cell><cell>-10099.26</cell></row><row><cell>Leak</cell><cell>-8397.24</cell><cell>-13257.20</cell><cell>-11627.22</cell><cell>-10107.05</cell></row><row><cell>DM</cell><cell>-7304.49</cell><cell>-12162.50</cell><cell>-11685.12</cell><cell>-10071.10</cell></row><row><cell>OU</cell><cell>-7303.49</cell><cell>-12134.47</cell><cell>-11695.08</cell><cell>-10095.90</cell></row><row><cell>FFI</cell><cell>-8408.66</cell><cell>-13255.61</cell><cell>-11678.24</cell><cell>-10110.17</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">FFI + Leak -8368.34</cell><cell>-13222.14</cell><cell>-11715.04</cell><cell>-10058.60</cell></row><row><cell>LI</cell><cell>-8407.78</cell><cell>-13212.73</cell><cell>-11885.96</cell><cell>-10370.22</cell></row><row><cell>LI + Leak</cell><cell>-8387.80</cell><cell>-13240.42</cell><cell cols="2">-11955.85 -10459.55</cell></row><row><cell>LCA</cell><cell>-8365.80</cell><cell cols="3">-13237.99 -11983.08 -10440.10</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Experiment 2 (Dutilh, Forstmann, Vandekerckhove, &amp;</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Wagenmakers, 2013)</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Our second experiment uses the data from Dutilh et al. (2013), who aimed to un- derstand how the latent components of the decision process -via the EZ di↵usion model (Wagenmakers, van der Maas, &amp; Grasman, 2007) -were e↵ected by errors, and how this di↵ered between younger and older adults. Specifically, Dutilh et al. (2013) had each partic- ipant make decisions under speed and accuracy emphasis (separate sessions), using the EZ di↵usion model to estimate the parameter values for decisions made after correct responses, and decisions made after error responses. As with Experiment 1, although double respond-</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Summary statistics for the participants in Experiment 2 for the speed emphasis condition.Di↵erent columns provide di↵erent pieces of information, and di↵erent rows provide the information for di↵erent subjects. Abbreviations can be found inTable 2.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Sub</cell><cell>MRT</cell><cell cols="5">P(C) P(DR) P(DR|C) P(DR|E) P(C|DR) N trials</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell cols="2">0.4297 0.9295</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0714</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell cols="3">0.4609 0.8326 0.0088</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0526</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell cols="3">0.4328 0.8421 0.0115</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0729</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell cols="3">0.392 0.6308 0.0063</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0171</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell cols="3">0.4558 0.6111 0.0033</cell><cell>0.0018</cell><cell>0.0056</cell><cell>0.3333</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell cols="3">0.4648 0.9496 0.0168</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.3333</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>7</cell><cell cols="3">0.3693 0.8255 0.0169</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0968</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>8</cell><cell cols="3">0.4286 0.8786 0.0022</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0182</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>9</cell><cell cols="3">0.3957 0.7244 0.0079</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0286</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>10</cell><cell>0.4828</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>11</cell><cell>0.4051</cell><cell cols="2">0.891 0.0062</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0571</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>12</cell><cell cols="3">0.4094 0.9057 0.0101</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.1071</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>13</cell><cell cols="3">0.4665 0.9447 0.0158</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.2857</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>14</cell><cell cols="3">0.4703 0.8371 0.0181</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.1111</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>15</cell><cell cols="3">0.4155 0.8484 0.0273</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.1798</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Average 0.4319 0.8434 0.0104</cell><cell>0.0001</cell><cell>0.1027</cell><cell>0.0238</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>BIC values for all 9 models (columns) for each of the 15 participants (rows) in Experiment 2. The best model for each participant is in bold within the table. Note that BIC is on the deviance scale, and therefore, smaller values indicate better performance.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">Sub RDM Leak DM</cell><cell>OU</cell><cell cols="2">FFI FFI + Leak</cell><cell>LI</cell><cell cols="2">LI + Leak LCA</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>-748</cell><cell cols="2">-826 -953</cell><cell>-946</cell><cell>-967</cell><cell>-964</cell><cell>-1030</cell><cell>-1024</cell><cell>-1025</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>-127</cell><cell cols="2">-165 -297</cell><cell>-291</cell><cell>-297</cell><cell>-291</cell><cell>-348</cell><cell>-343</cell><cell>-343</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>-505</cell><cell cols="2">-567 -915</cell><cell>-902</cell><cell>-933</cell><cell>-925</cell><cell>-1061</cell><cell>-1058</cell><cell>-1055</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>124</cell><cell>132</cell><cell>-291</cell><cell>-285</cell><cell>-290</cell><cell>-285</cell><cell>-430</cell><cell>-422</cell><cell>-430</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell cols="2">1158 1171</cell><cell>215</cell><cell>223</cell><cell>139</cell><cell>152</cell><cell>-71</cell><cell>-60</cell><cell>-70</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>-207</cell><cell cols="2">-204 -223</cell><cell>-218</cell><cell>-223</cell><cell>-216</cell><cell>-236</cell><cell>-229</cell><cell>-229</cell></row><row><cell>7</cell><cell>-599</cell><cell cols="4">-703 -1120 -1113 -1111</cell><cell>-1107</cell><cell>-1274</cell><cell>-1268</cell><cell>-1270</cell></row><row><cell>8</cell><cell>-503</cell><cell cols="2">-546 -788</cell><cell>-781</cell><cell>-802</cell><cell>-797</cell><cell>-902</cell><cell>-897</cell><cell>-903</cell></row><row><cell>9</cell><cell>-44</cell><cell>-88</cell><cell>-653</cell><cell>-642</cell><cell>-649</cell><cell>-642</cell><cell>-855</cell><cell>-852</cell><cell>-852</cell></row><row><cell>10</cell><cell>-227</cell><cell cols="2">-225 -230</cell><cell>-225</cell><cell>-231</cell><cell>-225</cell><cell>-233</cell><cell>-230</cell><cell>-230</cell></row><row><cell>11</cell><cell>-575</cell><cell cols="2">-701 -886</cell><cell>-882</cell><cell>-882</cell><cell>-878</cell><cell>-959</cell><cell>-957</cell><cell>-951</cell></row><row><cell>12</cell><cell>-647</cell><cell cols="2">-797 -981</cell><cell>-978</cell><cell>-974</cell><cell>-973</cell><cell>-1051</cell><cell>-1044</cell><cell>-1041</cell></row><row><cell>13</cell><cell>-578</cell><cell cols="2">-661 -763</cell><cell>-757</cell><cell>-760</cell><cell>-756</cell><cell>-790</cell><cell>-787</cell><cell>-784</cell></row><row><cell>14</cell><cell>-172</cell><cell cols="2">-195 -313</cell><cell>-311</cell><cell>-314</cell><cell>-310</cell><cell>-348</cell><cell>-341</cell><cell>-334</cell></row><row><cell>15</cell><cell>-829</cell><cell cols="4">-915 -1205 -1197 -1233</cell><cell>-1219</cell><cell>-1349</cell><cell>-1339</cell><cell>-1343</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>BIC values for all 9 models (columns) for each of the 15 participants (rows) in Experiment 2, using the alternative definition of double responding and all three between-trial variability parameters. The best model for each participant is in bold within the table. Note that BIC is on the deviance scale, and therefore, smaller values indicate better performance.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">RDM Leak</cell><cell>DM</cell><cell>OU</cell><cell cols="2">FFI FFI + Leak</cell><cell>LI</cell><cell cols="2">LI + Leak LCA</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell cols="5">-1043 -1035 -1026 -1022 -1037</cell><cell>-1023</cell><cell>-1050</cell><cell>-1048</cell><cell>-1041</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>-353</cell><cell>-347</cell><cell>-322</cell><cell>-318</cell><cell>-344</cell><cell>-335</cell><cell>-355</cell><cell>-349</cell><cell>-346</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell cols="5">-1124 -1120 -1038 -1035 -1115</cell><cell>-1106</cell><cell>-1126</cell><cell>-1123</cell><cell>-1122</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>-480</cell><cell>-469</cell><cell>-412</cell><cell>-404</cell><cell>-473</cell><cell>-452</cell><cell>-471</cell><cell>-464</cell><cell>-460</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>-159</cell><cell>-156</cell><cell>-95</cell><cell>-88</cell><cell>-153</cell><cell>-139</cell><cell>-155</cell><cell>-157</cell><cell>-159</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>-253</cell><cell>-247</cell><cell>-230</cell><cell>-225</cell><cell>-247</cell><cell>-241</cell><cell>-247</cell><cell>-242</cell><cell>-241</cell></row><row><cell>7</cell><cell cols="5">-1326 -1320 -1228 -1227 -1316</cell><cell>-1307</cell><cell>-1319</cell><cell>-1309</cell><cell>-1310</cell></row><row><cell>8</cell><cell>-943</cell><cell>-940</cell><cell>-884</cell><cell>-880</cell><cell>-936</cell><cell>-923</cell><cell>-937</cell><cell>-929</cell><cell>-929</cell></row><row><cell>9</cell><cell>-925</cell><cell cols="2">-927 -777</cell><cell>-772</cell><cell>-905</cell><cell>-903</cell><cell>-917</cell><cell>-911</cell><cell>-910</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">10 -235</cell><cell>-229</cell><cell>-232</cell><cell>-227</cell><cell>-229</cell><cell>-223</cell><cell>-229</cell><cell>-224</cell><cell>-224</cell></row><row><cell>11</cell><cell>-963</cell><cell>-956</cell><cell>-959</cell><cell>-955</cell><cell>-951</cell><cell>-951</cell><cell>-966</cell><cell>-964</cell><cell>-948</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">12 -1047 -1040 -1010 -1007 -1040</cell><cell>-1025</cell><cell>-1038</cell><cell>-1029</cell><cell>-1031</cell></row><row><cell>13</cell><cell>-771</cell><cell>-767</cell><cell>-781</cell><cell>-779</cell><cell>-774</cell><cell>-773</cell><cell>-785</cell><cell>-778</cell><cell>-779</cell></row><row><cell>14</cell><cell>-354</cell><cell>-351</cell><cell>-359</cell><cell>-355</cell><cell>-354</cell><cell>-349</cell><cell>-361</cell><cell>-356</cell><cell>-351</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">15 -1427 -1421 -1341 -1341 -1416</cell><cell>-1405</cell><cell>-1420</cell><cell>-1414</cell><cell>-1413</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table SM2 :</head><label>SM2</label><figDesc>BIC values for all 9 models (rows) for each of the 15 participants (columns) in Experiment 2. The best model for each participant is in bold within the table. Note that BIC is on the deviance scale, and therefore, smaller values indicate better performance.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table SM3</head><label>SM3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>for BIC).</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Note that this definition means that there was only a single source of between-trial variability allowed in all models: starting point variability.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Table SM3: BIC values for all 9 models (columns) for each of the 4 participants (rows) in Experiment 1. The best model for each participant is in bold within the table. Note that BIC is on the deviance scale, and therefore, smaller values indicate better performance.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intentional maps in posterior parietal cortex. Annual review of neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Buneo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="220" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An analysis of the saccadic system by means of double step stimuli</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jürgens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Vision research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="967" to="983" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The physics of optimal decision making: A formal analysis of models of performance in two-alternative forced choice tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Moehlis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="700" to="765" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions reduce sensitivity to subsequent information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Bronfman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Brezis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Donner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">282</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1810" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The simplest complete model of choice response time: Linear ballistic accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating methods for approximating stochastic di↵erential equations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcli↵</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="402" to="410" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributional reaction time properties in the Eriksen task: Marked di↵erences or hidden similarities with the Simon task?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Burle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Spieser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Servant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hasbroucq</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1003" to="1010" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision field theory: A dynamic-cognitive approach to decision making in an uncertain environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="432" to="459" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamics of saccade target selection: race model analysis of double step and search step saccade production in human and macaque</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camalier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gotler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Murthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Palmeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Vision research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2187" to="2211" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Space and attention in parietal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Colby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual review of neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="349" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A psychophysiological investigation of the continuous flow model of human information processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Coles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gratton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bashore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Eriksen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Donchin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">529</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust standards in cognitive science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Crüwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Stefan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Brain &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison between mechanisms of multi-alternative perceptual decision making: ability to explain human behavior, predictions for neurophysiology, and relationship with decision theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ditterich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">184</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Di↵usion versus linear ballistic accumulation: Di↵erent models for response time, same conclusions about psychological mechanisms?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dutilh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Annis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cassey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Grasman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The quality of response time data inference: A blinded, collaborative assessment of the validity of cognitive models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A di↵usion model account of age di↵erences in posterror slowing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dutilh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vandekerckhove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology and Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A di↵usion model decomposition of the practice e↵ect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dutilh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vandekerckhove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tuerlinckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1026" to="1036" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing the practical di↵erences between model selection methods in inferences about choice response time tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A method, framework, and tutorial for e ciently simulating models of decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Behavior research methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What factors are most important in finding the best model of a psychological process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comment on Navarro</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PsyArXiv</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal or not; depends on the task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">People adopt optimal policies in simple decision-making, after practice and guidance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="597" to="606" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When humans behave like monkeys: Feedback delays and extensive practice increase the e ciency of speeded decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">184</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of passing time in decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="316" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Need for closure is associated with urgency in perceptual decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bushmakin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1193" to="1205" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of conflict di↵usion models in the flanker task through pseudolikelihood bayes factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Servant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">114</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">E↵ects of crossmodal divided attention on late ERP components. II. Error processing in choice reaction tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Falkenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hohnsbein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hoormann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Blanke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Electroencephalography and Clinical Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="447" to="455" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic mental models: A Brunswikian theory of confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Ho↵rage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kleinbölting</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="506" to="528" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An electromyographic investigation of the e↵ect of stimulus-response mapping on choice reaction time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hasbroucq</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Burle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Akamatsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Vidal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C.-A</forename><surname>Possamai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="157" to="162" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A practical guide to the probability density approximation (PDA) with improved implementation and error characterization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interference e↵ects of choice on confidence: Quantum characteristics of evidence accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kvam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pleskac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10645" to="10650" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Information theory of choice-reaction times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R J</forename><surname>Laming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling reaction time and accuracy of multiple-alternative decisions. Attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Leite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcli↵</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="246" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experimental validation of the di↵usion model based on a slow response time paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lerche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1194" to="1209" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Response times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">E↵ects of alcohol and practice on choice reaction time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Maylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="465" to="475" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An application of the poisson race model to confidence calibration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Merkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Van Zandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">391</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parameter recovery for the leaky competing accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Miletić</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Van Maanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Post choice information integration as a causal determinant of confidence: Novel data and a computational account</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="147" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Murthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shorter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Priddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Schall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontal eye field contributions to rapid corrective saccades</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1457" to="1469" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Between the devil and the deep blue sea: Tensions between scientific judgement and statistical model selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Brain &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What a di↵erence a parameter makes: A psychophysical comparison of random dot motion algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Pilly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Seitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Vision Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1599" to="1612" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two-stage dynamic signal detection: A theory of choice, decision time, and confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pleskac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="864" to="901" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Errors and error correction in choice-response tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="264" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time to detect errors as a function of factors a↵ecting choice-response time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Three kinds of error-signalling responses in a serial choice task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological refractory delay and response-stimulus interval duration in serial, choice-response tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="219" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consciousness is slower than you think</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology Section A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1081" to="1092" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some errors of perceptual analysis in visual search can be detected and corrected</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cumming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vyas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="332" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What does a man do after he makes an error? An analysis of response programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rodgers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="727" to="743" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Processing a display even after you make a response to it. How perceptual errors can be corrected</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vyas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology Section A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The hare and the tortoise: Emphasizing speed can change the evidence used to make decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Averell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1226" to="1243" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Suboptimality in perceptual decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Denison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="107" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcli↵</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling response times for two-choice decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcli↵</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rouder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of sequential sampling models for two-choice reaction time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcli↵</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="367" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling confidence and response time in recognition memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcli↵</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Starns</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling response times, choices, and confidence judgments in decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcli↵</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Starns</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="697" to="719" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating parameters of the di↵usion model: Approaches to dealing with contaminant reaction times and parameter variability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcli↵</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tuerlinckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="481" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Changes of mind in decisionmaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Resulaj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wolpert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">461</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating the dimension of a model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="464" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using covert response activation to test latent assumptions of formal decision-making models in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Servant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montagnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Burle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10371" to="10385" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Small is beautiful: In defense of the small-n design</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2083" to="2101" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models for choice-reaction time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="260" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disentangling decision models: From independence to competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A markov chain monte carlo version of the genetic algorithm di↵erential evolution: Easy bayesian computing for real parameter spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ter Braak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistics and Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="249" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The racing di↵usion model of speeded decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/xuwbk</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/xuwbk" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using time-varying evidence to test models of decision dynamics: Bounded di↵usion vs. the leaky competing accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">79</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A generalized, likelihood-free method for posterior estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sederberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="250" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A method for e ciently sampling from distributions with correlated dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sederberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="368" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The framing of decisions and the psychology of choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">211</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="458" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The time course of perceptual choice: the leaky, competing accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="550" to="592" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A di↵usion model decomposition of the e↵ects of alcohol on perceptual decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dutilh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychopharmacology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">219</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1017" to="1025" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian approach to di↵usion models of decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vandekerckhove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tuerlinckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<editor>V. M. Sloutsky, B. C. Love, &amp; K. McRae</editor>
		<meeting>the 30th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cognitive Science Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1429" to="1434" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response reversals in recognition memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Van Zandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Maldonado-Molina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1147</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic models of simple judgments: I. Properties of a selfregulating accumulator module</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vickers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, and Life Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="194" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Nonlinear Dynamics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic models of simple judgments: II. Properties of a selforganizing PAGAN (parallel, adaptive, generalized accumulator network) model for multichoice tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vickers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, and Life Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Nonlinear Dynamics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpreting the parameters of the di↵usion model: An empirical validation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Rothermund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1206" to="1220" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An EZ-di↵usion model for response time and accuracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J L</forename><surname>Van Der Maas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P P P</forename><surname>Grasman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing the validity of conflict drift-di↵usion models for use in estimating cognitive processes: A parameter-recovery study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Servant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="286" to="301" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Zeno&apos;s paradox in decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yearsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">283</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1828" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of error detection: conflict monitoring and the error-related negativity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="931" to="959" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
