<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Neural evidence for age-related deficits in the representation of state spaces</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexa</forename><surname>Ruel</surname></persName>
							<email>alexa.ruel@mail.concordia.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Concordia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H4B 1R6</postCode>
									<settlement>Montreal</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Bolenz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Chair of Lifespan Developmental Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Dresden</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dresden</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Cluster of Excellence &quot;Science of Intelligence&quot;</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shu-Chen</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Chair of Lifespan Developmental Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Dresden</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dresden</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Cluster of Excellence &quot;Centre</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Tactile Internet with Human-in-the-Loop&quot;</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Technische Universität Dresden</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dresden</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Education and Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Freie Universität Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Eppinger</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Concordia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H4B 1R6</postCode>
									<settlement>Montreal</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">PERFORM center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Concordia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H4B 1R6</postCode>
									<settlement>Montreal</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Chair of Lifespan Developmental Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Dresden</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dresden</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Neural evidence for age-related deficits in the representation of state spaces</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>reinforcement-learning</term>
					<term>model-based</term>
					<term>model-free</term>
					<term>task demands</term>
					<term>single-trial EEG</term>
					<term>ERP</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Under high cognitive demands, older adults tend to resort to simpler, habitual or model-free decision strategies. This age-related shift in decision behavior has been attributed to deficits in the representation of the cognitive maps, or state spaces, necessary for more complex modelbased decision-making. Yet, the neural mechanisms behind this shift remain unclear. In this study we used a modified two-stage Markov task in combination with computational modeling and single-trial EEG analyses to establish neural markers of age-related changes in goal-directed decision-making under different demands on the representation of state spaces. Our results reveal that the shift to simpler decision strategies in older adults is due to a) impairments in the representation of the transition structure of the task and b) a diminished signaling of the reward value associated with decision options. In line with the diminished state space hypothesis of human aging, our findings suggest that deficits in goal-directed, model-based behavior in older adults result from impairments in the representation of state spaces of cognitive tasks.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>RUNNING HEAD: Age-related deficits in the representation of state spaces The ability to make goal-directed decisions that rely on mental models of the environment has been shown to decline with advancing age over adult development. However, the neural mechanisms underlying these age-related deficits in complex decision-making remain unclear. In the current study, we administered a modified two-stage Markov task and used computational modeling in combination with single-trial EEG analyses to examine the neural mechanism behind the age-related shift towards model-free behavior in older adults.</p><p>Rather than making decisions guided by a mental model of the task environment (i.e., model-based decision-making), older adults tend to engage in a simpler model-free strategy, which involves learning associations between choice actions and rewards <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bolenz, Kool, Reiter &amp; Eppinger, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Eppinger, Heekeren &amp; Li, 2015)</ref>. Recent work suggests that instead of being explained by changes in motivational factors, the shift towards model-free decision-making in older adults seems to result from age-related difficulties in representing a mental model of the task environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Eppinger, Kray, Mock &amp; Mecklinger, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Eppinger &amp; Kray, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr"></ref> Hämmerer &amp;Eppinger, 2012), a critical prerequisite for model-based decision making.</p><p>Specifically, through manipulating incentives and task (transition) structure complexity, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bolenz et al., (2019)</ref> demonstrated that the complexity is what mattered when it came to engagement in more cognitively demanding strategies such as model-based learning. These difficulties seen in older adults could arise from the deterioration of prefrontal brain regions during aging <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Eppinger, Walter, Heekeren &amp; Li, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Raz et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Resnick, Pham, Kraut, Zonderman &amp; Davatzikos, 2003)</ref> as these regions are thought contribute to representing a mental model of the task environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Schuck et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Wilson, Fern &amp; Tadepalli, 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">, Vikbladh et al, 2019</ref>. Agingrelated declines in dopamine modulation of the frontal-striatal network (see <ref type="bibr">Li &amp; Rieckmann,</ref> 2014 for a review) may also contribute to less distinctive representations of state spaces. In line with this view, work by Wunderlich and colleagues showed that administration of L-DOPA in younger adults (to augment dopamine concentration) enhanced model-based over model-free control <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Wunderlich, Smittenaar &amp; Dolan, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>In this study, our aim was therefore twofold; a) to determine if reducing the demands on representing a mental model of the state transitions may lead older adults to engage in greater model-based decision-making, and b) to examine the neural dynamics underlying age-related deficits in goal-directed decision-making. To do so, we recorded electroencephalography <ref type="bibr">(EEG)</ref> activity and adopted a single trial EEG regression approach (based on <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Fischer &amp; Ullsperger, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Fischer, Danielmeier, Villringer, Klein &amp; Ullsperger, 2016)</ref>. This novel approach allowed us to directly examine previous hypotheses regarding the relationship between prediction errors and neural data for both age groups, and therefore provide unique insights into the neural mechanism underlying the age-related shift toward model-free decision-making in older adults.</p><p>To address our first aim, we had younger and older adults complete a modified two-stage Markov decision task with two conditions which differed with respect to the predictability of the state transitions (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). In the low demand condition, common transitions between states occurred on 80% of the trials whereas rare transitions occurred on 20% of the trials. In this condition, the transition structure of the task should be simpler to represent, and thus the upcoming state should be easier to predict. In contrast, in the high demand condition, common transitions occurred on 60% of the trials whereas rare transitions occurred on 40% of the trials.</p><p>In this condition the representation of the task transition structure should be less differentiated, and it should be harder for subject to predict the upcoming state. We hypothesized that both age groups would demonstrate a greater contribution of model-based decision-making in the low demand compared to the high demand condition. To address the second aim, we investigate the neural dynamics underlying age-related differences in model-free and model-based decision making and focus on components of event-related potential (ERP) that have been shown to reflect model-based and model-free decision processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger, Walter &amp; Li, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Sambrook, Hardwick, Wills, &amp; Goslin, 2018)</ref>: the stimulus-locked P300 component and two feedbacklocked components (feedback-related negativity (FRN) and reward-related positivity (RewP)). In line with previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Gläscher, Daw, Dayan &amp; O'Doherthy, 2010)</ref>, we assume that the P300 component covaries with the degree to which participants update their internal state and value representation on a trial-by-trial basis <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gläscher et al., 2010)</ref>.</p><p>To examine the neural mechanisms underlying feedback processing during decisionmaking, we focus on the FRN and RewP components. While the FRN has been suggested to be sensitive to negative prediction errors during reinforcement learning tasks (signed prediction errors; <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Nieuwenhuis et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Walsh &amp; Anderson, 2012)</ref> and more recently shown to reflect surprise (unsigned prediction errors; <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cavanagh, Figueroa, Cohen &amp; Frank, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Talmi, Atkinson, El-Deredy, 2013)</ref>, it has also been shown to be modulated by PEs when behavioral adjustments are required <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cavanagh, Figueroa, Cohen &amp; Frank, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Hauser et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Talmi, Atkinson &amp; El-Deredy, 2013)</ref>, making its specific relationship to PEs unclear.</p><p>While some work suggests that the RewP component may be more related to tracking RPE magnitudes on positive outcomes reward feedback, there remains evidence that these two feedback-locked components share some degree of overlap, making studying these components in isolation difficult.(see <ref type="bibr">Holroyd, Kringolson &amp; Lee, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Holroyd, Pakzad-Vaezi &amp; Kridolson, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Proudfit, 2015)</ref>. Thus, together, although positive and negative outcomes seem to generate ERPs with opposite polarities, the exact relationship between these components and RPEs remains unclear. In contrast to the P300, we did not expect these feedback-locked components to vary across demand conditions (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Eppinger et al., 2017)</ref>. However, consistent with previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Eppinger et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Eppinger &amp; Kray, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hämmerer, Li, Müller &amp; Lindenberger, 2011)</ref> predicted that the amplitude of the FRN and RewP components during probability reinforcement learning would be attenuated in old age.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method Participants</head><p>Twenty-eight healthy young adults and 30 healthy older adults participated in the study.</p><p>Participants were recruited via the participant pool of the Lifelab in the Chair of Lifespan Developmental Neuroscience. We excluded participants from analysis for whom 20% of reaction times were under 200 ms (1 younger adult, 3 older adults) or who showed an insufficient understanding of the task during the practice trials, assessed by choice behavior (2 older adults).</p><p>The final sample size therefore consisted of 26 younger adults (Mage = 23.73 years, SD = 3.08, 11 males), and 25 older adults (Mage = 72.32 years, SD = 3.36, 13 males). All participants gave informed written consent before participating. The ethics committee of the Technische Universität Dresden approved the study. Participants received a minimum payment of 5.00 euros and an additional amount (up to 8.00 euros) depending on rewards obtained within the task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimuli</head><p>Stimuli for the first stage of the task were two colored figures, representing the two different choice options. Stimuli at the second stage was 8 pairs of colored figures (i.e., Gogos) which were created using free software. To avoid carryover effects, 2 new pairs of stimuli were used in each block of the task. All stimuli were further processed in Adobe Photoshop. Stimuli for the second stage of the task were on a blue or brown background, representing the two different states participants could transition to at the second stage. Feedback stimuli for each trial either indicated a reward of 10-euro cents in green or 0-euro cents in red (i.e., no reward). All stimuli were presented on a 19-inch CRT computer screen using the Eprime 2.0 software (PST Inc., Pittsburgh, PA).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task</head><p>A modified version of the two-stage Markov decision-task (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Daw, Gershman, Seymour, Dayan &amp; Dolan, 2011)</ref> was administered to all participants (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Eppinger et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Eppinger et al., 2017)</ref>. All participants completed two 60%-40% transition probability blocks, and two 80%-20% transition probability blocks, corresponding to a high demand and low demand condition, respectively. Each block contained 116 trials. Block order alternated within participants and was counterbalanced across participants. Before the start of each condition block, participants were informed about the transition probability condition.</p><p>The task involved two decision stages with one decision at each stage. During the first stage, participants had to make a choice between two first-stage options (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref>).</p><p>Depending on this choice, participants ended up in one of two possible second-stage states based on the transition probabilities: In the example illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, the left option is associated with a higher probability (i.e., common trials, 60% or 80%) of transitioning to the lower left second-stage state, and a lower probability (i.e., rare trials, 40% or 20%) of transitioning to the lower right second-stage state. The reverse is true for the right stimulus at stage one. Secondstage states were represented by two colored squares (with a separate color in each individual state) and upon these squares, the second-stage choice options (Gogo figures) were displayed between which participants made a choice. Finally, second-stage choices were either rewarded (10-euro cents) or unrewarded (0-euro cents) and the probability of receiving a reward followed from the chosen second-stage option. Consequently, at the second stage of the task, participants had to learn which of the 4 stimuli is currently associated with the highest probability of reward.</p><p>However, to ensure participants continuously learn during the task, the reward probabilities fluctuated over time based on four independent Gaussian random walks with a standard deviation of 0.025 and reflecting boundaries of 0.25 and 0.75 (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Doll, Simon &amp; Daw, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Choice options at both stages were randomly counterbalanced to appear on the left or right side of the screen. Responses at both stages were made by using the "f" key for the left option, and "j" key for the right option using a standard keyboard. Choices were presented for a response window of 2 s and after a choice was made, the chosen option was highlighted for the remaining time. If participants did not make a choice within the response window, the trial ended, and the task proceeded with the next trial. The colored squares signaling the second stages and the received reward at the end of the trial were each presented for 1 s. Prior to both decision stages and the reward, a fixation cross was displayed for 500 ms. To ensure all participants understood the task, a cover story was applied. The cover story was about a businessman who had to decide between two airline companies. Each airline (represented by two different figures) would bring the businessman to one of two islands on which two populations of inhabitants could be found (i.e., the Gogo figures on the blue and brown background colors).</p><p>However, the airlines are somewhat unreliable regarding their destinations, and thus end up on one island most of the time, but the other some of the time (i.e., reflecting the 80%-20% and 60%-40% transition probabilities). The task of the businessman is to make as much money as possible by tracking information about the reward probabilities of the options at the second stage of the task and the transition structure at the first stage. Importantly, participants are informed that the productivities (reward probabilities) of the populations change across time. At the first stage, each stimulus has a higher probability of resulting in a transition to one of the two second stage states (common transitions: 80% or 60%) and a lower probability of leading to the other of the two (rare transitions: 20% or 40%). Due to the greater predictability of the transitions in the 80%-20% condition, we predicted that both age groups should demonstrate greater model-based decision-making in this condition in contrast to the 60%-40% condition. (b) Trial procedure of the two-stage task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>While the experimenter prepared the electroencephalogram (EEG), participants completed a demographic questionnaire as well as the BIS/BAS personality questionnaire <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Carver &amp; White, 1994)</ref>, the identical pictures, spot a word <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Yuspeh &amp; Vanderploeg, 2000)</ref> and an N-back task. Before starting the experimental task, all participants completed a computer training session. During this training session, participants were familiarized with the reward probability structure of the task and had to perform 10 choices between options with a fixed reward probability of 60%. To help their understanding of the probabilistic structure of the task, the experimenter explained the reward probabilities in terms of absolute numbers (i.e., receiving a reward in approximately six of ten trials). Participants then completed 10 trials on which they had to find the option (out of two) with the highest reward probability. After the successful completion of these 10 training trials, the experimenter explained that the reward probabilities would change slowly across the experiment. Participants were shown two examples of the random walks <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig 1a)</ref>. In the next part of the training phase, participants were introduced to the transition probabilities connecting the first and the second stage of the task. They were explained that the task involved common and rare transitions and shown an illustration of these transitions (similar to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig 1a)</ref>. Following this explanation, participants completed ten trials in which they practiced transitioning from the first to the second stage of the task. At the end of the training session, participants completed 30 full practice trials of the experimental task which involved different stimuli than in the experimental task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>Behavioral data were analysed using R (R Development Core Team, 2010), while the RL model (based on <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Eppinger et al. 2017)</ref> and the single trial regression analyses (based on Fischer <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">&amp; Ullsperger, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Fischer, Danielmeier, Villringer, Klein &amp; Ullsperger, 2016)</ref> were implemented using the mfit toolbox <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Gershman, 2016)</ref> MATLAB (Mathworks Inc. Natick, MA). EEG data were processed and analysed in MATLAB using EEGLAB <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Delorme &amp; Makeig, 2004</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>First Stage Choice Data</head><p>In an initial attempt to descriptively capture the degree to which participants engaged in model-based decision-making in the two conditions we ran a multi-level regression analysis of stay-switch behavior at the first stage of the task. Stay-switch behavior was defined as the probability of repeating a choice at the first stage as a function of the transition (common, rare) and the feedback (reward, no reward) on the previous trial. Mean stay probabilities were analysed using a mixed effects logistic regression with the factors of age group (younger or older adults), condition (60%-40% or 80%-20%), previous transition (common or rare) and previous trial feedback (reward or no reward). All regressions were run using the lme4 package <ref type="bibr">(Bates, Maechler, Bolker &amp; Walker, 2013)</ref> in R (R Development Core Team, 2010).</p><p>Based on past results <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Daw, Gershman, Seymour, Dayan &amp; Dolan, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Eppinger et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Eppinger et al., 2017)</ref>, we predicted that a pure model-free decision strategy will be reflected by a main effect of reward ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref>). That is, that participants using a purely modelfree strategy should be more likely to repeat choices that were rewarded on the previous trial and more likely to switch their first stage choice after non-rewarded trials. In contrast, a model-based decision strategy should be reflected by an interaction between the transition and the feedback received on the previous trial. This is the case because a pure model-based agent would be more likely to repeat choices after rewarded trials with a common transition and after non-rewarded trials with a rare transition. They would also be more likely to switch first-stage choices after rewarded trials with a rare transition and after non-rewarded trials with a common transition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational Modeling</head><p>To better understand the mechanisms underlying choice behavior in the task we ran a modified version of a well-established computational model <ref type="bibr">(Daw, German, Seymour, Dayan &amp; Dolan, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Eppinger et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Eppinger et al., 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wunderlich et al., 2012)</ref>. Each participant's choice behavior was fitted using a hybrid RL model. This model first acquires independent state-action values (Q values) for both a model-free and a model-based decisionmaking algorithm and then computes an integrated Q value as a weighted mean of model-based and model-free Q values. This weighting is controlled by a model-based weight which ranges from 0 to 1 and was held constant across trials for a given participant (but varies between conditions). A model-based weight closer to 0 represents a greater contribution of model-free behavior, while in contrast, a model-based weight closer to 1 reflects a greater contribution of model-based decision-making. Further, the integrated Q values were converted into choice probabilities by using a softmax function (see equation 6).</p><p>The model parameters were estimated for each condition separately and participant individually as maximum a posteriori estimates. These parameters were held constant across trials but were allowed to vary across participants and within each condition across states for the same participant. Trial by trial reward prediction errors (RPEs) were extracted for each participant and were consequently used as predictors in the single trial EEG regression analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description of the computational model</head><p>In each trial t of the task, a participant visited two states s1,t and s2,t at the first and second stage, respectively, decided for two actions a1,t and a2,t and received a final reward rt at state 2.</p><p>We model the reward expectation held for each state-action pair as Q(s,a). Specifically, the reward expectations held by the model-free decision-making system are represented by <ref type="bibr">QMF(s,a)</ref> and the reward expectations held by the model-based decision-making system are represented by QMB(s,a).</p><p>Model-free state-action values. Model-free state-action values were updated using SARSA () temporal-difference learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Rummery &amp; Niranjan, 1994)</ref>. After each trial, a reward prediction error δ was computed as the difference between the expected and the actual experienced reward for each of the two decision stages.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">1, = Q MF ( 2, , 2, ) − ( 1, , 1, ) 2, = − ( 2, , 2, )</formula><p>These RPEs were then used to update the state-action values according to the equation</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">( 2, , 2, , ) = ( 2, 2, ) + 2 2 ,<label>(1)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">( 1, , 1, ) = ( 1, , 1, ) + 1 δ 1 + 1 2 (2)</formula><p>where αi represented the learning rate at a given stage, and λ represented the eligibility trace decay.</p><p>By means of the eligibility trace, RPEs from the second stage of the Markov task can immediately result in an update of the model-free reward expectations at the first stage.</p><p>Following the established version of the reinforcement-learning model <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Daw et al., 2011)</ref>, the eligibility traces are not assumed to carry over from trial to trial because the task structure involved constantly changing reward probabilities (determined by the random walks) for each option across trials.</p><p>Model-based state-action values. Model-based state-action values are computed for each trial using Bellman's equation <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Sutton &amp; Barto, 1998</ref>) by taking the model-free state-action values from the second stage and the transition probabilities into account (Eq. 3):</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">( 1, , 1, ) = 1 * [max a ( 2, = 1, ) ] + 2 * [max a ( 2, = 2, ) )] ,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The p1 and p2 in Eg. 3 refer to the probabilities of transitioning to each of the two secondstage states after choosing action a1,t ( pcommon for common transitions 1-pcommon for rare transitions). Since transition probabilities were not explicitly instructed, we estimated pcommon as a free parameter in both transition probability conditions. Note that in the two-stage Markov task, the transition matrix is constant; thus, our model does not update the transition probabilities on a trial-to-trial basis but considers transition probabilities to be constant within each experimental condition.</p><p>Finally, the action-value for the full hybrid model (Qnet) was calculated as the weighted sum of the model-based and model-free action-values:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">= * ( 1, , 1, ) + (1 − ) * ( 1, , 1, ),<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where is the weighting parameter. At the second stage, the Qnet state-action value is equal to the model-free state-action value (Qnet|S2= QMF|S2).</p><p>Softmax rule. Choice probabilities at the first stage were calculated according to a softmax rule:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">1 ( 1 , ) = ( 1 * [ | 1 ( 1 , )+ * ( 1 )]) ( ( 1 * [ | 1 ( 1 , )+ * ( 1 )]) )+( ( 1 * [ | 1 ( 2 , )+ * ( 2 )]) )<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where 1 represents the inverse softmax temperature parameter which controls the distinctiveness of the choices within each stage. We allowed both learning parameters (α1, α2) as well as the softmax temperature parameters ( 1 , 2 ) to change between both stages of the task. The indicator function rep(a) is 1 if a is a top-stage action and is the same as was chosen on the previous trial and zero otherwise. Together, the rep(a) function and the parameter capture the degree of perseveration ( &gt; 0) or switching ( &lt; 0) for the first stage <ref type="bibr">(Lau &amp; Glimcher, 2005)</ref>.</p><p>Choice probabilities at the second stage were calculated similarly as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">2 ( 1 , ) = ( 2 * | 2 ( 1 , )) ( 2 * | 2 ( 1 , )) + ( 2 * | 2 ( 2 , ))<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The model therefore contained eight parameters (α1, α2, 1 , 2 , , , , pcommon) and this set of parameters was estimated separately for each individual participant for each of the two conditions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EEG recordings and Analysis</head><p>Two approaches were used to examine the EEG data based on our predictions: (1) ERP analyses that allow us to study the P300 and feedback-locked components (FRN and RewP) across conditions and (2) Multiple single-trial robust regression analyses that allow us to examine the trial-wise correlation between ERP components and time-varying parameters from the computational model. Specifically, we explored the prediction that the P300 covaries with value prediction errors (VPEs) at the second stage of the task while variance in the FRN and</p><p>RewP may be explained by participants' reward prediction errors (RPEs).</p><p>Pre-processing. EEG and electrooculography (EOG) were recorded continuously from 64 active Ag/AgCl electrodes embedded in an elastic plastic cap, using a BrainVision Recorder (Brain Products GmbH, Gilching, Germany). The electrodes were placed according to the international 10-10 system. During the recording, electrodes were referenced to the right mastoid, and rereferenced offline to the average of the left and right mastoids. The EEG signal was first filtered using a band pass filter in the range of 0.01 and 100Hz and were digitized with a sampling rate of 1000Hz. The ground electrode was placed above the forehead. Vertical and horizontal EOGs were recorded next to each eye and below the left eye. Electrode impedances were kept below 5kΩ.</p><p>For all statistical analyses, in addition to being re-sampled at 500Hz, a low-pass filter of 30Hz and a high-pass filter of 0.5Hz were applied to the EEG data. Next, bad channels were linearly interpolated and artifacts were rejected by visual inspection of the continuous data.</p><p>Visual rejection resulted in 6.38% of trials being rejected for younger adults, and 5.83% of trials for older adult groups. Each data set was then epoched (-1 to 3s) surrounding the second stage choice and run through independent component analysis (ICA) to allow for further artifact rejection. Blinks, eye movements and muscle components determined using the ICA were marked and were rejected from further data analysis. All trials for which participants did not provide a first or a second stage response were removed from both the EEG and behavioral data.</p><p>ERP Analysis. The larger 4s epochs were then re-epoched (-200ms to 800ms) around the first stage choices, second stage stimuli and feedback phases of the task, where 0 corresponds to stimuli/feedback onset. These epochs were then baseline corrected by subtracting the average of the first 200ms pre-stimulus activity from the entire epoch (-200 to 800ms). To match trial numbers across transition probability conditions (i.e., 80%, 60%, 40% and 20%) we randomly drew a subset of trials according to the number of trials in the least frequency condition (20%) in each condition to calculate the individual participant ERP averages, resulting in 32 trials for the second stage stimulus-locked ERPs and 29 trials for the feedback-locked ERPs.</p><p>Stimulus-locked ERPs at the first stage: Choice Period. We analysed two ERPs at the first stage choice period: the N200 and P300 components at Pz. The N200 was measured as the mean amplitude in a 220-320ms time window after the onset of the first stage stimuli for younger adults, and as the mean amplitude in the 230-330ms time window for older adults. The P300 was measured as the mean amplitude in a 300-400ms time window after the onset of the first stage stimuli for younger adults, and as the mean amplitude in the 350-450ms time window for older adults. These times were determined separately for both age groups by building a 100ms window around the peaks which were determined by visual inspection. We then used a repeated measures ANOVA with the between subject's factor age group (younger and older adults) and the within subject's factors condition (80%-20% and 60%-40%) and transition type (common, rare).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimulus-locked ERPs at the second stage: Transition Phase.</head><p>The P300 component at the transition phase of the task was measured as the mean amplitude in a 300-400ms time window after the onset of the color patches during the transition phase for younger adults, and as the mean amplitude in the 410-510ms time window after stimulus onset for older adults. We also examined the transition phase effects at the frontal electrode FCz as the mean amplitude in a 300-400ms time window for younger adults, and as the mean amplitude in the 410-510ms time window after stimulus onset for older adults. These times were determined separately for both age groups by building a 100ms window around the peaks which were determined by visual inspection. To examine these components, we used a repeated measures ANOVA with the between subjects factor of age group (younger and older adults) and the within subjects factors of condition (80%-20% and 60%-40%) and transition type (common, rare). after stimulus onset for older adults. These times were determined separately for both age groups by building a 100ms window around the peaks which were determined by visual inspection. To examine the mean N200 and P300 amplitudes, we used a repeated measures ANOVA with the between subjects factor age of group (younger and older adults) and the within subjects factors of condition (80%-20% and 60%-40%) and transition type (common, rare).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimulus-locked</head><p>Feedback-locked ERPs. The feedback-locked ERPs were measured as the mean amplitude in the 210-to 310-ms time window after stimulus onset for younger adults, and in the 250-to 350-ms time window for older adults. These times were determined separately for both age groups by building a 100ms window around the peaks which were determined by visual inspection. For analyzing differences in these amplitudes, we used a repeated measures ANOVA with the between subjects factor of age group (younger and older adults) and the within subjects factors of condition (80%-20% and 60%-40%) and feedback (reward, no reward). From the first level regressions, we extracted values for each subject in each condition for the time window of interest based on the maximal effects at the first level. In order to capture the maximum amplitudes found at the first stage, we used a time window of 330-430ms. These b values from the first level regressions were standardized by their SDs before being averaged within each subject to ensure comparability between subjects. These new β weights representing the effect of VPE on the EEG signal were then used as the dependent variable in a set of twoway ANOVAs using condition and age group as predictors. This second level of analysis allowed for the examination of main effects of condition and age on the VPE β weights as well as the interaction effect between condition and age group on the VPE β weights. The main effects are therefore interpreted as an interaction between VPE and the main effect predictor on the P300 component, while a significant interaction is interpreted as a 3-way interaction.</p><p>In a separate analysis, we regressed the current trial's transition (common vs. rare) on the second stage stimulus-locked EEG data to examine the effect of transition on the signal in each condition. Analyses examining the effect of VPE and transition on the P300 component were run separately due to the collinearity between these predictors. All steps of analysis were identical to those described for the VPE regression and ANOVA. See Supplemental Material ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>) for details.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Multiple Single-Trial Robust Regression of Feedback-locked ERPs.</head><p>To examine if RPEs explained significant variance in the two feedback-locked components (FRN and RewP), we regressed trial-by-trial signed and unsigned RPEs on the feedback-locked EEG data in each condition. All steps of analysis were identical to those described for the VPE regressions. Using signed RPEs as predictor, first stage regressions revealed maximum amplitudes of positive going EEG activity at electrode Pz approximately 270ms after stimulus onset in the 60%-40% condition, and around 270ms after feedback-onset in the 80%-20% condition, consistent with the RewP component. We therefore used a 220-320ms time window for the second level analyses.</p><p>In contrast, using unsigned RPEs as predictor, the first stage regressions revealed a significant age group effect, but no significant effects of condition. We therefore did not run second level analyses using unsigned RPEs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Choice Behavior</head><p>In line with previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Daw et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Eppinger et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Eppinger et al., 2017)</ref>, we examined choice behavior (stay/switch) at the first stage was analysed using condition (80%-20%, 60%-40%), previous trial transition (common, rare), the previous trial feedback (reward, no reward), as well as age group (younger adults, older adults) as predictors in a mixed-effects logistic regression (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">table 1</ref>). This analysis revealed significant main effects of age group (β = -0.400, SE = 0.107, p &lt; 0.001) and feedback (β = 0.280, SE = 0.046, p &lt; 0.001). As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref>, older adults had a greater tendency to repeat their choices at the first stage than younger adults and across age groups participants were more likely to stick to their choice after rewarded compared to unrewarded trials. As expected based on previous studies, the analysis revealed a set of signficant two and three way interaction between the factors (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">table 1</ref>). Most importantly we also obtained the predicted four-way interaction between the factors age group, condition, transition and feedback (β = -0.060, SE = 0.020, p = 0.001). To further examine this interaction, we performed separate regression analyses for each age group. These analyses revealed significant three-way interactions between condition, transition and feedback in both age groups (younger adults: β = -0.215, SE = 0.026, p &lt; 0.001, older adults: β = -0.081, SE = 0.032, p = 0.011; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Supplementary Table S1</ref> for regression by group).</p><p>To further analyse these interactions, we performed analyses separately for the two conditions and age groups.</p><p>In the 60%-40% condition, we obtained significant transition by feedback interaction for younger adults (β = 0.266, SE = 0.031, p &lt; 0.001) but not older adults (β = 0.047, SE = 0.041, p = 0.247). In contrast, in the 80%-20% condition, we obtained a significant interaction between transition and feedback for both age groups (younger adults: β = 0.706, SE = 0.042, p &lt; 0.001;</p><p>older adults: β = 0.220, SE = 0.050, p &lt; 0.001).</p><p>Together, these results suggest that younger adults show model-based behavior in both conditions yet relied more heavily on this strategy in the 80%-20% compared to the 60%-40%</p><p>condition (β of 0.71 vs. 0.27). Older adults, in contrast, demonstrated no evidence of modelbased decision-making in the 60%-40% condition but did engage in the model-based decision strategy in the 80%-20% condition (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref>). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational Modeling Results</head><p>The analysis of estimated model parameters revealed a significant main effect of condition (F(1,49) = 5.288, p =0.026), a trending main affect of age (F(1,49) = 3.072, p =0.086) and a trending age by condition interaction (F(1,49) = 3.355, p =0.073) on the mixing weight parameter (Ω). In line with our behavioral results, this suggests that both age groups showed greater model-based behavior in the 80%-20% condition as compared to the 60%-40% condition.</p><p>In addition to the condition differences in the mixing weight parameter, we found significant age by condition interactions for the softmax (β1) (F(1,49) = 4.729, p = 0.035) and</p><p>learning rate (α1) parameters at the first stage (F(1,49) = 6.738, p = 0.012) as well as the pcommon parameter (F(1,49) = 8.487, p = 0.005)(see Supplemental Material <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table S2</ref>). To further analyse these interactions, we performed analyses separately for the two age groups.</p><p>Analyses in younger adults revealed larger β1 and pcommon parameters in the 80%-20%</p><p>condition as compared to the 60%-40% condition (β1: t = -2.044, p = 0.048; pcommon t = -4.589, p &lt; 0.001) whereas no such effects were obtained for older adults (p's &gt; 0.665). The condition differences in the softmax parameter suggest that younger adults had a better representation of the value of the choice options than older adults did at the first stage of the task. The condition differences in the pcommon parameter indicate that the younger adults had a more distinctive representation of the transition probabilities in the 80%-20% condition as compared to the 60%-40% condition.</p><p>Our analyses also revealed a main effect of age group for the learning rate at the second stage (α 2 ; F(1,49)=4.412, p = 0.041), indicating that in younger adults recent outcomes had a greater impact on value predictions than in older adults. We also found a main effect of age group for the choice stickiness parameter, ( ; F(1,49)=17.177, p &lt; 0.001) suggesting that older adults showed more perseverative behavior than younger adults in both conditions.</p><p>Together these findings show that the pronounced differences in model-based decision-making that we observed in the descriptive analyses may not be due to underlying differences in the degree of model-basedness between age groups but may reflect differences in the representation of the transition probabilities as well as in the distinctiveness of the choice patterns at the first stage. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ERP Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimulus-locked ERPs at the first stage: Choice Period</head><p>In line with previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger et al., 2017)</ref>, the analysis of the first stage stimuluslocked ERPs revealed a main effect of age group for the N200 component, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(F(1,49)</ref> = 5.898, p = 0.020). In addition, we found a main effect of age group (F(1,49) = 10.343, p = 0.003), and a main effect of condition (F(1,49) = 5.582, p = 0.022) for the P300 component. However, no significant interaction effects were for either of the components. These effects reflect that both the N200 and P300 were larger for younger adults as compared to older adults. Further, the P300</p><p>was larger in the 80%-20% condition for both age groups (see Supplemental <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure S2</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimulus-locked ERPs at the second stage: Transition Phase</head><p>The  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure S3</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimulus-locked ERPs at the second stage: Second stage Stimuli</head><p>The analysis of the stimulus locked ERPs at the second stage revealed a main effect of transition, indicating that larger P300 components were elicited following common compared to rare transitions (F(1, 49) = 38.008, p &lt; 0.000). Further, we found significant interactions between transition and age group (F(2,47) = 26.377, p &lt; 0.000) we well as between transition and transition condition (F(2,47) = 4.296, p = 0.044). To further examine the P300 effects, we ran the ANOVAs separately for the two age groups. For the younger adults, the analysis revealed a main effect of transition (F(1,24) = 50.073, p &lt; 0.001), as well as a significant interaction between transition and condition (F(1, 50) = 4.3087, p= 0.042). For older adults, the same analysis revealed no significant main effects or interactions (p's &gt; 0.265) (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig. 3A</ref>). Based on past work demonstrating that the parietal P300 component decreases with advancing age, while the frontal P300 may not (van Dinteren, Arns, Jongsma &amp; Kessels, 2014), we ran a post-hoc ERP analysis at electrode Fz. The results revealed no significant transition by condition interaction at electrode Fz for older adults, F(1, 50) = 0.5564, p= 0.459 indicting that the absence of transition effects is not due to an overall reduced P300 response at parietal sights.</p><p>Taken together, the results show a greater P300 component in the 80%-20% condition compared to the 60%-40% condition in younger adults whereas no effect of transition probability was observed in older adults. In line with the findings from the simulated behavioral data, we interpret the larger P300 component seen in the 80%-20% condition for younger adults as evidence for an increased ability to represent the task structure in this condition. The lack of a condition effect in the older adults reveal that a more predictable environment did not help them represent the task structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feedback-locked ERPs</head><p>The analysis of the feedback-locked components (FRN and RewP) revealed main effects of feedback (reward vs. no reward) (F(1,49) = 227.538, p&lt; 0.000), condition (F(1,49) = 4.670, p = 0.036) and age group (F(1,49)= 5.561, p= 0.023). Moreover, we obtained significant interactions between feedback and age group (F(1,49)= 57.339, p&lt; 0.000) as well as between condition and age group (F(1,49)= 8.144, p = 0.007). To further analyse these effects, we examined each age group separately.</p><p>For younger adults, this analysis revealed a main effect of feedback (F(1,24)= 193.478, p&lt;0.000) as well as a main effect of condition (F(1,24)= 9.084, p = 0.006). These main effects demonstrate that 1) the feedback component was larger (more negative going) for no reward feedback as compared to reward feedback and 2) was more negative in the 80%-20% condition as compared to the 60%-40% condition. For older adults, this analysis revealed only a main effect of feedback (F(1,23)= 37.211, p&lt; 0.001) which reflects a greater (more negative) FRN on no reward compared to reward trials (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig 3B)</ref>.   <ref type="bibr">(blue)</ref> and no rewards (red) for younger adults, and older adults. Bottom: The topographical map displays of the differences between no reward and reward feedback across for younger adults, and older adults.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Single Trial EEG Regression Results</head><p>Following work by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Fischer and Ullsperger (2013)</ref> and Fischer and colleagues (2016) we ran Multiple Single-Trial Robust Regression analyses on the EEG data to examine the impact of state and reward prediction errors on the corresponding event-related potentials. We then used standardized β weights from first the level analysis as the dependent variable in two-way ANOVAs involving the within-subject factor transition condition and the between-subjects factor age group (for details see Method section).</p><p>VPE effects on the second stage P300 component. The analysis of the effects of VPE' s on the P300 component revealed a significant main effect of age group (F(1, 49) = 10.770, p = 0.001) and a significant interaction between age group and transition condition (F(1, 49) = 5.361, p = 0.023). To further examine the age group x transition condition interaction effect, we analysed each group separately.</p><p>This analysis revealed a significant main effect of transition condition for younger adults (F(1,49) -4.405, p = 0.041), but not older adults (F(1,49) = 1.188, p = 0.281). As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 4A</ref>, in younger adults VPEs explained significantly more variance in the P300 in the 80%-20% condition (M= 0.477, SD = 1.006) compared to the 60%-40% condition (M= -0.037, SD = 0.739). No such effect was observed in older adults.</p><p>Together, these results demonstrate that, in younger adults, the P300 component covaries with VPEs across trials and this effect is more pronounced in the 80%-20% condition in which the younger adults had a more differentiated representation of the task environment. In contrast, in older adults the P300 signal was not explained by VPEs in either condition, which points to age-related deficits in the prediction of the value of states on the second stage of the task. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 4B</ref>, these findings suggest that the feedback-locked components (FRN and RewP) are more tightly linked to RPEs in younger compared to older adults.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The ability to make goal-directed decisions that rely on mental models of the environment has been shown to decline with advancing age <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bolenz et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Eppinger et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Eppinger et al., 2015)</ref>. However, the neural mechanisms underlying these age-related deficits in model-based decision-making are unclear. In the current study we used a modified version of a well-established sequential decision-making task and a novel neurocomputational approach involving model-based single-trial EEG analyses to (1) determine whether age differences in decision-making depend on the ability to internally represent the structure of the environment (the state space of the task) and (2) establish neural markers of age-related decline in goal-directed decision-making.</p><p>Younger and older adults completed a modified version of a two-stage sequential decision task (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Daw et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Eppinger et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Eppinger et al., , 2017</ref> in which we manipulated the demands on the representation of the state space in two conditions; a high representational demand condition in which the transition probabilities between the first and the second stage of the task were less differentiated (60%-40%) and a low representational demand condition in which the transition probabilities between these states were more differentiated (80%-20%) (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>).</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref>, the descriptive analyses revealed greater model-based behavior in both age groups in the low demand condition. In contrast, while younger adults demonstrated a significant contribution of model-based behavior in the high demand condition, in older adults we found no evidence for model-based behavior in this condition.</p><p>To better understand the mechanisms underlying these descriptive results we used a modified version of a hybrid reinforcement learning model (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Daw et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Eppinger et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Eppinger et al., 2017</ref>) which was fit to task behavior. The advantage of the computational modeling approach over the descriptive analysis (which just considers choices on the first stage of the task) is that the model can be used decompose behavior across stages of the task into different assumed mechanisms. One of these parameters is the so-called Omega-( ) Parameter, which reflects degree of model-based decision-making in the task. In line with our predictions, we found a main effect of condition, indicating that both age groups demonstrated an increase in model-based decision-making in the low demand compared to the high demand condition (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref> and <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>). Yet, in contrast to the descriptive results (and our predictions), we did not obtain a significant age group by condition interaction in the analysis in the -parameter.</p><p>However, we did find expected the two-way interactions for two other parameters that are related to decision behavior at the first stage. Specifically, younger adults showed an enhanced ability to discriminate between the two first stage choices ( 1 ) and a higher perceived common transition probability (pcommon) in the low demand compared to the high demand condition. No such effects were observed in older adults.</p><p>Taken together, there are two major conclusions that can be drawn from the analysis of the behavioral data. (1) Younger and older adults show greater model-based decision-making when the transition structure between states is more differentiated. This finding adds to the literature in younger adults by showing that it is not just motivational factors that support modelbased decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bolenz et al., 2019)</ref> but that the complexity of the task (transition) structure matters when it comes the engagement in decision strategies that are more cognitively demanding. The fact that we also observe a shift in the degree of model-based behavior from the high to the low demand condition in older adults, may be even more noteworthy. Results from a previous study <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bolenz et al., 2019)</ref> show that in contrast to younger adults, greater incentives do not lead to more model-based behavior in older adults. This suggests that it is not older adults'</p><p>willingness to engage in model-based behavior but deficits in the cognitive resources available to do so that limits them. Thus, when the cognitive demands on the representation of the task structure are reduced (such as when transition probabilities are more differentiable) older adults do show the ability to engage in greater model-based decision-making. (2) With respect to the computational mechanisms underlying age differences in model-based behavior in the two conditions, we observed an interesting mismatch between the outcome of the choice data regression analyses and the results of the computational modeling. Our descriptive regression analysis of first stage choice behavior reveals pronounced age differences in the condition effects on model-based behavior (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref>). However, these are not mirrored by a significant age group x condition interaction in the omega parameter in the computational modeling analysis.</p><p>Instead, we found that younger had a better subjective representation of the transition probabilities (reflected in the pcommon-parameter) as well as a more differentiated representations of the action values associated with the choice options than older adults. In line with previous work using a similar task by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Decker et al., (2016)</ref> who demonstrated that children had a good representation of the decision-making environment, but nevertheless failed to engage in significant model-based behavior, we hypothesize that the greater sensitivity of younger adults to the condition manipulation may not reflect greater model-based behavior per se but rather results from a greater ability to represent the transition probabilities between the first and second stage of the task.</p><p>To investigate the neural dynamics underlying age-related differences in model-based decision-making, we used two different analyses: a standard ERP analysis and multiple singletrial robust regression analyses (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Fischer &amp; Ullsperger, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Fischer et al., 2016)</ref>. To our knowledge, no prior study has examined age-related changes in decision-making using single trial EEG regression analyses. This method allows us to directly examine previous hypotheses regarding the relationship between computational parameters from the model and neural data for both age groups, and therefore provide unique insights into the neural mechanism underlying the age-related shift toward model-free behavior in older adults.</p><p>For both analyses, we focused on ERP components that have been shown previously to reflect model-based and model-free decision processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Sambrook et al., 2018)</ref>: the second-stage stimulus-locked P300 component and two feedback-locked components (FRN and RewP).</p><p>In line with our previous results <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger et al., 2017)</ref>, an analysis of the stimuluslocked ERPs at the second stage of the task showed a larger P300 component in response to common as opposed to rare transitions in younger adults. Further, among younger adults the difference between common and rare transitions was larger in the 80%-20% condition compared to the 60%-40% condition. This finding points to a more differentiated representation of the task transition structure in the 80%-20% condition among young adults, which is in line both with our computational modelling results and with previous work suggesting that the P300 covaries with the degree to which participants update their representation of the probabilistic transition structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger et al., 2017)</ref>. The single-trial analyses support this view by showing that in the younger adults, trial-by-trial changes in transition type predict changes in the second stage stimulus-locked EEG data (P300), whereas this is not the case in older adults.</p><p>In older adults the ERP analyses showed a larger P300 component for common compared to rare transitions, but no significant effect of demand condition. This finding suggests that the older adults were generally sensitive to the probability of outcomes of their choices but were unable to represent differences in probabilistic transition structures. This interpretation is consistent with our computational modelling results, showing no difference in the pcommon parameter between demand conditions in the elderly as well as with recent findings, suggesting that older adults may have deficits in the adjustment of internal models of the task environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bolenz et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Hämmerer et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Using single trial regression analyses, we also examined whether older adults differed from younger adults in their ability to predict the expected value of the state they ended up in on the second stage of the task (we refer to this as the state value prediction error (VPE)). VPEs were computed using Qvalues from the computational model. Therefore, these VPEs reflect participants ability to represent the relationship between their choice at the first stage of the task and the value of the options they arrive at during the second stage. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 4</ref>, this analysis revealed that in younger adults the P300 component covaries with the VPE and that this effect is more pronounced in the low demand condition compared to the high demand condition.</p><p>Thus, younger adults were better able to predict the value of the upcoming state in the more differentiable state transition structure (i.e., in the 80%-20% condition). In older adults, we observed no such relationship between VPEs and the P300 component. In our view, the most plausible interpretation of these results is that the age-related deficits in state value predictions are a downstream consequence of diminished representations of the task structure.</p><p>Based on previous work suggesting that the FRN and RewP components are involved in tracking RPEs following negative and positive feedback respectively, but share overlapping activity <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Eppinger et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Eppinger &amp; Kray, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Holroyd, Kringolson &amp; Lee, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Nieuwenhuis et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Proudfit, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Walsh &amp; Anderson, 2012)</ref>, we examined age-related differences in the trial-by-trial relationship between feedback-locked activity and reward prediction errors (RPEs) during learning. Given the current debate regarding the interpretation of these feedback-locked potentials), we examined both signed and unsigned</p><p>RPEs in order to determine if these feedback-locked signal covary with the degree to which participants recognized feedback as better or worse than predicted (signed RPE; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Ullsperger, Fischer, Nigbur &amp; Endrass, 2014)</ref> or the degree of surprise following feedback (unsigned RPE; <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cavanagh et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Talmi et al., 2013</ref> First, we investigated age differences in the feedback-locked activity <ref type="bibr">(FRN and RewP)</ref> averaged across trials and as a function of transition probability and reward outcome (reward and no reward). Based on previous results <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger et al., 2017)</ref> we predicted to see a more negative component (FRN) following unrewarded compared to rewarded trials (RewP), but we did not expect it to covary across transition probability conditions. Consistent with these predictions, both age groups showed a more negative going FRN component in response to unrewarded compared to rewarded feedback which elicited a RewP component (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Nieuwenhuis et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Walsh &amp; Anderson, 2012)</ref>. Furthermore, the effect of reward outcome did not differ across transition probability conditions, which replicates our own previous results <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Eppinger et al., 2017</ref>) (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 4</ref>).</p><p>To examine age difference in the neural dynamics of reward prediction error processing, we performed two analyses: The first analysis used trial-by-trial signed reward prediction errors (RPEs) as the independent variable whereas the second analysis used unsigned RPEs.</p><p>Interestingly, the first analysis revealed that trial-by-trial signed RPEs explained significant variance in the feedback-locked component for both younger and older adults in both the 60%-40% and 80%-20% condition. No such statistically significant effects were found in the second analysis when using the unsigned RPEs. While at first glance, this analysis seems to be in line with previous work on the FRN <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Fischer &amp; Ullsperger, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Talmi et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Walsh &amp; Anderson, 2012)</ref>, suggesting that our feedback-locked components reflect the processing of signed reward prediction errors during reinforcement learning, a disconfirmatory study would be needed to further examine the exact relationship between the FRN, the RewP and RPEs.</p><p>To summarize, we find that when the cognitive demands on representing the task environment are increased, older adults tend to resort to a simpler, model-free decision-making strategy as opposed to a more demanding and flexible model-based strategy. The ERP results</p><p>show that this shift in decision strategies in older adults results from deficits in their ability to 1) represent the probabilistic transition structure of the task and 2) predict the value of upcoming choice options. Thus, in line with the diminished state space hypothesis of human aging, our findings indicate that deficits in goal-directed, model-based behavior in older adults may result from impairments in the representation of state spaces of cognitive tasks. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>(a) Schematic representation of the modified two-stage Markov decision task. After making a first stage decision, participants made a second stage decision before either obtaining a reward or no reward on a given trial.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>ERPs at the second stage: Second stage Stimuli. The P300 component at the second stage of the task was measured as the mean amplitude in a 330-to 430-ms time window after stimulus onset (appearance of the two second stage choice stimuli on top of the colored background) for younger adults, and as the mean amplitude in the 430-to 530-ms time window</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Multiple</head><label></label><figDesc>Single-Trial Robust Regressions. To examine the relationship between variablesextracted from the computational model(VPE, RPE)  and EEG signals we used single-trial robust regressions in a multi-level approach. We first used general linear models (GLM) to regress single-trial EEG activity at each electrode and time point against the variables extracted from the computational model. The resulting regression weights from these analyses were standardized and averaged across their respective time windows. We then used these values in set of two-way ANOVAs to examine the effects of age group and condition on the association between computational parameters and single trial EEG signals.Multiple Single-Trial Robust Regression of stimulus-locked ERPs at the second stage.To examine if VPEs explained significant variance in the P300 component elicited by second stage stimuli, we regressed trial-by-trial VPEs on the second stage stimulus-locked EEG data in each condition (60%-40% and 80%-20%) (based on<ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Fischer &amp; Ullsperger, 2013;</ref> Fisher et al., 2016).Regressions were run separately by condition to allow for the effect of condition to be examined at the second stage (described below). Both regressions (one per condition) were run at the subject level, resulting in a set of b values (and their associated p-values) per subject per condition. These b values therefore represent the average effect of the VPEs at each electrode in 10ms windows from -200 to 600ms. These first stage regressions revealed maximum amplitudes of positive going EEG activity at electrode Pz approximately 350ms after stimulus onset in the 60%-40% condition, and around 410ms after stimulus-onset in the 80%-20% condition which are consistent with the P300 component.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Probability of repeating first choice (stay behavior) as a function of the transition on the previous trial (common or rare transition) and the feedback on the previous trial (reward or no reward). Stay probabilities are displayed separately for each condition (60%-40% and 80%-20%) across both age groups (younger and older adults). Vertical black lines represent the median, while boxes represent the inter-quartile range. Black dots represent individual participants' data, and the black outline represents the overall distribution.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>analysis of the transition phase ERPs at Pz revealed only a main effect of condition (F(1,49) = 18.6239, p &lt; 0.001) showing that both age groups revealed a larger component (more positive going) in the 60%-40% condition (M= 2.730, SD = 5.924) as compared to the 80%-20% condition (M = 1.391, SD = 4.540). Transition phase ERPs at the FCz revealed a main affect of transition (F(1,49)= 5.422, p = 0.024) as well as an interaction between transition and condition (F(1,49) = 5.045, p = 0.029) (see Supplemental</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>A) Top: ERPs elicited by second-stage stimuli at electrode Pz, displayed separately for the 80%-20% condition (red) and the 60%-40% condition (blue), as well as the common transitions (solid lines), and rare</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Analysis of feedback-locked EEG data. The second level analysis of the feedbacklocked component revealed only a significant main effect of age group (F(1,49) = 31.685, p &lt; 0.001), indicating that the RPEs explained significantly more variance in the feedback component for younger adults (M= 0.432, SD = 1.069) than older adults (M= -0.479, SD= 0.234).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>A) ERPs elicited by second-stage stimuli at electrode Pz of VPE variance at the second stage choice period displayed separately for young and older adults and 60%-40% and 80%-20% condition. VPEs were averaged in to high (red), neutral (blue) and low (green) values according to a tertiary split. The shaded areas within each plot represents the window of analysis (330-430ms). Topographies of maximum amplitudes are overlaid on each plot (350ms in the 6040 condition and 410ms in the 8020 condition). B) Feedback-locked ERPs at</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Funding:</head><label></label><figDesc>This work was supported by a grant from the German Research Foundation (DFG) [SFB 940/2 B7] as well as the National Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC), [funding reference number N01882] the DFG, German Research Foundation under Germany's Excellence Strategy -EXC 2002/1 "Science of Intelligence" -Project ID 390523135 and the EXC 2050/1 Cluster of Excellence "Centre for Tactile Internet with Human-in-the-Loop" Project ID 390696704. Furthermore, this research was undertaken, in part, thanks to funding from the Canada Research Chairs program.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Mixed-effects logistic regression on stay probabilities for first-stage choices.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Predictor</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Model parameters in each condition for both age groups.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>α1</cell><cell>α2</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell>pcommon</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Younger Adults 60%-40%</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>25 th percentile</cell><cell cols="5">0.245 0.516 3.335 2.395 0.095 0.288 0.389 0.543</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Median</cell><cell cols="5">0.530 0.600 4.495 3.254 0.161 0.448 0.482 0.659</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>75 th percentile</cell><cell cols="5">0.640 0.754 5.618 3.916 0.226 0.675 0.635 0.877</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>80%-20%</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>25 th percentile</cell><cell cols="5">0.203 0.482 4.156 3.138 0.109 0.487 0.386 0.861</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Median</cell><cell cols="5">0.365 0.628 5.321 3.948 0.141 0.630 0.518 0.966</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>75 th percentile</cell><cell cols="5">0.627 0.741 8.197 4.977 0.204 0.757 0.631 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Older Adults</cell><cell>60%-40%</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>25 th percentile</cell><cell cols="5">0.067 0.078 4.418 1.707 0.176 0.072 0.055 0.507</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Median</cell><cell cols="5">0.256 0.428 4.723 2.191 0.348 0.562 0.310 0.657</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>75 th percentile</cell><cell cols="5">0.561 0.642 6.464 3.514 0.472 1.00</cell><cell>0.528 1.00</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>80%-20%</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>25 th percentile</cell><cell cols="5">0.337 0.082 4.332 1.719 0.181 0.245 0.332 0.512</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Median</cell><cell cols="5">0.470 0.532 4.848 2.122 0.256 0.951 0.539 0.658</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>75 th percentile</cell><cell cols="5">0.730 0.942 6.145 3.265 0.471 1.00</cell><cell>0.654 1.00</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements:</head><p>The authors thank all participants for taking part in the study.</p><p>Age-related deficits in the representation of state spaces</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mächler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bolker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1406.5823</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacontrol of decision-making strategies in human aging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bolenz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kool</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Reiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Eppinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Elife</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">49154</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral inhibition, behavioral activation, and affective responses to impending reward and punishment: the BIS/BAS scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">319</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontal theta reflects uncertainty and unexpectedness during exploration and exploitation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Figueroa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cerebral cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2575" to="2586" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-based influences on humans&apos; choices and striatal prediction errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Seymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1204" to="1215" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From creatures of habit to goaldirected learners: Tracking the developmental emergence of model-based reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Decker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Otto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hartley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="848" to="858" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">EEGLAB: an open source toolbox for analysis of single-trial EEG dynamics including independent component analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Delorme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Makeig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of neuroscience methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ubiquity of model-based reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Doll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current opinion in neurobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1075" to="1081" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">To choose or to avoid: age differences in learning from positive and negative feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Eppinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Better or worse than expected? Aging, learning, and the ERN</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Eppinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mecklinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="539" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Of goals and habits: age-related and individual differences in goal-directed decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Eppinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Walter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Heekeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">253</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age-related prefrontal impairments implicate deficient prediction of future reward in older adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Eppinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Heekeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurobiology of aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2380" to="2390" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electrophysiological correlates reflect the integration of model-based and model-free decision information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Eppinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Walter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Real and fictive outcomes are processed differently but converge on a common adaptive mechanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ullsperger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1243" to="1255" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender influences on brain responses to errors and post-error adjustments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Danielmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Villringer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ullsperger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical priors for reinforcement learning models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">States versus rewards: dissociable neural prediction error signals underlying model-based and model-free reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gläscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O'doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="595" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dopaminergic and prefrontal contributions to reward-based learning and outcome monitoring during child development and aging. Developmental psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hämmerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Eppinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">862</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Life span differences in electrophysiological correlates of monitoring gains and losses during probabilistic reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hämmerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-C</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Lindenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="579" to="592" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The feedback-related negativity (FRN) revisited: new insights into the localization, meaning and network organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Iannaccone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Stämpfli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Drechsler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Brandeis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walitza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of human error processing: reinforcement learning, dopamine, and the error-related negativity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Holroyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Coles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">679</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward positivity elicited by predictive cues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Holroyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Krigolson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroreport</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="249" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The feedback correct-related positivity: Sensitivity of the event-related brain potential to unexpected positive feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Holroyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Pakzad-Vaezi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Krigolson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="688" to="697" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuromodulation and aging: implications of aging neuronal gain control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-C</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rieckmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Neurobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="148" to="158" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational account of altered error processing in older age: dopamine and the error-related negativity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nieuwenhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Ridderinkhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Talsma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Coles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Holroyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Van Der Molen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The reward positivity: From basic research on reward to a biomarker for depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Proudfit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="449" to="459" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Raz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Lindenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rodrigue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kennedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Head</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Williamson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regional brain changes in aging healthy adults: general trends, individual differences and modifiers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Acker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cerebral cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1676" to="1689" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Longitudinal magnetic resonance imaging studies of older adults: a shrinking brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Resnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kraut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Zonderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Davatzikos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3295" to="3301" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On-line Q-learning using connectionist systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rummery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Niranjan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-free and model-based reward prediction errors in EEG</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Sambrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hardwick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wills</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">178</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="162" to="171" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human orbitofrontal cortex represents a cognitive map of state space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Schuck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Niv</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1402" to="1412" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to reinforcement learning Cambridge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>MIT press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The feedback-related negativity signals salience prediction errors, not reward prediction errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Talmi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>El-Deredy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8264" to="8269" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural mechanisms and temporal dynamics of performance monitoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ullsperger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nigbur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Endrass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combined frontal and parietal P300 amplitudes indicate compensated cognitive processing across the lifespan</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Van Dinteren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Arns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Jongsma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kessels</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in aging neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">294</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hippocampal contributions to model-based planning and spatial memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Vikbladh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Meager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Blackmon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Devinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="683" to="693" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning from experience: event-related potential correlates of reward processing, neural adaptation, and behavioral choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1870" to="1884" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using trajectory data to improve bayesian optimization for reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tadepalli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="282" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine enhances model-based over modelfree choice behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wunderlich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Smittenaar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="418" to="424" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spot-the-Word: A measure for estimating premorbid intellectual functioning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Yuspeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Vanderploeg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Archives of Clinical Neuropsychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
