<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">How Decisions and the Desire for Coherency Shape Subjective Preferences Over Time</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Hornsby</surname></persName>
							<email>adam.hornsby.10@ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>WC1H 0AP</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bradley</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Love</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>WC1H 0AP</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">The Alan Turing Institute</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<addrLine>1 dunnhumby, 184 Shepherds Bush Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>W6 7NL</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">How Decisions and the Desire for Coherency Shape Subjective Preferences Over Time</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:33+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent findings suggest a bidirectional relationship between preferences and choices such that what is chosen can become preferred. Yet, it is still commonly held that preferences for individual items are maintained, such as caching a separate value estimate for each experienced option. Instead, we propose that all possible choice options and preferences are represented in a shared, continuous, multidimensional space that supports generalization. Decision making is cast as a learning process that seeks to align choices and preferences to maintain coherency. We formalized an error-driven learning model that updates preferences to align with past choices, which makes repeating those and related choices more likely in the future. The model correctly predicts that making a free choice increases preferences along related attributes. For example, after choosing a political candidate based on trivial information (e.g., they like cats), voters&apos; views on abortion, immigration, and trade subsequently shifted to match their chosen candidate.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Every day, people are confronted with countless choices for which there is no objectively correct answer. These tend to be either preference judgments or moral decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> . Rather than being guided by extrinsic feedback, people choose these options freely for themselves, using their subjective preferences. We therefore refer to these choices as free choices. But how do people acquire these subjective preferences in the first place? The aim of this research is to understand the basis of people's subjective preferences.</p><p>We might learn about our own preferences in the same way we learn about others'; by observing and then rationalizing behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> . This is because we tend to lack introspective access to the mechanisms driving our behavior, meaning that we have to post-rationalize in order to make sense of it <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> . In a dramatic demonstration of this, people have been tricked by mischievous experimenters into justifying choices that they did not actually make <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> . For example, after choosing their favourite flavour of jam in a taste test, participants were tricked into then justifying a different choice by experimenters, who covertly switched them mid-way through the experiment <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8</ref> . Thus, rather than accessing the reasons for their choices directly, people seem to retrospectively infer them using evidence of their historic choices, even when that evidence isn't valid.</p><p>As well as facilitating the inference of preferences, past choices also shape them. This has been demonstrated in studies of free choice, which show that after freely choosing an option, people tend to increase their subjective preference for it <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref> . In the original free-choice paradigm, Brehm <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11</ref> asked participants to rate a set of items (e.g. snack products), choose between two similarly rated options and finally to rate the full set again. Results showed that after making the forced choice, they had an increased preference for the chosen item on the final rating and a decreased preference for the rejected item. This is surprising, because it suggests that merely choosing or rejecting an option causes a person to update their subjective preference for it.</p><p>Although there has been some debate as to the validity of the free-choice paradigm in its original format, more recent studies have suggested that choice-based learning is real. For example, one particular concern about the original paradigm was that the first rating phase was noisy and therefore an imperfect measure of people's true preferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26</ref> . However, researchers have since overcome this concern using various methodological adaptations, demonstrating choice-induced preference change does occur <ref type="bibr">13, 15-17, 19-21, 27</ref> and can be long-lasting <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12</ref> . For example, Sharot, Velasquez and Dolan <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> asked participants to blindly choose between masked holiday destinations, which were only revealed to participants after one of two keys had been pressed. Subsequent ratings of those destinations were consistent with choice-induced preference change, even though choices had been randomly assigned to participants. More recent analyses of data collected from supermarket shoppers in-the-wild gives further credence to the claim that choices are self-reinforcing. In particular, a recent study of 283,000 British consumers found that their tendency to repeat a choice (i.e., exploit) strengthened as a function of the number of previous repetitions <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> . The consensus from studies inside and outside the laboratory is that free choices appear to be self-reinforcing, such that people come to prefer the options they choose.</p><p>Studies of free choice imply that people refer to past acceptances and rejections to infer what they like and dislike <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28</ref> . Yet, we know that people can also infer the value of things they've never tried. For example, one could infer that they would not enjoy sky diving, despite having never tried it. How do people do this? Rather than caching the value of individual options (e.g. beer varieties), people likely represent options and preferences within a shared, continuous, multidimensional space (e.g., varieties of hop, brand and brewing style). As depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure  1</ref>, representing options and preferences in this way is beneficial, in that it provides a lower-dimensional learning problem and allows one to infer the relative value of any option in their environment, irrespective of whether it has been tried.</p><p>Making free choices may therefore serve a considerably broader function than first thought, helping us to learn more deeply about ourselves and the world around us. Specifically, if options are represented within the same attribute space, then free choices may help to determine where one's preferences lie within that space. In this paper, we propose that the position of one's preferences is determined by a general, error-driven learning process, where the error term seeks to make the last choice more likely to repeat. As well as increasing the likelihood of past choices being repeated -as has been shown in real supermarket consumers <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> -one should also increase their preferences for other options to the extent that they are similar to those previously chosen. While surprising, striving for internal coherency in this way may make sense in a world where choices can be evaluated across a multitude of different 2/17 criteria.</p><p>We begin by demonstrating how the intrinsic desire to maximize coherency between past choices and present preferences can elicit strong subjective preferences in the absence of extrinsic reinforcement. In accordance with our proposed theory, we develop a computational cognitive model that learns preferences over choice attributes and uses past choices as the basis for updating them. We call it the Coherency Driven Choice (CDC) model. CDC is similar to models of human category learning, which use object attributes to categorize exemplars (e.g., using wings, beaks and feathers to describe birds) <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35]</ref> . However, rather than updating based on corrective feedback, our model self-supervises using its past choices, thereby making them and similar options more likely to be sampled. Through simulation, we show how this mechanism can drive complex, multidimensional preferences from free choices alone. Thus, error-driven, self-supervision helps the agent to maximize coherency between its preferences and choices over time. As a result, CDC can achieve a sense of order in environments where there are innumerable possible options and dimensions by which to score them.</p><p>After presenting this formal demonstration of our theory, we validate its predictions using a large-scale experiment of human participants. Chiefly, the error-driven nature by which CDC learns means that it will update its preferences in order to maximize the perceived contrast between accepted and rejected options. This is analogous to contrastive learning effects in category learning, where the experience of contrasting category exemplars causes perceived category averages to drift apart and become idealized <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36</ref> . Results from Experiment 1 demonstrated that people update their preferences in exactly this way following a choice. Specifically, participants were shown to prefer never-before-seen patterns if they happened to be on the back of a toy robot they had just designed. The more discriminating the pattern was to the initial robot, the more likely they were to prefer it.</p><p>Whereas Experiment 1 concerned preference formation in a novel and well-controlled domain, Experiment 2 evaluated the model's predictions in a domain in which people hold strong, preexisting preferences. In particular, Experiment 2 evaluated whether participants would retrospectively update their political beliefs following a vote. Results revealed that after choosing between two electoral candidates based on trivial grounds (e.g., whether they liked cats or dogs), participants were more likely to agree with a political belief later revealed by their chosen candidate, irrespective of whether that belief was traditionally left or right wing (e.g., pro-choice vs. pro-life abortion rights). Thus, these results support the key claims of our proposed theory, in that they suggest that people retrospectively update their preferences to be coherent with their past choices. Significantly, this even occurs in domains where people possess strong prior preferences that likely have strong subjective significance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Simulating free choices demonstrates how strong preferences can be learned over time</head><p>To illustrate how one could learn strong subjective preferences by virtue of their choice trajectory, we formalized our account of subjective preference formation and decision making in a cognitive model (i.e., the CDC model) and simulated it. In the simulated environment, there were two choice types that didn't vary on the first dimension but varied significantly on the second dimension. This is analogous to choosing between two beer brands that are similar in taste but contrast in the color of branding. A visualization of this model and the results of this simulation are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> .</p><p>After simulating 10,000 forced-choices, CDC eventually came to posses preferences resembling the first choice type (i.e., type a). After an initial sequence of random actions, CDC began to quickly develop a preference in retrospect of them, and thus select choices consistent with this new-found preference. This process was then self-reinforcing, further strengthening preferences and therefore the likelihood for choice type a over time. Thus, when consumers become less likely to explore new products the more they exploit the same, it may be because their preferences are being self-reinforced by their past choices, as shown in this simulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> .</p><p>Uniquely, as CDC chose more of choice type a, the preferences and attention of the model moved most in favour of the attributes of the choice that made it unique. This is a known consequence of discrimination learning, but uniquely demonstrated here within the context of subjective preference change <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[37]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> . Exaggerating preferences in this way helped the model to maximize the perceived contrast between the accepted and rejected choices. This increases the likelihood of the past choice type being sampled again and reduces the likelihood of the rejected option being selected. Continuing the example introduced above, this suggests that a person will have an over-exaggerated preference toward the unique branding of their preferred beer, helping to retrospectively justify their apparent preference.</p><p>Of course, when formalizing a cognitive theory, one must make some assumptions about the world. For example, in the case presented here, one could argue that people do not always have complete knowledge of the attributes describing each option at the time of decision. Indeed, one may need to taste a product to know how salty it is, or they may vote for a political candidate before learning of their stance on free-trade. In this case, our model would simply use a placeholder for their preference on that particular attribute. Upon revelation of the attribute value for their prior choice (e.g., discovering how salty a snack was), they would then move their preference toward the attribute point in question.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>People prefer novel patterns associated with their prior choice</head><p>The new account proposed in this paper suggests that by learning preferences over attributes of choices, people can generalize their preferences to novel options that are associated with ones previously chosen. Moreover, as has been shown in error-driven accounts of category learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36</ref> , it predicts that people will update their preferences in the direction of the most discriminative elements of their choice, in order to maximize the likelihood it being repeated.</p><p>Experiment 1 aimed to validate these predictions. Here, participants were asked to design a robot (the trial flow is depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 3a</ref>). They were then introduced to a second robot, before both turned around revealing previously unseen, randomly assigned patterns on their backs. Finally, participants were asked to choose between three patterns; one that was unique to the back of the robot they had previously designed (i.e. chosen unique), another that was shared across the backs of the two robots and a final pattern that was unique to the back of the robot they hadn't designed (i.e. non-chosen). It was hypothesized that -consistent with a discriminative account of learning -participants would prefer those novel patterns to the extent that they were uniquely associated with the robot they had just designed.</p><p>The proportion of times each image type was selected as a first, second and third preference is pictured in <ref type="figure">Figure  3b</ref>. As indicated by the figure, results were in line with the hypothesis that participants' most preferred the unique chosen pattern, followed by the shared pattern and finally, the non-chosen pattern (omnibus non-parametric Friedman test of differences among repeated-measures χ 2 = 137.48, p &lt; 0.001). Specifically, summed preferences for the chosen-unique patterns (Median = 9, IQR = 4.0) were stronger than that for the shared items (Median = 9, IQR = 3.0) (Wilcoxon signed-rank Z = −2.91, p &lt; 0.005, r = 0.09) and the non-chosen items (Median = 11, IQR = 5.0) (Z = −12.08, p &lt; 0.001, r = 0.39). A final test also revealed that preferences for the shared items were stronger than that for non-chosen items (Z = −11.70, p &lt; 0.001, r = 0.38) <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> .</p><p>These results supported our two key hypotheses and therefore the key claims of our theory. Firstly, participants exhibited an increased preference for the chosen-unique and shared patterns, demonstrating that they generalized their preference learned from the initial choice to the novel patterns by virtue of their association. Consistent with the behaviour of our model formalization, people appear to generalize their preferences to novel items that share attributes with choices just made.</p><p>Secondly, participants demonstrated an increased preference for the chosen-unique pattern over the shared pattern and a reduced preference for the pattern unique to the rejected option. This is consistent with a discriminative account of learning, in that it suggests that people update their preference towards attributes that discriminate their prior choices. Results from category learning have shown that experiencing contrasting category exemplars causes the perceived difference between categories to drift apart and become idealized. For example, because people are used to contrasting diet foods with high calorie foods, they are more likely to suggest celery as a prototypical diet food, even though it is extreme for its category <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36</ref> . Choosing freely between options appears to have similar effects during preference learning, in that preferences update to maximize the perceived contrast between the accepted and rejected options. This functions to maintain coherence between past choices and present preferences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>People adjust their existing political beliefs to be consistent with their prior vote</head><p>The experimental results presented so far have provided controlled, experimental support for our error-driven account of subjective preference formation and decision making. Outside the lab however, people usually have strong prior preferences for options, which likely interacts with their intrinsic tendency to coherency maximize.</p><p>The aim of Experiment 2 was therefore to explore the extent to which people retrospectively update their existing preferences following a free choice. Specifically, we evaluated whether people would modify their political beliefs after a vote. Participants from the U.S. were shown two political candidates and asked to vote for one, based on some trivial attributes (e.g., whether they liked cats or dogs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> . This experimental procedure is depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 4a</ref>. Following the vote, these chosen and non-chosen political candidates revealed randomly assigned, opposing controversial beliefs on a particular topic. These beliefs were either traditionally left or right-wing. For example, if randomly assigned to the abortion issue, the chosen candidate would either show "Abortion: Pro-choice" or "Abortion: Pro-life". Participants were then asked to state the extent to which they agreed with their chosen candidate's newly revealed belief using a slider. Finally, they were asked to state their preferred party out of the Democrats or Republicans.</p><p>Our primary hypothesis was that people would show higher levels of agreement for the right-wing view (e.g., pro-choice abortion rights) if their chosen candidate revealed support for that view, compared to the left-wing view. This would provide support for the theory presented here and suggest that, following a vote, people are prone to adjust their political beliefs to be coherent with their chosen candidate. While expecting that people would feel inclined to agree with their chosen candidate's newly revealed opinion, we also secondarily hypothesized that this would be more pronounced for Republican participants. This is because Republicans generally tend to be more conformist, value loyalty to the in-group and tend to be more submissive to authority <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref> . Whilst this is a secondary prediction that does not directly flow from our core theory, we believe that domain and group differences -such as the ones described above -could affect the extent to which people update their preferences following a choice. Therefore, in addition to the primary aim of evaluating CDC's predictions in regards to strongly-held, existing preferences, Experiment 2 also provides an initial exploration of group differences across domains.</p><p>In support of the primary hypotheses, results revealed that participants' stated degree of belief was significantly influenced by the belief revealed by their chosen candidate (non-parametric two-way analysis of variance (ANOVA) F(1, 952) = 28.89, p &lt; 0.001, CL=0.563) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4</ref> . In particular, those that voted for a candidate that later revealed a right-wing opinion (Median = 56.0, IQR = 76.00) agreed an average of 43.59% more with the right-wing view compared to if the candidate later revealed a left-wing view (Median = 39.0, IQR = 69.75).</p><p>In support of the secondary hypothesis, there was also a significant interaction between party affiliation and the degree of agreement with the right-wing view (F(1, 952) = 11.77, p &lt; 0.001). A first Mann-Whitney U test looking at the responses of Democrats revealed that they only slightly increased their level of agreement for the right-wing view if their candidate revealed a right-wing view (Median = 40.0, IQR = 78.00) compared to if it revealed a left-wing view (Median = 31.5, IQR = 65.75); this difference was marginally significant (U = 43584.5, p=0.054), but had a very low effect size (CL = 0.518). In contrast, the second test looking at Republicans revealed a larger effect, in that -if one's candidate later revealed a more right-wing opinion -they were 65.66% more in agreement with the the right-wing view (Median = 82.0, IQR = 59.75) compared to when the candidate revealed a more left-wing view (Median = 49.50, IQR = 70.25) (U = 10131.5, p&lt;0.001, CL = 0.629) <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> . Thus, Republicans appeared to be particularly prone to adjusting their beliefs so as to be consistent with their last choice, even when this choice was based on trivial grounds (e.g., the fact that their candidate liked cats).</p><p>It is notable that Republicans were particularly willing to adjust their preferences to be coherent with their prior choices. For example, Republicans' median support for pro-life abortion policies was 60% higher when their chosen candidate later expressed support for pro-life policies (Median=96.0, IQR=61.50) compared to pro-choice policies (Median=60.0, IQR=88.00) (the remaining within-topic comparisons are depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 4c</ref> and 4d, and described in the supplemental). One possibility is that only Republicans adjust their preferences to be consistent with a choice, across all domains. To confirm that this was not the case, we replicated the first experiment, asking about party affiliation at the end of the study. Results revealed that both Democrats and Republicans exhibited preferences for the final pattern in ways consistent with the reported findings above (see the supplemental for details). Thus, a more likely explanation of our results is that there are group and domain differences guiding the extent to which people learn from their past choices. For example, US conservatives are typically more conformist and generally trusting of their elected officials than Democrats, which may make them more likely to assimilate the beliefs of their chosen officials <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">42,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">43</ref> . Political groups may also differ in how they value group affiliation <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">44</ref> . These topics are deserving of future study in the context of the work presented here.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>In this article, we proposed a novel account of subjective preference formation and decision making. In our model, choice options and preferences are represented in a common continuous, multi-dimensional space. When people choose options within this space, their preferences are updated to increase the likelihood of their previous choices. The objective of decision making is therefore to reduce the error between one's past choices and present preferences; we refer to this general mechanism as coherency maximization. Consistent with patterns of repeatpurchasing observed in supermarket consumers <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> and studies of choice-induced preference change <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref> , coherency maximization boosts the likelihood of past choices being repeated by shifting preferences towards the chosen item and away from rejected alternatives. As was shown in a simple simulation, this mechanism can elicit strong subjective preferences in the absence of extrinsic feedback. Thus, our model is well-suited to navigating the complex choices encountered in everyday life.</p><p>Following from this account, one would expect preferences to be exaggerated towards attributes that favored the past choice and diminished towards attributes associated with rejected choices. Results from the first experiment showed that preferences are updated in accordance with these predictions. Concretely, the more uniquely associated a novel pattern was to the back of a toy robot they had previously designed, the more likely participants were to prefer it. Given that we tend to lack direct introspective access to the mechanisms driving our behaviour, post-rationalizing choices may be a reasonable way to make sense of ourselves and the world around us <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> . Our model shows that simple learning processes can achieve similar ends by updating underlying preferences to align with choice.</p><p>These learning rules can be seen as reflecting an internal drive for internal consistency, which is pivotal to rational models of decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45</ref> . For example, it is often assumed that subjective choices should be stochastically transitive <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46</ref> . When preferences are not transitive, people can become liable to manipulation (or "dutch booking") <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">47</ref> . For example, if out of three beers, a person prefers beer A over B, beer B over C but would rather have C than A, their preferences are cyclical. This person could be tricked into paying for a series of costly trades in which the drinker ended with his original beer. In subjective domains, internal consistency may be at times the only rational strategy that is feasible.</p><p>The second experiment explored how the tendency to maximize coherency interacted with people's prior preferences. The results indicated that after voting for a political candidate based on trivial criteria (e.g., the candidate likes cats), participants were more likely to agree with a controversial opinion later revealed by the candidate, such as their stance on abortion rights. This held up as a main effect, supporting our claim that people retrospectively update their preferences over attributes of their past choices to make them more likely. The fact that this was particularly pronounced for Republicans supported our secondary hypothesis that this mechanism can vary between groups, consistent with previous studies demonstrating individual differences in choice-induced preference change <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23</ref> . However, while individual differences may partly explain our results, it is likely that other variables outside the scope of our theory also influence decisions, such as how important affiliation is to different groups. Specifically, while Republicans adjusted their preferences more than Democrats in the second experiment, a replication of the first experiment (see Supplement) revealed no difference between the groups when choosing between novel options. In future research, the prominence of choice-induced preference change within certain groups or domains could be estimated by fitting the CDC model to different decision tasks.</p><p>Although our studies involved brief decision-making episodes, the basic mechanisms considered here may also 6/17 apply at longer timescales. Indeed, this work was partially motivated by Riefer et al.'s <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> discovery of self-reinforcing purchasing patterns in supermarket consumers, which extended over several months. If CDC's predictions for how preferences change held over extended periods of time, the practical consequences and possibilities for behavioural change would be substantial. For instance, CDC predicts that purchasing the same type of food should increase preference for associated attributes. This can be problematic in cases where the food is unhealthy (e.g., high in sodium or saturated fat). For example, studies of nutrition have shown that repeated exposure to a particular ingredient (e.g., sodium) increases one's desire and lowers their sensitivity to it, making it difficult for them to adjust when they go on a diet <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[48]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[49]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[50]</ref> . The advent of targeted recommender systems means that these cyclical effects may be being perpetuated further. While recommender systems often reduce diversity of alternatives in the environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">51</ref> , coherency maximization causes preferences to become less diverse, thereby perpetuating the problem. Rather than blindly targeting people based on their previous consumption, marketers could incorporate external objectives to their targeting algorithms. For example, our theory predicts that recommending healthy alternatives that are similar to people's existing preferences could lead to long-term improvements in their choices.</p><p>The modeling approach presented here is readily extended to account for the richness of people's preferences. Unlike how CDC was formalized here, people are unlikely to have a single preference across each respective attribute. For example, while a foodie might prefer expensive, locally produced foods, they may also be happy to watch affordable, mass produced television. People may have different preferences for the same attribute (e.g., cost) depending on context. Fortunately, it would be straightforward to extend CDC to have multiple preference vectors to capture this context dependence, much like how category learning models can have multiple clusters in which only the most contextually relevant one is updated during a learning episode <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref> . Such a model would cast coherency maximization as a process that occurs within a domain (e.g., food, entertainment, etc.) as opposed to globally.</p><p>In conclusion, preferences and choices can be characterized as existing within a common space. While we prefer options that match our preferences, we also appear to engage in error-driven learning to update our preferences to accommodate our past choices. Because preference and choice representation lie in a shared multidimensional space, the choices we make have consequences (i.e., spillover effects) for related future choices. For example, people may be prone to agree with a controversial opinion held by a political candidate, by virtue of the fact that they voted for them. Although this behavior may appear irrational, being internally coherent may be the best we can hope for in complex, subjective domains. Being aware of these coherency maximizing dynamics may make it possible for people to ameliorate some of the potentially harmful consequences. For example, if a voter chooses a candidate based on tax policy, perhaps being mindful of that fact will make the voter less likely to reflexively adopt their candidate's positions on unrelated issues. Likewise, these same coherency maximizing principles could be incorporated into recommender systems to help consumers achieve some positive goal, such as eating more healthily.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>7/17</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Simulation</head><p>Observations in the environment were randomly sampled from distributions of two clusters. Choice type a had a cluster centroid of (0.2, 0.8) whilst choice type b had a cluster centroid of (0.2, 0.2). The standard deviation of each cluster was determined apriori to be 0.05; thereby making the two choice types linearly separable. A total of 500 observations were simulated.</p><p>The agent was initialised with middling preferences and attention weights across the two attributes of (0.5, 0.5). It was also set to have a learning rate of 0.01, ε = 0.05 and λ = 1. Choices were simulated for 10,000 timesteps. At each timestep, the agent was forced to choose between two randomly-selected options from each choice type using an ε-greedy action selection strategy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1: People prefer novel patterns associated with their prior choice</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>One thousand and three participants were recruited from Amazon Mechanical Turk (mturk). Mturk (www.mturk.com) is known for being an inexpensive source of reliable human data <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">52</ref> . Participants were required to have completed &gt;1000 tasks (or HITs) and have an acceptance rate greater than 95%. Participants had to be based in the US or Canada. Data from 37 participants were removed due to having an average response time two standard deviations greater than the mean (&gt;17.64s). The mean age of the participants was 37.0 (SD=11.4) and 50.2% were male. Participants were paid 50¢ for participating, which is typical for mturk <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">53</ref> . Overall, the experiment took about 10 minutes <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design</head><p>The experiment used a between-groups design with 10 trials. Participants either chose a pattern that belonged to the back of the robot they previously designed (i.e., chosen-unique), the one they didn't design (i.e., non-chosen) or was shared across both. The dependent variable was therefore the sum of the preferences over each of the choice types across each of the 10 trials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Apparatus &amp; Stimuli</head><p>The study was designed using JavaScript and was accessed in a web browser. The task was presented in a 700 x 700 pixel screen. During the design phase of the experiment, participants responded by choosing attributes from a drop-down box. When stating their design preferences in the final phase, participants were asked to click each robot in order of their preference (from highest to lowest).</p><p>Each robot was designed using the Support Vector Graphics (SVG) format. These robots had a front -which could be designed by participants -and a back, which contained randomly-assigned patterns.</p><p>During the design phase, participants could design three aspects of the front of their robot; the stomach texture, the visor border colour and the eye colour. In each trial, participants could choose between two randomly-selected options for each design aspect.</p><p>In the final phase of each trial, participants were shown multicoloured geometric patterns. In total, there were three patterns per trial. One pattern appeared on one random half of the back of the robot they had previously designed. Another pattern appeared on one random half of the back of the robot they had not designed. The final design was shared such that it appeared on both remaining halves of the two turned robots.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants were initially briefed about the experiment and asked to supply their age and gender. They were told that the task would take about 10 minutes and would require them to design robots and make choices. On each trial, participants were shown a robot with a randomly selected name and asked to design it. The hope was that by designing the robot, they would become more motivated about their choice, increasing ecological validity. They could choose between one of two randomly selected options for each of the three design aspects. After completing <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> Both experiments presented here were in compliance with UCL's code of ethics</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>8/17</head><p>the design, participants were then introduced to a new, frowning anti-robot. This anti-robot was designed using all the attributes that the participant had previously eschewed. In addition, participants were warned that the anti-robot did not like the participants' design. They were then asked to reassure their own robot by clicking on it. After clicking on their own robot, both robots then turned around revealing randomized patterns on their backs (described above). The two robots then moved to the back of the screen. Three patterns -either shared across both or unique to one of the robots at the back of the screen -then appeared at the front of the screen and participants were asked to choose their favourite in order of preference. Participants completed 10 such trials with patterns, robot names, and other trial details randomized for each trial, they were debriefed, thanked for their participation and paid immediately.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2: People adjust their existing political beliefs to be consistent with their prior vote</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>One thousand participants were recruited using mturk. All participants were required to have had at least 1000 of their previous tasks accepted on mturk, have a 95% mturk task acceptance rate and be based in the United States. All participants were paid 50¢ for participating. Of the participants, 47 were removed due to a lack of apparent concentration or understanding of the task. Specifically, 45 participants were removed for having response times more than two standard deviations from the mean for the vote response (n = 26, &gt; 38.68s) and the slider response (n = 19, &gt; 55.38s). A further 2 participants were removed for clicking more than 50 times during the whole experiment. Of the final 953 participants, 50.26% were male, 49.53% were female and the remainder specified as 'other'. The mean age was 37.44 (SD = 11.67). Of the participants, 64.53% said they affiliated more closely with Democrats, whereas the remainder said they affiliate more closely with Republicans. Data was collected in late July 2018.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design</head><p>The experiment used a 2 x 2 between-groups design. The experiment involved one trial. Participants either chose a candidate that -previously unbeknownst to them -revealed a more left-wing view or a more right-wing view. Furthermore, participants either affiliated more closely with Democrats or Republicans. The dependent variable was the slider value of the participant, normalized by political direction. Specifically, these values ranged from 1 to 100, where higher values indicated more agreement with the right-wing view and lower values indicated more agreement with the more left-wing view. Note that the initial vertical location of the candidates, the allocation of neutral and controversial attributes, and the final horizontal locations of the candidates were all fully randomized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Apparatus &amp; Stimuli</head><p>The study was designed using JavaScript and was accessed in a web browser. The task was presented in a 1000 pixel wide screen. Participants were shown two of a possible four faces taken from the Chicago Face Database <ref type="bibr">54 7</ref> . To control for noise emerging from other, well-documented biases, all faces were controlled to be male, Caucasian and ranging between the ages of 37 and 43. Faces were randomly assigned one of four names. These were either James Smith, Michael Johnson, John Williams, Graham Brown. These names were sourced from a list of the most popular first and second Caucasian names in the United States.</p><p>The neutral opinions of participants are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. The controversial political opinions of participants are shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants were initially briefed about the purpose of the experiment. They were told that the task would take about 5 minutes to complete and would require them to vote for political candidates. After the briefing, participants began the trial. To first ensure that the participants were alert, they were told to read a short experimental briefing. Within this briefing was the instruction to click on the name of the university (which was displayed at the top of the "Abortion: Prolife" Immigration "I support policies that would increase immigration"</p><p>"I support policies that would decrease immigration"</p><p>Trade "I support tariffs on imports" "I support free trade" screen). After clicking this, a new panel was revealed displaying some text ("It's time to vote for a candidate! Please click on a candidate to vote") and two political candidates in gray cards; one above the other. Within each card and underneath the candidate's photographs was their name and then a list of "My opinions". These lists initially displayed opposing neutral opinions selected from the same neutral topic, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. The assignments of photographs, names, neutral topics and vertical alignment were all randomized. Participants were asked to vote for a candidate using this neutral information by clicking on their card. After voting, the cards then moved to a left or right position on the screen, aligning horizontally with each other. This horizontal allocation was also randomized. The voted and non-voted candidates then immediately revealed opposing political opinions from the same topic in their list of opinions. A blue "New" button drew attention to this newly-revealed belief. The window then moved down to reveal a new section, containing some text and a slider. The text informed participants in bold lettering that "Your candidate has revealed a new opinion above! How much do you agree with your candidate's newly revealed opinion?" Participants were prompted to use the new slider to state the extent to which they agreed with the candidates' newly revealed opinions. Small avatars of the candidate's faces were shown on either side of the slider, with a gray tick or white cross below the ones that were previously chosen, respectively. There were also prompts below each avatar reminding participants of the newly revealed controversial opinion of the candidate. Note that the slider was not initialized with any starting value. Sliding closer towards the chosen candidates indicated higher levels of agreement with that candidate. The slider had 100 possible positions. The photographs, names, neutral and political opinions and left/right direction of movement were all randomly assigned between participants.</p><p>After confirming the slider position, participants were asked to state which party they most affiliated with (Democrat or Republican), their gender and their age. Following task completion, they were thanked for their participation and paid immediately. To illustrate how this theory can materialize in strong subjective preferences, we formalize it in a computational cognitive model, known as Coherency Driven Choice (CDC). a, CDC possesses a preference and attention-weight vector. When evaluating options, the model evaluates the similarity between its own attention-weighted preference and the attributes of the available options. The closer an option's attributes are to the model's attention-weighted preferences, the more likely the model is to select it. b, Following a choice, CDC update's its preference vector to make the past choice most likely using gradient descent, thereby moving toward the prior choice in attribute space. c, CDC also adjusts its attention weights to make prior choice more likely, effectively warping the preference space so that it becomes more sensitive to the attended attribute. d, As the model grows to prefer the options it initially chose, it tends to repeat the same choice type more over time. e, The model was simulated for 10,000 timesteps in a simple environment in which there were two choice types. Due to happenstance in the initial choices, the model began to prefer choice type a, adjusting its preferences and attention weights in favor of the attributes that make it unique. The preference history is coloured by attention weight ratio, such that blacker colors indicate a greater deal of attention paid towards attribute 2. a b <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>. a, The trial sequence observed by participants. First, participants were introduced to a robot and asked to design aspects of it. They were then introduced to a new robot, which was designed differently. These robots then turned around, revealing random patterns on their backs. One pattern was unique to the robot participants' had previously designed (i.e., chosen-unique), one was shared across both robots (i.e., shared) and the other was unique to the robot they had previously eschewed (i.e., non-chosen). Participants were then asked to rank the patterns in order of preference. b, This chart depicts the proportion that each image type was chosen as a first, second and third preference (with standard error bars). These results are consistent with the theory presented here, which predicts that choice-based learning generalizes most strongly to the unique, most-discriminating feature of the original choice (i.e., chosen unique), followed by the shared feature.</p><p>16/17 <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. a, Participants were initially asked to vote for a candidate based on trivial characteristics. Both candidates then revealed opposing beliefs on a more controversial belief. Participants were then asked to rate how much they agreed with their candidate's newly revealed opinion. b, If voting for the candidate affects the extent to which participants agree with the later-revealed political belief, then one would expect participants to show different levels of agreement between groups, depending on whether their candidate revealed a traditionally left-wing view or a right-wing view. c, The results of the experiment are shown in kernel density plots (with rugplots below to depict the individual data points). These reveal that Republican participants were particularly prone to adjusting their preference to be in accordance with that revealed by their chosen candidate. d, Plotting effect sizes for each per-topic comparison shows that Republicans were particularly prone to adjusting their preferences.</p><p>17/17</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. To illustrate how this theory can materialize in strong subjective preferences, we formalize it in a computational cognitive model, known as Coherency Driven Choice (CDC). a, CDC possesses a preference and attention-weight vector. When evaluating options, the model evaluates the similarity between its own attention-weighted preference and the attributes of the available options. The closer an option's attributes are to the model's attention-weighted preferences, the more likely the model is to select it. b, Following a choice, CDC update's its preference vector to make the past choice most likely using gradient descent, thereby moving toward the prior choice in attribute space. c, CDC also adjusts its attention weights to make prior choice more likely, effectively warping the preference space so that it becomes more sensitive to the attended attribute. d, As the model grows to prefer the options it initially chose, it tends to repeat the same choice type more over time. e, The model was simulated for 10,000 timesteps in a simple environment in which there were two choice types. Due to happenstance in the initial choices, the model began to prefer choice type a, adjusting its preferences and attention weights in favor of the attributes that make it unique. The preference history is coloured by attention weight ratio, such that blacker colors indicate a greater deal of attention paid towards attribute 2.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A summary of the neutral statements shown to participants</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Topic Statements</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Pets</cell><cell>"I like cats" "I like dogs"</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Sport</cell><cell>"I'm a baseball fan" "I'm a basketball fan"</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Food</cell><cell cols="2">"My favorite Italian food is pizza" "My favorite Italian food is spaghetti"</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Table 2. A summary of the controversial statements revealed by candidates following a vote</cell></row><row><cell>Topic</cell><cell>Left-wing</cell><cell>Right-wing</cell></row><row><cell>Abortion</cell><cell>"Abortion:</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Pro-choice"</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">The formal model is described in the supplemental 3/17</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">All Wilcoxon-signed rank tests were evaluated against a Holm-Bonferroni corrected alpha value for multiple comparisons 4/17</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">More information about the experimental design and stimuli is available in the methods section<ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4</ref> We report the common language (CL) effect size for all pairwise comparisons<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> For all multiple comparisons reported in this paper, significance values were compared against a Holm-Bonferroni corrected α value 5/17</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">These faces can be identified in the Chicago Face Database using the target codes WM-023, WM-221, WM-223 and WM-248 9/17</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We would like to thank Sébastien Ohleyer, Mina </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contributions statement</head><p>A.N.H. wrote the first draft of the paper, implemented the experiments and performed the analyses. B.C.L. and A.N.H. jointly devised the approach, model, and experimental design.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability</head><p>Data will be available at https://osf.io/5bvmp/ after publication. Code is available at https://github. com/anhornsby/coherent-representations. A Docker container for replicating our simulations and statistical analyses will be available at https://hub.docker.com/r/adamnhornsby/coherent-representations after publication. Many popular models of decision-making cannot easily explain how people form strong subjective preferences for free choices made in the wild. a, In standard decision theory, it is assumed that preferences remain stable over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30</ref> . Indeed, for many researchers, the challenge is often learning what people's preferences are (e.g., by asking them to choose between options), rather than understanding how they became. b, Reinforcement Learning (RL) models contrast in that they assume preferences change over time. Specifically, RL agents learn to prefer actions with a higher expected reward, which they learn as they monitor extrinsic feedback from their environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> . While RL has been shown to account for many aspects of human learning well (for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32</ref> ), these investigations have been largely confined to objective tasks, where there is a clear extrinsic signal steering the decision-maker. c, Studies of free choice -where there is no objectively correct answer -have shown that merely choosing an item increases one's preference for it. This has often been taken to imply that free-choices are self-reinforcing, so as to increase preferences toward the chosen option. Yet, caching values in this way would arguably not scale well, as it would require people to keep track of every item they'd ever tried. d, In this paper, we propose a novel theory of subjective preference formation and decision making that arguably scales better to free choices made in the real world. According to this theory, people encode preferences over attributes of free choices, such as the hop content in beer. After making a decision, they then update their preferences in the direction of the attributes that defined their prior choice, thereby increasing their preference for it, as well as for other options that have similar attributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>13/17</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinction between Externally vs. Internally Guided Decision-Making: Operational Differences, Meta-Analytical Comparisons and Their Theoretical Implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nakao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ohira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Northoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.3389/fnins.2012.00031</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-perception: An alternative interpretation of cognitive dissonance phenomena</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1037/h0024835</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-perception theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0065-2601(08)60024-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0065-2601(08" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60024" to="60030" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rationalization is rational</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1017/S0140525X19001730</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Brain Sci. 1-69</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Psychology: The science of mental life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Buckhout</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
			<publisher>Harper &amp; Row</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Consciousness: Respectable, useful, and probably necessary</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mandler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Telling more than we can know: Verbal reports on mental processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nisbett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">231</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Magic at the marketplace: Choice blindness for the taste of jam and the smell of tea</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Johansson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Tärning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sikström</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Deutgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2010.06.010</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2010.06.010" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">These two are different. Yes, they&apos;re the same: Choice blindness for facial identity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sauerland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.concog.2016.01.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.concog.2016.01.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Conscious. Cogn</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="104" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">False beliefs and confabulation can lead to lasting changes in political attitudes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Strandberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sivén</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Johansson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pärnamets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1037/xge0000489</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Psychol. Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1382" to="1399" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Postdecision changes in the desirability of alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Brehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1037/h0041006</idno>
		<idno>1402.2198</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Abnorm. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Choice Reveals and Shapes Expected Hedonic Outcome</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sharot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>De Martino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4972-08.2009</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Choice-induced preference change and the free-choice paradigm: A clarification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Alos-Ferrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.2062507</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2062507" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How actions create -not just reveal -preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2007.10.008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2007.10.008" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Changing value through cued approach: An automatic mechanism of behavior change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schonberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/nn.3673</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Action and valence modulate choice and choice-induced preference change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Koster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Duzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1371/journal.pone.0119682</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relation between choice-induced preference change and depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miyagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miyatani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nakao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1371/journal.pone.0180041</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Endogenous formation of preferences: Choices systematically change willingness-to-pay for goods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Voigt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Murawski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bode</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Psychol. Learn. Mem. Cogn</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1872</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Autonomous mechanism of internal choice estimate underlies decision inertia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Akaishi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Umeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nagase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sakai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2013.10.018</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.10.018" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Post-response β γ power predicts the degree of choice-based learning in internally guided decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nakao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/srep32477</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sour grapes and sweet victories: How actions shape preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Vinckier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006499</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Comput. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive dissonance resolution depends on episodic memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chammat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">41320</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Reinforcement Learning Mechanism Responsible for the Valuation of Free Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cockburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G E</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1016/j.neuron.2014.06.035</idno>
		<idno>NIHMS150003</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coherency-maximizing exploration in the supermarket</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Riefer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Prior</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pavey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Love</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/s41562-016-0017</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How choice affects and reflects preferences: Revisiting the free-choice paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Risen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0020217</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0020217" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Pers. Soc. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="573" to="594" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice-induced preference change in the free-choice paradigm: A critical methodological review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Izuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00041</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">41</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do decisions shape preference?: Evidence from blind choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sharot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Velasquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797610379235</idno>
		<idno type="PMID">20679522</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797610379235" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1231" to="1235" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of cognitive dissonance and choice-induced preference change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Izuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1073/pnas.1011879108</idno>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1408.1149</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22014" to="22019" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Von Neumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Morgenstern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rubinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theory of Games and Economic Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1944" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>60th Anniversary Commemorative Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Glimcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chapter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-0-12-374176-9.00032-4</idno>
		<idno>1016/ B978-0-12-374176-9.00032-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10" />
		<title level="m">Towards a standard back-pocket model</title>
		<editor>Glimcher, P. W., Camerer, C. F., Fehr, E. &amp; Poldrack, R. A.</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="521" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement Learning: An Introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1109/TNN.1998.712192</idno>
		<idno>1603.02199</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1054" to="1054" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Value Learning through Reinforcement: The Basics of Dopamine and Reinforcement Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tobler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Cited By 24</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ALCOVE: An exemplar-based connectionist model of category learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The generalized context model: An exemplar model of classification. Formal approaches categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Nosofsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="39" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SUSTAIN: a network model of category learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Love</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Medin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gureckis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="332" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory for category information is idealized through contrast with competing options</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Love</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="234" to="242" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of pavlovian conditioning: Variations in the effectiveness of reinforcement and nonreinforcement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rescorla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Class. conditioning II: Curr. research theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of feature-label-order and their implications for symbolic learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ramscar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Yarlett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Denny</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Thorpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1551-6709.2009.01092.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1551-6709.2009.01092.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="909" to="957" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A neurology of the conservative-liberal dimension of political ideology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mendez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The J. neuropsychiatry clinical neurosciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When morality opposes justice: Conservatives have moral intuitions that liberals may not recognize</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Haidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1007/s11211-007-0034-z</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Justice Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="98" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Political conservatism as motivated social cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Glaser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kruglanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sulloway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1037/0033-2909.129.3.339</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="375" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Liberals, conservatives, and conformity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sistrunk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Halcomb</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychon. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="350" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An asymmetrical &quot;president-in-power</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Morisi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Jost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1017/S0003055418000850</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">effect. Am. Polit. Sci. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="614" to="620" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Knowledge Illusion: Why We Never Think Alone</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sloman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Fernbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<pubPlace>Riverhead Books</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Foundations of Statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
			<publisher>Wiley Publications in Statistics</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A neural substrate of prediction and reward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Montague</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1126/science.275.5306.1593</idno>
		<idno>NIHMS150003</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Outlines of a formal theory of value, i</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C C</forename><surname>Mckinsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Suppes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philos. science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="160" />
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long-term reduction in dietary sodium alters the taste of salt. The Am</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bertino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Beauchamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Engelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/ajcn/36.6.1134</idno>
		<ptr target="http://oup.prod.sis.lan/ajcn/article-pdf/36/6/1134/24160706/1134.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Clin. Nutr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1134" to="1144" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fat preference and adherence to a reduced-fat diet. The Am</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Mattes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1093/ajcn/57.3.373</idno>
		<ptr target="http://oup.prod.sis.lan/ajcn/article-pdf/57/3/373/24112120/373.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Clin. Nutr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="373" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sweet and sour preferences in young children and adults: role of repeated exposure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Liem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>De Graaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.physbeh.2004.08.028</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physbeh.2004.08.028" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physiol. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="421" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Filter Bubble: What the Internet Is Hiding from You (Penguin Group , The</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pariser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating amazon&apos;s mechanical turk as a tool for experimental behavioral research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J C</forename><surname>Crump</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Mcdonnell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gureckis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1371/journal.pone.0057410</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The labor economics of paid crowdsourcing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Horton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Chilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1145/1807342.1807376</idno>
		<idno>DOI: 10.1145/ 1807342.1807376</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The chicago face database: A free stimulus set of faces and norming data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Correll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wittenbrink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.3758/s13428-014-0532-5</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behav. Res. Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1122" to="1135" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
