<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Investigating (Sequential) Unit Asking: An Unsuccessful Quest for Scope Sensitivity in Willingness to Donate Judgements</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
							<email>m.maier@ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucius</forename><surname>Caviola</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Schubert</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Centre for Philosophy of Natural and Social Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Economics and Political Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">J L</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vanessa</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>26 Bedford Way 129-B</addrLine>
									<postCode>WC1H 0AP</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Central University Research Ethics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Investigating (Sequential) Unit Asking: An Unsuccessful Quest for Scope Sensitivity in Willingness to Donate Judgements</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:39+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>unit asking</term>
					<term>scope insensitivity</term>
					<term>judgement and decision making</term>
					<term>boosting</term>
					<term>charitable giving</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>for feedback on a previous version of the manuscript. We conducted two additional pilots that we considered less relevant for the main insights in this paper, which are reported in the Appendix. Data, code, materials, and preregistration are available at https://osf.io/qjuhb/. Note that we improved the analysis throughout the project. To keep consistency, we present all the studies here with the analysis technique pre-registered for Study 3. An alternative write-up with analyses exactly as preregistered is available in the OSF project. The conclusions are the same in terms of the Bayes factor categories unless stated otherwise. This project was supported by a PhD scholarship provided by Longview Philanthropy to MM.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Marcinkiewicz (2016)</ref> <p>asked participants to donate to the charity Global Alliance for Improved Nutrition to help children affected by a food shortage in Mali. He used a CUA technique as described in the previous section -first asking participants how much they would be willing to donate to help one child and then how much they would be willing to donate to help 4, <ref type="bibr">20, 200, or 2000 children (this scope varied between-subjects)</ref>. While participants donated more to help the group of children than a single child, the group donation did not differ between groups of 4, 20, 200, and 2000 affected children. This finding calls into question whether Unit Asking really increases scope sensitivity in willingness to donate (WTD) judgements or rather gives a single one-off boost.</p><p>Consequently, more research is required to test whether CUA actually makes participants scope sensitive. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Marcinkiewicz (2016)</ref> also showed that the higher the scope, the lower people's desire to be consistent. Because SUA presents a smaller increase in scope for each step, we predict that SUA will elicit scope sensitivity where CUA does not. The second goal of this paper is to test whether either CUA or SUA can result in (ordinal) scope sensitivity, such that people give more to larger numbers of affected individuals.</p><p>In the following five studies, we first compare SUA, CUA, and Direct Asking (DAonly asking a single question about the full scope) and: a) replicate the beneficial effect of CUA over DA in WTD judgements; b) show that SUA increases WTD judgements over CUA (Studies 1a and 1b). In Study 2, we test whether CUA and SUA make participants scope sensitive by varying Asking Type and Scope. Study 2 failed to find evidence for scope sensitivity. Study 3 also observed no evidence for scope sensitivity, despite seeking to provide optimal conditions for it. Study 4 switches to contingent valuation instead of a WTD judgement dependent variable by asking participants how much money would be needed to help x individuals, rather than how much they would donate to help x individuals. In the contingent valuation task, all asking techniques (including direct asking) showed scope sensitivity. This scope sensitivity was enhanced using SUA, but not CUA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and Procedure</head><p>Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hsee et al. (2013)</ref>, participants were first asked to imagine that the principal of a neighbourhood kindergarten had sent them an email to ask for money that would be used to buy Christmas gifts for children:</p><p>Imagine the following: Christmas is around the corner. The principal of a neighborhood kindergarten has sent you an email asking for donations. You know her personally and trust her words. The email directs you to a website with the following questions. Please answer these questions as if you were making actual donation decisions.</p><p>They were then directed to a site that described a kindergarten with 100 children from low-income families and asked participants how much they would be willing to donate:</p><p>Thanks for visiting our website. Please read the following carefully and answer the ensuing questions. Even if you are not willing to make a donation, please still answer the questions; you may simply enter $0. You can revise your answers, and your answers will not be recorded until you move on to the next page.</p><p>Our kindergarten currently has 100 children (like the one pictured below), they are all from low-income families. And their parents have little money to buy Christmas gifts for them. We hope you can make a donation, so we can buy Christmas gifts for them.</p><p>We used 100 children instead of the 20 used in the original study, since a setup with a larger scope seemed more appropriate to test the sequential asking technique. The experiment had three conditions.</p><p>In the control condition (as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hsee et al., 2013)</ref>, participants were asked directly how much they would be willing to donate to buy Christmas gifts for 100 children:</p><p>Please think about all 100 of these children. How much are you willing to donate to help these 100 children? Please enter the amount of money you decide and agree to donate: __ $</p><p>In the CUA condition (as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hsee et al., 2013)</ref>, participants first indicated how much they would be willing to donate to help one child and only afterwards (on a separate page) asked how much they would be willing to help 100 children. In other words, we first asked:</p><p>Before you decide how much to donate to help these 100 children, please first think about one such child and answer a hypothetical question: How much would you donate to help this one child? Please indicate the amount here: __ $"</p><p>After filling in this amount, they were asked the following question on the next page:</p><p>Now please think about all 100 of these children. How much are you willing to donate to help these 100 children? Please enter the amount of money you decide and agree to donate: __ $ Finally, in the SUA condition (novel to this study), participants were also asked to indicate how much they would be willing to donate to help one child first (as in the CUA condition). However, instead of extending directly to 100 children, we scaled up the scope sequentially by asking (on separate pages) their WTD judgements for 2, 5, 10, 20, 50, and only then 100 children. In general, the increase per step can be determined by the nth root of the full scope, where n is the number of steps (i.e. here, <ref type="bibr">6</ref> √ 100). This increase is founded in Fechner's law, postulating that the subjective intensity of stimulus corresponds logarithmically to the stimulus intensity <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Fechner, 1860)</ref>. This law suggests that increasing the number of children by a constant multiplier will correspond to increasing by a constant sum in terms of participants' subjective stimulus intensity. We additionally round to the next multiple of five for small numbers and the next multiple of ten for larger numbers to make the numbers more intuitive to participants (e.g., in this study, we use 50 rather than 46 as implied by the formula).</p><p>Participants provided their responses by typing any amount they saw fit (in US dollars) into a free text response box.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>Difficulties in Analyzing WTD Judgements. Open response WTD judgements often result in large outliers due to the lack of an upper bound. Previous papers on Unit</p><p>Asking address this by winsorizing outliers and then employing a t-test or ANOVA <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Hsee et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Karlsson et al., 2020)</ref>. Winsorizing replaces values above the 95th percentile of values provided with the value exactly at the 95th percentile, to reduce the skew in the data. However, winsorizing is often not effective. Even after winsorizing, the data is extremely skewed. This can make inferences overly dependent on the small subset of participants that indicate extremely large WTDs. We illustrate this using the data of Study 1a as an example. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows the distribution of WTD judgements in the three different groups after winsorizing. The distributions are still extremely skewed, and hence the application of methods assuming normally distributed residuals is not appropriate.</p><p>Winsorizing is also theoretically dubious. If a participant indicates a very high WTD judgement, it seems plausible that: (1) they did not take the task seriously and should be excluded; and/or (2) that they would actually donate that much. We are not aware of any mechanism which would give rise to the idea that they meant to indicate the value that the 95th percentile participant indicated (winsorizing). We can also consider the influence of individual datapoints on the observed pattern of significance. As an example of how strongly outliers affect statistical significance patterns under winsorizing, let us consider the comparison of DA (black) and CUA (red) groups. Naively analyzing the winsorized data indicates that CUA is more effective than DA, t(202.95) = 3.0677, p = .002. However, even though the comparison contains 271 participants and the p-value is small, the pattern of significance hinges upon the WTD judgements of 6 participants. If we remove the 6 highest values in the CUA group, the difference between the groups no longer attains the accepted significance level, t(226.26) = 1.916, p = .057. This should give some intuition about how unstable the classical inference using winsorized data is in WTD judgements.</p><p>Our Analytic Approach. Due to the highlighted limitations associated with winsorizing, we take a different approach in the current manuscript, which provides Bayesian models with lognormal likelihood, and non-parametric frequentist solutions to accommodate the skew in observed responses. Because we cannot meaningfully analyze scope insensitivity for participants who donated $0 (as they would donate $0 for any scope under scope consistency as well as scope inconsistency), and because the lognormal model cannot accommodate zeros, we excluded these participants in the following analyses. Our approach evolved during the project and this was the pre-registered approach for Study 3.</p><p>This is the analysis we focus on for all studies in the manuscript. An alternative write-up with analyses exactly as preregistered is available in the OSF project. The conclusions are the same in terms of the Bayes factor categories unless stated otherwise in footnotes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>Densities of WTD judgements in Study 1a After Winsorizing. Note. Black is the DA group, red the CUA group, and blue the SUA group.</p><p>To test the differences between conditions, we specified a Bayesian analysis using the package BRMS <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bürkner, 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bürkner, , 2018</ref>. We always compared the likelihood of the data under one model assuming a difference in WTD judgements to a model assuming no difference in WTD judgements using the bridgesampling package <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Gronau, Sarafoglou, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Gronau, Singmann, et al., 2017)</ref>. We refer to comparisons of two groups as t-tests and to comparisons of more than two groups as ANOVAs. Because our data was expected to be positive and quite skewed, we used a lognormal likelihood rather than the more common Gaussian likelihood (WTD i ∼ Lognormal(µ i , σ 2 ), where i denotes the condition). As well as visually confirming the shape of the data, we also validated the likelihood function by comparing lognormal and normal likelihood models with leave-one-out cross validation <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Vehtari et al., 2017)</ref>, which indicated superior performance of the lognormal models.In addition, the exponent of µ should usually approximate the empirical median of the data on a linear scale, although the two can differ where the data cluster around prominent numbers (e.g., 20, 50). This is observed in our data. We present posterior medians (i.e., exp(µ)) in addition to the empirical medians in our visualization of the results.</p><p>The analysis was conditional on participants donating at all (i.e., by removing zeros), and we also removed values larger than $10,000 (and note any instances where inferences are affected by this exclusion). We checked that our intervention did not affect the number of people donating in the first place, using a Bayesian contingency table analysis in the BayesFactor R package <ref type="bibr">(Morey et al., 2015)</ref>, with assumed sampling type joint multinomial and prior concentration one.</p><p>For the main analysis, we used a prior of normal(µ = 3, σ = 1) on the intercept. We used a prior of normal(0.4, 0.4) on the main effect of Asking Type. Finally, we used a prior of normal(1, 0.5) on σ. As the median of the lognormal distribution corresponds to exp <ref type="bibr">(µ)</ref> this implies that we expect a median donation of exp(3) = 20.9 in the control group and exp(3 + 0.4) = 29.96 in the intervention group. In addition, these priors result in reasonable prior predictives for this kind of donation task (see Appendix C, i.e., the mean and CI predicted from the priors are similar to values we would expect).</p><p>We use Bayes factors as our primary inference criteria <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Etz &amp; Wagenmakers, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Jeffreys, 1961;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Kass &amp; Raftery, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Rouder &amp; Morey, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Wrinch &amp; Jeffreys, 1921)</ref>. A Bayes factor compares the probability of the data under the null (no effect) to the alternative as specified by the prior distributions outlined above. As a general rule of thumb, Bayes factors between 1 and 3 are regarded as anecdotal evidence, Bayes factors between and 10 are regarded as moderate evidence, and Bayes factors larger than 10 are regarded as strong evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Jeffreys, 1939;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>. The inverse of the Bayes factor can be used to describe evidence for the null hypothesis. For example, a Bayes factor between 1/3 and 1/10 would be considered moderate evidence for the null. For robustness, we also analyzed the data with frequentist non-parametric tests.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect on Proportion of Participants Donating and Summary Statistics</head><p>A Bayesian contingency table analysis indicated that the intervention did not affect the share of participants donating in the first place (DA: 10.37%, CUA: 13.43%, SUA:</p><p>14.18%; BF 10 = 0.032; see Appendix D for the share of participants donating at all across conditions in all experiments). Our main analysis excludes WTD judgements of 0 (51 participants) and larger than 10,000 (zero participants). <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> visualizes the median WTD judgements for all WTD questions asked (i.e., per step), whereas <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> visualizes the WTD judgements only for the total scope of 100 children. The median donation for 100 children in the DA condition condition was $20, the median donation for 100 children in the CUA condition was $25, and the median donation for 100 children in the SUA condition was $75. For one child, the median donation was $10 in both intervention conditions. In line with the random assignment, a Wilcoxon test shows no evidence that SUA and CUA conditions differed in terms of donations for one child (W = 6526, p = .774).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of SUA and CUA on Donations</head><p>The 3-level ANOVA on WTD judgements to 100 children indicated overwhelming evidence for an effect of condition (BF 10 = 4.65 ×10 9 ). Pairwise comparisons indicated strong evidence for an effect of CUA in comparison to the DA condition (BF 10 = 33.08),</p><p>overwhelming evidence for SUA in comparison to the DA condition (BF 10 = 22.43 ×10 10 ), and strong evidence for SUA in comparison to CUA (BF 10 = 22101.89). The results were also corroborated with a frequentist analysis using non-parametric Wilcoxon tests (all p-values &lt; .01). As predicted, this study: (1) replicated the effectiveness of CUA in increasing WTD judgements compared to DA;</p><p>(2) showed that our extension to SUA gives a considerable additional boost over CUA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1b</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>This study was a preregistered direct replication of Study 1 (https://osf.io/uchq8).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>This study received ethical approval from Harvard University's ethics review board.</p><p>We paid participants $0.31 for this 2-minute study. The study was uploaded on February 3rd 2021 on Positly for US participants. Initially, 507 participants signed up for the study.</p><p>We excluded one participant who indicated that their age as 3963. The mean age was 40.69 (sd = 12.64). 248 participants were female, 256 were male, one indicated gender 'other', and one did not indicate their gender.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect on Proportion of Participants Donating and Summary Statistics</head><p>A Bayesian contingency table analysis indicated that the intervention did not affect the share of participants donating in the first place (DA: 11.76%, CUA: 13.43%, SUA:</p><p>14.18%; BF 10 = 0.015). We excluded WTD judgements of 0 (60 participants) and larger than 10,000 (3 participants; conclusions are unaffected by this exclusion unless indicated in a footnote). We proceeded to the main analysis with the remaining 443 participants. children in the DA condition was $20, the median donation for 100 children in the CUA condition was $50, and the median donation for 100 children in the SUA condition was $50. Note that if many participants indicated exactly the median, the distribution of WTD judgements between groups may still differ even though the medians are the same. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref> shows that this is indeed the case and more WTD judgements are above the median for SUA, compared with CUA, which is also reflected in the posterior medians (red line). The median donation to help one child was $18.50 in the CUA condition and $15 in the SUA condition. In line with the random assignment, a Wilcoxon test shows no evidence that SUA and CUA conditions differ in terms of donations for one child (W = 11267, p = .453).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of SUA and CUA on Donations</head><p>The 3-level ANOVA indicated overwhelming evidence for an effect (BF 10 = 2.63 × 10 11 3 Only 3.08 when not excluding the participants donating more than $10,000. The change in evidence is quite large as one of the excluded participants indicated they would donate 1 million dollars. As this is likely not indicative of their actual behaviour, we believe much more weight should be given to the analysis with exclusions.  In summary, Study 1b replicated the result that CUA increased WTD judgements over DA and that SUA additionally increased WTD judgements in comparison to CUA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>Studies 1a and 1b showed that SUA elicited higher average WTD judgements for groups of 100 than DA and CUA. However, to demonstrate scope sensitivity, we need to</p><p>show that the donation is larger when more units are under consideration (e.g., people donate more to help 10,000 people than to help 100 people). Therefore, Study 2 not only varied Asking Type but also the maximum Scope (100 vs. 10,000).</p><p>When scaling up SUA to a higher scope, there are fundamentally two possible approaches. First, one can keep the increase per step constant. In this case, a larger number of steps will be required to still reach the same full scope for a larger scope size (e.g., <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2,</ref><ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">50,</ref><ref type="bibr">100,</ref><ref type="bibr">200,</ref><ref type="bibr">500,</ref><ref type="bibr">1000,</ref><ref type="bibr">2000,</ref><ref type="bibr">5000,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">000)</ref>. Second, one can keep the number of steps constant. This will result in a higher increase per step, which is required to reach a larger scope with the same number of steps (e.g., 1, 5, 20, 100, 500, 2000, 10,000). In Study 2, we investigated both of these options.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hypotheses</head><p>We preregistered three hypotheses:</p><p>1. In a 2×2 analysis with factors Asking Type (Direct vs. CUA) and Scope (100 vs.</p><p>10,000), there will be no interaction of Asking Type and Scope (replicating Marcinkiewicz, 2016).</p><p>2. In a 2×2 analysis with factors Asking Type (CUA vs. SUA) and Scope (100 vs.</p><p>10,000), there will be an interaction of Asking Type and Scope such that SUA minus CUA is positive, and larger for Scope 10,000 than Scope 100.</p><p>3. If the effect of SUA is partially driven by an increase in the number of steps, we will observe that participants in the increase per step constant condition (SUAI) would donate more for 10,000 children than those in the number of steps constant condition (SUA). 4</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>This study received ethical approval from the Ethics Chair for the Department of Experimental Psychology, UCL (Project ID No: EP/2021/001). We paid participants between $0.40 and $0.65 for participating in a 3-5 minute study (depending on condition).</p><p>The study was uploaded on August 24th and 25th, 2021, targeting US participants via</p><p>Positly. Based on our preregistered stopping rule, we used Bayesian sequential analysis starting with 280 participants, adding 140 additional participants in two steps until we reached 560 participants (including WTD judgements of 0). 562 participants signed up and we did not exclude any based on age. 285 were female, 275 male, and 2 indicated gender 'other' with mean age of 40.16 (sd = 12.07).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental Conditions</head><p>We employed a similar method to Study 1 with a number of changes. To allow more realistic scaling up to larger scopes, we replaced the kindergarten example with a vignette describing a food shortage in Ethiopia. Participants were told that in one area of the country, 100 or 10,000 children were affected by the shortage and asked how much they wanted to donate to the charity "Global Alliance for Improved Nutrition" to help the children in need (based on <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Marcinkiewicz, 2016)</ref>. The combinations of Scope and Asking</p><p>Type required to answer our Research Questions resulted in seven conditions. Participants were randomly assigned into one of the following conditions (with the exact sequence of the number of children mentioned stated in parentheses):</p><p>1. Scope 100 x DA (100) 2. Scope 10,000 x DA (10,000)</p><p>3. Scope 100 x CUA (1, 100) 4. Scope 10,000 x CUA (1, 10,000) 5. Scope x SUA <ref type="bibr">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2,</ref><ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">50,</ref><ref type="bibr">100)</ref> 6. Scope 10,000 x SUA -number of steps constant <ref type="bibr">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">100,</ref><ref type="bibr">500,</ref><ref type="bibr">2000,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">000)</ref> 7. Scope 10,000 x SUAI -increase per step constant <ref type="bibr">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2,</ref><ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">50,</ref><ref type="bibr">100,</ref><ref type="bibr">200,</ref><ref type="bibr">500,</ref><ref type="bibr">1000,</ref><ref type="bibr">2000,</ref><ref type="bibr">5000,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">000)</ref> Each Unit Asking condition also included the following, exploratory, desire for consistency measure: "You said you would give X dollars for a single child and Y dollars for the group of N children. In doing so, were you trying to be consistent? That is, were you trying to allocate for each child in the group of N children as much as money as for the single child? (1 = not at all, 4 = somewhat 7= yes, absolutely)". The variables X, Y, and N were adapted based on the participant's responses. The consistency measure was asked at the end of the study to avoid any influences on the key variable of interest (WTD).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>We used the same analysis as Study 1b with the addition of a prior of normal(0.25, 0.25) on the interaction. The reason why the priors are increasingly more narrow is that,</p><p>given the lognormal likelihood, the prediction on the linear scale corresponds to the exponent of the marginal mean. Therefore, using similar priors on main effects and interactions would result in the prediction of an extremely large interaction effect on the linear scale. We tested for the presence of the hypothesized interactions by comparing models that include the interaction to models that do not include the interaction using Bayes factors. In addition, we conducted a frequentist analysis using rank-based (non-parametric) tests for main effects and interactions with the package rfit <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kloke, McKean, et al., 2012)</ref>, and independent sample Wilcoxon tests when comparing pairwise differences.</p><p>(SEQUENTIAL) UNIT ASKING 24</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>As we did not achieve sufficient evidence on all three critical tests in the preregistered intermittent analyses, we collected the full sample of 562, consistent with our preregistration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect on Proportion of Participants Donating and Summary Statistics</head><p>A Bayesian contingency table analysis again indicated that the intervention did not affect the share of participants donating at all (BF 10 = 0.19; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table D1</ref> for proportions).</p><p>Therefore, we proceeded to the main analysis excluding WTD judgements of 0 (133 participants) and larger than 10,000 (exclusions by condition: DA = 2; CUA = 2; SUAnumber of steps constant = 11; SUA -increase per step constant = 4; conclusions are unaffected by this exclusion unless indicated in a footnote), leaving us with a total of 410 participants. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> shows the median WTD judgements per step and <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> shows the distribution of WTD judgements for the total number of children (see also <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table D1</ref>). In line with the random assignment, a Wilcoxon test shows no evidence that SUA and CUA conditions differ in terms of donations for one child (W = 10992, p = .767). 5</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H1: Comparing CUA and DA</head><p>The first hypothesis, that CUA would not make participants scope sensitive, received only weak support. A Bayesian interaction test in a 2x2 ANOVA with factors Scope (100 vs. 10,000) and Asking Type (DA vs. CUA) implied weak evidence against an interaction of Asking Type and Scope (BF 10 = 0.50). 6 In addition, there was strong <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The reason why the medians in the Figure for one child are different even though there is no significant difference is that participants cluster their responses around prominent numbers (i.e., 10, 20, 50).</p><p>Therefore, only a few participants changing their judgement can result in a jump between two prominent numbers.</p><p>evidence for a main effect of CUA vs. DA (BF 10 = 10.03) . A non-parametric ANOVA also found no evidence for an interaction of Asking Type and Scope, F (1, 228) = 0.49, p =</p><p>.488, and a significant main effect of CUA vs. DA, F (1, 228) = 5.11, p = .025.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 6</head><p>Median WTDs for Each Step in Study 2. Note. Error bars indicate interquartile range. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We found only moderate evidence when not excluding WTDs larger than $10,000 (BF 10 = 6.48). Note. Grey area indicates empirical density. Black lines indicate empirical medians. Red lines indicate posterior medians. SUAI is for SUA with increase per step constant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H2: Comparing SUA and CUA</head><p>We found weak evidence against the second prediction that SUA would result in more scope consistency than CUA, as revealed by an interaction between SUA (number of steps constant) vs. CUA and Scope (BF 10 = 0.64) 8 . As in the previous study, we found a main effect of SUA vs. CUA (BF 10 = 11.70) 9 , although the evidence here is much weaker.</p><p>These findings were corroborated with a non-parametric, frequentist analysis finding no interaction, F (1, 247) = 0.35, p = .552, and a (just) significant main effect of SUA vs.</p><p>CUA; F (1, 247) = 3.96, p = .047. Further, when only comparing the increase in WTD <ref type="bibr">8</ref> We find moderate evidence for this interaction when not excluding participants donating more than $10,000 (BF 10 = 3.61), and strong evidence against this when using the preregistered model judgements under SUA vs. CUA for Scope 100, which is similar to Study 1, the evidence for the effect is only moderate (BF 10 = 4.085) 10 . This is surprising given the strong evidence found in Study 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H3: Comparing Different Types of SUA</head><p>We found no evidence that donations were higher for 10,000 children in the SUAI (increase per step constant) condition than the SUA (constant number of steps) condition, as revealed by a t-test (BF 10 = 0.67). 11 This is also supported by a non-parametric</p><p>Wilcoxon test, W = 1473, p = .949.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory Analyses: Investigating Judgements in Intermediate Steps and</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Desire For Consistency</head><p>The donation patterns so far give rise to some interesting avenues for more detailed examination. Two conditions used identical sequences of steps up to 100 participant: SUA with constant increase per step for Scope 10,000, dotted grey line in <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>; SUA for Scope 100, solid black line in <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. This raises the question of why the WTD judgements are not higher for the full scope in SUAI with constant increase per step for Scope 10,000, given the larger number of affected individuals as well as larger number of steps. Two explanations come to mind: (1) participants reach some kind of donation ceiling after which they do not donate more;</p><p>(2) participants (who were informed in the beginning what the maximum scope would be) think ahead and donating less for one child when they know the full scope will be higher. In other words, they might first form a judgement about what to donate according to the full scope and then donate a proportional fraction of this to one child. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> shows the share of participants that indicate a strong monotonic increase at each step (i.e., donate more for more children). <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> confirms what is suggested by <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. In the Scope 100 condition, more participants increase on each step in comparison to the Scope 10,000 condition. In addition, the proportion of participants increasing is lower for the larger scopes in the Scope 10,000 condition. In other words, both looking ahead and reaching a donation ceiling may play a role in this donation behaviour. To test this, we conducted a linear regression predicting the number of strong monotonic increases from the WTD judgements for a single child. However, we did not find any evidence for the notion that WTD judgements for one child were related to monotonic increases for any of the 3 SUA conditions (maximum Scope 100: F (1, 79) = 2.18, p = .501, maximum Scope 10,000 &amp; increase per step constant: F (1, 77) = .764, p = .385, and maximum Scope 10,000 &amp; number of steps constant: F (1, 77) = .666, p = .417).</p><p>Finally, we found evidence against an effect of Asking Type on our exploratory measure, 'desire for consistency' (BF 10 = 0.055), which we included in line with <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Marcinkiewicz (2016)</ref>,. However, this might not rule out 'desire for consistency' as an explanation for the effect given the likely insensitivity of this one item measure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>We again replicated the benefit of SUA over CUA; however, the evidence was much weaker than in Study 1 (though still moderate in strength).</p><p>We found no evidence that unit asking increased scope sensitivity in this study.</p><p>This finding holds for SUA and CUA -both techniques only give a constant boost independent of scope. In other words, repeated asking leads people to indicate higher WTD judgements, but this effect appears independent of Scope (the number of children affected). Perhaps the most surprising result is that we do not observe scope sensitivity in the SUAI -increase per step constant -condition. To explain this result, we suggest that some participants might reach a donation ceiling (as suggested by the smaller number of participants displaying monotonic donation patterns for the larger number of affected individuals -see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>). Alternatively, some participants might seek to ensure consistency by donating less to a single child when they had an idea of what the maximum scope would be. Finally, some participants might simply find the large number of repetitive questions that were asked in this condition unpleasant or irritating and, therefore, disengage from the task. Study 3 included alternative optimal conditions for observing scope sensitivity on the basis of these conjectures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>Study 3 aimed to provide the most favourable conditions for scope sensitivity. To reduce the likelihood of participants reaching a donation ceiling, we reduced the maximum scope in this study from 10,000 to 50. Achieving scope consistency for such a smaller scope is likely more realistic, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hsee et al. (2013</ref><ref type="bibr">Hsee et al. ( , p.1806</ref>) would appear to agree: "We should also note, however, that the ability of unit asking to increase scope sensitivity is likely limited; if the target numbers are large -for example, 1,000 versus 10,000 -respondents may encode either number as 'a lot' and not differentiate the two". To avoid participants planning forward when knowing the maximum scope, we included conditions where we do not tell participants the maximum scope in advance of the iterative procedure. Finally, we also reverted back to the kindergarten vignette that we had used in Study 1 which showed the strongest benefit of SUA over CUA. Overall, we aimed to test the following four preregistered research questions in this study:</p><p>1. Can we identify scope sensitivity for any of the asking techniques?</p><p>2. Does SUA increase WTD judgements over CUA?</p><p>3. Does SUA make participants more scope sensitive than CUA?</p><p>4. Does telling people the maximum scope beforehand affect scope sensitivity?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>This study received ethical approval from the Ethics Chair for the Department of Experimental Psychology, UCL (Project ID No: EP/2021/001) and was preregistered at https://osf.io/ezrs9. We paid participants $0.37 for participating in a 2-minute study. We did not include a DA condition this time as, at this point, it is well established that people are scope insensitive under DA, and that both CUA and SUA increase WTD judgements relative to this baseline.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect on Proportion of Participants Donating and Summary Statistics</head><p>We used the same statistical model as in Study 2. Asking Type did not affect the number of participants donating in the first instance (BF 10 = 0.03, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table D2 for</ref> proportions). We proceeded to our main analysis, excluding participants that donated 0 (70 participants) and participants that donated more than 10,000 (0 participants). shows the distributions of WTD judgements for the full scope (see also <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table D2</ref>). In line with the random assignment, a Wilcoxon test shows no evidence that SUA and CUA conditions differed in terms of donations for one child (W = 26393, p = .916).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 8</head><p>Median WTDs for Each Step in Study 3.  *SUA conditions where the maximum Scope was unknown to participants. In all other conditions the maximum Scope is known.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ1: Can We Identify Scope Sensitivity in Any Format?</head><p>We tested this with four comparisons between the WTD judgements for 50 vs. 10 participants for both CUA and SUA (i.e., in terms of the Experimental Conditions 1 vs. 2, increase per step constant comparison, we found weak evidence that participants donated more with larger scopes (BF 10 = 2.55). In addition, for SUA (number of steps constant),</p><p>we also have one condition where participants knew the maximum scope when starting the experiment. Here we find weak evidence for participants donating less on the larger scopes (BF 10 = 0.36). In sum, Study 3 did not reveal convincing evidence for scope sensitivity in any format. This lack of evidence is also corroborated by non-parametric Wilcoxon tests.</p><p>This indicates no evidence for scope consistency under CUA (p = .357), no evidence for scope consistency under SUA (number of steps constant, p = .241), no evidence for scope consistency under SUAI (increase per step constant, p = .077), and no evidence for scope consistency when telling people the maximum scope beforehand (p = .883). for an interaction in the number of steps constant condition, F (1, 287) = 3.06, p = .081;</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ2: Does</head><p>however, it does show evidence for a (just) significant interaction for SUAI (increase per step constant), F (1, 286) = 5.21, p = .023.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ4: Does Telling People the Maximum Scope Beforehand Affect Scope</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sensitivity?</head><p>When testing an interaction between telling people the maximum scope before and Scope (i.e., 3 &amp; 4 vs. 5 &amp; 6), we find no evidence that telling people the maximum scope beforehand increases scope sensitivity (BF 10 = 0.42) for the SUA conditions. This is also confirmed by a robust frequentist ANOVA, F (1, 281) = 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion Study 3</head><p>Effect of SUA vs. CUA No Evidence for a Difference in Study 3. In this study, we did not find evidence for the main effect of SUA. Importantly, we also did not find evidence against an effect of SUA. To investigate whether this result is driven by the smaller scope in this study, we compared the SUA vs. CUA effect in this study (for the condition with 50 participants) to that in Study 1a (Scope = 100), where we found the strongest effect of SUA. We tested the interaction between Condition (SUA vs. CUA) and Study to investigate whether the difference in conditions was affected by the study. As we did not have a Unit Asking condition where the scope was known in advance in Study 3, we used the conditions where the scope is not known for this comparison. We only found weak (and non-significant) evidence for this interaction (Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 2.32;</p><p>nonparametric ANOVA: F (1, 373) = 1.400, p = 0.237). We conclude, therefore, that the effect of SUA vs CUA does not reliably differ across the studies.</p><p>Effect of SUA vs. CUA Across All Donation Studies. To further test the overall effect of SUA, we pooled the data from all four studies and one study presented in Appendix A, which employed a different design that likely diminished the effectiveness of SUA. We tested for an overall effect of SUA vs. CUA across these five studies using a</p><p>Bayesian mixed-effects model with random effects for Study and Scope. We used the same priors as in Study 3 and BRMs' default priors on the random effects 13 . When pooling across studies, we only find moderate evidence for an effect of SUA in comparison to CUA (BF 10 = 3.65). If we only look at the studies in the main text of this manuscript, the evidence is somewhat stronger (BF 10 = 4.50). In conclusion, when pooling across all relevant studies, there is moderate evidence that SUA results in higher WTD judgements for helping multiple individuals than does CUA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>No Evidence for Scope Sensitivity under CUA and SUA</head><p>We again did not observe any evidence for scope sensitivity, even after creating these most favorable conditions to observe scope sensitivity in donation judgements. We believe the two most likely explanations for this result are:</p><p>1. Even with reduced scope, participants' budget constraints limit their donation judgements to an extent that scope sensitivity may not be observed with WTD judgements.</p><p>2. None of the asking techniques promotes scope sensitivity in general.</p><p>If the first explanation is correct, we would expect to see evidence for scope sensitivity in a contingent valuation version of the study. In other words, instead of asking participants how much money they would donate to buy Christmas gifts for the children, one would ask how much money they think is required to buy Christmas presents for these children. As no willingness for a personal donation is asked for, budget constraints would no longer explain the lack of scope sensitivity. We tested such a contingent valuation setup for Study 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 4</head><p>To switch to a contingent valuation setup in Study 4, we replaced the question about donations in Study 3 with the following question:</p><p>Please think about all [10 in the lower scope condition] of these children. How much money do you think is needed to buy Christmas gifts for these 50 children?</p><p>Please indicate the amount here: __$</p><p>We modified the background scenario from Study 3 by telling participants that they are active in the local community and occasionally give advice to people in their community when they have admin. related questions. In a next step, we informed them that the principal of a neighbourhood kindergarten has contacted them to ask how much money they think is needed to buy Christmas gifts for the children. We elicited the contingent valuation judgements with the different asking techniques specified in Study 3.</p><p>The aim of this study was to test the following preregistered research questions: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect on Proportion of Participants Donating and Summary Statistics</head><p>The statistical model was the same as in Study 3. However, this time none of the participants indicated an amount of zero, thus, we did not conduct the contingency table analysis and proceeded directly to our main analysis, excluding participants who indicated more than 10,000 (12 participants, four for each asking type; conclusions are unaffected by this exclusion unless indicated in a footnote). <ref type="figure">Figure 10</ref> visualizes the median contingent valuation trajectories for the different steps, and <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref> shows the distribution of contingent valuation judgements for the full scope. The figures suggest that this time participants did increase their judgements for larger numbers of affected children. In line with the random assignment, a Wilcoxon test shows no evidence that SUA and CUA conditions differed in terms of valuations for one child (W = 15195, p = .140).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 10</head><p>Median Contingency Valuation Judgements for Each Step in Study 4.  . SUAI is for SUAI (increase per step constant).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ1 &amp; RQ2: Which Asking Technique Induces the Highest Valuation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Judgements?</head><p>When comparing DA and CUA (Conditions 1 &amp; 2 vs 3 &amp; 4), we find no evidence for a difference in judgements (Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 0.21, frequentist analysis: W = 11060, p = .653).</p><p>When comparing SUA to CUA, we also find no evidence for a difference in judgements when using the number of steps constant condition (Conditions 3 &amp; 4 vs 5 &amp; 6;</p><p>Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 0.87, frequentist analysis: W = 10378, p = 0.329 ); however, we find moderate evidence with the increase per step constant, SUAI, condition (Conditions 3 (SEQUENTIAL) UNIT ASKING 41 &amp; 4 vs 5 &amp; 7, Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 6.13 14 , frequentist analysis: W = 1093, p = .102).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ3: Which Asking Techniques Induce Scope Sensitivity?</head><p>When comparing donations for Scope 10 and Scope 50 we find strong evidence for scope sensitivity for all of the asking techniques:</p><p>• DA (Conditions 1 vs 2): Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 3.46 × 10 12 ; frequentist analysis: </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">W =</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion Study 4</head><p>For contingent valuation judgements, we only find evidence for a benefit of SUA over CUA in average judgements when using the increase per step constant condition, SUAI, rather than the number of steps constant condition. We further find evidence for an interaction between Scope and CUA vs SUA, for both SUA types. In other words, SUA may only increase contingent valuation judgements if: (1) the scope is larger than ten and</p><p>(2) a sufficient number of steps is asked (in this case five steps). Further, we find that people are scope sensitive in a contingent valuation setting even under DA. Notably, this scope sensitivity can further be enhanced using SUA but not using CUA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>We tested whether Unit Asking makes people scope sensitive as claimed in previous research. We found that Unit Asking only gives a one-off boost to WTD judgements, independent of scope. In other words, participants donated more under Unit Asking as opposed to Direct Asking; however, this increase was independent of the number of individuals affected and, therefore, does not seem to reflect genuine scope sensitivity.</p><p>We also introduced a new variant of Unit Asking, which we call Sequential Unit Asking (SUA). SUA extends Classical Unit Asking (CUA) by asking a sequence of questions scaling up with scope. We found evidence in three out of four studies that SUA increased WTD judgements over CUA. In addition, when pooling across all studies we found overall evidence that SUA increased WTD judgements over CUA. However, this increase also seems to come only as a limited series of one-off boosts rather than covarying with scope.</p><p>We further investigated contingent valuation judgements, where we found the inverse pattern in comparison to WTD judgements. People were scope sensitive under all of the asking techniques but CUA and SUA did not strongly increase judgements in comparison to direct asking. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> gives on overview of the results across all five studies.</p><p>Finally, we advanced the methodology for analyzing willingness to donate (WTD) judgements. We showed that the oft-used method of winsorizing and using conventional t-tests is problematic, as even after winsorizing the inference is not robust to outliers.</p><p>Instead, we used a Bayesian model with lognormal likelihoods that can directly accommodate skew. We share the analysis code in our OSF project so that other researchers might use the methodology when analyzing WTD judgements, or other judgements with similar distributional properties (i.e., extreme positive skew &amp; zeros are reasonably excluded).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Why is it Difficult to Create Scope Sensitivity in WTD Judgements and Easier in Contingent Valuation?</head><p>A possible explanation for the difficulty of making people scope sensitive in WTD judgements using the different Unit Asking manipulations is based on mental accounting.</p><p>In line with research on this topic <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Sussman et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Thaler, 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Thaler, , 1999</ref>, participants might have a fixed budget of how much they are willing to give to charity. This allocated money might already be exploited on relatively small numbers of children; therefore, participants do not usually increase their WTD judgements anymore for larger scopes in the Unit Asking condition. This is also reflected in comments that we got from participants in Study 2, where we included an open feedback box. For example, one participant indicated "I have a certain amount total I'm willing to give ($15), so after that is reached I'm not willing to give anymore." and another participant said "I have limited funds so I can only donate so much regardless of the number in need." Versions of these comments were echoed by a considerable proportion of participants. Even though we tried to mitigate the problem by reducing the maximum scope in Study 3, it is still possible that both Note. "+ + +" denotes Strong evidence for H 1 , "++" denotes moderate evidence for H 1 , "+" denotes weak evidence for H 1 , "−" denotes weak evidence for H 0 , "−−" denotes moderate evidence for H 0 , and "− − −" denotes strong evidence for H 0 . Medians and Means here reported including donations of 0.</p><p>SUA uses the number of steps constant condition for scaling up the scope. For Study 2, SUA refers to the condition, where the maximum scope was not known for comparability. As only for Study 4 the judgements differed strongly based on scope, we distinguish between Scope 10 and Scope 50 for this study. * Unlike CUA, SUA further increased scope sensitivity above direct asking.</p><p>studies had reached the donation ceiling for most participants on both scopes, thus 735 diminishing scope sensitivity.</p><p>In contrast, the contingent valuation setting removes this possibility: participants are asked how much money is needed to buy Christmas presents. This explains why participants are more readily scope sensitive even without using CUA or SUA. This baseline scope sensitivity can be further enhanced by SUA. However, we only observe a weak form of scope sensitivity, where participants donate more for more children, but this number does not increase proportionally with the scope, a finding that is qualitatively in line with previous literature on scope insensitivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Dickert et al., 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dickert et al., , 2015</ref>.</p><p>Overall, we conclude that when (hypothetical) personal funds are at stake, participants are reluctant to even show weak scope sensitivity, and only strong manipulations such as repeated asking will induce increases in donations. On the other hand, people readily show scope sensitivity for contingent valuation judgements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Future Directions</head><p>In this manuscript, we have focused solely on hypothetical WTD judgements. A standard suggestion for future research would therefore be to include incentive compatible studies. We do not, however, perceive these as a fruitful avenue for future research in this area for three reasons. First, in the current studies, our observations of different results between WTD judgements and contingent valuation judgements, coupled with participants' references to budgetary constraints in open-text feedback, suggests our participants did take the hypothetical judgements seriously, and were restricted by real-world budgets. Second, the long ongoing debate about how much financial incentives change participant behaviour in the social and behavioural sciences <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Camerer &amp; Hogarth, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hertwig &amp; Ortmann, 2001)</ref>, mostly concludes that "the effects of incentives are mixed and complicated" <ref type="bibr">(Camerer &amp; Hogarth, 1999, p. 1)</ref>. While research has found that reliance on hypothetical donations increases mean donations <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bekkers, 2017)</ref>, to our knowledge there is no evidence that hypotheticality influences differences between conditions in WTD judgements. Finally, incentive compatible studies typically provide an endowment and ask participants to donate a proportion of this (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Schoenegger &amp; Costa-Gomes, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Small et al., 2007)</ref>, which is a considerably different task from the majority of real-life donation decisions. Given that our participants appeared to take the WTD task seriously (as evidenced above), we would see such an incentive compatible task as more different from real donation decisions than our hypothetical tasks, especially as it induces an upper bound on how much participants can donate (the endowment), which would make it more difficult to study scope sensitivity. To determine how to maintain potential donors' interest and lever the benefits of SUA in the real-world, a naturalistic field study would be required. Such a study would enable stronger conclusions as to the effectiveness of SUA in increasing charitable donations 'in the wild.'</p><p>Further, in line with previous studies on Unit Asking <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Hsee et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Karlsson et al., 2020)</ref>, we only include a picture of one needy child and don't increase the number of children in the picture as scope increases. The fact that the Unit Asking method increases average donations provides evidence that participants are able to scale their concern with the number of children, at least in an ordinal way, even when visualizations of the scope are not provided. However, adding visualizations to represent additional children may help induce scope sensitivity in combination with (Sequential) Unit Asking. Identifying appropriate visualisations might therefore be one avenue for future research to further increase scope sensitivity (see, for example, this educational video for visualization/animation techniques https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEENEFaVUzU).</p><p>Finally, future work may also explore different sequences of steps. Study showed that the effect of SUA levels off when including too many steps. It would be interesting to further investigate at which point the effect of SUA begins to level off (although leveling off would likely depend on a number of contextual factors, such as the maximum scope). In addition to changing the number of steps, one could also change the ordering of steps, or include steps in random order to further investigate how the effects are shaped by the step order.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>This paper showed the difficulty in inducing scope sensitivity in WTD judgements.</p><p>Contrary to previous claims, Unit Asking does not increase scope sensitivity in separate evaluation, but instead gives a one-off boost to WTD judgements. However, our findings also suggest that this one-off boost is increased by asking additional stepwise questions, a technique we term Sequential Unit Asking.</p><p>Pilot 2 -Budget Constrains as Explanation for The Effectiveness of SUA over CUA</p><p>In pilot two, we aimed to investigate whether a possible mechanism explaining the effectiveness of SUA was that people disengage when they need to increase the donation too much in one step. In other words, they might donate beyond budget constraints. We manipulated this by starting out from a small donation of $0.1 for one child resulting in a small donation even after multiplying with 100 versus a larger donation of $10 where people should disengage when directly jumping to a consistent donation of $1000 for the full scope.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental Conditions</head><p>This study employed a 2 (technique: SUA vs. CUA) x 2 (costs: small vs. large)</p><p>between-subjects design. We manipulated the costs required to donate to help one child.</p><p>The vignette was similar to Study 1, with the modification that this time participants were asked to donate to help treat parasitic worms, with treatment costing either large ($10) or small ($0.1). One group was told that 10cts are needed to help one child that is sick of parasitic worms, while the other group that $10 are needed to cure this disease. In addition, we varied SUA vs. CUA. We hypothesized that both interventions should work similarly when only 10cts were required to help one child but that SUA would work remarkably better when $10 was required to help one child. In other words, there would be an interaction between Asking Type (SUA vs. CUA) and the costs of saving one child. We also randomized whether money was displayed in cents or in dollars to check for an effect of the currency unit. In addition, for our analysis, we rescaled the group giving only $0.1 by multiplying it by 1000 so that the interaction effect could be analyzed.</p><p>The vignette was similar to Study 1, with the modification that this time participants were asked to donate to help treat parasitic worms, with treatment costing either large ($10) or small ($0.1). In addition, all values were presented on the cents scale and the dollar scale since we had suspected that participants are primed to donate more when the currency unit is dollar compared to cents. To check this idea, half of the participants saw all units in dollars and the other half in cents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>We used a Bayesian ANOVA in the package BRMS as in the previous study. Because we cannot meaningfully analyze scope insensitivity for participants that donated 0 (as they would donate 0 for any scope under scope consistency as well as scope inconsistency), we excluded these participants. We excluded unbelievably large WTD judgements of more than $10,000. As our data was (after excluding the zeros) expected to be positive and quite skewed, we used a lognormal likelihood rather than the more common Gaussian likelihood.</p><p>We used a prior of normal(3,1) on the intercept, normal(0, 0.4) on the scope (as we expected scope insensitivity) and normal(0.4, 0.4) on the main effect of Asking Type, normal(0.25, 0.25) on the interaction and normal(1, 0.5) on σ. The reason why the priors are increasingly more narrow is that given the lognormal likelihood the prediction on the linear scale corresponds to the exponent of the marginal mean. Therefore, using similar priors on main effects in interactions would result in the prediction of an extremely large interaction effect on the linear scale. We tested for the presence of the hypothesized interactions by comparing models that include the interaction to models that do not include the interaction using Bayes factors. We also conducted a non-parametric analysis using robust ANOVA in the Rfit package.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>The study was run on the 23rd of January 2021, targeting American participants through positly. We paid participants $0.31 to participate in a 2.5-minute study. 2 participants were excluded because they indicated extremely high or negative age. The mean participant age was 443.12 (sd = 14.14). 97 participants were female, 103 were male, and 1 did not indicate their gender. This study was approved by University of Oxford (SEQUENTIAL) UNIT ASKING 55 Central University Research Ethics Committee (reference number R56657/RE001).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>A Bayesian contingency table analysis indicated that the intervention did not influence the share of participants donating (BF 10 = 0.19). Therfore, we proceeded to the main analysis, excluding 25 participants that donated 0 and 8 participants that donated more than 10,000. We find no evidence for a main effect of SUA vs. CUA (BF = 1.11) but evidence that people donate more when currencies are presented in terms of dollars rather than cents (BF 10 = 8.67). We find weak evidence against the predicted interaction of Asking Type with scope (BF 10 = 0.55). This is also corroborated by the robust ANOVA which finds no evidence for a main effect of Asking Type, F (1, 163) = 0.22, p = .637, a main effect of cents vs. dollars, F (1, 163) = 4.02, p = .047, and no evidence for an interaction effect of starting value and Asking Type, F (1, 163) = 0.010, p = .752.</p><p>To sum up, this study neither found a main effect of SUA nor the predicted interaction. We believe a crucial flaw of this study was that telling participants how much would be needed to save one child beforehand undermined the point of SUA or CUA because participants could already multiply without using any specific asking technique. This is also why we did not include it in the main part of the manuscript.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pilot 3 -Priming Scope Sensitivity</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>The aims of this study were twofold. First, to do a more fine-grained analysis of the Sequential Unit Asking technique. We varied the number of steps and investigated how that affects the amount that participants donate after the final step. In addition, we varied the difference between steps to see how this impacts the WTD judgements. Second, we tested whether, after being consistent for several small steps, people are primed to be consistent, thus making them more consistent in a later larger step.  <ref type="bibr">1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 20, 40, 60, 80, 100 [10 steps]</ref> Our first hypothesis was the people would give the most in the Max steps condition because there is some increase with each step. Our second hypothesis was that people give more in the consistency priming condition than in the equal spacing condition due to the priming idea discussed above. Our third hypothesis was that people would give more in the next-to-last step in the equal spacing condition (where there are 80 beneficiaries) than in the consistency priming condition (where there are five beneficiaries). This would show that conditional on the number of steps being fixed (and the size of all steps being the same), the participants will donate more the greater the size of each step is; in other words, they are at least somewhat scope sensitive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>We used a Bayesian ANOVA in the package BRMS as in the previous study. Because we cannot meaningfully analyze scope insensitivity for participants that donated 0 (as they would donate 0 for any scope under scope consistency as well as scope inconsistency), we excluded these participants. As preregistered, we excluded unbelievably large WTD judgements of more than $10,000. As our data was (after excluding the zeros) expected to be positive and quite skewed, we used a lognormal likelihood rather than the more common Gaussian likelihood. We used a prior of normal(3,1) on the intercept, normal(0, 0.4) on the scope (as we expected scope insensitivity) and normal(0.4, 0.4) on the main effect of Asking Type, normal(1, 0.5) on σ. The reason why the priors are increasingly more narrow is that given the lognormal likelihood, the prediction on the linear scale corresponds to the exponent of the marginal mean. Therefore, using similar priors on intercepts and slopes would result in the prediction of an extremely large difference between the groups. We tested for the presence of the hypothesized mean differences by comparing models that include the interaction to models that do not include the interaction using Bayes factors. In addition, we used non-parametric Wilcoxon tests to check the robustness of our conclusions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited American participants through positly. The study was run on 18th of February 2021. Participants received a payment of $0.36 to participate in a 3 minute study.</p><p>Initially, 201 participants signed up, we excluded 2 for indicating implausible age. In addition, we excluded 1 participant who donated more than $10,000. We also excluded two participants who indicated impossible ages. This left us with a final sample of 177 participants. Mean age was 43.39 (sd = 12.06). 91 participants were female and 108 were male. This study received ethical approval by Harvard University's ethics review board.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>As all conditions in this study were SUA conditions, we directly proceeded with excluding WTD judgements of 0 (21 participants) and more than 10,000 (1 participant).</p><p>We only found weak evidence that more steps lead to higher WTD judgements (bf 10 = 2.12). Hypothesis two was also not supported with only weak evidence that consistency priming improved performance over equal spacing (bf 10 = 1.97). Finally, we also found (SEQUENTIAL) UNIT ASKING 58 strong evidence that participants donated more for 80 in the equal spacing condition than for 5 in the consistency priming condition (bf 1 0 = 23.83). This is also corroborated by non-parametric Wilcoxon test (Hypothesis one: W = 1585.5, p = .1276; Hypothesis two: W = 2800.5, p = .095; Hypothesis three: W = 1307.5, p = .005).</p><p>(SEQUENTIAL) UNIT ASKING 59 Appendix C</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Prior Predictives for BRMs model</head><p>When sampling only from priors, we obtain predictions for the marginal means as in <ref type="figure">Figure C1</ref>. In other words, we would estimate a donation of 37 for the DA condition and a donation of 56 for the unit asking condition on a low scope. Because of the hypothesized interaction of Asking Type and scope under H 1 , we predicted a donation of 71 for unit asking and scope 10,000. The skew of the credible intervals is a feature of the lognormal likelihood, which helps accommodate strong positive outliers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure C1</head><p>Prior Predictives for the Lognormal Model.   Step 2: Fitting the Models Once we established that the proportion of participants donating in the first place is not affected, we can go ahead and fit the models. In order to test for the presence of a difference between groups, we specify one model that assumes a difference between groups (H ) to one model that does not assume a difference (H 0 ). We can see that this code specifies two competing models, the H 1 includes an effect of the intervention (WTD ∼ Experiment..Pilot.), whereas the H 0 model does not (WTD ∼ Experiment..Pilot.). Further, we specify the number of iterations and warmup for the MCMC sampling (details on MCMC sampling and checking of model convergence are beyond the scope of this guide, see, for example, McElreath, 2020) and prior distributions.</p><p>The priors here were based on pilot data. There is ample guidance available on different approaches to specifying prior distributions, and we refer the reader to the literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Stefan et al., 2022)</ref>. Finally, we specified family = lognormal(). This indicates that we are relying on a lognormal likelihood rather than a normal likelihood.</p><p>Step 3: Comparing the Models Finally, we compare the two models under consideration using Bayes Factors:</p><p>bayes_factor <ref type="bibr">(data.brms1, data.brms0)</ref> This code will use bridge sampling to estimate the Bayes factors (more details in <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Gronau, Sarafoglou, et al., 2017)</ref>. The Bayes factor compares the likelihood of the data under the two competing models. Here we calculate the Bayes factor in favor of the alternative (as data.brms1 is listed first in the brackets). As a rule of thumb, Bayes factors between 1 and 3 are considered weak evidence Bayes factors between 3 and 10 are considered moderate evidence, and Bayes factors larger 10 are considered strong evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>. When the evidence for the null is considered, the Bayes factor is simply inverted (BF 10 = 1/BF 01 ).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Error bars indicate the interquartile range.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 WTD</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Distribution for the Full Scope of 100 in Study 1a. Grey area indicates empirical density. Black lines indicate empirical medians. Red lines indicate posterior medians (i.e., the median of the posterior distribution for this parameter).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>displays WTD judgements per step after these exclusions.Figure 5shows the distribution of WTDs for the full Scope of 100 children. The median donation for 100</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Error bars indicate the interquartile range.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 WTD</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Distribution for the Full Scope in Study 1b. Grey area indicates empirical density. Black lines indicate empirical medians. Red lines indicate posterior medians (i.e., the median of the posterior distribution for this parameter).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>WTD Distribution for the Full Scope in Study 2.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>visualizes the median donation trajectories for the different steps, andFigure</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Error Bars Represent the Interquartile Range.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 9 WTD</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Distribution for the Full Scope in Study 3. Grey area indicates empirical density. Black lines indicate empirical medians. Red lines indicate posterior medians (i.e., the median of the posterior distribution for this parameter). SUAI is for SUA with increase per step constant.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Contingency Valuation Distribution for the FullScope in Study 4. Grey area indicates empirical density. Black lines indicate empirical medians. Red lines indicate posterior medians (i.e., the median of the posterior distribution for this parameter)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>= brm(bf(WTD ∼ Experiment..Pilot., center = FALSE), data = data, iter = 10000, warmup = 2000, chains = 4, cores = 12, thin = 2, refresh = 0, family = lognormal(), prior = c(prior(normal(0.4, 0.4), class = "b"), prior(normal(3, 1), class = "b", coef = "Intercept"), prior(normal(1,0.5), class = "sigma") ), save_all_pars = T) #H0 data.brms0 = brm(bf(WTD ∼ 1, center = FALSE), data = data, iter = 10000, warmup = 2000, chains = 4, cores = 12, thin = 2, refresh = 0, family = lognormal(), prior = c(prior(normal(3, 1), class = "b", coef = "Intercept"), prior(normal(1, 0.5), class = "sigma") ), save_all_pars = T)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>participants are more likely to keep increasing their donations, and which are more likely to drop out? One hypothesis is that participants that donate more for one child are more likely to drop out later, as they are more likely to run out of money.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Share of Participants Showing a Strong monotonic Increase in Scope 10,000 SUAI</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">(Increase per Step Constant) Condition and Scope 100 SUA Condition.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Step</cell><cell cols="2">SUA -maximum Scope 100 SUAI -maximum Scope 10,000</cell></row><row><cell>→ 2</cell><cell>52%</cell><cell>43%</cell></row><row><cell>2 → 5</cell><cell>53%</cell><cell>42%</cell></row><row><cell>5 → 10</cell><cell>45%</cell><cell>34%</cell></row><row><cell>10 → 20</cell><cell>33%</cell><cell>24%</cell></row><row><cell>20 → 50</cell><cell>36%</cell><cell>19%</cell></row><row><cell>50 → 100</cell><cell>31%</cell><cell>18%</cell></row><row><cell>100 → 200</cell><cell></cell><cell>19%</cell></row><row><cell>200 → 500</cell><cell></cell><cell>20%</cell></row><row><cell>500 → 1000</cell><cell></cell><cell>19%</cell></row><row><cell>1000 → 2000</cell><cell></cell><cell>11%</cell></row><row><cell>2000 → 5000</cell><cell></cell><cell>15%</cell></row><row><cell>5000 →10,000</cell><cell></cell><cell>15%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Which kinds of</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The study was uploaded between the fourth and sixth of November 2021, targeting US participants via Positly. Initially, 574 participants signed up, no participants were excluded by age, and none failed the attention check. The mean age was 40.31 (sd = 12.62). 289 participants were female, 279 were male, and 6 reported 'other'.To test the research questions, we used several combinations of Asking Type and Scope. Unless otherwise indicated, and unlike in Studies 1 and 2, participants were not informed of the maximum scope in advance. Participants were randomly assigned into one of the following conditions (with the exact sequence of steps stated in parentheses):</figDesc><table><row><cell>Experimental Conditions</cell></row><row><cell>1. Scope 10 x CUA (1, 10)</cell></row><row><cell>2. Scope 50 x CUA (1, 50)</cell></row><row><cell>3. Scope 10 x SUA (1, 2, 5, 10)</cell></row><row><cell>4. Scope 50 x SUA -number of steps constant (1, 4, 15, 50)</cell></row><row><cell>5. Scope 10 x SUA (1, 2, 5, 10) [participants know maximum scope when answering first</cell></row><row><cell>question]</cell></row><row><cell>6. Scope 50 x SUA -number of steps constant (1, 4, 15, 50) [participants know</cell></row><row><cell>maximum scope when answering first question]</cell></row><row><cell>7. Scope 50 x SUAI -increase per step constant (1, 2, 5, 10, 20, 50)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Does SUA Make Participants More Scope Sensitive Than CUA?</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>just)</cell></row><row><cell>significant in favor of SUA (W = 9159, p = .047). When instead comparing SUAI (increase</cell></row><row><cell>per step constant, 1 &amp;2 vs 3 &amp; 7) to CUA we find weak evidence for a difference: Bayesian</cell></row><row><cell>analysis: BF 10 = 2.68, Frequentist analysis: W = 9919.5, p = .018. Note, however, that we</cell></row><row><cell>preregistered to use SUA (number of steps constant) to test RQ2.</cell></row><row><cell>RQ3: For the interaction between Asking Type (SUA [number of steps constant] vs.</cell></row><row><cell>CUA) and Scope (10 vs. 50; i.e., 1 &amp; 2 vs 3 &amp; 4), we find no evidence that SUA increases</cell></row><row><cell>scope consistency in comparison to CUA (BF 10 = 1.17). When instead testing this</cell></row><row><cell>interaction using SUAI (increase per step constant; i.e., 1 &amp; 2 vs. 3 &amp; 7), we find weak</cell></row><row><cell>evidence that SUAI increases scope consistency in comparison to CUA (BF 10 = 2.48). This</cell></row></table><note>SUA Increase WTD Judgements Over CUA? Comparing SUA (number of steps constant) to CUA (1 &amp; 2 vs. 3 &amp; 4), we find no evidence for or against an effect of SUA (BF 10 = 0.99). 12 The Wilcoxon test is (finding is partially in line with a non-parametric interaction test, which shows no evidence</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The study was uploaded on the 10th of February, 2023 via Positly. Initially, 567 participants signed up, 1 participant was excluded because they did not indicate their age, and 28 failed the attention check (a question asking how many children were in the kindergarten). The mean age of participants was 41.26 (sd = 11.77) with 268 being female, 265 male, and 5 reporting 'other'.</figDesc><table><row><cell>(SEQUENTIAL) UNIT ASKING</cell><cell>38</cell></row><row><cell>study. Experimental Conditions</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">To test the preregistered research questions, we randomly assigned participants to</cell></row><row><cell>one of the following combinations of Asking Type and Scope:</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1. Scope 10 x DA (10)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2. Scope 50 x DA (50)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>3. Scope 10 x CUA (1, 10)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>4. Scope 50 x CUA (1,50)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1. Does Classical Unit Asking (CUA) increase judgements over Direct Asking (DA)? 5. Scope 10 x SUA (1, 2, 5, 10)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2. Does Sequential Unit Asking (SUA) increase judgements over CUA? 6. Scope 50 x SUA -number of steps constant (1, 4, 15, 50)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>3. Which asking techniques induce scope sensitivity? 7. Scope 50 x SUAI -increase per step constant (1, 2, 5, 10, 20, 50)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>4. Does CUA make participants more scope sensitive than DA?</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>5. Does SUA make participants more scope sensitive than CUA?</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Method</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Participants</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">This study was approved by the Ethics Chair for the Department of Experimental</cell></row><row><cell>Psychology, UCL (Project ID No: EP/2022/001) and preregistered at</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">https://osf.io/abcd12. Participants were paid $0.46 for their participation in a 2.5-minute</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Bayesian analysis BF 10 = 4.16, frequentist analysis, F (1, 294) = 4.31, p = .039) 15 , while for the increase per step constant condition we find strong evidence for this effect (interaction of Conditions 3 &amp; 4 vs 5 &amp; 7; Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 36.05, frequentist analysis: F (1, 297) = 12.915, p &lt; .001)</figDesc><table><row><cell>843, p &lt; .001.</cell></row><row><cell>• CUA (Conditions 3 vs 4): Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 2.48 × 10 6 ; frequentist analysis:</cell></row><row><cell>W = 1186.5, p &lt; .001.</cell></row><row><cell>We find evidence against the hypothesis that CUA makes participants more scope</cell></row><row><cell>sensitive than DA (interaction of Conditions 1 &amp; 2 vs 3 &amp; 4; Bayesian analysis: BF 10 =</cell></row><row><cell>0.32, fequentist analysis: F (1, 298) = 0.33, p = 0.564).</cell></row><row><cell>RQ5: Does SUA Make Participants More Scope Sensitive Than CUA?</cell></row><row><cell>For the number of steps constant condition, we find moderate evidence that SUA</cell></row><row><cell>makes participants more scope sensitive than CUA (interaction of Conditions 3 &amp; 4 vs 5 &amp;</cell></row><row><cell>6;</cell></row></table><note>• SUA (Conditions 5 vs 6): Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 1.59 × 10 15 ; frequentist analysis: W = 771.5, p &lt; .001 • SUA (increase per step constant; Conditions 5 vs 7): Bayesian analysis: BF 10 = 1.82 × 10 16 ; frequentist analysis: W = 724, p &lt; .001 RQ4: Does CUA Make Participants More Scope Sensitive Than DA?</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table Summary of</head><label>Summary</label><figDesc>Results Across All Four Studies</figDesc><table><row><cell>Study</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Evidence</cell><cell>Evidence</cell><cell>Evidence</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(Median)</cell><cell>(Median)</cell><cell>(Median)</cell><cell>for SUA</cell><cell>for Scope</cell><cell>for Scope</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>DA</cell><cell>CUA</cell><cell>SUA</cell><cell>over CUA</cell><cell>Sensitivity</cell><cell>Sensitivity</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>CUA</cell><cell>SUA</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Donation Judgements</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Study 1a</cell><cell>$27.36</cell><cell>$81.13</cell><cell>$177.58</cell><cell>+ + +</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>N/A</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>($10)</cell><cell>($20)</cell><cell>($50)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Study 1b</cell><cell>$42.14</cell><cell>$72.70</cell><cell>$231.01</cell><cell>+ + +</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>N/A</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>($20)</cell><cell>($25)</cell><cell>($50)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Study 2</cell><cell>$85.92</cell><cell>$136.74</cell><cell>$257.01</cell><cell>+ + +</cell><cell>−</cell><cell>−</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>($10)</cell><cell>($25)</cell><cell>($50)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Study 3</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>$86.36</cell><cell>$97.27</cell><cell>−</cell><cell>−−</cell><cell>−</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>($30)</cell><cell>($50)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Contingent Valuation Judgements</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Study 4</cell><cell>$479.34</cell><cell>$637.97</cell><cell>$627.77</cell><cell>−</cell><cell>+ + +</cell><cell>+ + +  *</cell></row><row><cell>(Scope 10)</cell><cell>($300)</cell><cell>($500)</cell><cell>($500)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Study 4</cell><cell>$1853.51</cell><cell>$1697.73</cell><cell>$2059.93</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>(Scope 50)</cell><cell>($1000)</cell><cell>($1000)</cell><cell>($1375)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table D1</head><label>D1</label><figDesc>Median WTD judgements For The Seven Conditions of Study 2 Note. * SUA scaling up with increase per step constant.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">Condition Scope Median % Donating</cell></row><row><cell>DA</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>$15</cell><cell>36.59</cell></row><row><cell>CUA</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>$40.0</cell><cell>17.28</cell></row><row><cell>SUA</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>$79.0</cell><cell>14.81</cell></row><row><cell>DA</cell><cell cols="2">10,000 $30.0</cell><cell>30.00</cell></row><row><cell>CUA</cell><cell cols="2">10,000 $50.0</cell><cell>23.75</cell></row><row><cell>SUA</cell><cell cols="2">10,000 $75.0</cell><cell>15.19</cell></row><row><cell>SUAI *</cell><cell cols="2">10,000 $50.0</cell><cell>27.85</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table D2</head><label>D2</label><figDesc>Median WTD judgements For The Seven Conditions of Study 3 Note. * SUA scaling up with increase per step constant.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Condition Scope</cell><cell cols="2">Median % Donating</cell></row><row><cell>CUA</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>$50.0</cell><cell>9.76</cell></row><row><cell>SUA</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>$50.0</cell><cell>15.48</cell></row><row><cell>SUA</cell><cell cols="2">10 &amp; scope known $50.0</cell><cell>11.39</cell></row><row><cell>CUA</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>$40.0</cell><cell>8.43</cell></row><row><cell>SUA</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>$50.0</cell><cell>14.63</cell></row><row><cell>SUA</cell><cell cols="2">50 &amp; scope known $50.0</cell><cell>10.84</cell></row><row><cell>SUAI *</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>$75.0</cell><cell>14.81</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Because of the extreme brevity of the task, we did not add an attention check in this study. However, we added an attention check in Study 3, finding that it led to no additional exclusions.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">We initially preregistered to also look at an ANOVA interaction in this case; however, we realized that for Scope 100, the two Asking Types do not differ. Therefore, we used a t-test only on Scope 10,000.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">We found strong evidence under the preregistered model.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">Only 2.37 without the exclusions.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3"> vs. 4, 3 vs. 7, and 5 vs. 6). We found moderate evidence that participants donate the same for 50 vs. 10 individuals for CUA (BF 10 = 0.29). For SUA, we compared the Scope 10 condition to the Scope 50 condition (number of steps constant) and the Scope 50 condition (increase per step constant). We found no evidence for either the null or alternative hypothesis for the number of steps constant comparison (BF 10 = 0.86). For the</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="14">Only weak evidence when not excluding donations larger than 10 000, BF 10 = 2.5415 Without the exclusion of donations larger 10,000 BF 10 = 2.93, frequentist analysis, F (1, 294) = 2.63, p = .106</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Step-by-Step Guide to the Bayesian Analysis This Appendix contains a step-by -tep guide to the Bayesian Analysis executed in this paper, including R code. All anlyses use R version 4.1.2, and the packages brms version</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coherent arbitrariness&quot;: Stable demand curves without stable preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Prelec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/00335530360535153</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/00335530360535153" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determinants of insensitivity to quantity in valuation of public goods: Contribution, warm glow, budget constraints, availability, and prominence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/1076-898X.2.2.107</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/1076-898X.2.2.107" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">107</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Words and deeds of generosity: Are decisions about real and hypothetical money really different? https</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bekkers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">brms: An R package for Bayesian multilevel models using Stan</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-C</forename><surname>Bürkner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18637/jss.v080.i01</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v080.i01" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advanced Bayesian multilevel modeling with the R package brms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-C</forename><surname>Bürkner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.32614/RJ-2018-017</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.32614/RJ-2018-017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The R Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="411" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of financial incentives in experiments: A review and capital-labor-production framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hogarth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1007850605129</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1007850605129" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Escaping affect: How motivated emotion regulation creates insensitivity to mass suffering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cameron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1007850605129</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1007850605129" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring natural resource damages with contingent valuation: Tests of validity and reliability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Desvousges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Dunford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Boyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Contributions to Economic Analysis</title>
		<editor>B. H. Baltagi &amp; F. Moscore</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valuations of human lives: Normative expectations and psychological mechanisms of (ir) rationality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dickert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11229-012-0137-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11229-012-0137-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthese</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">189</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scope insensitivity: The limits of intuitive valuation of human lives in public policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dickert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jarmac.2014.09.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jarmac.2014.09.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Research in Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Haldane&apos;s contribution to the Bayes factor hypothesis test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Etz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1214/16-STS599</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1214/16-STS599" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistical Science</title>
		<editor>J. B. S</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="329" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fechner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Elemente der psychophysik</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1860" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Breitkopf u. Härtel</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A tutorial on bridge sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gronau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sarafoglou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Matzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Leslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Forster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Steingroever</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2017.09.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmp.2017.09.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bridgesampling: An r package for estimating normalizing constants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gronau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Singmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.48550/arXiv.1710.08162</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1710.08162" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experimental practices in economics: A methodological challenge for psychologists?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ortmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X01004149</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X01004149" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="403" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unit asking: A method to boost donations and beyond</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1801" to="1808" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797613482947</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797613482947" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jeffreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theory of probability</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1939" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1st ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jeffreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theory of probability</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valuing public goods: The purchase of moral satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Knetsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Environmental Economics and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0095-0696(92)90019-S</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0095-0696(92" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">90019</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic preferences or attitude expressions?: An analysis of dollar responses to public issues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ritov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schkade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Varian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="242" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1007835629236</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1007835629236" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unit Asking-a method for increasing donations: A replication and extension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Karlsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hellström</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Moche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1930297500008184</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1930297500008184" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="989" to="993" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/01621459.1995.10476572</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/01621459.1995.10476572" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="795" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rfit: Rank-based estimation for linear models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kloke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Mckean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of R</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">57</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian cognitive modeling: A practical course</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diagnosing Insensitivity to Scope in Contingent Valuation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Lopes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kipperberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Environmental and Resource Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="191" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10640-020-00470-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10640-020-00470-9" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing the fundamental assumption of choice experiments: Are values absolute or relative</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Luisetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bateman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Land Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="284" to="296" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Increasing charitable donations: The limits of the unit asking effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Unpublished Master Thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcelreath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Statistical rethinking: A Bayesian course with examples in R and Stan</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Utilitarianism. Fraser&apos;s Magazine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Mill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1879" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teaching Bayes&apos; theorem: Strength of evidence as predictive accuracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rouder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Morey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Statistician</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="186" to="190" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00031305.2017.1341334</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/00031305.2017.1341334" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sure-thing vs. probabilistic charitable giving: Experimental evidence on the role of individual differences in risky and ambiguous charitable decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Schoenegger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Costa-Gomes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0273971</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0273971" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A New Way To Increase Charitable Donations: Does It Replicate?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Simmons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://datacolada.org/2013/10/02/3-a-new-way-to-increase-charitable-donations-does-it-replicate/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affect, moral intuition, and risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/1047840X.2010.521119</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/1047840X.2010.521119" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="398" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sympathy and callousness: The impact of deliberative thought on donations to identifiable and statistical victims</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Small</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="153" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.obhdp.2006.01.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.obhdp.2006.01.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical challenges and methodological flexibility in prior elicitation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Stefan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/met0000354</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/met0000354" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="197" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Framing charitable donations as exceptional expenses increases giving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sussman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Alter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xap0000047</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xap0000047" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">130</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental accounting and consumer choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mksc.4.3.199</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mksc.4.3.199" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental accounting matters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing the transitivity of reported risk perceptions: Evidence of coherent arbitrariness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Loughran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1745-9125.12154</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1745-9125.12154" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Criminology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A psychological perspective on charitable giving and monetary donations: The role of affect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-45500-2_14</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-45500-2_14" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Psychological perspectives on financial decision making</title>
		<editor>T. Zaleskiewicz &amp; J. Traczyk</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="331" to="345" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical bayesian model evaluation using leave-one-out cross-validation and waic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gabry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistical Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1413" to="1432" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scope insensitivity in contingent valuation of complex environmental amenities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Veisten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Hoen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Navrud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Strand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jenvman.2004.07.008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2004.07.008" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Environmental Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="317" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian thinking for toddlers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian benefits for the pragmatic researcher</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Morey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0963721416643289</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0963721416643289" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On certain fundamental principles of scientific inquiry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wrinch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jeffreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14786442108633773</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14786442108633773" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Magazine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="390" />
			<date type="published" when="1921" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">rstan version 2.21.3, and BayesFactor version 0.9.12. This Appendix is merely intended as a conceptual explanation for the most important parts of the R code; for a more general accessible introductions to Bayesian statistics, see Wagenmakers (2020) and Wagenmakers</title>
		<idno>2.16.3</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Step 1: Testing Whether Proportion of Participants Donating in the First Place is Affected After reading in the data (and excluding participants that failed attention checks</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Control&quot;)$WTD) &gt; 0), sum(na.omit(subset(data, Experiment..Pilot. == &quot;Control&quot;)$WTD) == 0), sum(na.omit(subset(data, Experiment</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Pilot. == &quot;Intervention1&quot;)$WTD) &gt; 0), sum(na.omit(subset(data, Experiment..Pilot. == &quot;Intervention1&quot;)$WTD) == 0), sum(na.omit(subset(data, Experiment..Pilot. == &quot;Intervention2&quot;)$WTD) &gt; 0), sum(na.omit</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>#Construct Matrix of Counts counts &lt;-c(sum(na.omit(subset(data, Experiment..Pilot. ==. subset(data, Experiment..Pilot. == &quot;Intervention2&quot;)$WTD) == 0)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">#Check whether it depends on the manipulation BayesFactor::contingencyTableBF(counts, sampleType = &quot;jointMulti</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
