<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<title level="a" type="main">SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:39+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>teleology</term>
					<term>intentional stance</term>
					<term>intuition</term>
					<term>dual-process theory</term>
					<term>implicit belief</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>This research did not receive any specific grant from funding agencies in the public, commercial, or not-for-profit sectors. We have no conflicts of interest to disclose. Data and code for analysis are stored on OSF and can be accessed at the following URL: https://osf.io/pw7vm/?view_only=ac540355ec00438e89b4fc841a386179. This link has been anonymised for the peer review process.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Why are you reading this article? You might answer this question by referring to a series of events in your past which culminated in an interest in teleological reasoning or speeded decision-making tasks. Another possible answer is that you are reading this article to learn whether speeded decision-making can reveal tacit teleological tendencies. Whereas the former is a causal explanation about teleology, the latter is a teleological explanation about teleology. Put simply, teleological explanations are those in which something is explained with reference to a function, outcome, or goal <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hempel &amp; Oppenheim, 1948)</ref>.</p><p>Teleological reasoning is commonly used to explain the actions of intentional agents (as in the example above), the existence of human-made artefacts (e.g., "pens exist for writing"), and sometimes controversially (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dennett, 2017)</ref>, biological traits (e.g., "birds have wings in order to fly"). For intentional action and the existence of human-made artefacts, teleological reasoning is appropriate because both can be explained with reference to the intentions of an agent. If an agent creates a pen with the intention that this device will allow him or her to write, then that pen exists for writing. In the case of biological traits, teleological reasoning is appropriate not because of intentional action, but because of the consequence aetiology of natural selection <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Dennett, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Lombrozo &amp; Carey, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Wright, 1976)</ref>. That is, "birds have wings in order to fly", because the function of flight resulted in fitness advantages for those creatures with ancient wing-like structures. The function that wings serve, is the very reason for their current existence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">Intention-Based Teleology</head><p>Teleological reasoning is sometimes used to explain things which cannot be attributed to the actions of an intentional agent or the consequence aetiology of natural selection.</p><p>According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kelemen (1999a)</ref> all teleological reasoning is psychologically based in the application of an intentional stance <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Dennett, 1987)</ref>. This intention-based theory of teleology SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 4 posits that from an early age, an intentional stance is applied beyond the domain of explaining intentional action. This is similar to the idea that the actual domain of a modular cognitive process extends beyond the module's proper domain (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Atran &amp; Norenzayan, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Boyer, 1994)</ref> 1 . Just as the application of an intentional stance to its proper domain results in a teleological explanation (e.g., "she crossed the road in order to get to the other side"), the application of this stance beyond its proper domain also results in a teleological explanation (e.g., "the computer crashed in order to annoy me"). As teleological beliefs are said to be based in the application of this early-developing predictive strategy, according to <ref type="bibr">Kelemen</ref>, people often hold teleological beliefs even when the actions of an intentional agent are lacking. One domain of teleological reasoning that has received considerable attention, is the function-based explanation of biological and nonbiological natural entities (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kelemen, 1999c;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Willard et al., 2020)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.1.">Non-Experimental Evidence for Intention-Based Teleology</head><p>Teleological explanations such as "rivers flow downstream in order to get to the ocean", or "trees produce oxygen so that animals can breathe", tend to be accepted by children to a greater extent than adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kelemen, 1999b)</ref>. However, under certain circumstances, adults also display high levels of acceptance for such teleological explanations. Rates of teleological acceptance in adults are positively correlated with anthropomorphism <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">White et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Willard et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Willard &amp; Norenzayan, 2013)</ref> and belief in God <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kelemen &amp; Diyanni, 2005</ref>), suggesting that 1 Although a discussion of modularity is beyond the scope of the current paper, there are many accessible sources on this topic (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Grossi, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Kurzban, 2010)</ref>. Modularity theory posits that certain neural circuits are domain specific <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Fodor, 1983)</ref>. That is, cognitive modules selectively respond to certain stimuli in the environment. By the proper domain of a module, we mean the class of stimuli that a given cognitive process evolved "in response to" (e.g., a face detection module afforded fitness advantages to organisms with this neural circuit by allowing them to recognise faces of conspecifics). By the actual domain of a module, we mean all the stimuli to which a given cognitive process responds to (e.g., a face detection module may respond to masks because masks resemble faces). SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 5 teleological reasoning is facilitated by notions of intentionality (whether to the natural world itself or to an intending designer). However, even non-religious individuals display evidence of teleological beliefs about biological and nonbiological natural entities <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Järnefelt et al., 2015)</ref>, supporting the view that such beliefs represent somewhat of a default mode of explanation.</p><p>Convergent non-experimental evidence also suggests that when people lack an alternative causal explanation, or that when access to the cognitive resources needed to inhibit intuitions is limited, people tend to be more accepting of teleological explanations about biological and non-biological natural entities. Evidence for this claim comes from studies showing increased teleological acceptance in 1) Alzheimer's patients relative to agematched controls <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Lombrozo et al., 2007)</ref>; 2) individuals with low levels of formal education relative to those with high levels of formal education <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Casler &amp; Kelemen, 2008)</ref>; and 3) children relative to adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kelemen, 1999b)</ref>. Further non-experimental evidence comes from the negative relationship between performance on the Cognitive Reflection Test (CRT) and rates of acceptance for teleological explanations about biological and non-biological natural entities <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Zemla et al., 2012)</ref>. Each item in the CRT is designed to elicit an intuitively appealing, yet incorrect response (e.g., "if you are running a race and you pass the person in second place, what place are you in?"). In this example, the intuitive response is "first place", but the correct response is "second place". As performance on the CRT requires an individual to inhibit the intuitive response, the negative relationship between CRT performance and rates of teleological acceptance has been taken as evidence that compared to low-scoring CRT participants, high-scoring CRT participants may simply be better at inhibiting their teleological intuitions. SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 6</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.2.">Experimental Evidence for Intention-Based Teleology</head><p>Experimental evidence for the claim that adults find teleological explanations about biological and nonbiological natural entities compelling, comes from the use of speeded vs.</p><p>un-speeded decision-making tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Mills &amp; Frowley, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref>. In this paradigm, participants are allocated to either a speeded or un-speeded condition and are asked to respond "true" or "false" <ref type="bibr">(or "yes" or "no")</ref> to a series of teleological test statements and control statements. In the speeded condition, participants typically have either 3200ms <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Mills &amp; Frowley, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref> or 5000ms <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Mills &amp; Frowley, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Rottman et al., 2017)</ref> to respond to each statement 2 . The logic behind using a speeded decision-making paradigm in the study of tacit teleological tendencies, is based in dual-process theories of reasoning (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">De Neys, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Evans &amp; Stanovich, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pennycook et al., 2015)</ref>. As time-pressure limits the opportunity to reflect upon and inhibit an initial response, responses in the speeded condition are thought to provide an indication of pre-reflective belief <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013)</ref>. Consistent with the non-experimental evidence, studies employing this paradigm have reported significantly greater teleological acceptance in the speeded condition compared to the un-speeded condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.3.">Problems with Speeded Decision-Making</head><p>Despite the consistency between experimental and non-experimental evidence, a potential problem with the speeded vs. un-speeded paradigm, as it is commonly used, is that it may lead to selection bias. Inclusion criteria vary across studies, but participants in both conditions are typically required to respond correctly to a certain percentage of control statements, ranging from just 25% correct <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009)</ref>, to over 80% correct <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref>. Additionally, participants in the speeded condition are required to answer a certain percentage of test statements within the time limit, ranging from 25% <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009)</ref>, to over 75% <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref>. These inclusion criteria can result in a higher rate of exclusion in the speeded condition compared to the un-speeded condition. For example, despite <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al. (2020)</ref> allocating 138 participants to either a speeded or un-speeded condition at a ratio of 1.5 (speeded): 1 (un-speeded), only 34 participants in the speeded condition and 54 in the unspeeded condition met the inclusion criteria. The different rates of exclusion mean it is possible that the participants vary systematically in certain ways between the two conditions.</p><p>As mentioned previously, there is a negative relationship between CRT performance and rates of teleological acceptance in the absence of time pressure <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Zemla et al., 2012)</ref>. Given that each question on the CRT is designed to elicit an intuitively appealing incorrect answer, performance on the CRT requires an individual to first inhibit their intuitions, and to then reflect to produce the correct response. This leads to two possibilities regarding the relationship between CRT performance and inclusion in the decision-making task. If high-scoring CRT participants are more likely to pause and reflect before providing an answer, this could lead to the systematic exclusion of these individuals in the speeded condition if they fail to answer a sufficient percentage of test statements within the time-limit. Due to the negative relationship between CRT performance and teleological acceptance, excluding high-scoring CRT participants in the speeded condition could artificially increase rates of teleological acceptance in this condition. However, it is also conceivable that high-scoring CRT participants may be better able to answer quickly when under time pressure to respond. As such, this could lead to the systematic exclusion of lowscoring CRT participants in the speeded condition, thereby artificially decreasing rates of teleological acceptance in this condition. Either of these possibilities would be problematic SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 8 for the claim that speeded decision-making can provide an accurate assessment of tacit teleological tendencies.</p><p>While the finding of increased teleological acceptance in the speeded compared to unspeeded condition appears to be robust <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020</ref>; but see <ref type="bibr">Liquin &amp; Lombrozo, 2018 -study 5)</ref>, this alone is not evidence of tacit teleological tendencies. The claim that this paradigm provides evidence of such tacit tendencies, rests on the idea that the difference in responses between conditions is due to the speeded condition limiting the opportunity to inhibit reflective thought. However, in this paradigm, participants also respond to a series of objectively false and objectively true control statements in either condition. As such, unless we are also willing to concede that speeded decision-making provides evidence of implicit belief in things that are objectively false (e.g., "people smoke cigarettes in order to get lung cancer"), or evidence of implicit disbelief in things that are objectively true (e.g., "doctors prescribe antibiotics in order to treat infections"), the effect of time pressure must be greater for teleological test statements than for control statements.</p><p>At present, there is little evidence to suggest that the effect of time pressure is greater for teleological test statements than for control statements. This is not necessarily due to the absence of such evidence in the data, but rather, due to the ways in which results have been reported, and to the slight differences in procedures across studies. For example, by presenting groups of participants with statements on an overhead screen for varying durations (un-speeded; moderately-speeded, 5000ms; and fast-speeded, 3200ms) and asking them to respond by ticking boxes on an answer sheet, studies have found an effect of speed on response accuracy for certain teleological statements <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Mills &amp; Frowley, 2014)</ref>. When looking at control statement accuracy, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Kelemen and Rosset (2009)</ref> found that un-speeded participants were significantly less accurate than the other groups SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 9 (Study One), although this effect failed to replicate in a second study (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Mills &amp; Frowley, 2014)</ref>. However, given the manipulation of speed in these studies involved participants being presented with statements on an overhead screen and responding by ticking boxes on an answer sheet, it was possible for participants to respond after the statements had disappeared from the screen. Therefore, it may not be so surprising that using this procedure, participants were still highly accurate in responding to control statements in the speeded conditions.</p><p>A more rigorous approach has been to use computerised tasks to limit not only the duration of presentation, but also the response window. Using this approach, studies have found an interaction between condition (un-speeded, speeded) and statement-type accuracy (teleological, control). However, the way in which this interaction has been reported does not necessarily provide evidence of tacit teleological tendencies. Using the speeded vs. unspeeded paradigm to investigate the teleological beliefs of professional scientists, <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Kelemen et al. (2013)</ref> found a larger mean difference between conditions for test statements (14% difference) than control statements (3% difference). Similarly, using an undergraduate sample, <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al. (2020)</ref> found a larger mean difference between conditions for test statements (18.9% difference) than control statements (3.5% difference). Such results have also been replicated in a Chinese adult sample <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Rottman et al., 2017)</ref>, with a larger mean difference between conditions for test statements (14% difference) than control statements (6% difference). Examination of the descriptive statistics in these studies show that although the mean differences were indeed larger for test statements than for control statements, since control statements tend to be answered quite accurately, the variation in responses was also larger for test statements than for control statements. As measures of effect size take account of not only a difference in means, but also some component of error variance (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Lakens, 2013</ref>), a greater mean difference in response accuracy between conditions for test statements SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 10 than for control statements, does not necessarily equate to a larger effect size for the former than for the latter.</p><p>Finally, even if it can be shown that speeded decision-making has a greater effect on test statement accuracy than on control statement accuracy, this would still not necessarily provide evidence of implicit teleological beliefs. As placing participants under cognitive load has been shown to increase yea-saying <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Knowles &amp; Condon, 1999)</ref>, it is possible that speeded decision-making merely increases the likelihood of accepting statements as true. As the control statements used in the previously mentioned studies describe things which are objectively true or false, when presented without a time-limit, they tend to be accepted at close to ceiling and floor levels, respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021)</ref>. If speeded decisionmaking does increase the likelihood of accepting statements as true, then comparing test statement accuracy to the aggregate of all control statements may be problematic, as the true control statements could reduce the difference in accuracy between conditions for control statements as a whole. As teleological test statements describe beliefs that adults are hypothesised to inhibit, a stronger test of the hypothesis that speeded decision-making can uncover tacit teleological tendencies, would be to compare the effect of time pressure for teleological test statements relative to control statements that are objectively false. To provide evidence of tacit teleological tendencies, this paradigm must be able to demonstrate that the effect of time pressure for test statements is significantly greater than the effect of time pressure for false control statements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">Current Studies</head><p>In summary, there are three key issues in studies that have used the speeded vs. un- responses to teleological test statements to the aggregate of all control statements (i.e., those which are objectively false and those which are objectively true), may obscure differences in accuracy between conditions. In the current two studies, we aimed to explore these issues and determine whether the speeded decision-making paradigm provides evidence of tacit teleological tendencies. These studies were approved by the [BLINDED] University Human Research Ethics Committee (protocol number <ref type="bibr">[BLINDED]</ref>), under the project titled "The Intentional Stance and Teleological Endorsement".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Study One</head><p>In Study One, we sought to explore the issues raised above using a large online sample. First, we investigated whether the typical speeded vs. un-speeded paradigm results in selection bias. Due to the higher expected rate of exclusion in the speeded condition compared to the un-speeded condition, and due to the additional inclusion criterion and greater difficulty of the task in the former, we predicted that participants who met inclusion criteria in the speeded condition would differ significantly in their ability to inhibit intuitions relative to participants who did not meet inclusion criteria in this condition. Second, we investigated whether the speeded vs. un-speeded paradigm provides evidence of a dissociation between implicit and explicit teleological beliefs. If implicit teleological beliefs are truly driving the effects of interest, then the effect of time pressure should be greater for teleological test statements than for control statements. Specifically, any increase in rates of acceptance for teleological test statements under time pressure, should not be attributable to acceptance of statements that are objectively false. The preregistration for Study One can be accessed at https://osf.io/v83zm/?view_only=c9f406b1bf5d4f8e9cb5bf6a96301de1. SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 12 2.1. Methods</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1.">Participants</head><p>An international pool of 273 native English-speakers were recruited through the online service, Prolific. This sample size was chosen based on previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013)</ref> and taking into consideration the expected high rate of exclusion in the speeded condition. Participants received payment of £2.22 for taking part in an online study that took approximately 15 minutes to complete. As we aimed to investigate whether inclusion in the speeded condition varied systematically with the tendency to inhibit intuitions, and as highly educated individuals tend to be both less teleological <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013)</ref> and more analytical <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Purcell et al., 2020)</ref>, only individuals with formal educational qualifications no higher than an undergraduate university degree were eligible to participate. Before exclusion, the sample consisted of 92 atheists, 64 agnostics, 111 Christians 3 , 5 Muslims, and 1 Jew.</p><p>Ages ranged from 16 to 73 (M = 32.77, SD = 13.37), with 141 females, 130 males, and two non-binary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2.">Materials</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2.1.">Teleological Beliefs Scale. Participants completed the Teleological Beliefs</head><p>Scale (TBS: <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Roberts et al., 2021)</ref> which measures teleological beliefs about biological and non-biological natural entities. The TBS contains 98 statements across six categories: biological teleological test (n = 14; e.g., "Plants consume CO2 in order to reduce greenhouse gases"), non-biological teleological test (n = 14; e.g., "The Earth has a moon in order to control the tides"), false causal (n = 25; e.g., "Pebbles have rounded edges because they are little"), false teleological (n = 10; e.g., "Houses have doorbells in order to make dogs bark"), true causal (n = 25; e.g., "Fireworks explode because gunpowder ignites when a fuse is lit"), and true teleological (n = 10; e.g., "Alarm clocks beep in order to wake people up"). In the current study, we collapsed both categories of test statements, both categories of false control statements, and both categories of true control statements. Participants responded "true" or "false" to each statement, and a total score for each category was calculated as the proportion of statements endorsed. The teleological test statements displayed good internal consistency (α = .894).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2.2.">Attributions of Intentionality. To replicate findings of teleological beliefs</head><p>about biological and non-biological natural entities being positively predicted by attributions of intentionality (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Willard et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Willard &amp; Norenzayan, 2013)</ref>, we included measures of anthropomorphism and religious belief.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2.2.1.">Anthropomorphism. Participants completed the Anthropomorphism</head><p>Questionnaire (AQ: <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Neave et al., 2015)</ref>, which contains 20 items measuring anthropomorphic experiences in childhood (e.g., "When I was a child, I held birthday parties for my favourite toys") and adulthood (e.g., "I sometimes feel that the sea can be angry"). Each item is scored on a scale from 0 (Not at all) to 6 (Very much so). A total score is obtained by summing all items, such that scores have a potential range of 0 to 120. Internal consistency for the AQ was excellent (α = .939).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2.2.2.">Religious Belief. Participants completed a reduced version of the Centrality</head><p>of Religiosity Questionnaire (r-CRS: <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Huber &amp; Huber, 2012)</ref>. The full version of the CRS contains 15 items balanced across five subscales: experience (e.g., "How often do you experience situations in which you have the feeling that God or something divine intervenes in your life?"), ideology (e.g., "To what extent do you believe that God or something divine exists?"), intellect (e.g., "How often do you think about religious issues?"), private practise (e.g., "How often do you pray?"), and public practise (e.g., "How often do you take part in SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 14 religious services?"). As belief in God is not necessarily related to a desire to learn about religious topics (intellect subscale) or attendance at religious services (public practise subscale), we used a reduced version of the CRS which contained only the experience, ideology, and private practise subscales <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021)</ref>. Responses to questions about the frequency of personal prayer were scored on a scale from 1 (Never) to 8 (Several times a day) and then later recoded to a five-point scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Huber &amp; Huber, 2012)</ref>. The remaining questions were scored on a scale from 1 (Never/ Not at all) to 5 (Very often/ Very much so).</p><p>A total score is calculated by taking the mean of all items. The r-CRS displayed excellent internal consistency (α = .967).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2.3.">Inhibition of Intuitions.</head><p>To investigate whether the tendency to inhibit intuitions negatively predicted scores on the TBS, and whether participants in the speeded condition were systematically excluded according to their tendency to engage in reflective thought, participants completed an extended version of the Cognitive Reflection Test (CRT).</p><p>The original CRT contains three questions (e.g., "A bat and a ball cost $1.10 in total. The bat costs $1.00 more than the ball. How much does the ball cost?": <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Frederick, 2005</ref>). In the current study, we used slightly re-worded versions of the original three questions (e.g., "The ages of Mark and Adam add up to 28 years. Mark is 20 years older than Adam. How many years old is Adam?"). Additionally, the extended version of the CRT contains four less math focused questions (e.g., "Emily's father has three daughters. The first two are named April and May. What is the third daughter's name?": <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Thomson &amp; Oppenheimer, 2016)</ref>. Each question is designed to elicit an intuitively appealing yet incorrect answer which must be inhibited to produce the correct response. A total score on the CRT is calculated as the number of correct responses, such that scores have a possible range of 0 to 7. The internal consistency of the CRT was acceptable (α = .725). SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 15</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.3.">Procedure</head><p>Participants were provided a link which redirected them to the study which was hosted on Gorilla.sc. After providing informed consent, participants were quasi-randomly assigned to either a speeded or un-speeded condition of the TBS to ensure a balanced design.</p><p>In the un-speeded condition, participants were instructed to "read each statement carefully and respond according to what you believe", whereas in the speeded condition, participants were instructed to "read each statement and respond as quickly and as accurately as possible". Participants responded "true" or "false" to each item by pressing the J or F key, respectively. In the speeded condition, participants had 3200ms in which to respond to each statement in the TBS. If they failed to respond within 3200ms, the next item appeared on the screen. In both conditions, once an item was first presented on the screen, there was a 500ms window in which responses were not recorded. This was both to encourage participants to process the statement, and to ensure that participants in the speeded condition did not begin responding to a statement at 3200ms but make their response once the following item was Consistent with previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref>, participants in either condition were excluded for failing to correctly respond to 80% of control statements, or for failing to respond to 75% of teleological test statements within the time-limit in the speeded condition. In the un-speeded condition, 11 participants failed to meet the inclusion criterion (n = 100), whereas in the speeded condition, 62 participants failed to meet the inclusion criteria (n = 100). The difference in inclusion between conditions was statistically significant χ 2 (1) = 27.00, p &lt; .001. SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 16</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1.">Correlations Between Predictors and Responses on the Teleological Beliefs Scale</head><p>We first explored the relationships between acceptance of teleological explanations about biological and non-biological natural entities, accuracy in responding to control statements that were objectively true or objectively false, and anthropomorphism (AQ), belief in God (r-CRS), and inhibition of intuitions (CRT). As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>, before participant exclusion, anthropomorphism and belief in God displayed weak but significant positive relationships with teleological acceptance, whereas inhibition of intuitions displayed a moderate-to-strong significant negative relationship with teleological acceptance.</p><p>Anthropomorphism and belief in God were weakly and negatively related to false control statement accuracy, whereas inhibition of intuitions had a moderate-to-strong positive relationship with false control statement accuracy. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2.">Inclusion and Exclusion</head><p>Scores on the CRT displayed moderate to strong significant relationships with both teleological acceptance and accuracy for false control statements. As accuracy on control statements was one of inclusion criteria, next we explored whether scores on the predictor variables differed between those who met and those who did not meet the inclusion criteria.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>, there was no significant difference in anthropomorphism between included and excluded participants, t(271) = -0.62, p = .537, d = 0.085. However, compared to excluded participants, those who met inclusion criteria expressed less belief in God, t(271) = -2.44, p = .015, d = 0.334, and were better able to inhibit their intuitions, t(271) = 4.75, p &lt; .001, d = 0.650. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3.">The Effect of Speed on Teleology</head><p>To investigate whether speeded decision-making reveals tacit teleological tendencies, using only participants who met the inclusion criteria, we compared responses to the teleological test statements and control statements between the speeded and un-speeded conditions. If teleological beliefs about biological and non-biological natural entities are a "developmentally persistent cognitive default" <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr">(Kelemen et al., , p. 1075</ref>, and if speeded decision-making can be used as a method for uncovering such beliefs, then time pressure should have a significantly greater effect for teleological test statements than for control statements. To allow for a meaningful comparison of statement types, responses to teleological test statements and false control statements were reverse-coded, such that higher scores represented greater accuracy rather than greater acceptance. We conducted a 2 (condition: speeded, un-speeded) x (3) (statement-type: teleological test, false control, true control) ANOVA with accuracy as the dependent variable.</p><p>The effects of condition, F(1, 198) = 58.49, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .228, and statement-type, F(1, 396) = 606.34, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .754, were both significant, but as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, were qualified by a significant condition by statement-type interaction, F(1, 396) = 13.03, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .062. To explore this interaction, three contrasts were performed in which we compared the difference between conditions on test statement accuracy relative to overall control statement accuracy (contrast 1), test statement accuracy relative to false control statement accuracy (contrast 2), and test statement accuracy relative to true control statement accuracy (contrast 3). Mean accuracies are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>.</p><p>SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 20 198) = 10.99, p = .001, ηρ 2 = .053). However, the effect of time pressure on teleological test statement accuracy was stronger than the effect of time pressure on true control statement accuracy, t(198) = 5.50, p &lt; .001, d = 0.778, and this difference was statistically significant (F(1, 198) = 15.62, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .073). These results suggest that with the inclusion criteria of &gt; 80% accuracy on control statements and &gt; 75% of test statements answered within the time limit, speeded responding has a greater effect on control statement accuracy than on teleological test statement accuracy. This effect was driven by decreased accuracy for false control statements in the speeded condition rather than by changes in teleological endorsement. A possible objection to the previous analysis is that perhaps certain teleological test statements tend to be answered correctly, whereas certain others tend to be answered SPEEDED</p><note type="other">DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 22</note><p>incorrectly. If response latencies differed systematically across statements, then the previous null result could be due to statement-specific variation in latencies. That is, perhaps people are faster to accept than to reject teleological statements about biological and nonbiological natural entities in general, but perhaps the statements in the Teleological Beliefs Scale that people tend to accept, also happen to be those that take longer to process regardless of the response. To rule out this alternative explanation, we repeated the previous paired t-test, but restricted the analysis to statements with a mean accuracy of between 0.4 and 0.6. As before, </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">the</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Discussion</head><p>Study One replicated the previously reported relationships between teleological beliefs about biological and nonbiological natural entities and anthropomorphism <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Willard et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Willard &amp; Norenzayan, 2013)</ref>, belief in God <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kelemen &amp; Diyanni, 2005)</ref>, inhibition of intuitions <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Zemla et al., 2012)</ref>. Specifically, teleological beliefs were positively predicted by anthropomorphism and belief in God, and negatively predicted by the tendency to inhibit intuitions. The negative relationship between inhibition of intuitions and teleological beliefs is particularly important, as this has been taken as evidence that teleological beliefs can be conceptualised within a dual-process framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Zemla et al., 2012)</ref>. According to this view, teleological beliefs about biological and non-biological natural entities are intuitively appealing, and to not express such beliefs, effortful thought must be engaged <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>However, we also found that the tendency to inhibit intuitions was positively related to accuracy in responding to control statements that were objectively false. Given the inclusion criterion of responding to over 80% of control statements correctly, the bivariate relationships highlighted the possibility that participants could be systematically excluded from the task according to their ability to inhibit intuitions.</p><p>As expected, the rate of exclusion in the speeded condition was significantly higher than in the un-speeded condition. Collapsed across conditions, participants who met the inclusion criteria were significantly less religious and significantly better at inhibiting their intuitions. This is problematic, as it demonstrates the systematic exclusion of certain individuals in one condition, but not in the other. The direction of this relationship was such that individuals who tend to express more teleological beliefs are systematically excluded from the speeded condition, thereby potentially resulting in decreased teleological acceptance in this condition. In other words, the exclusion of these individuals from the speeded condition may provide an overly conservative estimate of tacit teleological tendencies.</p><p>However, more fundamentally problematic for claims of speeded decision-making providing evidence for tacit teleological tendencies, was the effect of time pressure on responses to teleological test statements and control statements. The results of Study One showed that the effect of time pressure for teleological test statements, was weaker than the effect of time pressure for control statements on average. Contrast testing revealed that this difference was driven by reduced accuracy when responding to objectively false control statements in the speeded condition. Rather than time pressure uncovering tacit teleological tendencies, this suggests that time pressure increases acceptance of things which are false; of which, it could be argued, teleological explanations about biological and nonbiological natural entities are a part.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 24</head><p>Although the effect of time pressure on control statement accuracy relative to teleological test statement accuracy highlights a methodological issue, examination of response latencies for correctly rejected and incorrectly accepted teleological test statements suggests a problem with theory. The basis for using speeded decision-making to uncover tacit teleological tendencies, is that additional processing, and hence, time, should be required to inhibit the expression of such beliefs. Contrary to these predictions, we found that response latencies for correctly rejected and incorrectly accepted teleological test statements did not differ. Even when restricting our analysis to those statements with a mean acceptance of between 40% and 60%, there was no evidence of a difference in response latencies between correct and incorrect responses on these items. In both cases, Bayesian analyses suggested there was moderate to strong evidence in favour of the null hypothesis of no difference in latencies between correct and incorrect responses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Study Two</head><p>The findings of systematic exclusion in the speeded condition and the comparison of effect sizes rather than absolute differences in means between conditions have not previously been reported in the literature. In Study Two, we sought to replicate the results of Study One using an undergraduate sample. First, we predicted that participants who met inclusion criteria would be significantly better at inhibiting their intuitions compared to participants who did not meet inclusion criteria. Second, we predicted that the effect of time pressure would be significantly greater for false control statements than for teleological test </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2.">Materials</head><p>The materials were identical to Study One.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.3.">Procedure</head><p>The procedure was identical to Study One. In the un-speeded condition, 6 participants failed to meet the inclusion criterion, whereas in the speeded condition, 76 participants failed to meet inclusion criteria. This resulted in a final sample of n = 119 in the un-speeded condition, and n = 49 in the speeded condition. The difference in rates of inclusion between conditions was statistically significant χ 2 (1) = 88.90, p &lt; .001.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1.">Correlations Between Predictors and Responses on the TBS</head><p>As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref>, before participant exclusion, anthropomorphism (AQ) was positively correlated with teleological acceptance, whereas inhibition of intuitions (CRT) was negatively correlated with teleological acceptance. In contrast to Study One, the relationship between belief in God (r-CRS) and teleological acceptance was non-significant.</p><p>Anthropomorphism and belief in God were negatively related to accuracy for false control statements, and inhibition of intuitions was positively related to accuracy for false control statements. Inhibition of intuitions also displayed a weak positive relationship with accuracy for true control statements.</p><p>SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>26</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2.">Inclusion and Exclusion</head><p>The bivariate correlations conceptually replicated the key findings from Study One.</p><p>Performance on the CRT was significantly related not only to teleological acceptance, but to accuracy for control statements. Given the control statement accuracy inclusion criterion, we sought to replicate the finding that inhibition of intuitions varied systematically with inclusion status. As shown in  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3.">The Effect of Speed on Teleology</head><p>Using only participants who met the inclusion criteria, we compared responses to the teleological test statements and control statements between the speeded and un-speeded condition. We conducted a 2 (condition: speeded, un-speeded) x (3) (statement-type: teleological test, false control, true control) ANOVA with accuracy as the dependent variable.</p><p>The effects of condition, F(1, 166) = 58.57, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .261, and statement-type, F(1, 332) = 401.76, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .708, were both highly significant, but as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, were qualified by a significant condition by statement-type interaction, F(1, 332) = 16.38, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .090. To explore this interaction, the same three contrasts were performed as in Study One. Mean accuracies are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 6</ref>.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.4.">Response Latencies</head><p>We next investigated response latencies for correctly rejected and incorrectly accepted teleological test statements. Following the same procedure as Study One, using only the un- </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Discussion</head><p>Using an undergraduate sample, Study Two replicated the key findings from Study</p><p>One. Acceptance of teleological statements about biological and non-biological natural entities was positively related to anthropomorphism and negatively related to inhibition of intuitions. Importantly, the tendency to inhibit intuitions was also positively related to accuracy for false control statements. Rates of exclusion differed significantly between conditions, and participants who met the inclusion criteria were significantly better at inhibiting their intuitions compared to those who did not meet the inclusion criteria. In combination, these results suggest that individuals who are worse at inhibiting their intuitions are disproportionately excluded from the speeded condition.</p><p>Study Two also replicated the finding of speeded decision-making having a significantly greater effect on false control statement accuracy than on teleological test statement accuracy. These findings suggest that the previously reported increase in teleological acceptance in a speeded condition relative to an un-speeded condition (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref>, may be due to increased acceptance of explanations which are objectively false, rather than tacit teleological tendencies. Finally, replicating the findings from Study One, we found that response latencies for correctly rejected and incorrectly accepted teleological test statements did not differ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">General Discussion</head><p>The central claim of an intention-based theory of teleology, is that due to an early developing understanding that intentional agents have purposes, people have a developmentally persistent tendency to explain the world in terms of purpose and function <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kelemen, 1999a)</ref>. While there is convergent non-experimental evidence to support this claim (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Casler &amp; Kelemen, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Lombrozo et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Zemla et al., 2012)</ref>, experimental evidence comes from comparing rates of teleological acceptance in speeded and un-speeded conditions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Mills &amp; Frowley, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref>. Studies employing this paradigm have reported that by limiting the time available to reflect upon beliefs, participants show increased teleological acceptance relative to an unspeeded condition. This difference in teleological acceptance between conditions has been taken as evidence that adults have tacit teleological tendencies.</p><p>Consistent with theoretical <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kelemen, 1999a)</ref> and empirical work <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Willard et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Willard &amp; Norenzayan, 2013)</ref>, we found that teleological beliefs about biological and non-biological natural entities were positively related to anthropomorphism and, in Study One, belief in God. Importantly, in both studies we found that teleological beliefs were negatively related to the tendency to inhibit intuitions. This is consistent with previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Zemla et al., 2012)</ref>, and supports the view that an intention-based theory of teleology can be conceptualised within a dual-process framework. This dual-process perspective suggests that teleological beliefs about biological and non-biological natural entities represent a "developmentally persistent cognitive default" <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr">(Kelemen et al., , p. 1075</ref>. Although teleological beliefs about biological and non-biological natural entities may be less frequently expressed by adults than by children, according to this view, such beliefs continue to have an intuitive appeal throughout adulthood.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 32</head><p>Using both an online community sample and an undergraduate psychology student sample, the current studies identified several problems with the use of the speeded vs. unspeeded paradigm in the study of teleological beliefs. As this paradigm necessitates the exclusion of participants who respond inaccurately to control statements or fail to respond to a sufficient proportion of test statements within the time limit, this leads to different rates of exclusion between the conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Roberts et al., 2020)</ref>. Exclusion was also found to vary systematically with the tendency to inhibit intuitions, with participants scoring lower on the CRT more likely to be excluded. Due to the significantly higher rate of participant exclusion in the speeded condition than in the un-speeded condition, participants scoring lower on the CRT were disproportionately excluded in the speeded condition, but not in the un-speeded condition. As scores on the CRT were negatively related to rates of teleological acceptance, systematically excluding low-scoring CRT participants from the speeded condition means this paradigm may artificially decrease the mean rate of teleological acceptance in the speeded condition following participant exclusion. As a result, this paradigm may provide an overly conservative estimate of teleological acceptance in the speeded condition.</p><p>More problematic for research employing this paradigm in the study of teleological beliefs, is that the effect of time pressure on teleological acceptance, which has previously been taken as evidence of tacit teleological tendencies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Mills &amp; Frowley, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref>, was weaker than the effect of time pressure on control statement (in)accuracy. That is, although the mean difference in accuracy between conditions was larger for teleological test statements than for control statements, the variation in accuracy for teleological test statements was also larger than for control statements. In both studies, the effect of time pressure for control statement inaccuracy was driven by responses to control statements that were objectively false. Rather than speeded decision-making uncovering tacit teleological tendencies, these findings suggest SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 33 that speeded decision-making increases rates of acceptance for statements that are objectively false. Therefore, unless we are willing to concede that people implicitly believe that "post-it notes are sticky because they are yellow", or that "people smoke cigarettes in order to get lung cancer", it is problematic to claim that this paradigm provides evidence of tacit teleological tendencies.</p><p>While our results show that the speeded vs. un-speeded paradigm does not provide evidence for a dissociation of implicit and explicit teleological beliefs, in isolation, this would be considered a methodological issue, but not necessarily a theoretical one. That is, an</p><p>intention-based theory of teleology suggests that teleological beliefs about biological and non-biological natural entities are a "developmentally persistent cognitive default" <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr">(Kelemen et al., , p. 1075</ref>, but this theory does not rest on the claim that a speeded decisionmaking task can uncover such tendencies. However, the appropriateness of speeded decision-making in dissociating implicit and explicit teleological beliefs, is based on two theoretical assumptions. First, teleological beliefs are conceptualised as existing within a dual-process framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Kelemen &amp; Rosset, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Zemla et al., 2012</ref>).</p><p>According to this view, there exist two qualitatively different types of cognitive processes;</p><p>type-1 processes which are fast, effortless, and do not require working memory, and type-2 processes which are slow, effortful, and do require working memory (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Evans &amp; Stanovich, 2013</ref>). In the current context, teleological beliefs are conceptualised as resulting from a type-1 process. According to this view, as speeded responding precludes the opportunity to engage in reflective thought, responses in the speeded condition are said to reflect a person's belief at an implicit level. Second, it is implicitly assumed that teleological and non-teleological beliefs about a given entity or phenomenon cannot coexist at a prereflective level and be held with equivalent conviction. The finding that response latencies did not differ between teleological statements that were correctly rejected and teleological SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 34 statements that were incorrectly accepted, suggests that if this first assumption is true, and teleological beliefs do result from type-1 cognitive processes, the second assumption must be false.</p><p>Although non-experimental evidence suggests teleological beliefs are the default when alternative causal modes of explanation have not been obtained through formal education <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Casler &amp; Kelemen, 2008)</ref>, or when alternative knowledge structures are impaired as a result of neurodegeneration <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Lombrozo et al., 2007)</ref>, this does not speak to whether the non-teleological beliefs of educated individuals without neurological impairment are merely "expressed", or whether they are held at a deeper "implicit" level. Recent work in the field of judgment and decision-making suggests that multiple automatic responses to a given stimulus can occur in parallel <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(De Neys, 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pennycook et al., 2015)</ref>. For example, people are intuitively aware of both the believability  and logical structure of arguments <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Morsanyi &amp; Handley, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Trippas et al., 2016)</ref>, despite the fact that each of these factors may interfere with judgements of the other factor. People may hold implicit teleological beliefs about biological and nonbiological natural entities, but if they also have an intuitive awareness of an alternative non-teleological explanation, time pressure would not necessarily lead to the expression of the teleological explanation over the alternative. Given the broader field of thinking and reasoning has moved towards dual-process models which allow for multiple type-1 processes to co-occur, theories which situate teleological beliefs with a dual-process framework should do the same. Future research should seek to test alternative paradigms that are not contingent upon the assumption that teleological and nonteleological beliefs about a particular entity cannot coexist implicitly and be held with equivalent conviction.</p><p>Drawing from the judgement and decision-making literature, one such alternative approach would be to make use of the belief bias effect. When asked to judge an argument as SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 35 either logically valid or invalid, people are often biased by their belief in the conclusion of the argument <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Pennycook et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Pennycook et al., , 2014</ref>. Specifically, when a logically valid argument contains an unbelievable conclusion, or when a logically invalid argument contains a believable conclusion, people experience a conflict between logical validity and belief, and are less accurate and slower to respond compared to when the logical validity and believability of the conclusion are congruent <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Trémolière et al., 2014)</ref>. By pairing teleological and non-teleological conclusions with both logically valid and logically invalid argument structures, it would be possible, based on an individual's stated beliefs, to determine whether they should experience a conflict for any given argument.</p><p>Making use of the belief bias effect in this way, it may be possible to dissociate implicitly held and explicitly expressed teleological beliefs.</p><p>Although the current findings may seem inconsistent with the existing literature in showing that the speeded vs. un-speeded paradigm does not provide evidence of a dissociation of implicit and explicit teleological beliefs, many aspects of our work are consistent with the existing literature. First, the bivariate relationships between belief in God, anthropomorphism, inhibition of intuitions, and teleological acceptance replicate previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Roberts et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Willard et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Willard &amp; Norenzayan, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Zemla et al., 2012)</ref>. Second, in terms of the effect of time pressure on teleological test statements, the difference in accuracy between conditions (17% Study One; 21% Study Two) are similar to previously reported findings. In fact, the mean difference between conditions reported in previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Roberts et al., 2020)</ref> are contained within the confidence intervals of the current results. In conjunction with the fact that the findings of Study One replicated when using a large undergraduate sample in Study Two, this provides additional confidence in the current results.</p><p>SPEEDED  In summary, the current studies have shown that the standard experimental paradigm for demonstrating tacit teleological tendenciesto compare rates of teleological acceptance in an un-speeded condition to that in a speeded conditionmay not, in fact, provide evidence for such tendencies. Rather, this paradigm results in selection bias and increased rates of acceptance for statements that are objectively false. This is more than just a methodological issue, as the use of speeded decision-making in this context is based on the theoretical assumption that teleological beliefs can be conceptualised within a dual-process framework.</p><p>We have argued that for the dual-process perspective of teleological beliefs to accommodate the current results, a particular aspect of this view may need to be modified. Teleological beliefs about biological and nonbiological natural entities may well be a "developmentally persistent cognitive default" <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kelemen et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr">(Kelemen et al., , p. 1075</ref>, but for adults who have learnt alternative mechanistic explanations, there is no reason why teleological beliefs could not coexist with their non-teleological alternatives at an implicit level. This reframing of the current dual-process perspective of teleology would not only align with recent theoretical and empirical work within the broader field of thinking and reasoning <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(De Neys, 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Howarth et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Morsanyi &amp; Handley, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Pennycook et al., 2015)</ref>, but it would also inform new methodologies in the study of teleological beliefs. Speeded decision-making does not reveal tacit teleological tendencies, and this reframing of the dual-process perspective of teleology explains why.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>speeded decision-making paradigm to explore implicit teleological beliefs. First, differing inclusion criteria between experimental conditions may lead to the systematic exclusion of certain individuals from one condition, but not the other. Second, reported interactions SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 11 between speed and item type have not included enough information to ascertain whether implicit teleological beliefs are truly driving the effects of interest. Third, comparing</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>presented. After completing the TBS, participants completed the Anthropomorphism Questionnaire, reduced Centrality of Religiosity Scale, and extended Cognitive Reflection Test in a Latin square design.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>paired t-test revealed no significant difference in response latencies between correctly rejected (M = 4800.63, SD = 2550.46) and incorrectly accepted teleological test statements (M = 5048.01, SD = 3601.71), t (86) = -0.64, p = .524. A Bayesian paired t-test using an uninformative prior provided strong support for the null hypothesis of no difference between conditions (BF10 = 0.077) 4 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>would be expected if the speeded decision-making paradigm revealed tacit teleological tendencies, the effect of time pressure on control statement accuracy in aggregate, t(166) = 5.58, p &lt; .001, d = 1.286, was stronger than the effect of time pressure on teleological test statement accuracy, t(166) = 5.60, p &lt; .001, d = 0.951. This comparison was statistically significant, F(1, 166) = 15.55, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .086. Similarly, the effect of time pressure on false control statement accuracy, t(166) = 8.65, p &lt; .001, d = 1.467, was stronger than the effect of time pressure on teleological test statement accuracy, F(1, 166) = 8.96, p = .003, ηρ 2 = .051. However, the effect of time pressure on teleological test statement accuracy was stronger than the effect of time pressure on true control statement SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 29 accuracy, t(166) = 1.86, p = .065, d = 0.315, and this comparison was statistically significant, F(1, 166) = 20.66, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .111.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>speeded condition (N = 119), mean latencies were calculated separately for correctly and incorrectly answered teleological test statements for each participant. Standardised scores were computed based on these means, resulting the exclusion of four participants with zscores greater than 4.25. All other z-scores were within a range of -0.75 to 2.13. Next, standardised scores were calculated for individual trials. Latencies for trials with a corresponding z-score greater than +/-3 were replaced with the mean latency of either correctly or incorrectly answered trials. A further four participants were excluded for nothaving both correct and incorrect responses to the test statements, leaving 111 participants. A paired t-test revealed no significant difference in response latencies between correctly rejected (M = 4812.52, SD = 1919.15) and incorrectly accepted teleological test statements (M = 4898.53, SD = 2386.45), t (110) = -0.43, p = .668. A Bayesian paired t-test using an uninformative prior provided strong support for the null hypothesis of no difference between conditions (BF10 = 0.077).As a more conservative test of the difference in response latencies between correctly rejected and incorrectly accepted teleological test statements, we restricted our analysis to statements with a mean accuracy of between 40% and 60%. As before, the paired t-test revealed no significant difference in response latencies between correctly rejected (M = 4786.37, SD = 2559.61) and incorrectly accepted teleological test statements (M = 5110.01, SD = 3108.70), t (98) = -1.06, p = .293. A Bayesian paired t-test using an uninformative SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 30 prior provided strong support for the null hypothesis of no difference between conditions (BF10 = 0.057) 5 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Correlations Between Teleology and Predictor Variables in Study One Prior to Exclusion</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Teleology</cell><cell>False</cell><cell>True</cell><cell>AQ</cell><cell>r-CRS</cell><cell>CRT</cell></row><row><cell>Teleology</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>False Control</cell><cell>-.587***</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-.66, -.50]</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>True Control</cell><cell>-.247***</cell><cell>.556***</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-.36, -.13]</cell><cell>[.47, .63]</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AQ</cell><cell>.181**</cell><cell>-.123*</cell><cell>-.026</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[.06, .29]</cell><cell>[-.24, -.01]</cell><cell>[-.15, .09]</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>r-CRS</cell><cell>.213***</cell><cell>-.197**</cell><cell>-.136*</cell><cell>.095</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[.10, .32]</cell><cell>[-.31, -.08]</cell><cell>[-.25, -.02]</cell><cell>[-.02, .21]</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CRT</cell><cell>-.414***</cell><cell>.406***</cell><cell>.170**</cell><cell>-.105</cell><cell>-.181**</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-.51, -.31]</cell><cell>[.30, .50]</cell><cell>[.05, .28]</cell><cell>[-.22, .01]</cell><cell>[-.29, -.06]</cell><cell>-</cell></row></table><note>Note. Pearson's r correlations with 95% confidence intervals [L, U]. N = 273 for all cells. "Teleology" represents agreement with test statements, whereas "False" and "True" represent accuracy for each category of control statements. AQ = anthropomorphism, r-CRS = belief in God, CRT = inhibition of intuitions.* p &lt; .05, ** p &lt; .01, *** p &lt; .001.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Comparison of Scores on Predictor Variables for Included and Excluded Participants in Study OneNote. Means are shown with standard errors in parentheses. 95% confidence intervals[L, U]  are shown for mean differences. Included n = 200. Excluded n = 73.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Included</cell><cell>Excluded</cell><cell>Difference</cell></row><row><cell>Anthropomorphism (AQ)</cell><cell>30.87 (1.82)</cell><cell>33.03 (2.96)</cell><cell>2.16 (3.50), [-4.73, 9.05]</cell></row><row><cell>Belief in God (r-CRS)</cell><cell>2.18 (0.08)</cell><cell>2.57 (0.15)</cell><cell>0.39 (0.16), [0.08, 0.71]*</cell></row><row><cell>Inhibition (CRT)</cell><cell>3.64 (0.13)</cell><cell>2.41 (0.24)</cell><cell>-1.22 (0.26), [-1.73, -0.72]***</cell></row></table><note>* p &lt; .05, *** p &lt; .001.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Accuracy for Statement Types as a Function of Condition after Participant Exclusion in Study One</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Teleological Test</cell><cell>Control Aggregate</cell><cell>False Control</cell><cell>True Control</cell></row><row><cell>Un-Speeded</cell><cell>0.62 (0.24)</cell><cell>0.95 (0.05)</cell><cell>0.95 (0.08)</cell><cell>0.95 (0.05)</cell></row><row><cell>Speeded</cell><cell>0.45 (0.19)</cell><cell>0.88 (0.05)</cell><cell>0.86 (0.09)</cell><cell>0.90 (0.06)</cell></row><row><cell>Difference</cell><cell>0.17 [0.11, 0.23]</cell><cell>0.07 [0.05, 0.08]</cell><cell>0.08 [0.06, 0.11]</cell><cell>0.05 [0.03, 0.06]</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Note. Means are shown with standard deviations in parentheses. 95% confidence intervals are shown [L, U]</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">for mean differences between conditions.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Contrary to what would be expected if the speeded decision-making paradigm revealed tacit teleological tendencies, the effect of time pressure on control statement accuracy in aggregate, t(198) = 9.19, p &lt; .001, d = 1.300, was stronger than the effect of time pressure on teleological test statement accuracy, t(198) = 5.57, p &lt; .001, d = 0.788. This difference was statistically significant, F(1, 198) = 14.18, p &lt; .001, ηρ 2 = .067. Similarly, the effect of time pressure on false control statement accuracy, t(198) = 7.27, p &lt; .001, d = 1.028, was stronger than the effect of time pressure on teleological test statement accuracy (F(1,</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Correlations Between Teleology and Predictor Variables in Study Two Prior to Exclusion</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Teleology</cell><cell>False</cell><cell>True</cell><cell>AQ</cell><cell>r-CRS</cell><cell>CRT</cell></row><row><cell>Teleology</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>False</cell><cell>-.624***</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-.69, -.54]</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>True</cell><cell>-.159*</cell><cell>.439***</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-.28, -.04]</cell><cell>[.33, .53]</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>AQ</cell><cell>.188**</cell><cell>-.211***</cell><cell>.065</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[.07, .31]</cell><cell>[-.33, -.09]</cell><cell>[-.06, .19]</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>r-CRS</cell><cell>.075</cell><cell>-.177**</cell><cell>-.038</cell><cell>.273***</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-.05, .20]</cell><cell>[-.30, -.06]</cell><cell>[-.16, .09]</cell><cell>[.15, .38]</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CRT</cell><cell>-.219***</cell><cell>.265***</cell><cell>.167**</cell><cell>-.203**</cell><cell>.140*</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-.33, -.10]</cell><cell>[.15, .38]</cell><cell>[.04, .29]</cell><cell>[-.32, .08]</cell><cell>[-.26, -.02]</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">Note. Pearson's r correlations with 95% confidence intervals [L, U]. N = 250 for all cells. "Teleology"</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">represents agreement with test statements, whereas "False" and "True" represent accuracy for each category</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">of control statements.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>* p &lt; .05, ** p &lt; .01, *** p &lt; .001.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>, included and excluded participants did not differ</cell></row><row><cell>significantly on anthropomorphism, t(248) = 1.83, p = .068, d = 0.247, or, in contrast to</cell></row><row><cell>Study One, belief in God, t(248) = 1.43, p = .155, d = 0.192. However, consistent with Study</cell></row><row><cell>One, compared to participants who failed to meet the inclusion criteria, those who met the</cell></row><row><cell>inclusion criteria were significantly better at inhibiting their intuitions, t(248) = -3.45, p &lt;</cell></row><row><cell>.001, d = 0.465.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Comparison of Scores on Predictor Variables for Included and Excluded Participants in Study Two</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Included</cell><cell>Excluded</cell><cell>Difference</cell></row><row><cell>Anthropomorphism (AQ)</cell><cell>30.48 (1.81)</cell><cell>36.57 (2.96)</cell><cell>6.09 [-0.45, 12.63]</cell></row><row><cell>Belief in God (r-CRS)</cell><cell>2.38 (0.08)</cell><cell>2.60 (0.13)</cell><cell>0.21 [-0.08, 0.50]</cell></row><row><cell>Inhibition of intuitions (CRT)</cell><cell>3.65 (0.13)</cell><cell>2.85 (0.19)</cell><cell>-0.80 [-1.25, -0.34]**</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Note. Means are shown with standard errors in parentheses. 95% confidence intervals [L, U] are shown for</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mean differences. Included n = 168. Excluded n = 82.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>** p &lt; .01.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Accuracy for Statement Types as a Function of Condition after Participant Exclusion in Study Two</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Teleological Test</cell><cell>Control Aggregate</cell><cell>False Control</cell><cell>True Control</cell></row><row><cell>Un-Speeded</cell><cell>0.61 (0.23)</cell><cell>0.93 (0.05)</cell><cell>0.95 (0.06)</cell><cell>0.91 (0.08)</cell></row><row><cell>Speeded</cell><cell>0.40 (0.19)</cell><cell>0.87 (0.05)</cell><cell>0.85 (0.09)</cell><cell>0.89 (0.07)</cell></row><row><cell>Difference</cell><cell>0.21 [0.13, 0.28]</cell><cell>0.06 [0.05, 0.08]</cell><cell>0.11 [0.08, 0.13]</cell><cell>0.02 [-0.001, 0.05]</cell></row></table><note>Note. Means are shown with standard deviations in parentheses. 95% confidence intervals are shown [L, U] for mean differences between conditions.</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">The instruction to "respond quickly" has also been used by Preston and Shin (2020). However, this study did not include an actual time limit.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Participants were able to select "Christian" or "Catholic". Although Catholicism is a form of Christianity, we found in previous research that a substantial proportion of Catholics selected "Other" as their affiliation and then specified that they were Catholic in a free-response box. In the current sample, 72 selected Christian and 39 selected Catholic.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Without the replacement of outliers, the interpretation of response latency comparisons did not change. All statements, t (97) = -0.86, p = .390; only statements endorsed at moderate rates, t (97) = 0.36, p = .723.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Without the replacement of outliers, the interpretation of response latency comparisons did not change. All statements, t (115) = -0.06, p = .948; only statements endorsed at moderate rates, t (102) = 0.55, p = .583.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Religion&apos;s evolutionary landscape: Counterintuition, commitment, compassion, communion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Atran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Norenzayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="67" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The naturalness of religious ideas: A cognitive theory of religion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Boyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>University of California Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developmental continuity in teleo-functional explanation: Reasoning about nature among Romanian Romani adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Casler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/15248370802248556</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/15248370802248556" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognition and Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="340" to="362" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bias and conflict: A case for logical intuitions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>De Neys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691611429354</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691611429354" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dual process theory 2.0 (W</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>De Neys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>. De Neys</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Belief inhibition during thinking: Not always winning but at least taking part</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>De Neys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Franssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2009.07.009</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2009.07.009" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The intentional stance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">From bacteria to Bach and back</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>W. W. Norton &amp; Company</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dual-process theories of higher cognition: Advancing the debate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S B T</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stanovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691612460685</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691612460685" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The modularity of mind: An essay on faculty psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fodor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effortless nature of conflict detection during thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Franssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>De Neys</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Thinking &amp; Reasoning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/13546780802711185</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/13546780802711185" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive reflection and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Frederick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1257/089533005775196732</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1257/089533005775196732" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A module is a module is a module: evolution of modularity in Evolutionary Psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Grossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dialectical Anthropology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10624-014-9355-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10624-014-9355-0" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Studies in the logic of explanation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Hempel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Oppenheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophy of Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="175" />
			<date type="published" when="1948" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The logic-bias effect: The role of effortful processing in the resolution of belief-logic conflict</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Howarth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Handley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13421-015-0555-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-015-0555-x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="330" to="349" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3390/rel3030710</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3390/rel3030710" />
		<title level="m">The centrality of religiosity scale (CRS). Religions, 3</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="710" to="724" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The divided mind of a disbeliever: Intuitive beliefs about nature as purposefully created among different groups of nonreligious adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Järnefelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Canfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2015.02.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2015.02.005" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">140</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="88" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Beliefs about purpose: On the origins of teleological thought</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>M. C</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The descent of mind: Psychological perspectives on hominid evolution</title>
		<editor>Corballis &amp; S. E. G. Lea</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="278" to="310" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The scope of teleological thinking in preschool children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0010-0277(99)00010-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0010-0277(99)00010-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why are rocks pointy? Children&apos;s preference for teleological explanations of the natural world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1440" to="1452" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0012-1649.35.6.1440</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0012-1649.35.6.1440" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intuitions about origins: Purpose and intelligent design in children&apos;s reasoning about nature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Diyanni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15327647jcd0601</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327647jcd0601" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognition and Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Human function compunction: Teleological SPEEDED DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 39 explanation in adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Rosset</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="143" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2009.01.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2009.01.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Professional physical scientists display tenacious teleological tendencies: Purpose-based reasoning as a cognitive default</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rottman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Seston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">142</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1074" to="1083" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0030399</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0030399" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why people say &quot;yes&quot;: A dual-process theory of acquiescence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Knowles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Condon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037//0022-3514.77.2.379</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//0022-3514.77.2.379" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="386" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Why Everyone Else is a Hypocrite: Evolution and the Modular Mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kurzban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: A practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lakens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00863</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00863" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structure-function fit underlies the evaluation of teleological explanations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Liquin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lombrozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2018.09.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2018.09.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Functional explanation and the function of explanation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lombrozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Carey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2004.12.009</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2004.12.009" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="204" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inferring design: Evidence for a preference for teleological explanations in patients with Alzheimer&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lombrozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Zaitchik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="999" to="1007" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Promiscuous Teleology and the effect of Locus of Control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mills</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Frowley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Irish Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/03033910.2015.1011192</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/03033910.2015.1011192" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Logic feels so good-I like it! evidence for intuitive detection of logicality in syllogistic reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Morsanyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Handley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0026099</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0026099" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="596" to="616" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Neave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Saxton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hönekopp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.paid.2014.08.041</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.paid.2014.08.041" />
		<title level="m">The influence of anthropomorphic tendencies on human hoarding behaviours. Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="219" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive style and religiosity: The role of conflict detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cheyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Barr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Koehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fugelsang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13421-013-0340-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-013-0340-7" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Belief bias during reasoning among religious believers and skeptics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cheyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Koehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fugelsang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-013-0394-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-013-0394-3" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="806" to="811" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What makes us think? A threestage dual-process model of analytic engagement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fugelsang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Koehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2015.05.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2015.05.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain-specific experience and dualprocess thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Purcell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wastell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sweller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Thinking and Reasoning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/13546783.2020.1793813</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/13546783.2020.1793813" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The design stance, intentional stance, and teleological beliefs about biological and non-biological natural entites</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Handley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Polito</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1720" to="1748" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/pspp0000383</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/pspp0000383" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teleology and the intentions of supernatural agents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wastell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Polito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.concog.2020.102905</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.concog.2020.102905" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Consciousness and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102905</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rottman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Seston Schillaci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelemen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/2153599X.2015.1118402</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/2153599X.2015.1118402" />
		<title level="m">Cultural influences on the teleological stance: evidence from China. Religion, Brain &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating an alternate form of the cognitive reflection test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Oppenheimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The grim reasoner: Analytical reasoning under mortality salience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Trémolière</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>De Neys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Bonnefon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Thinking and Reasoning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/13546783.2013.823888</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/13546783.2013.823888" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Logic brightens my day: Evidence for implicit sensitivity to logical validity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Trippas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Handley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Verde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Morsanyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1448" to="1457" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xlm0000248</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000248" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How cultural learning and cognitive biases shape religious beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baimel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Norenzayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.copsyc.2020.07.033</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.copsyc.2020.07.033" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cognitive Biases and Religious Belief: A Path Model Replication in the Czech Republic and Slovakia With a Focus on</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Willard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cingl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Norenzayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Anthropomorphism. Social Psychological and Personality Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="106" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1948550619841629</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1948550619841629" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive biases explain religious belief, paranormal belief, and belief in life&apos;s purpose</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Willard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Norenzayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="391" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2013.07.016</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2013.07.016" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Teleological explanations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
			<publisher>University of California Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Analytical Thinking Predicts Less SPEEDED</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Zemla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Steiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sloman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>DECISION-MAKING AND TELEOLOGY 42</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teleological Reasoning and Religious Belief</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 38th Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the 38th Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1217" to="1222" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
