<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Semi-Integrative Approach to Understanding and Intervening on False News Sharing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anton</forename><surname>Gollwitzer</surname></persName>
							<email>anton.gollwitzer@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">BI Norwegian Business School</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Oslo</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tump</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Exzellenzcluster Science of Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cameron</forename><surname>Martel</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Sloan School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominik</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Exzellenzcluster Science of Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">Philipps University of Marburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Marburg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mubashir</forename><surname>Sultan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt University of Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><forename type="middle">H J M</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Exzellenzcluster Science of Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Max Planck Institute for Human Development &amp; BI Norwegian Business School</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Semi-Integrative Approach to Understanding and Intervening on False News Sharing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:40+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>false news</term>
					<term>false news sharing</term>
					<term>semi-integrative</term>
					<term>integrative design</term>
					<term>misinformation</term>
					<term>drift-diffusion modeling Significance Statement</term>
					<term>2023; Stencel et al.</term>
					<term>Study concept and design: A.G.. Data preparation and acquisition: A.G. and A.N.T. Data analysis and interpretation: A.N.T and D. D. Manuscript-draft: A.G.</term>
					<term>A.N.T. Manuscript-critical</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The risks of false news-its potential to distort public opinion and erode trust-have driven extensive research on potential countermeasures. Yet, there has been no comprehensive, comparative, and computational investigation of false news sharing and how to mitigate it. To address this, we apply a semi-integrative experimental approach that directly compares multiple false news interventions, examines individual-and item-level modifiers of intervention efficacy, and uses computational modeling to uncover the decision-making processes underlying these effects. We find that warning labels and media literacy interventions most effectively improve news sharing quality, followed by a social norm intervention. Accuracy prompts were least effective. Supporting generalizability, intervention effects remained consistent across individualand item-level characteristics, including age, analytical thinking, and political-lean. Supporting specificity, each intervention influenced news sharing quality through distinct decision-making processes. By applying a semi-integrative approach, we offer an in-depth understanding of false news sharing and how to mitigate it.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2021)</head><p>. As a result, researchers and practitioners have developed a wide ranging toolbox of psychologically informed interventions that show promise in addressing gaps in the identification and moderation of online misinformation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Lewandowsky et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kozyreva et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b99">Roozenbeek et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b117">Van Bavel et al., 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Psychological factors play a significant role in misinformation spread, including false news sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Ecker et al., 2022)</ref>. Confirmation bias and political polarization encourage people to share belief-aligned news <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">(Osmundsen et al., 2021)</ref>, cognitive laziness leads to difficulties in truth discernment <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019)</ref>, reward-based habits encourage unreflexive sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Ceylan et al., 2023)</ref>, and people believe misinformation even after it has been debunked (continued influence effect; <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Lewandowsky et al., 2012)</ref>. Nonetheless, intervention research has had some success at tackling false news, for instance, applying warning labels to misleading posts effectively reduces belief in and spread of misinformation (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Martel &amp; Rand, 2023b)</ref>. Despite this, warning labels have limitations; they require changing existing media environments and an objective criterion to identify false news, such as manual fact-checking. As a result, their applicability and scalability may be limited, particularly when compared to interventions that aid or empower individuals to make more accurate sharing decisions (e.g., nudging or boosting interventions; <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Hertwig &amp; Grüne-Yanoff, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Kozyreva et al., 2022)</ref>. Such interventions include, for instance, prompting individuals to focus on the accuracy of information (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b88">Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2022)</ref>, forewarning individuals that they might encounter misinformation (inoculation and prebunking; <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Leder et al. 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Lewandowsky &amp; van der Linden, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b102">Roozenbeek et al., 2022b)</ref>, informing people of social norms against sharing false news (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Andi &amp; Akesson, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Gimpel et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b92">Pretus et al., 2022)</ref>, and media literacy trainings <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Guess et al., 2020)</ref>. Each of these interventions has been shown to increase truth discernment and reduce false news sharing (for an overview, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Kozyreva et al., 2022)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The One-Shot Problem</head><p>Despite these advancements, research on false news suffers from a "one-shot" or "one-at-at-time" problem-a problem that is widespread in psychology and more generally in the social sciences. While replicability and reproducibility initiatives have strengthened research practices (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Nosek et al., 2022)</ref>, psychological studies still largely remain narrow and suffer from a lack of systematic integration (the "one-shot" problem; e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Almaatouq et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Muthukrishna &amp; Henrich, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Newell, 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b118">Van Bavel et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b125">Watts, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b127">Yarkoni, 2020)</ref>. For instance, it is common practice for independent research labs to conduct limited, singular experiments in which only a few parameters are included and design choices are selected unsystematically (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b100">Roozenbeek et al., 2022a)</ref>. This one-shot problem holds true for false news research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Guay et al., 2023)</ref>. Few studies have compared the effectiveness of various false news interventions (though see <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Fazio et al., 2024</ref> for a large-scale comparison), and it remains unclear which interventions are effective for which audiences. The parameter space around false news interventions is largely undefined, and results across studies reveal inconsistencies (for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Ecker et al., 2022)</ref>. For instance, it is contested whether people's susceptibility to false news is driven primarily by cognitive complacency (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019)</ref> or political ideology and myside bias (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b100">Roozenbeek et al., 2022a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b117">Van Bavel et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b119">Van der Linden, 2022)</ref>. Inconsistent findings like these are rooted, in part, in the practice of conducting one-shot studies.</p><p>To address the one-shot problem in psychology and the social sciences, researchers can apply integrative approaches to experimental science (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b124">Watts, 2011)</ref>. Integrative approaches or frameworks explicitly consider the experimental space surrounding a psychological phenomenon-for instance, the impact of varying manipulations, the time allotted to the task, the degree of incentives, and item-level and individual-level modifiers-thus, creating a parameter space around a construct or behavior (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Almaatouq et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Larson, 2013)</ref>. With rapid advancements in data collection techniques (and sufficient financial resources), this approach is becoming more viable among researchers, who can now simultaneously deploy as many elements as an infrastructure can support (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Almaatouq et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Awad et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b90">Peterson et al., 2021)</ref>. For instance, recent work has mapped out broad parameter spaces around moral decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Awad et al., 2018)</ref>, risky decision-making , group synergy <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Almaatouq et al., 2021)</ref>, and subliminal priming <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Baribault et al., 2018)</ref>. These efforts provide a much more detailed and in-depth picture into human behaviors (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b124">Watts, 2011</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>An Integrative Approach to False News Sharing</head><p>To begin to address the one-shot problem in false news research, we apply elements of integrative experimental design to false news sharing. Our approach considers the parameter space around false news sharing, including potential interventions to mitigate this behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Almaatouq et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b124">Watts, 2011)</ref>. Specifically, we integrate three experimental components-each well-supported by empirical research but typically studied in isolation-into a unified framework.</p><p>First, we apply a multi-treatment design, estimating the average treatment effects of multiple manipulations by employing a multi-arm approach that directly compares several established false news sharing interventions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Milkman et al., 2022)</ref>. Second, we examine effect heterogeneity, assessing how news sharing and intervention effectiveness varies across participant-level and stimulus-level characteristics by considering individuals' attributes, such as age and gender, and news items' attributes, such as the degree of sensationalism or political-lean (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Baker, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Bryan et al., 2021)</ref>. Third, we investigate the underlying mechanisms, applying computational modeling to uncover the decision-making processes that drive false news sharing and intervention effectiveness (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Fudenberg et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>. By combining these three well-established experimental components, we offer a uniquely broad insight into false news sharing and, crucially, how to mitigate this behavior.</p><p>The first component of our approach is a multi-treatment or comparative intervention design (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Milkman et al., 2022)</ref>. This method directly compares multiple theoretically grounded interventions to assess their comparative effectiveness, in the present case, in terms of their effectiveness at reducing false news sharing. By systematically manipulating these interventions, we can estimate causal treatment effects (average treatment effects; ATEs), and determine their relative impact. Despite its value, this level of comparative analysis-comparing the efficacy of numerous interventions-has been surprisingly underexplored in false news research; it remains unclear which interventions are more or less powerful than others at attenuating false news sharing (though see <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Fazio et al., 2024</ref> for one large-scale comparison).</p><p>The second component of our approach maps the parameter space around false news sharing and false news interventions by considering how theoretically-motivated individual-and item-level characteristics modify these effects (effect heterogeneity; <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Bryan et al., 2021)</ref>. At the individual level, this analysis identifies who is more or less at risk for sharing false news and how intervention effectiveness varies across individuals (personalized or fine-tuned interventions; e.g., . These modifiers include both demographic factors-such as age, gender, and income-and psychological traits, including cognitive styles, personality, and beliefs. At the item level, we assess how features of the news content itself predicts false news sharing and whether intervention effectiveness depends on these characteristics (item-response theory; <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Baker, 2001</ref>).</p><p>Item-level attributes can include, for instance, the sensationalism, political leaning, and familiarity of news articles. Crucially, we do not experimentally manipulate these individual-or item-level characteristics. Instead, we treat them as effect modifiers rather than interaction terms, as we do not necessarily assume a direct causal effect of these covariates on outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b120">(VanderWeele, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Hernán &amp; Robins, 2024)</ref>.</p><p>The first two components of our approach-multi-treatment design and individual-and item-level effect heterogeneity (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Baker, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Bryan et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Milkman et al., 2022;</ref>-go beyond the scope of many one-shot studies in false news research. However, they leave an important level of analyses absent: the cognitive and decision-making processes that underlie news sharing behavior. As process variables inform precise psychological theorizing, the third component of our approach involves applying computational modeling to quantify the decision-making processes underlying false news sharing and the effectiveness of false news interventions.</p><p>To accomplish this aim, we apply drift-diffusion modeling (DDM), a well-defined modeling technique that captures the decision-making processes in choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Fudenberg et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>. DDM can capture the choice of whether to share or not share a news item and how interventions influence such news sharing choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Lin et al., 2023)</ref>. DDM leverages participants' choices and response times to estimate three key decision parameters: the starting point-the overall initial bias towards one choice (share vs. not share news items); the drift rate-the information collected over time in favor of one choice (e.g., share) over another (e.g., not share); and the boundary separation-the amount of information gathered before making a choice (share vs. not share). By applying DDM, we can model the specific pathways that lead to news sharing tendencies <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Mulder et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Lin et al., 2023)</ref>, how interventions shift these decision-making processes, and how individual-and item-level characteristics modify these processes to inform personalized and context-dependent intervention outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b131">(Zhao et al., 2022)</ref>.</p><p>Taken together, integrating these three experimental components into a unified framework provides a more precise and in-depth understanding of false news sharing. By simultaneously assessing the effectiveness of multiple interventions, the heterogeneity of these effects across individuals and news content, and the decision-making processes underlying these decisions, our approach offers a comparative, conditional, and mechanistic insight into false news sharing and how to mitigate this behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Semi-Integrative Approach</head><p>The present experimental approach aligns with but also diverges from previously proposed experimental approaches, in particular integrative approaches (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Almaatouq et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b124">Watts, 2011)</ref>. One key distinction is the inclusion of process-focused computational modeling, specifically drift-diffusion models (DDMs), which uncover the decision-making processes underlying a behavior or choice. Most existing integrative approaches do not incorporate this level of process-based analysis (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Awad et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Almaatouq et al., 2023)</ref>.</p><p>Another distinguishing feature is its semi-integrative design. Unlike fully integrative or high-throughput approaches that require tens of thousands to millions of participants due to the extensive crossing of between-participant factors (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Awad et al., 2018)</ref>, our proposed approach does not systematically cross interventions or manipulations with one another. While this unfortunately reduces the dimensionality of the parameter space being mapped, it significantly lowers the required sample size and study costs, making the approach more feasible. In some situations, such as is the case for false news sharing, combining interventions (e.g., implementing both warning labels and accuracy prompts simultaneously) may offer only marginal knowledge gains while dramatically increasing complexity. Thus, our approach prioritizes maximizing knowledge acquisition while maintaining practicality and cost-effectiveness.</p><p>Despite going beyond one-shot approaches, we do not wish to overstate the novelty of our semi-integrative approach. The individual components of this approach-comparing multiple treatments, analyzing heterogeneity across individuals and stimuli, and applying computational modeling to capture process-level mechanisms-are all well-established research practices <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Milkman et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Bryan et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Fudenberg et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">Ratcliff et al., 2016</ref>). Yet, studies that integrate all three components within a single experimental design remain rare (but see Zhao et al., 2022 for one example). Despite its availability, this experimental approach is often neglected in favor of top-down designs that focus on isolated effects and consider singular levels of analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Present Work</head><p>To reveal the comparative effectiveness of multiple false news sharing interventions, we included four empirically established approaches: accuracy prompts, warning labels, social norm interventions, and media literacy tips (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Kozyreva et al., 2022</ref>; see Methods for details; see Figures S1-S4). A no-treatment control condition was also included for comparison's sake. The interventions were selected due to their prominence in false news research (e.g., , their broad applicability (e.g., media literacy; e.g., <ref type="bibr">Andi et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Epstein et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Mosseri, 2016)</ref>, and prior mixed findings (e.g., accuracy prompts; <ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Pennycook et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b95">Rathje et al., 2022)</ref>. The interventions also represent a range of conceptual dimensions, differing in whether they are content-specific (e.g., warning labels applied to particular news items) or content-neutral (e.g., social norm interventions applied across all news items) <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Kozyreva et al., 2022)</ref>, and in whether they target the existing media environment (e.g., warning labels) or enhance individual decision-making skills (e.g., media literacy) <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Hertwig &amp; Grüne-Yanoff, 2017)</ref>. Given this variation, the interventions were theoretically expected to load onto different decision-making processes as quantified by the DDM analyses. For instance, we expected warning labels to load more on the starting point bias (one's initial bias to share vs. not share) while media literacy tips should load more on the boundary separation (the amount of information gathered before making a sharing decision).</p><p>In terms of individual-level characteristics, we included demographic, social media use, and psychological variables that have been examined in previous false news research, for instance, age, political knowledge, time spent on social media, and political orientation <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Bryanov &amp; Vziatysheva, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Sindermann et al., 2020)</ref>. In terms of item-level characteristics, we included attributes quantified by an independent research group, for instance, the sensationalism, familiarity, and political-lean of the news items . Participants were preselected based on their propensity to share news online to avoid floor effects and to focus on habitual news sharers <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Ceylan et al., 2023)</ref>. Participants were asked to repeatedly choose whether to share or not share news items.</p><p>Our design involved both pre-and post-intervention trials and true and false news items.</p><p>This design allowed us to not only examine the comparative strength of several false news interventions but also the role of individual-level modifiers, item-level modifiers, and decision-making processes in true and false news sharing at three different levels of analysis: <ref type="formula">1</ref>baseline sharing behavior before the interventions (pre-intervention), (2) the change in sharing behavior over the course of the task (time effect), and (3) the influence of the interventions on sharing behavior (intervention effect). Taken together, the present approach provides a uniquely broad, multi-level view of false news sharing; we reveal who is most likely to share false news, the cognitive processes involved, and how interventions shape this behavior across baseline tendencies, repeated exposure, and multiple intervention effects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We planned to recruit 1,300 participants from the United States via Prolific, aiming for at least ~200 participants per condition after exclusions. This sample size was chosen to reliably detect effects of moderate or large magnitude, rather than very small effects that may be statistically significant but less actionable. In line with this reasoning, a sensitivity power analysis indicated that a sample of 200 participants per condition provided 93% power to detect intervention effects of small to moderate size (0.35 on probit scale; corresponding to 3-4 percent points marginal effect) and intervention-modifier effects of moderate size (0.3 on probit scale; corresponding to ~3 percent points marginal effect per moderator SD). This analysis was conducted by simulating datasets with varying effect sizes, each with 200 agents per condition, and applying the below described regression analysis to determine the effect detection (see <ref type="figure">Figure S5</ref> and Supplemental Materials).</p><p>To avoid floor effects and intervene on habitual sharers of news (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Ceylan et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Guess et al., 2019)</ref>, participants were asked in a pretest to rate how often they share news articles, ranging from 1 (never) to 5 (always). 1 In line with standard practice in intervention research to exclude individuals who weakly or do not exhibit the target behavior, only participants who responded 3 or above were invited to the study, resulting in a total sample of 1,321 participants (~66%; from 1,989 possible respondents).</p><p>Participants were excluded if they failed an attention precheck (n = 70), did not complete any part of the news sharing task (n = 99) 2 , completed only part of the news sharing task (n = 4), responded unrealistically quickly on the news sharing task (i.e., response time &lt; 200 ms in more than half of trials; n = 4), responded unrealistically slowly on the news sharing task (i.e., response time &gt; 30 s in more than half of trials; n =1), or because of missing data on one or more of the individual-level characteristic measures (n =1). The observed drop-out rate after having started the news sharing task (&lt;.01%), was significantly lower than that observed in an alternate multi-intervention examination of false news sharing (~16.45%; <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Fazio et al., 2024)</ref>. We also excluded 14 participants who reported their gender as nonbinary, as this small sample skews statistical models. The final sample included 1,128 participants (M age = 41.09, SD age = 14.19; 562 female).</p><p>Data Availability: All data and analysis files can be found on OSF. The study was preregistered at https://aspredicted.org/blind.php?x=6HV_3FD. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We confirm that we have reported all measures, conditions, data exclusions, and how we determined the recruited sample sizes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Procedure</head><p>Participants first completed a survey assessing potential individual-level modifiers, including psychological, knowledge, and demographic variables. Next, they completed the news sharing task, which included 40 unique news items: 20 pre-intervention and 20 post-intervention trials. The trials included both true and false news <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Guay et al., 2023)</ref>. In each trial, participants saw a single news item (headline and accompanying image; each unique news item was presented only once to participants; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>) and decided whether to share it or not. The five conditions (between participants)-accuracy prompt, warning labels, social norm information, media literacy tips, and a no-treatment control-were presented to participants at the halfway point (i.e., after 20 trials). News item-level modifiers (e.g., sensationalism, familiarity) were sourced from an independent sample. Descriptive statistics of all included measures are available on OSF under R Markdown.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Individual-Level Characteristics</head><p>We included demographic, social media use, knowledge-based, and psychological characteristics that have been examined in previous false news research (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Bryanov &amp; Vziatysheva, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Sindermann et al., 2020)</ref>.</p><p>The demographic information consisted of age, gender, education, and political orientation.</p><p>Education was assessed via a 7-point scale: "What is the highest level of education you have completed?" (1 = High-School No Diploma, 2 = High-School Diploma, 3 = Some College, 4 = Associate Degree, 5 = Bachelor's Degree, 6 = Master's Degree, 7 = Professional Degree or Doctorate Degree). Political orientation was assessed using a 9-point Likert scale: "Where on the following scale of political orientation would you place yourself?" (1 = Extremely Liberal to 5 = Moderate to 9 = Extremely Conservative). Finally, we calculated a political congruency variable, which entailed the extent to which participants' political orientations aligned with the political leanings of specific news items (calculated by zero-centering both variables at the politically neutral point and then multiplying them).</p><p>We measured the quantity of social media use with four-items. Participants responded to:</p><p>"How often are you on on social media (eg. Facebook, Twitter)?", "How often do you post or share content on social media?" (1 = Never, 2 = Every few weeks, 3 = 1 to 2 days a week, 4 = 3 to 6 days a week, 5 = About once a day, 6 = 2 to 5 times a day, 7 = 5 to 10 times a day, 8 = Over 10 times a day), "On an average day in the past week, how many minutes would you say you spent on social media <ref type="bibr">(eg. Facebook, Twitter)</ref>?" (open-ended response); and "Over the past week, how often did you get news from social media (eg. Facebook, Twitter)?" (1 = Never, 2 = Hardly Ever, 3 = Sometimes, 4 = Fairly Often, 5 = Very Often). The overall quantity of social media use was determined by averaging these four items, after centering around the mean and scaling the variables by their standard deviation.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b104">(Sirlin et al., 2021)</ref>. The second media literacy measure was a four-item digital literacy quiz (e.g., "Which of the following four passwords is the most secure?" 1 = WTh@5Z, 2 = Boat1234, 3 = intro*48, 4 = 123456; <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Levin &amp; Redmiles, 2021)</ref>. The two media literacy measures were combined into a single measure by scoring incorrect responses on each of the five questions as 0 and correct responses as 1 and averaging across these scores. Political knowledge was measured using a four-item quiz on U.S. politics (e.g., "Whose responsibility is it to decide if a law is constitutional or not?" 1 = The President, 2 = Congress, 3 = The Supreme Court, 4 = The Parliament; averaged: 0 = Incorrect, 1 = Correct; <ref type="bibr" target="#b114">Tappin et al., 2021)</ref>.</p><p>For psychological variables, participants answered a three-item cognitive reflection test (CRT) that measures analytic thinking by using problems with intuitively compelling but incorrect answers (averaged: 0 = Incorrect, 1 = Correct; Thomson &amp; Oppenheimer, 2016). They also completed a three-item misplaced certainty scale, which assessed their tendency to feel certain about claims that are opposed by counter-evidence or judged skeptically by others (e.g., "I feel certain about things that most people think lack clear evidence"; 1 = Never, 7 = Often; e.g., <ref type="bibr">Gollwitzer et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr">Oettingen et al., 2022)</ref>. 4</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Item-Level Characteristics</head><p>We considered six item-level characteristics of the 40 news items presented to participants.</p><p>We used item-level estimates from an independent sample <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">(Pennycook &amp; Binnendyk, 2022)</ref> to avoid biasing our participants' judgments by having them view the same headlines multiple times (e.g., rating believability before or after deciding whether to share). Because such consensus item-level estimates can shift over time, and as recommended by <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Pennycook and Binnendyk (2022)</ref>, we ensured that our data collection (October 2022) occurred relatively close to when these estimates were originally obtained (January 2022).</p><p>These six item-level characteristics included: the news items' positive valence ("To what extent does this headline make you feel good <ref type="bibr">[happy, excited, hopeful, etc.]</ref>?"; 1 = Not at all to 6 = Extremely), sensationalism ("To what extent is this headline sensationalist and/or exaggerated?"; 1 = Not at all to 6 = Extremely), perceived importance ("Is the headline important?"; 1 = Extremely unimportant to 6 = Extremely important), familiarity ("Are you familiar with the above headline [have you seen or heard about it before]?"; 1 = Not at all to 6 = Extremely), and political leaning ("Is the headline more favorable for Democrats or Republicans?"; 1 = More favorable for Democrats to 6 = More favorable for Republicans). From each news item's political leaning we also calculated its absolute partisanship (i.e., distance from politically neutral), ranging from 0 (Neutral) to 2.5 (Strongly favorable for Republicans/Democrats). Additional characteristics (e.g., negative valence) exhibited high multicollinearity and were thus excluded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>News Item Sharing Task</head><p>Participants read: "In this task you will see a series of news headlines that previously appeared on a social media feed (e.g., Facebook). For each news headline, you will be asked whether you want to share that news headline with other people. When doing so, please imagine that you are sharing (or not sharing) these news headlines on a real media profile you use." After a practice round <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2</ref>), participants were informed that they would see 40 headlines, with a break after the first 20 headlines. The intervention treatment occurred during this break. The preand post-intervention blocks each included half true and half false news items, as well as half pro-Democrat and half pro-Republican items (per block: 5 true pro-Democrat, 5 true pro-Republican, 5 false pro-Democrat, and 5 false pro-Republican items). The order of these trials within the pre-and post-intervention blocks was randomized. For each item, participants decided whether to share the news item by clicking on either "Do Not Share" or "Share" <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2</ref>).</p><p>The 40 news items were selected from a previously validated database of 200 items provided by another research group (see ; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> for examples). A challenge in studying news sharing behavior is the potential for a low prevalence of sharing decisions. To reduce the risk of floor effects, we selected the 40 items from the 200-item database based on their higher likelihood to be shared (as rated by an independent sample) and ensured a balance in veracity (half true, half false) and political lean (half pro-Democrat, half pro-Republican). All news items were sourced from the internet and had previously been shared on social media. All false news items were fact-checked false by reputable third-party fact-checkers;</p><p>all true items were screened as true and selected from mainstream publications . See the R Markdown file on OSF for descriptive statistics of the news items.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Format of News Item Question</head><p>Note. The practice item that participants saw at the start of the news sharing task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Interventions</head><p>After completing the 20 pre-intervention trials, participants were randomly assigned to a no-treatment control condition or one of four interventions: an accuracy prompt (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Pennycook et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b88">Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2022)</ref>, warning label (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Brashier et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Martel &amp; Rand, 2023a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Martel &amp; Rand, 2023b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Mena, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Pennycook et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b91">Porter &amp; Wood, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b105">Sharevski et al., 2022)</ref>, social norm (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Andi &amp; Akesson, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Epstein et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Gimpel et al., 2021)</ref>, or media literacy intervention (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Guess et al., 2020)</ref>. 5 See Figures S1-S4 for materials of each of the tested interventions.</p><p>Accuracy Prompt Intervention. In the accuracy prompt intervention, participants judged the accuracy of a single news item with the goal to shift their attention towards accuracy while completing the news sharing task . Participants received the following instructions: "You are halfway through the task. We would like to pretest a news headline for future studies. We are interested in whether people think it is accurate or not. We only need you to give your opinion about the accuracy of a single headline. We will then go back to the primary sharing task." Participants then saw one of four politically neutral news items (two false and two true; taken from , and evaluated the veracity of the item: "To the best of your knowledge, is the above headline accurate?" (yes or no). Participants then received feedback whether their choice was correct or not. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Warning Label Intervention. The warning label intervention consisted of a visual</head><p>warning label added to the false news items (adapted from Facebook's warning label; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Martel &amp; Rand, 2023a)</ref>. In the post-intervention trials, an overlay was added on top of the false news items: "False Information. Checked by independent fact checkers." The overlay was transparent to allow participants to still view the news item underneath, and was selected because Facebook was using this warning label at the time of our study <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Martel &amp; Rand, 2023a)</ref>. Participants were not informed that these labels would be added to the false news items. Halfway through the task, and before the warning labels were applied, they saw only a message that read: "You are halfway through the task." See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref>. We would like to share some of our previous work with you. In an earlier study, we found that 98% of people think that it is very important to *only* share news articles on social media if this news is accurate." See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure S3</ref>.</p><p>Media Literacy Intervention. The media literacy intervention provided participants with 10 media literacy tips for spotting and responding to false news online (taken from <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Guess et al., 2020)</ref>, such as "Be skeptical. False news stories often have catchy headlines in all caps with exclamation points. If shocking claims in the headline sound unbelievable, they probably are," and "Some stories are intentionally false. Think critically about the stories you read, and only share news you know to be credible". See <ref type="figure">Figure S4</ref>.</p><p>No-Treatment Control. Participants in the no-treatment control condition read: "You are halfway through the task."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview</head><p>Our semi-integrative experimental approach allows us to uncover the comparative effect sizes, individualized intervention outcomes, and decision-making processes underlying intervening on false news sharing. We first examined news sharing behavior, followed by the processes underlying these decisions (using DDM). In both analyses, we considered three sharing contexts:</p><p>(1) 'baseline' sharing behavior before the interventions (pre-intervention), (2) the change in sharing behavior over the course of the task (time effect), and (3) the causal influence of the interventions on sharing behavior (intervention effect). We also examined the role of individual-level characteristics (e.g., age, political orientation, social media use) in these three contexts of sharing behavior. Because several item-level characteristics were found to be collinear with news Item Veracity (e.g., false news was generally rated as more sensationalist than true news), we examined item-level characteristics separately for true and false news. Finally, building on these analyses, we examined sharing behavior and intervention efficacy for two subpopulations that are particularly at risk of sharing false news: older individuals and conservatives (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Guess et al., 2019)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Regression Models</head><p>We employed Bayesian generalized linear mixed-effect regression models to investigate sharing choices. In these models, we treated sharing ("not share"/"share") as a binary response variable via a probit link function. We analyzed our data in an analogous way to Signal Detection Theory (SDT) which teases apart the response bias (i.e., overall response tendency) and discrimination ability (i.e., classification accuracy) of participants <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Macmillan &amp; Creelman, 2004)</ref>.</p><p>Specifically, we differentiated between overall sharing tendency ( ; sharing across true and false β news) and sharing quality ( ; sharing true over false news). β</p><p>Given the probit regression framework, the intercept of the model corresponded to the sharing tendency, and the coefficient describing the influence of Item Veracity (False = -0.5, True = 0.5) represented the sharing quality (for detailed description see supplementary material). As such, all predictor coefficients describe the influence on the sharing tendency except for predictors including an interaction with Item Veracity, the coefficients of which describe the influence on sharing quality. This approach aligns with recent analysis recommendations in false news research <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Guay et al., 2023)</ref> and mirrors the approach used in signal detection tasks on false news detection <ref type="bibr" target="#b112">(Sultan et al., 2022)</ref>. Across our models, we accounted for individual differences in overall sharing tendencies by including random intercepts and differences sharing quality by including Item Veracity as random slopes for each participant. Additionally, we accounted for item-level differences by adding item ID as a random intercept in all models.</p><p>To ensure that the inferences did not depend on the model specification, we ran simpler models with each individual-level or item-level characteristic separately. Given that the results of simple and complex models align, we concluded that the models are not overfitting and that the inferences are robust. Additional model details are explained in the results section. For a detailed description of the model structures and robustness analyses, see supplemental materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Drift Diffusion Models (DDMs)</head><p>The main parameters of the mixed-effect Bayesian DDMs were estimated with the BRMS package <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Bürkner, 2017)</ref>. The BRMS package, which is a well-established and reliable tool for estimating DDMs, has been widely validated in decision-making research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Lin et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Cochrane et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Donzallaz et al., 2023)</ref>.</p><p>We applied a regression framework for parameter estimation with the Wiener response distribution, which is essentially a nonlinear generalized regression of the joint response time and choice distribution, simultaneously estimating the main parameter of the models: starting point bias, drift rate, and boundary separation. This framework allowed us to estimate DDM parameters with regression predictors (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Boehm, Steingroever, &amp; Wagenmakers, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b121">Vandekerckhove, Tuerlinckx, &amp; Lee, 2011)</ref>. The regression formula paralleled the regression models with some changes to account for the cognitive characteristics of the three metrics of DDMs. Specifically, we predicted start point, drift, and boundary separation in terms of: 1) pre-intervention, (2) time effect, and (3) intervention effect, using the formulas from the corresponding non-DDM regression models for each of the three main parameters.</p><p>In line with past work, we excluded all predictor terms with Item Veracity predicting the starting point or boundary separation because inferring the item's veracity is part of the evidence accumulation process; we only consider sharing quality when modeling the drift rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Lin et al., 2023)</ref>. One exception to this, however, was modeling the influence of warning labels; in this case, the accuracy of the item can be inferred at the start of the decision process (starting point) as the warning labels saliently signal the accuracy of the item.</p><p>We formalized the DDM as a hierarchical (i.e., mixed effect) model, by using the same random-effect structure as described in regression models. Given that the start point is restricted to the interval [0, 1] and the boundary separation must be greater than 0, we utilized a logit link function to model the starting point and a log link function to model the boundary separation.</p><p>Coefficients are reported on their respective logit and log scales. For a detailed description of the model specifications and the model estimates, see supplemental materials and <ref type="table">Tables S4-S6,</ref> respectively. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S14</ref> shows the parameter recovery analysis. For all parameters, the generating and recovered parameters were highly correlated, showing that each parameter describes a distinct mechanism and that their effect magnitudes are interpretable. Posterior predictive checks show that the DDM can recover population-level ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S15</ref>) and individual-level ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S16</ref>) choice and response time patterns.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>All Models</head><p>To aid interpretability, all predictors in the models describing individual-or item-level characteristics were mean centered and continuous variables scaled by their standard deviation. In our analysis, we report the 95% credible intervals for each coefficient to determine whether the effect is credible, based on whether the interval overlaps with zero. Additionally, we provide evidence ratios (ERs), which are equivalent to one-sided Bayes factors, to quantify the relative posterior probability for a directed effect (e.g., an increased sharing tendency) compared to its alternative (e.g., no change or a reduced sharing tendency), offering a continuous measure of evidence <ref type="bibr">(Krass &amp; Raftery 1995)</ref>. For predicted marginal effects of the interventions we report the median and the 95% highest posterior density (HPD). Note that while our research design allows for causal identification of the effects of Condition (the experimental interventions; ATEs), the reported relationships between behavior and individual-or item-level characteristics should be interpreted as descriptive rather than causal. This distinction is crucial because, unlike the interventions that were experimentally manipulated, the demographic factors were not manipulated, meaning that we cannot rule out all possible backdoor paths (i.e., confounding paths; <ref type="bibr">Hernán &amp; Robins, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">Pearl et al., 2016)</ref>. All analyses were performed with the R package BRMS <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Bürkner, 2017)</ref>. Visual inspection of the chains and their Rhat values (Rhat ≤ 1.01; see Tables S1-S12) confirmed that all models converged.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Regression Models</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pre-Intervention</head><p>Model 1 investigated pre-intervention sharing tendency and sharing quality (in the first half of the task). The model included the individual-level characteristics as predictors (to investigate sharing tendency) and the two-way interactions between the individual-level characteristics and  <ref type="figure">Figure S6</ref>).  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 3A</ref>. For coefficients, see <ref type="table">Table S1</ref>. For model predictions of the influence of individual-level characteristics on sharing decisions on a percentage scale, see <ref type="figure">Figure S7</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pre</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time Effect</head><p>Model 2 examined the effect of time on sharing. Model 2 echoed Model 1, but we added Time (pre-versus post intervention) and the two-way interactions between Time and each of the individual-level characteristics as predictors to estimate the change of sharing tendency over time.</p><p>We further added the two-way interaction of Time and Item Veracity and the three way interactions between Time, Item Veracity, and each of the individual-level characteristics to estimate how sharing quality changed over time. To account for individual differences in sharing changes from the first to the second half of the task, we added Time as a random slope to the participant level  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 3B</ref> shows that these β effects were largely independent of individual-level characteristics (see also <ref type="table">Table S2)</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Intervention Effects</head><p>Model 3 estimated the average treatment effects (ATEs) of the interventions by comparing participants' behavioral changes from pre-to post-intervention in each of the intervention conditions to the no-treatment control condition. Building on Model 2, we estimated the change in sharing tendency and sharing quality over time separately for control and intervention treatments, which allowed us to compute the contrast in this pre-post change between conditions, corresponding to the causal effect of the interventions (mirroring a difference-in-difference approach). In the model, this is achieved by adding Condition (no-treatment control, accuracy prompt, warning labels, norm intervention, media literacy tips; with control condition as the reference) alone and in interaction with the terms that included Time (pre-versus post-intervention). The moderating effect of those interventions was estimated by adding an interaction of this contrast (i.e., the difference-in-difference) and the mean-centered individual-level characteristics. See supplemental materials for a detailed description of the model and <ref type="table">Table S3</ref> for regression coefficients.</p><p>We observed significant variation across the interventions. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows the average sharing probability for true and false news, both pre-and post-intervention, for each intervention (as compared to the no-treatment control condition). <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> shows the change in sharing behavior from pre-to post-intervention in each condition. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> shows the associations between individual-level characteristics and overall sharing tendency as well as sharing quality per intervention. We report the results for each intervention in turn.  <ref type="figure">Figure 5A</ref>).</p><p>The smaller reduction in overall news sharing in the accuracy prompt condition was particularly pronounced for individuals with higher analytical thinking ( = 0.14, CI = [0.03, 0.26], ER &gt;100; β <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>).</p><p>Regarding sharing quality, participants in the accuracy prompt intervention exhibited an increase of 1.4% points in news sharing quality from pre-to post-intervention. This increase did not credibly differ from participants in the control condition, who exhibited a reduction of 2% points ( = 0.08, CI = [−0.12, 0.27], ER =3.4; <ref type="figure">Figure 5B</ref>), indicating that the accuracy prompt β intervention did not successfully reduce false news sharing. The observed findings were consistent across participants' characteristics ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). The marginal effect of the accuracy prompt intervention, as predicted by the model, is a 1.3% increase in sharing tendency (95% HPD: -0.6% to 3.3%) and a 3.3% increase in sharing quality (95% HPD: −0.3% to 6.9%). For model predictions of how the impact of the intervention varies across individual-level characteristics on a percentage scale, see <ref type="figure">Figure S8</ref>.  <ref type="figure">Figure 5A</ref>). This effect was consistent across β individual characteristics ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>).</p><p>Regarding sharing quality, participants in the warning labels intervention exhibited an increase of 8% points in sharing quality from pre-to post-intervention. This increase credibly differed from participants in the control condition, who exhibited a reduction of 2% points ( = β 0.78, CI = [0.55, 1.00], ER &gt;100; <ref type="figure">Figure 5B</ref>). This positive effect of warning labels on sharing quality was particularly pronounced for participants with lower levels of education ( = −0.25, β CI = [−0.46, −0.04], ER =85.2; <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). The marginal effect of the warning label intervention, as predicted by the model, is a reduction in sharing tendency by −3.2% (95% HPD: −5.1% to −1.6%) and a 7.44% increase in sharing quality (95% HPD: 3.8% to 11.3%). For model predictions of how the impact of the intervention varies across individual-level characteristics on a percentage scale, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">Figure S9</ref>.  Regarding sharing quality, participants in the social norm intervention exhibited an increase of 3.5% points in sharing quality from pre-to post-intervention. This increase credibly differed from participants in the control condition ( = 0.35, CI = [0.16, 0.55], ER &gt;100; <ref type="figure">Figure 5B</ref>). This β effect was consistent across individual characteristics ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). The marginal effect of the social norm intervention was a small increase in sharing tendency by 1.0% (95% HPD: −2.9% to 0.8%) and a 4.5% increase in sharing quality (95% HPD: 1.3% to 8.0%). For model predictions of how the impact of the intervention varies across individual-level characteristics on a percentage scale, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S10</ref>. β <ref type="figure">Figure 5A</ref>). This effect was consistent across individual characteristics ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>).</p><p>Regarding sharing quality, participants in the media literacy intervention exhibited an increase of 13% points in sharing quality from pre-to post-intervention. This increase credibly differed from participants in the control condition ( = 0.83, CI = [0.62, 1.04], ER &gt;100; Figure β 5B). This effect was consistent across individual characteristics ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). The marginal effect of the media literacy intervention is a small decrease in sharing tendency by 2.0% (95% HPD: −3.8% to −0.3%) and strong increase in sharing quality by 11.7% (95% HPD: 8.0% to 15.6%). For model predictions of how the impact of the intervention varies across individual-level characteristics on a percentage scale, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S11</ref>.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S12</ref>). Moreover, we conducted additional analyses to ensure our inferences did not depend on a specific model specification. Specifically, simpler models run with each individual-level characteristic separately (i.e., only one characteristic as predictor per model) confirmed all findings described above ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure   S13</ref>; see supplementary materials for model details). The consistent results from both the simple and complex models indicate that the models are not overfitting and that the inferences are robust.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Drift-Diffusion Models</head><p>We conducted mixed-effects Bayesian drift diffusion models (DDMs) to investigate the decision-making processes underlying participants' sharing choices. The model assumes that the news sharing decision process begins at a starting point or initial bias situated along a continuum ranging from "not share" to "share". The individual then accumulates evidence in favor of either option, which is represented by the drift rate. The drift in this context consists of two categories.</p><p>The first is the average drift towards "not share" or "share," which influences overall sharing tendency. The second is the change of the drift towards "share" or "not share" as a function of news accuracy influencing the sharing quality. Finally, the individual decides whether or not to share once they have gathered enough evidence. The amount of evidence required to reach these boundaries is quantified by the boundary separation. This approach aligns with that of <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Lin et al. (2023)</ref>, which also examined false news sharing depending on Item Veracity via DDMs.</p><p>We developed an open-source Shiny app that visualizes these metrics and the impact of the tested interventions on these dynamics, see https://alan-tump.shinyapps.io/DSIA/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pre-Intervention</head><p>First, we analyzed the pre-intervention behavior across all conditions by estimating the DDM parameters (starting point, drift rate, boundary separation) with the regression formula used for Model 1 (see above  <ref type="figure">Figure   7A</ref>). increased boundary separation-on average, these groups gathered more information before their sharing decision (see <ref type="table">Table S4</ref> for all statistics). Taken together, individual-level characteristics appear to meaningfully predict varying decision-making processes when making news sharing decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pre</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 7</head><p>The DDM Parameters Pre-Intervention and as a Function of Individual-Level Characteristics and Time Note. Panel A: DDM parameters (starting point, drift rate, and boundary separation) pre-intervention. Panel B: Changes in the DDM parameters over the course of the experiment (limited to no-treatment control condition). Baseline indicates the average effect irrespective of individual-level characteristics. The boundary separation, depicted in gray, is a model parameter that cannot be separated into factors attributed to either sharing tendency or sharing quality. Political orientation is coded from liberal (L) to conservative (C). Dots and error bars represent the mean and the 95% CI of the posterior distribution, respectively. * (°) indicates that the 95% (90%) CI does not overlap zero.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time Effect</head><p>To investigate the time effect with the DDM we included only data from the control condition (as was the case in the regression analysis) and applied the formula of Model 2. As in the pre-intervention DDM model, we excluded all terms containing Item Veracity for start point and boundary separation. We investigated how participants' starting point, drift rate, and boundary separation changed over time-from the first half of the experiment to the second half ( <ref type="figure">Figure 7B</ref>).  <ref type="figure">Figure 7B</ref>). These results suggest that decision-making processes over time trend towards lower overall news sharing (across true and false news) but not necessarily higher quality sharing.</p><p>The observed effects were moderated by several individual-level characteristics (see <ref type="table">Table   S5</ref>). For instance, the increase in starting bias against overall news sharing over time was 54.6, respectively). Said another way, with increased exposure to news items, greater analytical thinking and education-level appeared to push participants towards more accurate news sharing when deliberating on the news items.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Intervention Effects</head><p>We examined how participants' DDM parameters were influenced by the interventions <ref type="figure">(Figure 8</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S6</ref>) while accounting for the pre-intervention and time effects using the formula of Model 3, again with terms containing Item Veracity excluded for start point and boundary separation. However, we still include news Item Veracity to predict start points in the presence of warning labels as these labels saliently signal the veracity (see supplemental materials for model description).  <ref type="figure">Figure 8B</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Lin et al., 2023)</ref>. The accuracy prompt did not influence the boundary separation (β = 0.02, CI = [−0.02, 0.07], ER = 5.3; <ref type="figure">Figure 8C</ref>). These process results align with the observed non-credible effect of accuracy prompts on sharing behavior (in terms of sharing quality).</p><p>Individual-level characteristics impacted the starting point and drift rate in terms of overall sharing tendency (e.g., social media use, analytical thinking; see <ref type="figure">Figure 8A-B)</ref>. Regarding sharing quality, the accuracy prompt's lack of influence on drift was fairly robust to individual-level characteristics, except that participants with lower levels of education showed a greater drift rate towards sharing quality after the accuracy prompt (β = −0.07, CI = [−0.14, −0.00], ER = 42.9; <ref type="figure">Figure 8B</ref>). This raises the possibility that accuracy prompts may be effective for less educated individuals (see also <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>) by changing their deliberation (what they think about) during the sharing decision.  <ref type="figure">Figure 8B</ref>). Media literacy was the only intervention that increased the boundary separation, that is, led participants to deliberate longer before deciding whether to share or not (β = 0.12, CI = [0.01, 0.13], ER &gt;100; <ref type="figure">Figure 8C</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 8</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effects of Interventions on DDM Parameters as Compared to the No-Treatment Control Condition as a Function of Individual-Level Characteristics</head><p>Note. Panel A: Effects on starting point. We assume that the starting point can only be influenced by the news item's veracity in the presence of a warning label, which is an immediate and salient signal. Panel B: Effects on drift. Panel C: Effects on boundary separation, depicted in gray, which is a model parameter that cannot be separated into factors attributed to either sharing tendency or sharing quality. Baseline indicates the average effect irrespective of individual-level characteristics. Political orientation is coded from liberal (L) to conservative (C). Dots and error bars represent the mean and the 95% CI of the posterior distribution, respectively. * (°) indicates that the 95% (90%) CI does not overlap zero.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Item-Level Characteristics</head><p>Having considered individual-level characteristics, we turned to item-level characteristics, such as the sensationalism, importance, or familiarity of a news item. Unlike the individual-level models, these models included the item-level characteristics as predictors. Additionally, we examined true and false news sharing behavior separately instead of overall sharing tendency and sharing quality; exploratory analysis revealed that several item-level characteristics were collinear with news Item Veracity, which led to convergence issues when predicting sharing tendency and quality ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S17-S19</ref> Pre-intervention (the first half of the task), item-level characteristics did not appear to meaningfully impact either true or false news sharing behavior ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">Figure 9A</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S7</ref>; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S20</ref>).</p><p>The only credible effect was that participants shared more false news if its content was</p><p>Republican-leaning (as compared to Democrat-leaning) (β = 0.06, CI = [0.01, 0.12], ER = 79).</p><p>Item-level characteristics also neither interacted with the effects of Time (first to the second half of the task) on sharing behavior ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">Figure 9B</ref>, <ref type="table">Table S8</ref>), nor the effects of the interventions on sharing behavior ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">Figure 9C</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S9</ref>). The only credible results were that warning labels were  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">Figure 9C</ref>). As we did on the individual-level, and to account for issues surrounding model specification and overfitting, we conducted regression analysis with each item characteristic separately.. These simpler models confirmed the above described findings (see supplementary materials and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure   S21</ref>).</p><p>Regarding the DDMs, we found no credible effects of item-level characteristics on the drift rate either pre-intervention ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 10A</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S10</ref>) or over time ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 10B</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S11</ref>). We also found little evidence to support news item characteristics as modifying drift in terms of the intervention effects ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 10C</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S12</ref>).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tailoring Interventions to Vulnerable Subpopulations</head><p>Our semi-integrative experimental approach allowed us to identify which groups of people are more (or less) likely to share false news, and which decision-making processes underlie this behavior. In line with past research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Garrett &amp; Bond, 2021)</ref>, we find that conservatives are particularly susceptible to sharing false news <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Figure 3)</ref>. And, our DDM analysis suggests that this demographic group is characterized by a specific choice pathway: Their drift rate-what conservatives think about while making the decision to share or not share-appears to drive their lower sharing quality ( <ref type="figure">Figure 7A</ref>).</p><p>The applied semi-integrative approach can also inform which interventions are most likely to effectively improve the sharing behavior of at-risk groups, such as conservatives. We found warning labels and media literacy tips to be more effective than the social norm and accuracy prompt interventions, suggesting that the former may be better candidates. Moreover, the social norm intervention did not appear to be more or less effective as a function of political orientation.</p><p>Notably, while we found warning labels to be effective among conservatives, the beneficial effect of warning labels on the starting point was attenuated ( <ref type="figure">Figure 8A</ref>). That is, conservatives appear to continue to consider the content of news items even when they are clearly labeled as potentially false, suggesting that this intervention has a less direct impact on this specific group. In contrast, media literacy tips showed a promising trend to be particularly effective among conservatives ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>), specifically by increasing the drift towards news sharing quality ( <ref type="figure">Figure 8A</ref>). Media literacy tips may therefore be the best intervention for this at-risk group (at least when keeping variables outside of the scope of our study, such as potential scalability, constant).</p><p>To illustrate these results, and to allow researchers and policymakers to examine more fine-grained demographic groups (e.g., older conservatives; liberals with limited education), we created an open-source Shiny app (https://alan-tump.shinyapps.io/DSIA/) in which users can select specific individual characteristics and examine the effects of the tested interventions. The app serves as a rapid and intuitive way to assess intervention efficacy within various subsamples of interest, such as groups defined by age, gender, education, and political ideology. For example, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 11</ref> shows how the app can be used to visualize the effect of the media literacy intervention on older conservatives' news-sharing behavior.</p><p>While the app provides valuable insights, we stress that it is purely descriptive-it visualizes patterns observed in our experimental data and does not generate out-of-sample predictions. Users must take into account sample sizes when exploring subgroups and that the results reflect the estimated percentage difference to a counterfactual population that received no treatment rather than precise predictive estimates. A more robust prediction of intervention effectiveness for specific subgroups would require accounting for interactions between predictors and non-linear effects (e.g., U-shaped age effects), which would necessitate substantially larger datasets. Given the size of our dataset (five between-participant conditions with ~200 participants each), such methods would not be appropriate. 6</p><p>Instead, the app provides a structured way to explore how intervention effects are strengthened or weakened for different demographic groups in our data, offering insights into how interventions might be tailored to specific audiences. These findings can help inform the development of targeted intervention strategies, which should then be empirically validated. In doing so, the app contributes to the broader trend of data-as-public-good in the spirit of open science, facilitating further hypothesis testing and scientific advancement (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b122">Vlasceanu et al., 2024</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 11</head><p>Example of the Open-Source Shiny App for an At-Risk Group: Older Conservatives.</p><p>Note. The central panel compares evidence accumulation in the no-treatment control (solid lines) and the selected intervention (dashed lines) conditions. Sliders can be adjusted to investigate the influence of specific individual-level characteristics (here: older conservatives), and interventions can be selected from a dropdown list (here: media literacy tips). In this example, individuals in both conditions start their decision process relatively centrally. For true news the drift rate slightly trends towards "share" for individuals provided with media literacy tips (the green dashed line shows a slightly upwards trajectory), while those in the no-treatment control condition exhibit a slight trend towards "not share" (the solid green line). Conversely, for false news, individuals provided with media literacy tips exhibit a visually stronger drift rate towards "not share" (dashed purple arrow) than those in the no-treatment control condition (solid purple arrow). This difference in drift for true and false news is amplified by individuals in the media literacy tips condition accumulating more evidence before making a sharing decision, indicated by the larger boundary separation (dashed horizontal lines at the top and bottom of the DDM image), than those in the no-treatment control condition (solid horizontal lines). The panel on the right shows the predicted efficacy of the selected intervention as a function of the selected demographics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The goal of this work was to provide a broad, multi-level account of false news sharing and how best to curb it. To achieve this, we applied a semi-integrative approach that combined three key experimental components-each well-supported by prior research but often studied in isolation-into a unified framework: (1) multi-treatment, directly comparing multiple false news interventions;</p><p>(2) effect heterogeneity, examining how individual-and item-level characteristics shape false news sharing and intervention efficacy; and (3) mechanistic processes, using computational modeling to uncover the decision-making processes underlying these effects.</p><p>The first component, which compared multiple interventions, revealed clear differences in their effectiveness. Warning labels and media literacy tips most reliably improved news sharing quality, followed by the social norm intervention. Accuracy prompts were the least effective. The second component, by incorporating individual-and item-level characteristics, shed light on both the risk factors for false news sharing (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Baker, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Bryan et al., 2021)</ref> and the potential for tailoring interventions to specific groups (e.g., . While some individual-level characteristics, such as conservatism, were associated with poorer news sharing quality, they did not meaningfully alter intervention effectiveness. This suggests that the most effective interventions (e.g., warning labels) are broadly applicable, including for at-risk populations.</p><p>Item-level factors, such as the sensationalism and political leaning of news content, also had little impact on intervention efficacy, reinforcing the robustness of the tested interventions across different individuals and news types. Finally, the third component, which applied drift diffusion modeling (DDM), revealed the distinct decision-making processes underlying news sharing and the interventions' effects. Different interventions altered news sharing in significantly different ways. For instance, warning labels reduced sharing by shifting the initial starting point of the decision process, discouraging people from even beginning to deliberate on whether to share the flagged content. In contrast, social norm and media literacy interventions improved sharing quality by influencing how participants weighed evidence during the decision-making process itself.</p><p>These findings suggest that combining interventions targeting different decision-making mechanisms may enhance overall effectiveness.</p><p>Taken together, our findings provide a broad and integrative perspective on false news sharing and how to mitigate it, with implications for reducing its harmful consequences, including misinformed political activism (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Jacobson, 2023)</ref>, poor health decisions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Loomba et al., 2021)</ref>, and even violence <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Lewandowsky et al., 2013</ref>) (though see <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Altay et al., 2023)</ref>.</p><p>Simultaneously, the present work, along with several other examples (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b131">Zhao et al., 2022)</ref>, support the value of applying semi-integrative experimental approaches-for instance, systematically comparing multiple interventions, assessing effect heterogeneity, and examining underlying cognitive processes within a unified framework. These approaches provide a cost-effective way to move beyond the one-shot problem that plagues research in false news and the social sciences more generally-that is, the tendency for studies to test isolated hypotheses, consider only a few parameters, and rely on narrow, unsystematically selected design choices (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Almaatouq et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b125">Watts, 2017)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>False News Interventions</head><p>A key strength of the present work is the inclusion of multiple false news interventions within a single design <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Fazio et al., 2024)</ref>. Consistent with prior research, we find that warning labels, social norm cues, and media literacy interventions improve news sharing quality (at least in the context of a controlled experimental environment; e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Andı &amp; Akesson, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Guess et al., 2020)</ref>. Accuracy prompts, in contrast, did not produce a meaningful change in sharing behavior.</p><p>While this appears to contradict past findings (e.g., , the observed effect size aligns with prior studies. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Lin et al. (2023)</ref> found that accuracy prompts increased sharing discernment-in a DDM-based approach similar to ours-but the effect was small and emerged in an aggregate analysis across six studies <ref type="bibr">(N = 5,338)</ref>. Given that our design used a light-touch, single-headline accuracy prompt (whereas multi-headline prompts yield stronger effects; <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Epstein et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Fazio et al., 2024)</ref> and a smaller sample than <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Lin et al. (2023)</ref>, our study may have been underpowered to detect this subtle effect. That said, the practical significance of this smaller effect size remains an open question (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b92">Pretus et al., 2022)</ref>.</p><p>The multi-treatment component of our semi-integrative approach allowed us to directly compare the effectiveness of multiple interventions. Warning labels and media literacy tips were similarly effective at improving news sharing quality, and both outperformed the social norm intervention, which in turn was more effective than accuracy prompts (which showed no meaningful effect). Notably, replicating past findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Guess et al., 2020)</ref>, media literacy tips were just as effective as warning labels, despite warning labels being highly salient and explicit ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure  S2</ref>). From a theoretical perspective, media literacy tips qualify as a "boosting" intervention-one that enhances individuals' cognitive skills while preserving autonomy, rather than altering the external environment (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Hertwig et al., 2017)</ref>. Warning labels, by contrast, rely on an objective standard of accuracy, often determined through manual fact-checking-a method that is both resource-intensive and difficult to scale (see <ref type="bibr">Martel et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b110">Stencel et al., 2021)</ref>. These findings highlight media literacy tips as a particularly promising approach to combat false news, balancing effectiveness with practical feasibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Individual-Level Characteristics</head><p>The second component of our semi-integrative approach-examining effect heterogeneity-allowed us to identify which individual characteristics (e.g., age, gender, and political orientation) predict news sharing behavior and whether certain interventions are more or less effective for specific groups (personalized interventions; e.g., . At baseline (before any interventions), numerous individual-level traits predicted both overall sharing tendency and sharing quality. Identifying as male, being politically conservative, and lower analytical thinking (among other factors) predicted a greater overall sharing tendency (across true and false news). In line with past work, analytical thinking predicted greater sharing quality (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019)</ref>, as did liberalism (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Guess et al., 2019)</ref>, education-level, and political knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Mazepus et al., 2023)</ref>. Moreover, the positive effects of analytical thinking and education on sharing quality increased from the first to the second half of the news sharing task-as participants encountered more news trials (akin to scrolling through an online newsfeed).</p><p>In contrast, and surprisingly, political congruency-the extent to which a news item's political leaning aligned with a participant's ideology-was not associated with sharing quality (at baseline or over time). This suggests that poor news sharing quality is driven more by cognitive complacency and political identity than by political myside bias (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b100">Roozenbeek et al., 2022a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b117">Van Bavel et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b119">Van der Linden, 2022)</ref>. More broadly, these findings highlight key risk factors for false news sharing, including being male, intuitive thinking, and identifying as politically conservative, while challenging the common assumption that people share misinformation primarily because it aligns with their political beliefs.</p><p>Although individual characteristics predicted both overall news sharing rates and sharing quality, they did not meaningfully alter the effectiveness of the interventions. Of the 40 potential moderation effects (10 modifiers × 4 interventions), four were marginal and only one was credible ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>): Warning labels were more effective in improving news sharing quality among less-educated participants. Given our statistical power to detect moderate-sized moderation effects (~0.3, see <ref type="figure">Figure S5B</ref>), it is possible that smaller effects exist but are unlikely to be practically meaningful. These findings strongly support the generalizability of the observed intervention effects across diverse individual characteristics, suggesting that the most effective interventions-such as warning labels and media literacy tips-improve news sharing quality broadly, including among at-risk subgroups such as conservatives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Item-Level Characteristics</head><p>Our semi-integrative approach also accounted for item-level characteristics-an often overlooked level of analysis in one-shot psychological research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Clark 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Judd et al., 2012</ref>). In the case of news content, these characteristics include attributes such as the sensationalism, familiarity, and political-lean of a news item. Despite their potential relevance, and providing novel evidence for the item-level generalizability of false news interventions, these characteristics did not meaningfully alter intervention effects <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">(Figure 9</ref>). This finding is notable, as it suggests that interventions remain effective across key news types, including sensationalist and highly politicized content. Nevertheless, as artificial intelligence advances, false news is likely to become increasingly sophisticated and harder to detect, potentially changing the nature of these null effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b123">(Waldrop, 2023)</ref>. Future research should examine whether the tested interventions will remain effective as misinformation evolves.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decision-Making Processes</head><p>The third component of our semi-integrative approach used computational modeling, in the form of drift diffusion modeling (DDM), to uncover the cognitive and decision-making processes underlying false news sharing and the effects of the tested interventions. Doing so makes the present work among the first to systematically examine the choice processes underlying news sharing behavior (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Lin et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Orchinik et al., 2023)</ref>.</p><p>Overall Sharing at Baseline. We first considered the role of choice processes in participants' overall tendency to share news (both true and false news) before any interventions were introduced (at baseline). On average, participants began the decision-making process with a slight bias against sharing (starting bias) and became even less likely to share as they considered the news item's content (drift rate). These effects varied across individual characteristics ( <ref type="figure">Figure   7A</ref>). For example, younger participants exhibited a stronger initial reluctance to share (starting bias), liberals were more likely to suppress sharing based on content evaluation (drift rate), and older participants tended to gather more information before making a decision (boundary separation). These findings reveal that decision-making processes vary as a function of individuals' characteristics when making the decision to share (versus not share) news items.</p><p>Sharing Quality at Baseline. Beyond the general tendency to share news, decision-making processes also played a role in sharing quality before the interventions (at baseline). For instance, participants' consideration of the news items' content pushed them towards better sharing quality (drift rate; <ref type="figure">Figure 7A</ref>); this suggests that most people's cognition-what people think about when considering a news item-leads them towards sharing true over false news. This effect was especially pronounced among more analytical and reflective thinkers, liberals, those with higher education, and those with greater political knowledge-factors that appear to enhance the ability to discern false from true news. These findings help explain why some individuals are more susceptible to sharing false news. For example, people who rely less on analytical thinking (e.g.,</p><p>Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019) seem particularly vulnerable not because they share more news overall or because they fail to gather sufficient information, but rather because of what they focus on-or fail to consider-when making news sharing decisions.</p><p>The tendency for participants to exhibit better sharing quality as they considered a news item's content remained stable over time ( <ref type="figure">Figure 7B</ref>), suggesting that repeated exposure to news does not unfortunately, on its own, improve sharing quality. However, this null effect varied by individual characteristics-those higher in analytical thinking and education showed a stronger shift toward better sharing quality over time. This suggests that their cognitive approach to evaluating news becomes increasingly beneficial in environments where they encounter news repeatedly, such as online news feeds.</p><p>Intervention Effects. The tested false news interventions operated via distinct decision-making processes. As expected, the immediate salience of warning labels strongly deterred overall sharing and improved sharing quality early in the decision-making process by shifting participants' initial bias against sharing (starting bias; <ref type="figure">Figure 8A</ref>). However, this effect was less pronounced among conservatives and less-educated participants, who appeared to integrate warning labels into their decision-making later-during content evaluation rather than at the outset ( <ref type="figure">Figure 8B</ref>). This suggests that these groups continued to assess the content of news items even when a warning label was present, potentially allowing them to override the label if they found the content subjectively credible.</p><p>Unlike warning labels, the social norm and media literacy interventions primarily improved sharing quality by influencing how participants processed news content during decision-making (drift rate; <ref type="figure">Figure 8B</ref>). These effects were particularly pronounced among individuals with lower analytical thinking, suggesting that these interventions help this at-risk group (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019)</ref> to change their thinking (or lack thereof) when deciding whether to share.</p><p>Media literacy tips-unlike any other intervention and consistent with previous theorizing <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Guess et al., 2020)</ref>-also encouraged participants to gather more information before making a sharing decision (boundary separation; <ref type="figure">Figure 8C</ref>). This dual effect, increasing both deliberation (drift rate) and evidence accumulation (boundary separation), likely explains the intervention's strong overall efficacy. By prompting participants to weigh information more carefully before deciding, media literacy tips allow deliberation to exert a greater influence on sharing quality.</p><p>These findings not only clarify why, how, and for whom different interventions work, but also suggest which interventions could be complementary. While warning labels primarily influence decision-making at the outset, social norm and media literacy interventions shape what participants focus on when evaluating content. This highlights a key advantage of examining the cognitive mechanisms behind intervention effects-by understanding the underlying choice processes, we can better identify which combination of interventions maximizes efficacy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Subpopulations At-Risk for False News Sharing</head><p>The semi-integrative approach we applied provides insight into which subpopulations are most at risk for sharing false news and why. Consistent with prior research <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Guess et al., 2019)</ref>, our findings ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 3</ref>) indicate that conservatives are particularly vulnerable. Extending this work, we find that conservatives' lower news sharing quality ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 3A)</ref> is driven by how they process information during decision-making-specifically, by what they focus on (or fail to consider) and</p><p>by their tendency to gather less information before making a sharing decision. Notably, this effect is not due to a greater initial bias toward sharing news compared to liberals ( <ref type="figure">Figure 7A</ref>).</p><p>Our approach also sheds light on which interventions are most effective for at-risk populations and how these interventions exert their effects. For instance, our findings suggest that media literacy tips may be the most effective intervention for conservatives. This intervention showed a promising trend of improving conservatives' news sharing quality ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>), specifically by influencing their deliberation during content evaluation ( <ref type="figure">Figure 8B</ref>). In contrast, while warning labels were similarly effective, conservatives continued to assess the content of flagged news items rather than dismissing them outright. This reveals a degree of nuance. While warning labels are similarly effective across liberals and conservatives, they have a less direct impact on conservatives, potentially because conservatives are more likely to distrust fact-checking efforts in general <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">(Robertson et al., 2020)</ref>.</p><p>To help researchers and policymakers examine specific demographic groups within our studied population (e.g., conservatives, older individuals, liberals with limited education), we developed an open-source Shiny app (https://alan-tump.shinyapps.io/DSIA/). This tool provides a dynamic, interactive visualization of the tested interventions' effects, showing how these effects vary based on individual-and item-level characteristics <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 11</ref>; see Vlasceanu et al., 2024 for a similar approach). The app updates a visual representation of the DDM dynamically, allowing users to explore which of the four tested interventions most effectively reduced false news sharing-and how they did so in terms of the underlying decision-making processes-for specific target groups. However, we emphasize that the app is purely descriptive-it visualizes patterns observed in our data and does not generate out-of-sample predictions. Its findings are constrained by the study's sample size and design, making it a tool for exploration rather than prediction.</p><p>Nevertheless, the app offers a structured way to explore how intervention effects may vary across demographic groups, providing insights that can inform targeted intervention strategies. By making the app openly available, we contribute to the broader trend of data-as-public-good, fostering further hypothesis testing and scientific advancement (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b122">Vlasceanu et al., 2024)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Semi-Integrative Approaches as an Experimental Method</head><p>Our work not only advances false news research but also highlights semi-integrative experimental approaches as a method for studying human choice and behavior. Much of the social sciences suffer from a one-shot problem-studies are typically isolated, singular experiments that examine only a few parameters and rely on design choices selected unsystematically (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Almaatouq et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Muthukrishna &amp; Henrich, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Newell, 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b100">Roozenbeek et al., 2022a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b118">Van Bavel et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b125">Watts, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b127">Yarkoni, 2020)</ref>. The semi-integrative experimental approach applied here-combining multiple interventions, individual-and item-level modifiers, and computational choice modeling within a single framework-offers a way to address this limitation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Almaatouq et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Larson, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b124">Watts, 2011)</ref>. Similar semi-integrative frameworks as the one applied here could be applied to a wide range of domains. For instance, they could be used to study altruistic behavior and the effectiveness of prosocial interventions, or to examine more routine decisions, such as consumer choice. Supporting this broad applicability, semi-integrative designs have been applied successfully to compare multiple decision-making influences in simple contexts-such as evaluating how factors like recommendations, salience, and cost shape restaurant choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b131">(Zhao et al., 2022)</ref>.</p><p>Although integrative designs afford broader insights into psychological phenomena than narrow, single-effect studies, they have some costs. Primary among these is increased complexity, both in design and analysis, which typically necessitates larger sample sizes to achieve statistical power. Fully integrative approaches-those that cross multiple between-subjects factors-are resource-intensive, often requiring prohibitively large samples (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Almaatouq et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Awad et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Baribault et al., 2018;</ref>. The present semi-integrative design avoids such factorial complexity, deliberating attempting to balance inferential potential and practical feasibility. Our sample size of ~1,200 participants-well within the bounds of contemporary behavioral research-was sufficient to detect both average treatment effects and heterogeneity in those effects of moderate to large magnitude. For instance, we were well powered to detect increases in sharing quality, of approximately 3 to 4 percentage points. By striking a balance between real-world complexity and experimental feasibility, semi-integrative approaches may offer a scalable, efficient way to deepen our understanding of human decision-making across diverse settings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations</head><p>No single experimental approach can capture all dimensions, and the approach we applied is no exception. Certain parameters were beyond the scope of our study, leaving open questions for future research. For instance, we did not examine how the data collection platform might influence results-participants' intention to share false news can vary significantly across platforms (e.g., Lucid vs. Prolific; <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Martel &amp; Rand, 2023b)</ref>. Similarly, while our news stimuli varied along dimensions such as sensationalism and political leaning, these dimensions are far from fully representative. The tested interventions also leave room for further discussion. For example, in the media literacy intervention, we could have manipulated the number of tips provided, and in the accuracy prompt intervention, increasing the number of headlines participants evaluated may have led to more credible effects (as found in <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Fazio et al., 2024)</ref>. Expanding the parameter space around false news interventions remains an important direction for future research, offering further opportunities to refine, optimize, and generalize intervention strategies.</p><p>While our study examined effect modification (i.e., how individual-and item-level characteristics relate to treatment effects), we did not test causal interactions. This limits the generalizability of our findings to other populations, particularly outside the U.S., where different causal mechanisms may shape false news sharing and intervention effectiveness <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Bareinboim &amp; Pearl, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Deffner, Rohrer, &amp; McElreath, 2022)</ref>. That said, even non-causal associations between intervention effects and third variables are valuable for both researchers and practitioners, providing crucial guidance on who might benefit the most from a given intervention (as long as the distribution of covariates in the target population reasonably resembles the studied sample; Rohrer et al., 2022).</p><p>News sharing behavior in our task was simulated, with participants making explicit "share" vs. "not share" decisions for each news item. This reflects their immediate sharing intention in a controlled setting, which differs from real-world social media environments, where factors like audience composition, reputational concerns, platform algorithms, and social feedback influence what people ultimately share. While we use the term "false news sharing," it is important to note that sharing decisions in controlled experiments may not fully capture real-world sharing behavior.</p><p>Additionally, our task presented an equal number of true and false news trials, an artificial balance that differs from real-world veracity base rates <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">(Orchinik et al., 2023)</ref>. Although self-reported sharing intentions and lab-based sharing decisions are commonly used as proxies in misinformation research, relatively few studies have tested how well these proxies map onto real-world sharing. Providing some support for their validity, self-reported willingness to share political news in online surveys correlates well with actual social media sharing behavior <ref type="bibr">(Mosleh et al., 2020)</ref> News sharing behavior in our task was simulated, with an equal number of true and false news trials-an artificial balance that likely differs from real-world veracity base rates <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">(Orchinik et al., 2023)</ref>. Additionally, sharing behavior in our controlled setting may not fully capture the complexities of real-world social media environments, where factors such as the social relationship between the poster and the sharer, the size of a user's audience, and the demographic composition of their followers can all influence sharing decisions. That said, prior research suggests that self-reported willingness to share political news in online surveys correlates well with actual sharing behavior on social media (Mosleh et al., 2020), providing some confidence that our findings generalize to real-world settings.</p><p>The observed effectiveness of the tested interventions may also be shaped by external factors that were not accounted for in our study. For instance, false news interventions may elicit varying levels of resistance across different subgroups, differ in how engaging they are, and produce effects that vary in longevity. Media literacy tips, in particular, require more time and effort from users, which could limit their adoption outside a controlled study setting. However, as a boosting intervention (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Kozyreva et al., 2022)</ref>, media literacy may have a more lasting impact on sharing quality compared to interventions that rely on external cues, such as warning labels.</p><p>Additionally, our study did not examine whether the interventions differentially influenced how participants processed specific aspects of news items-such as headline titles, associated images, or source credibility. Future research should explore these finer-grained components of news evaluation to better understand the mechanisms driving intervention effects.</p><p>Our findings are limited to psychologically informed, individual-level interventions and do not speak to the effectiveness of system-level interventions. Addressing the spread of misinformation at scale is unlikely to be achieved through individual-focused strategies alone, as the underlying causes are largely systemic. Long-term behavioral change may require broader interventions, such as regulatory actions or platform design modifications <ref type="bibr">(Chater &amp; Loewenstein, 2022)</ref>. That said, individual-level interventions-such as labels, prompts, and media literacy tips-can still play a meaningful role in improving news sharing quality, particularly in the absence of systemic reforms. Our findings highlight how different interventions, when applied individually, influence sharing behavior, including among high-risk subpopulations <ref type="bibr">(Budak et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr">Brashier, 2024)</ref>. Future research should explore how individual-and system-level interventions interact, assessing whether their combined implementation offers a complementary and more effective approach to mitigating misinformation <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Bode &amp; Vraga, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Some research suggests that a significant share of misinformation is spread by well-known, verified, and highly influential users (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">DeVerna et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Grinberg et al., 2019)</ref>. While our sample included only participants who reported actively sharing news on social media, it is unlikely that it captured these high-profile accounts. Additionally, real-world misinformation spread is shaped by external forces-such as algorithmic amplification-that may constrain the effectiveness of applying these interventions at scale. Given these limitations, caution is warranted when extrapolating our findings to broader real-world contexts. The feasibility of implementing these interventions at scale remains uncertain, particularly in environments where misinformation is driven more strongly by structural and algorithmic dynamics than individual decision-making.</p><p>We examined the effects of interventions on false news claims with low plausibility, following the sampling approach of . Blatantly false claims represent a significant category of misinformation; their real-world relevance is underscored by field data showing that highly implausible articles from low-quality news sources are often widely shared (Stewart et al., 2021)-potentially because individuals endorse the general "gist" of their content rather than their literal accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Langdon et al., 2024)</ref>. Experimental evidence further suggests that, once exposed, false claims can exert strong and harmful effects on behavioral intentions <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Allen et al., 2024)</ref>. That said, our study did not examine misleading (rather than outright false) claims, which can still misinform and shape public beliefs. And, such content may be more impactful in practice. For instance, Allen et al. (2024) find that vaccine-skeptical news articles that are technically accurate but misleading (e.g., a headline stating, "Healthy doctor dies after receiving a COVID-19 vaccine") receive significantly more views on Facebook than blatantly false vaccine-skeptical content. Given their higher exposure rates, misleading claims may exert a greater cumulative influence on public attitudes and behaviors than outright falsehoods. Future research should examine how misinformation-targeting interventions-such as those tested here-perform against content that is technically true but misleading, as well as against false claims that vary in plausibility. Understanding how intervention efficacy differs across these categories will provide a more complete picture of how to combat misinformation in complex, real-world settings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Although many studies have examined false news sharing, there has been no broad, comparative, and computational analysis of this harmful behavior and the interventions designed to mitigate it. We addressed this gap by applying a semi-integrative experimental approach to false news sharing. Our approach revealed the comparative efficacy of multiple false news interventions, whether and how individual-and item-level characteristics shape false news sharing and intervention effectiveness, and the decision-making processes underlying all these effects. In doing so, we uncovered key insights into false news sharing, such as that existing interventions appear effective across numerous individual and content characteristics-including among significant risk factors, such as political conservatism. Though these insights contribute to ongoing efforts to curb false news sharing, intervention-based strategies alone are unlikely to be sufficient.</p><p>Substantial changes to the information ecosystem, such as the automated removal of false content and stricter enforcement against repeat offenders, are likely necessary to meaningfully reduce false news spread and influence.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>For knowledge-based variables, we included two measures of media literacy and one measure of political knowledge. The first media literacy measure assessed participants' knowledge of the Facebook algorithm: "How are decisions about what stories to show people on Facebook made?" (1 = At Random, 2 = By editors and journalists that work for news outlets, 3 = By editors and journalists that work for Facebook, 4 = By computer analysis of what stories might interest you)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Examples of News ItemsNote. Panels A, B: True news items. Panels C, D: False news items.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Social</head><label></label><figDesc>Norm Intervention. The social norm intervention was adapted from Epstein et al. (2021) and Gimpel et al. (2021) and included an injunctive norm intervention (i.e., what people should do). After the pre-intervention trials, participants read: "You are halfway through the task.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>-intervention sharing tendency and sharing quality varied as a function of individual characteristics (12 credible effects; Figure 3A). For instance, male participants exhibited a higher overall sharing tendency ( = 0.16, CI = [0.04, 0.27], ER &gt;100), while participants with higher β analytical thinking (higher CRT-scores) shared less ( = −0.14, CI = [−0.20, −0.08], ER &gt;100). β Additionally, and informing the debate about whether susceptibility to false news is driven by cognitive complacency, political ideology, or political myside bias (e.g., Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2021a; Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019; Roozenbeek et al., 2022a; Van Bavel et al., 2021; Van der Linden, 2022), higher analytical thinking (CRT-scores) and liberal political orientation credibly predicted greater sharing quality ( = 0.09, CI = [0.02, 0.15], ER &gt;100; and = 0.11, CI = β β [0.18, 0.04], ER &gt;100, respectively), while the political congruency of the news item-whether the item aligned with participants' own political orientation-did not ( = −0.01, CI = [−0.07, 0.08], β ER = 1.8). See</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>random intercepts. The time effect analysis was limited to participants in the no-treatment control condition (since Time and intervention effects are confounded in the other conditions). See supplementary material for details. Comparing sharing behavior from the first to the second half of the task revealed that participants shared less over time ( = −0.19, CI = [−0.28, −0.10], ER &gt;100) but did not exhibit a β change in sharing quality ( = 0.00, CI = [−0.15, 0.16], ER = 1).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, except that higher analytical thinking predicted a reduction in overall sharing tendency over time ( = −0.09, β CI = [−0.17, −0.01], ER =90.7), and higher analytical thinking and greater education levels predicted an increase in sharing quality over time ( = 0.16, CI = [0.01, 0.31], ER =56.8; and β β = 0.17, CI = [0.01, 0.33], ER =47.1; respectively).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Sharing Behavior Pre-Intervention as a Function of Individual-Level Characteristics and TimeNote. Orange dots represent coefficients of overall sharing tendency. Black dots represent sharing quality. Panel A: Participants' sharing behavior pre-intervention. Panel B: Change in participants' sharing behavior over the course of the experiment (limited to the no-treatment control condition). Baseline indicates the average effect irrespective of individual-level characteristics. Political orientation is coded from liberal (L) to conservative (C). Dots and error bars represent the mean and the 95% credible interval (CI) of the posterior distribution, respectively. * (°) indicates that the 95% (90%) CI does not overlap zero.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 4 Figure 5 Figure 6</head><label>456</label><figDesc>Participants' Sharing Probabilities forTrue and False News Items, Pre-and Post-Intervention    Note. Participants' sharing probabilities of true (green) and false (purple) news pre-and post-intervention. Each panel shows the sharing probabilities in the no-treatment control condition (dots; the same across panels) and the respective intervention (triangles). Panel A: accuracy prompts. Panel B: warning labels. Panel C: social norm. Panel D: media literacy. Dots and triangles depict the mean.Error bars: 2 SE. ± The Observed Effect of Interventions on Participants' Sharing Probabilities Note. Panel A: Overall change of participants' sharing probabilities from pre-to post-intervention (the first to the second half of the experiment) by condition. Panel B: Change in sharing quality from pre-to post-intervention (change in probabilities of sharing true news minus change in probabilities of sharing false news) by condition. Panel C: Change in sharing probabilities by condition, separately for true and false news. Bars show the empirical mean. Error bars: 2 SE. ± Effects of Interventions on Sharing Behavior as Compared to the No-Treatment Control Condition as a Function of Individual-Level Characteristics Note. Orange dots represent the overall sharing tendency. Black points represent sharing quality. Baseline indicates the average effect of the intervention irrespective of individual-and item-level characteristics compared to the no-treatment control condition. Political orientation is coded from liberal (L) to conservative (C). Dots and error bars represent the mean and the 95% CI of the posterior distribution, respectively. * (°) indicates that the 95% (90%) CI does not overlap zero.Accuracy Prompt Intervention. Participants in the accuracy prompt intervention exhibited a reduction of 1.4 percentage points (heretofore denoted as "% points") in overall sharing tendency (across true and false news) from pre-to post-intervention. This reduction credibly differed from participants in the control condition, who exhibited a reduction of 3% points ( = β 0.12, CI = [0.01, 0.24], ER &gt;51.1; coefficients are probit estimates, not probabilities;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Warning</head><label></label><figDesc>Label Intervention. Participants in the warning labels intervention exhibited a reduction of 4.3% points in overall sharing tendency from pre-to post-intervention. This reduction credibly differed from participants in the control condition, who exhibited a reduction of 3% points ( = −0.26, CI = [−0.39, −0.13], ER &gt;100;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Social</head><label></label><figDesc>Norm Intervention. Participants in the social norm intervention exhibited a reduction of 3% points in overall sharing tendency from pre-to post-intervention. This reduction did not credibly differ from participants in the control condition ( = −0.09, CI = [−0.20, 0.03], β ER =13.1; Figure 5A). This effect was moderated by media literacy; individuals with greater media literacy exhibited a smaller reduction in overall sharing tendency from pre-to post-intervention as compared to the control condition ( = 0.11, CI = [0.00, 0.21], ER =40; β</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 6).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Media</head><label></label><figDesc>Literacy Intervention. Participants in the media literacy intervention exhibited a reduction of 3.3% points in overall sharing tendency from pre-to post-intervention. This reduction did not credibly differ from participants in the control condition ( = −0.11, CI = [−0.23, 0.01];</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Comparative</head><label></label><figDesc>Effect Sizes. The interventions differentially influenced overall sharing tendency (across true and false news). The accuracy prompt intervention credibly increased overall sharing tendency compared to the other interventions (vs. warning label: = 0.38, CI = [0.27, β 0.49], ER &gt;100; social norm: = 0.21, CI = [0.11, 0.31], ER &gt;100; media literacy: = 0.24, CI β β = [0.13, 0.34], ER &gt;100). The warning labels intervention decreased the overall sharing tendency credibly more than either the social norm ( = −0.18, CI = [−0.29, −0.07], ER &gt;100) or media β literacy intervention ( = −0.15, CI = [−0.26, −0.03], ER =60.1). The social norm and media β literacy interventions did not differ in overall sharing tendency ( = 0.03, CI = [−0.08, 0.13], ER β =2.0). Regarding sharing quality, the warning label and media literacy interventions both effectively increased sharing quality to a similar degree ( = −0.06, CI = [−0.26, 0.15], ER =2.0). β Warnings labels and media literacy tips were also both credibly more effective than the social norm intervention (warning labels: = 0.42, CI = [0.23, 0.62], ER &gt;100; media literacy: = 0.48, CI β β = [0.29, 0.66], ER &gt;100). Finally, all three interventions were credibly more effective than the accuracy prompt intervention (warning label: = 0.70, CI = [0.51, 0.90], ER &gt;100; social norm: β = 0.28, CI = [0.10, 0.45], ER &gt;100; media literacy: = 0.76, CI = [0.58, 0.94], ER &gt;100). β β Inference Robustness Across Individual Characteristics. We inspected correlations between individual-level characteristics. Discounting issues surrounding multicollinearity, correlations between the individual-level predictors were small (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>-intervention DDM parameters varied as a function of individual-level characteristics. For instance, older participants exhibited a starting bias closer to sharing news (β = 0.10, CI = [0.07, 0.14], ER &gt;100) (Figure 7A). The observed drift rate against sharing news was particularly pronounced, for instance, for individuals identifying as female (β = 0.06, CI = [0.01, 0.11], ER &gt;100), more liberal participants (β = 0.09, CI = [0.06, 0.11], ER &gt;100), and for politically non-congruent news (β = 0.19, CI = [0.17, 0.20], ER &gt;100). The influence of news accuracy (sharing quality) on the drift was stronger, for instance, for more liberal participants (β = 0.06, CI = [0.03, 0.08], ER &gt;100), participants higher in analytical thinking (β = 0.04, CI = [0.01, 0.06], ER &gt;100), and participants with greater political knowledge (β = 0.07, CI = [0.04, 0.09], ER &gt;100). The boundary separation also varied as a function of several individual-level characteristics (Figure 7A). For instance, older participants (β = 0.07, CI = [0.05, 0.09], ER &gt;100) and participants with high media literacy scores (β = 0.03, CI = [0.02, 0.05], ER &gt;100) exhibited an</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Regarding change in overall sharing tendency, participants' starting bias and drift against sharing became more pronounced over time (β = −0.12, CI = [−0.20, −0.05], ER &gt;100 and β = −0.05, CI = [−0.09, −0.02], ER &gt;100, respectively), and the boundary separation reduced over time (β = −0.06, CI = [−0.10, −0.02], ER &gt;100). Regarding sharing quality, participants' drift rate did not change over time (β = 0.03, CI = [−0.03, 0.08], ER = 5.6;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>especially pronounced for participants with higher political knowledge (β = −0.13, CI = [−0.21, −0.05], ER &gt;100). The increase in the drift rate against sharing news over time was greater for individuals higher in analytical thinking (β = −0.05, CI = [−0.09, −0.01], ER &gt;100). And, while there was no baseline change of the drift rate regarding sharing quality, individuals with higher education levels and higher analytical thinking exhibited an increase in drift rate towards sharing quality over time (β = 0.06, CI = [0.01, 0.12], ER = 74.8 and β = 0.06, CI = [0.01, 0.12], ER =</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Accuracy</head><label></label><figDesc>Prompt Intervention. The accuracy prompt did not impact the starting point (β = 0.00, CI = [−0.10, 0.10], ER = 1, Figure 8A). And, while the accuracy prompt increased drift rate towards overall sharing (β = 0.06, CI = [0.01, 0.11], ER = 60.7), it did not increase the drift rate towards sharing quality, though the observed effect was directionally in line with past research (β = 0.02, CI = [−0.05, 0.09], ER = 2.2;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>Warning</head><label></label><figDesc>Label Intervention. The warning label intervention shifted participants' starting point towards less sharing overall (β = -0.28, CI = [-0.38, -0.17], ER &gt;100; Figure 8A), and towards greater sharing quality (β = 0.39, CI = [0.30, 0.47], ER &gt;100). In contrast, and likely due to their large impact on the starting point, warning labels had limited influence on the deliberation process-drift rate and boundary separation-despite the news items and warnings labels being present throughout the entire decision-making process (drift rate towards sharing quality: β = 0.04, CI = [−0.05, 0.12], ER = 4.8; boundary separation: β = 0.00, CI = [−0.04, 0.05], ER = 1.3; Figure 8B-C). The estimated DDM parameters varied as a function of several individual-level characteristics (Figure 8; Table S6). For instance, more conservative and less educated participants incorporated the warning labels less via the starting point (political leaning: β = −0.16, CI = [−0.24, −0.07], ER &gt;100; education: β = 0.12, CI = [0.04, 0.20], , ER &gt;100; Figure 8A) and more so via the drift rate (political leaning: β = 0.13, CI = [0.05, 0.21], ER &gt;100; education: β = −0.11, CI = [−0.19, −0.04], ER &gt;100;Figure 8B). Thus, they tended to continuously assess the news items in light of the warning label being present or absent. Finally, the drift rate towards sharing quality was also particularly pronounced for items that aligned with participants' political orientation (political congruence; β = 0.08, CI = [0.01, 0.15], ER &gt;67.0;Figure 8B).Social Norm Intervention. The social norm intervention did not change the starting point (β = −0.04, CI = [−0.14, 0.06], ER = 3.5;Figure 8A) but did increase news sharing quality via the drift (β = 0.08, CI = [0.02, 0.15], ER &gt;100;Figure 8B). Participants with lower analytical thinking exhibited a particularly pronounced drift towards higher sharing quality (β = −0.09, CI = [−0.16, −0.02], ER &gt;100;Figure 8B), indicating that intuitive thinkers were particularly likely to incorporate the normative information of the intervention when deliberating on the news items.Media LiteracyIntervention. The media literacy intervention, similar to the social norm intervention, did not change the starting point but did improve the sharing quality via drift (β = 0.24, CI = [0.17, 0.30], ER &gt;100; Figure 8A-B), and again, this was particularly true for participants with lower analytical thinking (β = −0.07 CI = [−0.14, −0.00], ER = 53.1) and for news items that aligned with participants' political orientation (political congruence (β = 0.07, CI = [0.01, 0.13]). (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). Except for this change, the conducted models mirrored the individual-level characteristics regression models (Models 1-3). Hence, we first investigated pre-intervention behavior with Model 4 (mirroring Model 1), time effects with Model 5 (mirroring Model 2), and treatment effects with Model 6 (mirroring Model 3). Similarly, the DDMs were the same as the DDMs investigating individual-level characteristics. However, we assumed that unlike individual-level characteristics, item-level characteristics can only influence the drift rate because item-level characteristics are attributes of the stimuli themselves-inferring and incorporating these characteristics is part of the information evaluation process described by the drift (see<ref type="bibr" target="#b126">Yang &amp; Krajbich, 2023)</ref>. For a full description of the regression and DDM models, see supplemental materials.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>particularly effective at reducing the sharing of Republican-leaning (vs. Democrat-leaning) false news items (β = −0.24, CI = [−0.44, −0.04], ER = 83,3) and highly partisan false news items (versus more politically neutral items) (β = −0.17, CI = [−0.31, −0.03], ER &gt;100;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>Figure 9 Sharing</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Behavior as a Function of Item-Level CharacteristicsNote. Panel A: Sharing behavior of participants pre-intervention. Panel B: Change in sharing behavior over the course of the experiment (limited to the no-treatment control condition). Panel C: Effects of interventions on sharing behavior. Baseline indicates the average effect irrespective of individual-and item-level characteristics. True and false news items were analyzed separately due to multicollinearity issues. Political leaning is coded from democratic favoring (D) to republican favoring (R) news. Dots and error bars represent the mean and the 95% CI of the posterior distribution, respectively. * (°) indicates that the 95% (90%) CI does not overlap zero.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Figure 10 DDM</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Parameters as a Function of Item-Level CharacteristicsNote. DDM parameters for starting point and boundary separation were estimated independent of news veracity (gray). Drift rate was estimated separately for true (green) and false (purple) news, as a function of news item characteristics. Panel A: Pre-intervention. Panel B: Change over time (from first to second half of the experiment). The start point and boundary separation, depicted in gray, are constant across true and false news. Panel C: Effects of the interventions on the drift rate. Baseline indicates the average effect irrespective of individual-and item-level characteristics. True and false news items were analyzed in separate models due to multicollinearity issues. Political leaning is coded from democratic favoring (D) to republican favoring (R) news. Dots and error bars represent the mean and the 95% CI of the posterior distribution, respectively. * (°) indicates that the 95% (90%) CI does not overlap zero.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>ER &gt;100; coefficients are on a probit scale). Participants shared 30% of the true news items and 14% of the false news items, suggesting they value accuracy when deciding to share ( β = 0.63, CI = [0.44, 0.82], ER &gt;100). Pre-intervention sharing tendency and sharing quality did not differ by condition (see</figDesc><table><row><cell>Item Veracity (to investigate sharing quality). The model included pre-intervention sharing across</cell></row><row><cell>all conditions. See supplementary material for details.</cell></row><row><cell>Pre-intervention, participants across conditions shared 22% of news items (across true and</cell></row><row><cell>false news), indicating a general inclination against sharing news ( = −1.15, 95% CI = [−1.26, β</cell></row><row><cell>−1.04],</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">As the conducted approach was "bottom-up" the pre-registration did not include specific hypotheses. For transparency's sake, we note that the pre-registration outlined the general analysis approach and did not include the specific model formulas.2 Failing to complete any part of the news sharing task could not have been impacted by condition, as the interventions occurred in the middle of the task itself.1  We note that the scale of this measure was not ideal, as it is somewhat unclear what 'always' indicates in terms of sharing behavior. This limitation should be considered when interpreting our findings.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">We additionally assessed when and on which platform participants use social media. This measure was not included in the analysis due to its complexity. We also assessed a measure of single items (e.g., "I am a gullible person"). These items were not included in the analysis given their unknown validity and reliability, and because they were assessed solely for exploratory purposes. All other assessed measures were included in the analysis.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Inoculation or prebunking interventions were not included as they are typically much longer than the other interventions (e.g.,<ref type="bibr" target="#b101">Roozenbeek &amp; Van der Linden, 2019)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">This is why we did not apply cross-validation or other machine learning-based analyses, which are designed for predictive accuracy rather than the description of observed experimental effects.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Germany's Excellence Strategy -EXC 2002/1 "Science of Intelligence" -project number 390523135. We are very thankful to Deborah Ain for editing the manuscript.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author Contributions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing Interests</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Misleading claims about tobacco products in YouTube videos: experimental effects of misinformation on unhealthy attitudes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Albarracin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Romer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hall Jamieson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Jamieson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Medical Internet Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">229</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The welfare effects of social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Allcott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Braghieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Eichmeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gentzkow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="676" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social media and fake news in the 2016 election</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Allcott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gentzkow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task complexity moderates group synergy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Almaatouq</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Alsobay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond playing 20 questions with nature: Integrative experiment design in the social and behavioral sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Almaatouq</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Suchow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Whiting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Misinformation on misinformation: Conceptual and methodological challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Altay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Berriche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acerbi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Media + Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20563051221150412</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nudging away false news: Evidence from a social norms experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Andı</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Akesson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Digital Journalism</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="106" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The moral machine experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Awad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dsouza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Henrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shariff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Rahwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">563</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The basics of item response theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ericae.net/irt/baker." />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causal inference and the data-fusion problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bareinboim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pearl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7345" to="7352" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metastudies for robust tests of theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Baribault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Oravecz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Vandekerckhove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2607" to="2612" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Swiss cheese model for mitigating online misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Vraga</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Bayesian regression to test hypotheses about relationships between parameters and covariates in cognitive models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Steingroever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior research methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1248" to="1269" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bourgin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reichman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive model priors for predicting human decisions</title>
		<idno>PMLR</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5133" to="5141" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determinants of individuals&apos; belief in fake news: A scoping review determinants of belief in fake news</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bryanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Vziatysheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">253717</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bourgin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reichman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive model priors for predicting human decisions</title>
		<idno>PMLR</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5133" to="5141" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Timing matters when correcting fake news</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Brashier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioural science is unlikely to change the world without a heterogeneity revolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tipton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yeager</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="980" to="989" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">brms: An R package for Bayesian multilevel models using Stan</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bürkner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of statistical software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sharing of misinformation is habitual, not just lazy or biased</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ceylan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2216614120</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The language-as-fixed-effect fallacy: A critique of language statistics in psychological research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of verbal learning and verbal behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="359" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple timescales of learning indicated by changes in evidence-accumulation processes during perceptual decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cochrane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sims</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bejjanki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bavelier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science of Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">19</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">It&apos;s the effect size, stupid</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Coe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">British Educational Research Association Annual Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002-09" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">14</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Digital transformation in healthcare: an ecosystem approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Constantinides</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<pubPlace>Taylor &amp; Francis</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A causal framework for cross-cultural generalizability. Advances in methods and practices in psychological science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rohrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcelreath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">25152459221106366</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Identification and characterization of misinformation superspreaders on social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Deverna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Aiyappa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pacheco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bryden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Menczer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2207.09524</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Emphasizing publishers does not effectively reduce susceptibility to misinformation on social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Dias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Concrete recommendations for cutting through misinformation during the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Donovan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Public Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="286" to="287" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creative or not? Hierarchical diffusion modeling of the creative evaluation process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Donzallaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Haaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">849</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ecker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Fazio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Brashier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychological drivers of misinformation belief and its resistance to correction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>&amp; Amazeen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developing an accuracy-prompt toolkit to reduce COVID-19 misinformation online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gully</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.37016/mr-2020-71</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.37016/mr-2020-71" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Kennedy School Misinformation Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How sample size influences research outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Faber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fonseca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dental Press Journal of Orthodontics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Combating misinformation: A megastudy of nine interventions designed to reduce the sharing of and belief in false and misleading headlines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fazio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Susmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Guess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Swire-Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/uyjha</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/uyjha" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024-06-23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing the drift-diffusion model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fudenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Newey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Strack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Strzalecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33141" to="33148" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conservatives&apos; susceptibility to political misperceptions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Garrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bond</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1234</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effectiveness of social norms in fighting fake news on social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gimpel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Heger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Olenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Utz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Management Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="196" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fake news on Twitter during the 2016 US presidential election</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Grinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Friedland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Swire-Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">363</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="374" to="378" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to think about whether misinformation interventions work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Guay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A digital media literacy intervention increases discernment between mainstream and false news in the United States and India</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Guess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lyons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nyhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Reifler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sircar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15536" to="15545" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Less than you think: Prevalence and predictors of fake news dissemination on Facebook</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Guess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nagler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4586</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Causal Inference: What If</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hernán</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Robins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
			<publisher>Chapman and Hall/CRC</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nudging and boosting: Steering or empowering good decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Grüne-Yanoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="973" to="986" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding (and Reducing) Inaction on Climate Change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hornsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fielding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Issues and Policy Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Treating stimuli as a random factor in social psychology: a new and comprehensive solution to a pervasive but largely ignored problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Judd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Westfall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kenny</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">54</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Dimensions, Origins, and Consequences of Belief in Donald Trump&apos;s Big Lie</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jacobson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/psq.12716</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/psq.12716" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Presidential Studies Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="289" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Political Science Quarterly</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Toolbox of Interventions Against Online Misinformation and Manipulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kozyreva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Lorenz-Spreen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Herzog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">K H</forename><surname>Ecker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/x8ejt</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/x8ejt" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="795" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">It&apos;s not literally true, but you get the gist:&quot; how nuanced understandings of truth encourage people to condone and spread misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Langdon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Helgason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Effron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">In search of synergy in small group performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The science of fake news</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Baum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Benkler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Greenhill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Menczer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Zittrain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">359</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1094" to="1096" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feedback exercises boost discernment of misinformation for gamified inoculation interventions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Schellinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Maertens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chryst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roozenbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">153</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2068</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cynical nonpartisans: the role of misinformation in political cynicism during the 2020 US Presidential Election. new media &amp; society</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Jones-Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Understanding the global landscape of digital skill on Facebook</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Redmiles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/a2bw4/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Misinformation and its correction: Continued influence and successful debiasing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ecker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Seifert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science in the Public Interest</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="106" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Stritzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Freund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Krueger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Misinformation, disinformation, and violent conflict: From Iraq and the &quot;War on Terror&quot; to future threats to peace</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">487</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Countering misinformation and fake news through inoculation and prebunking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Review of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="348" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Research commentary-too big to fail: large samples and the p-value problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lucas</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Shmueli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Systems Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="906" to="917" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thinking more or thinking differently? Using drift-diffusion modeling to illuminate why accuracy prompts decrease misinformation sharing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">230</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105312</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the impact of COVID-19 vaccine misinformation on vaccination intent in the UK and USA</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Loomba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>De Figueiredo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Piatek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>De Graaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="348" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Macmillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Creelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4324/9781410611147</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.4324/9781410611147" />
		<title level="m">Detection Theory: A User&apos;s Guide</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowds can effectively identify misinformation at scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Martel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="477" to="488" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fact-checker warning labels are effective even for those who distrust fact-checkers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Martel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/t2pmb</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/t2pmb" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Misinformation warning labels are widely effective: A review of warning effects and their moderating features. Current Opinion in Psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Martel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="page">101710</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information battleground: conflict perceptions motivate the belief in and sharing of misinformation about the adversary</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Mazepus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Osmundsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Petersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Toshkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Dimitrova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://hdl.handle.net/1887/3633934" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Plos One</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cleaning up social media: The effect of warning labels on likelihood of sharing false news on Facebook</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mena</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Policy &amp; internet</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="183" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A 680,000-person megastudy of nudges to encourage vaccination in pharmacies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Milkman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gandhi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Graci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gromet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Duckworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2115126119</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Addressing hoaxes and fake news</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mosseri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://about.fb.com/news/2016/12/news-feed-fyi-addressing-hoaxes-and-fake-news/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-12-15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bias in the brain: a diffusion model analysis of prior probability and potential payoff</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mulder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Boekel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2335" to="2343" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A problem in theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Muthukrishna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Henrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why people believe health misinformation and who are at risk? A systematic review of individual differences in susceptibility to health misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Nan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Thier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Science &amp; Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">You can&apos;t play 20 questions with nature and win: Projective comments on the papers of this symposium</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Visual information processing: Proceedings of the eighth annual Carnegie symposium on cognition</title>
		<editor>W. G. Chase</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="305" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Carnegie-Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Replicability, robustness, and reproducibility in psychological science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nosek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hardwicke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Moshontz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Allard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dreber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Vazire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="719" to="748" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Uncommon errors: Adaptive intuitions in high-quality media environments increase susceptibility to misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Orchinik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Martel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bhui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/q7r58</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/q7r58" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023-11-17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Partisan polarization is the primary psychological motivation behind political fake news sharing on twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Osmundsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Vahlstrup</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bechmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Petersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Political Science Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="999" to="1015" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Causal inference in statistics: A primer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pearl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Glymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Jewell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A practical guide to doing behavioral research on fake news and misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Binnendyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Newton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Collabra: Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">25293</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A practical guide to doing behavioural research on fake news and misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Binnendyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="Retrievedfromosf.io/xyq4t" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022-01-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mosleh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Arechar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Eckles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shifting attention to accuracy can reduce misinformation online</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">592</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="590" to="595" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fighting COVID-19 misinformation on social media: Experimental evidence for a scalable accuracy-nudge intervention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcphetres</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="770" to="780" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lazy, not biased: Susceptibility to partisan fake news is better explained by lack of reasoning than by motivated reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">188</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2018.06.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.06.011" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of fake news</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="402" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Examining false beliefs about voter fraud in the wake of the 2020 Presidential Election. The Harvard Kennedy School Misinformation Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accuracy prompts are a replicable and generalizable approach for reducing the spread of misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2333</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can democracy survive the Internet?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Persily</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Democracy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using large-scale experiments and machine learning to discover theories of human decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bourgin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reichman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">372</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1209" to="1214" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Political Misinformation and Factual Corrections on the Facebook News Feed: Experimental Evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1812" to="1817" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Pretus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hackenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tsakiris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Vilarroya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Bavel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Misleading count: An identity-based intervention to counter partisan misinformation sharing</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion decision model: Current issues and history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Letter to the editors of Psychological Science: meta-analysis reveals that accuracy nudges have little to no effect for US conservatives: regarding Pennycook</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rathje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roozenbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Traberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Bavel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who uses fact-checking sites? The impact of demographics, political antecedents, and media use on fact-checking site awareness, attitudes, and behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mourão</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Thorson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The International Journal of Press/Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="237" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of fake news on social media and its influence on health during the COVID-19 pandemic: A systematic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rocha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>De Moura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Desidério</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>De Oliveira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lourenço</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>De Figueiredo Nicolete</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">That&apos;sa lot to process! Pitfalls of popular path models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rohrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hünermund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Arslan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Elson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Methods and Practices in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">25152459221095827</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Countering Misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roozenbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Culloty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Suiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b100">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Susceptibility to misinformation is consistent across question framings and response modes and better explained by myside bias and partisanship than analytical thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roozenbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Maertens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Herzog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Geers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sultan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="547" to="573" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b101">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fake news game confers psychological resistance against online misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roozenbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>Palgrave Communications</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b102">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roozenbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rathje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b103">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological inoculation improves resilience against misinformation on social media</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6254</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b104">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital literacy is associated with more discerning accuracy judgments but not sharing intentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sirlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Arechar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.37016/mr-2020-83</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.37016/mr-2020-83" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Kennedy School Misinformation Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b105">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Misinformation warnings: Twitter&apos;s soft moderation effects on covid-19 vaccine belief echoes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sharevski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Alsaadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Jachim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pieroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computers &amp; Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102577</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b106">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">More than eight-in-ten Americans get news from digital devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shearer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pew Research Center</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b107">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">News use across social media platforms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shearer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gottfried</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b108">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The evaluation of fake and true news: on the role of intelligence, personality, interpersonal trust, ideological attitudes, and news consumption</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sindermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Schmitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rozgonjuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Elhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Montag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<pubPlace>Heliyon, 7</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b109">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Calculation of signal detection theory measures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stanislaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research methods, Instruments, &amp; Computers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b110">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fact-checking census shows slower growth. Duke reporters&apos; Lab</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stencel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Luther</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b111">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using effect size-or why the P value is not enough</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Feinn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Graduate Medical Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="282" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b112">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sultan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tump</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Geers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Lorenz-Spreen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Herzog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b113">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time pressure reduces misinformation discrimination ability but does not alter response bias</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">22416</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b114">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking the link between cognitive sophistication and politically motivated reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tappin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">150</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1095</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b115">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fighting falsity: Fake news, Facebook, and the first amendment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Timmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cardozo Arts &amp; Entertainment Law Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">669</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b116">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online misinformation about climate change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M D I</forename><surname>Treen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Neill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: Climate Change</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">665</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b117">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Political psychology in the digital (mis) information age: A model of news belief and sharing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Bavel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pärnamets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rathje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Doell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Issues and Policy Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b118">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual sensitivity in scientific reproducibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Bavel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mende-Siedlecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Reinero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6454" to="6459" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b119">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Misinformation: susceptibility, spread, and interventions to immunize the public</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41591-022-01713-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01713-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b120">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the distinction between interaction and effect modification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Vanderweele</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Epidemiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="863" to="871" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b121">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical diffusion models for two-choice response times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vandekerckhove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tuerlinckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">44</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b122">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Addressing climate change with behavioral science: A global intervention tournament in 63 countries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vlasceanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Doell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bak-Coleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Todorova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Berkebile-Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Grayson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5778</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b123">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to mitigate misinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Waldrop</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2314143120</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b124">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Everything is obvious:* Once you know the answer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>Crown Business</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b125">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Should social science be more solution-oriented?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b126">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic computational model of gaze and choice in multi-attribute decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">52</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b127">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Generalizability Crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Yarkoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b128">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An overview of online fake news: Characterization, detection, and discussion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ghorbani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Processing &amp; Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102025</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b129">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting fake news for reducing misinformation risks using analytics approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kauten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Deokar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Qin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Operational Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">279</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1036" to="1052" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b130">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An individualized intervention approach to improving university students&apos; learning performance and interactive behaviors in a blended learning environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Miao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hwang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interactive Learning Environments</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="245" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b131">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational mechanisms for context-based behavioral interventions: A large-scale analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Coady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2114914119</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
