<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Replicable evidence for uncalculating cooperation as a signal of trustworthiness</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jillian</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
							<email>jijordan@hbs.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Negotiation, Organizations &amp; Markets Unit</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard Business School</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Sloan School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute for Data</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Systems, and Society</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Brain and Cognitive Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Replicable evidence for uncalculating cooperation as a signal of trustworthiness</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:42+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>reputation</term>
					<term>observability</term>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>signaling</term>
					<term>replication</term>
					<term>CloudResearch</term>
					<term>Amazon Turk</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We investigate the replicability of prior work (Jordan et al., 2016) hypothesizing that &quot;uncalculating cooperation&quot; (i.e., cooperation without careful consideration of the costs and benefits) can signal an actor&apos;s commitment to behaving prosocially, and thus trustworthiness. Jordan et al. found that subjects recruited from Amazon Turk make less calculating cooperative decisions when their decision-making process is observable to others, suggesting that uncalculating cooperation is used to signal trustworthiness. Moreover, Jordan et al. found that uncalculating cooperation is perceived as a signal of trustworthiness (subjects preferentially trust cooperators who made uncalculating, rather than calculating, decisions) and actually is a signal of trustworthiness (uncalculating cooperators actually behave in a more trustworthy manner). A recent replication effort (Holzmeister et al., 2024)-investigating the replicability of 26 studies with MTurk samples published in PNAS between 2015-2018-attempted to replicate the finding that observability increases uncalculating behavior, with mixed results (a significant effect in one, both not both, of two batches of data collection). However, subjects in both batches of Holzmeister et al. data, who were recruited directly from MTurk, performed relatively poorly on task comprehension questions compared to Jordan et al., 2016. We thus present results from an additional pre-registered replication of Jordan et al., 2016, conducted through the CloudResearch platform, that recruited a more attentive sample (comparable to the original study), as well as analyses drawing on all studies collected thus far. Together, we find strong evidence that uncalculating cooperation is used as, perceived as, and actually is a signal of trustworthiness, especially among attentive samples.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Why do people sometimes cooperate without carefully considering the costs and benefits? Here, we investigate the replicability of a paper <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Jordan et al., 2016)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref> hypothesizing that such "uncalculating cooperation" serves to signal an actor's commitment to behaving prosocially, and thus trustworthiness.</p><p>Jordan et al. recruited subjects from MTurk to participate in a two-stage, incentivized economic game, as "Player A" or "Player B". In the "Helping Game" stage, Player A received 20¢ and decided whether to incur cost c to deliver 2c to a third-party (neither Player A nor Player B) (i.e., to "help" this third-party). Player A learned that c was between 0¢ and 20¢, but not the precise cost of helping. Then, Player A chose between (i) "looking" at the precise value of c, or (ii) deciding whether to help without looking (and thus making an "uncalculating" decision).</p><p>Next, a "Trust Game" occurred: Player B (who was not involved in the Helping Game) received 30¢ and decided how much to send to Player A; any money sent was tripled by the experimenter. Player A then decided what percentage of this tripled amount to return to Player B (without knowing how much Player B sent). Here, Player B's sending reflects their trust of Player B, and Player A's returning reflects their trustworthiness.</p><p>The key experimental manipulation was whether Player A's looking behavior was observable to Player B. In the process observable condition, Player B could condition their trust both on Player A's Helping Game decision (i.e., did Player A decide to help?) and decisionmaking process (i.e., did Player A look at the cost of helping before making this decision?). In the process hidden condition, however, Player B could condition their trust only on Player A's Helping Game decision-so looking was not observable.</p><p>Critically, Player As were less likely to look at the cost of helping in "process observable" than "process hidden", suggesting that they used uncalculating decisions to signal their trustworthiness. Furthermore, uncalculating cooperation was perceived as a signal of trustworthiness (Player Bs trusted Player As more if they helped without, rather than with, looking), and actually was a signal of trustworthiness (Player As who helped without looking returned more money in the Trust Game). Jordan et al. also found similar results in a second study, which operationalized "uncalculating" decision-making as deciding quickly, rather than with limited information.</p><p>In 2022, a team of researchers, investigating the replicability of 26 studies with MTurk samples published in PNAS between 2015-2018, attempted to replicate the finding that observability increases uncalculating behavior among Player As, with their results published in a 2024 paper <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref>. This team <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Holzmeister et al., 2024)</ref> planned to recruit approximately 1800 Player As and 1800 Player Bs, but inadvertently recruited 3600 Player As and 0 Player Bs. While this error did not influence the experience of focal participants (i.e., Player As), it introduced deception. Holzmeister et al. thus decided to discard their first batch of data without inspection, and to collect new Player A and B data.</p><p>The Holzmeister et al., 2024 data reveals that observability significantly increased uncalculating decision-making in "batch one" (i.e., the 3600 Player As initially collected), but not "batch two" (i.e., the 1800 Player As subsequently collected). However, subjects in both batches of Holzmeister et al. data, who were recruited directly from MTurk, performed relatively poorly on task comprehension questions compared to subjects in Jordan et al., 2016. Because the attentiveness of subjects recruited directly from MTurk has declined substantially in recent years (3), we conducted an additional pre-registered replication of Jordan et al., 2016 using CloudResearch, a third-party platform designed to help researchers recruit higher-quality samples from MTurk. Here, we report analyses of this study, and of all data collected so far.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Comprehension</head><p>Comprehension performance in our CloudResearch replication (Player As M = 5.49 [5.42, 5.62] of 7 questions correct, n = 1799; Player Bs M = 4.85 <ref type="bibr">[4.74, 4</ref>.97] of 6 questions correct, n = 451) was comparable to Jordan et al., 2016 (Player As M = 5.44 [5.34, 5.55], n = 735; Player Bs M = 4.89 <ref type="bibr">[4.80, 4</ref>.98], n = 735) and better than Holzmeister et al., 2024 batches 1 (Player As M = 4.24 <ref type="bibr">[4.17, 4</ref>.31], n = 3628; Player Bs not collected) and 2 (Player As M = 3.45 <ref type="bibr">[3.36, 3</ref>.55], n = 1826; Player Bs M = 4.03 <ref type="bibr">[3.96, 4</ref>.10], n = 1877).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Is uncalculating cooperation used as a signal of trustworthiness?</head><p>Among Player As, was uncalculating cooperation used as a signal of trustworthiness? We predict uncalculating behavior (i.e., the decision not to look at the helping cost) as a function of observability (1 = process observable, 0 = process hidden)-among all subjects, and among subjects correctly answering all "pre-treatment" comprehension questions (i.e., questions presented before assignment to observability condition). In <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> and <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, we plot and report observability effects within each study, and within meta-analyses of (i) the two batches of Holzmeister et al., 2024 data, (ii) all data excluding Jordan et al., 2016 (i.e., all replications but not the original study), and (iii) all data. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Uncalculating cooperation is used as a signal of trustworthiness. We plot observability effects on uncalculating behavior, within individual studies (shown are linear regression coefficients) and random-effects meta-analyses of sets of studies (shown are overall effects from meta-analysis). Error bars are 95% CIs. Is uncalculating cooperation used as a signal of trustworthiness? <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Uncalculating cooperation is used as a signal of trustworthiness. We report observability effects on uncalculating behavior within individual studies, and random-effects meta-analyses of sets of studies. We report results from logistic as well as linear regression models, and highlight significant effects in yellow. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> and <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> reveal directionally positive effects of observability within all studies and meta-analyses, which are significant among all subjects in all data sources except Holzmeister et al., 2024 batch 2, and among high comprehenders in all data sources except our CloudResearch Replication (where the effect is marginally significant) and Jordan et al., 2016. We thus find strong evidence that uncalculating cooperation is used to signal trustworthiness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Is uncalculating cooperation perceived as a signal of trustworthiness?</head><p>Among Player Bs, was uncalculating cooperation perceived as a signal of trustworthiness? In Jordan et al., 2016, Player Bs sent more money in the Trust Game to Player As who helped without (vs. with) looking, but did not similarly reward Player As who did not help without (vs. with) looking, resulting in a positive interaction between not looking and helping on sending. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2A</ref> and <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>   We plot the effect of Player A not looking on Player B's Trust Game sending, both to Player As who helped (top plot) and did not help (middle plot), as well as the interaction between not looking and helping on sending (bottom plot). (B) Uncalculating cooperation actually is a signal of trustworthiness. We plot the association between Player A not looking and Player A's Trust Game returning, both among Player As who helped (top plot) and did not help (middle plot), as well as the interaction between not looking and helping on returning (bottom plot). We plot effects within individual studies (shown are linear regression coefficients) and random-effects meta-analyses of sets of studies (shown are overall effects from meta-analysis). Error bars are 95% CIs.   <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. Uncalculating cooperation is perceived as a signal of trustworthiness. We report the effect of Player A not looking on Player B's Trust Game sending, both to Player As who helped and did not help, as well as the interaction between not looking and helping on sending. We report effects within individual studies and random-effects meta-analyses of sets of studies, and highlight significant effects in yellow.</p><p>Mirroring Jordan et al., 2016, across all data sources among all subjects and among perfect comprehenders, we find significant positive effects of not looking on sending to helpers, but not on sending to non-helpers, resulting in significant positive interactions between not looking and helping on sending. We thus find strong evidence that uncalculating cooperation is perceived as a signal of trustworthiness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Is uncalculating cooperation actually a signal of trustworthiness?</head><p>Finally, among Player As, was uncalculating cooperation actually a signal of trustworthiness? In Jordan et al., 2016, Player As who helped without (vs. with) looking returned significantly more money in the Trust Game, but this pattern did not hold among Player As who did not help, resulting in a positive interaction between declining to look and helping on returning. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2B</ref> and <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> investigate these patterns for each data source-among all subjects, and subjects who correctly answered all comprehension questions.</p><p>Among perfect comprehenders, results consistently mirror Jordan et al., 2016. Among helpers, the association between not looking and returning is always directionally positive, and significant in all data sources besides Holzmeister et al., 2024 batch 2. We also never find positive associations between not looking and returning among non-helpers, resulting in significant positive interactions between not looking and helping on returning in all data sources.</p><p>In analyses of all subjects, we replicate this interaction in all data sources, and never find positive associations between not looking and returning among non-helpers. And in Jordan et al., 2016 and our CloudResearch Replication, we find significant positive associations between not looking and returning among helpers. In both batches of Holzmeister et al., 2024 data, however, the positive interaction between not looking and helping unexpectedly reflects strong negative associations between not looking and returning among non-helpers that are significantly weaker, but also significantly negative, among helpers.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Uncalculating cooperation actually is a signal of trustworthiness. We report the association between Player A not looking and Player A's Trust Game returning, both among Player As who helped and did not help, as well as the interaction between not looking and helping on returning. We report effects within individual studies and random-effects metaanalyses of sets of studies, and highlight significant effects in yellow.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Across Jordan et al., 2016 and three pre-registered replication attempts from two teams, we find strong evidence that uncalculating cooperation is used as, perceived as, and actually is a signal of trustworthiness. Our results suggest that the findings from Jordan et al., 2016 are replicable, especially in analyses of attentive samples. Moreover, our results highlight the importance of recruiting high-quality online samples, underscore the value of third-party recruitment tools like CloudResearch, and suggest that, in a dynamic world, replicators may need to take novel steps to recruit samples that are comparable to those recruited in the past.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>We used the CloudResearch platform to recruit subjects from the set of "CloudResearch Approved Participants" (who have passed CloudResearch's attention and engagement measures), block "suspicious geocode locations", duplicate IPs, and workers with discrepant location information, and require workers to have taken at least 100 HITs-such that Amazon reports their approval rating-and to have an approval rating of at least 97%. Per our pre-registrations, to form our final samples, we included all complete survey responses with a unique IP address.</p><p>To test whether uncalculating cooperation is used to signal trustworthiness (i.e., whether observability increases uncalculating decision-making among Player As-the effect investigated by Holzmeister et al.), we recruited a target of n = 1800 Player As (pre-registration available at https://aspredicted.org/437_P7L; final n = 1799, mean age = 43.54 years, 47.69% male, 50.53% female, and 1.78% other gender identities). Of note, because our Player A study was motivated  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">= -8.93 [-10.93, -6.92]</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">= -29.64 [-37.48, -21.80]</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">= -10.94 [-14.24, -7.65]</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">= -16.72 [-30.88, -2.56]</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Associations between not looking and returning… Interaction between not looking and helping on returning</head><p>Associations between not looking and returning… Interaction between not looking and helping on returning by Holzmeister et al.'s investigation of the effect of observability on looking, our pre-registered analysis plan focuses on whether uncalculating cooperation is used as a signal of trustworthiness. However, for completeness, we also report non-preregistered analyses investigating whether uncalculating cooperation actually is a signal of trustworthiness (that analyze Trust Game returning decisions among Player As). We also recruited Player Bs, both to implement the economic game without deception, and to investigate whether uncalculating cooperation is perceived as a signal of trustworthiness (by analyzing Trust Game sending decisions among Player Bs). This investigation specifically requires analyzing sending decisions from Player Bs in the "process observable" condition (who can condition their sending decisions both on Player A helping and looking decisions). Thus, to test our "perceived as" hypothesis, we recruited a target of n = 450 Player Bs to the "process observable" condition-a relatively smaller number compared to our Payer A sample, given that testing the "perceived as" hypothesis involves a within-subjects analysis that requires fewer subjects to achieve adequate power (Player B study pre-registration available at https://aspredicted.org/8V5_JBH; final n = 451, mean age = 42.64 years, 48.56% male, 51.00% female, and .44% other gender identities).</p><p>To implement our economic game, we matched these 450 Player Bs with 450 of the 900 Player As assigned to the "process observable" condition. We also recruited two additional Player Bs, one to our "process observable" condition and one to our "process hidden" condition, not for data analysis purposes but specifically for the purpose of matching them, via one-to-many matching, with all remaining Player As. Specifically, we matched the Player B in the "process observable" condition with each of the remaining 450 Player As in the "process observable" condition, and we matched the Player B in the "process hidden" condition with each of the 900 Player As in the "process hidden" condition. After recruiting Player A and Player B subjects, we used the identical procedure to that used in Jordan et al., 2016 (described in detail below), with one minor exception: in our post-experimental questionnaire, we modified our demographics section to include gender identifies other than male or female.</p><p>We pre-registered logistic regressions for our analyses of looking behavior (a binary outcome). However, <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows linear regression coefficients, both for ease of interpretation and comparability to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> (where we analyze continuous outcomes using linear regression). In <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, we report statistical analyses for both linear and logistic regressions; these two approaches produce qualitatively identical results. All meta-analyses are random-effects metaanalyses; we find qualitatively identical results with fixed-effects meta-analyses.</p><p>Per our CloudResearch replication pre-registration, in our analyses of the effect of observability on uncalculating decision-making among high comprehenders, we restrict to Player As who passed our six pre-manipulation comprehension questions. Of note, Jordan et al., 2016 took a somewhat different approach, and instead restricted to Player As who correctly answered all seven comprehension questions, including one that was presented after subjects were randomly assigned to observability conditions. However, restricting only on the basis of premanipulation questions is more appropriate from a causal inference perspective, given that conditioning on post-treatment variables can undermine random assignment (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(4)</ref>).</p><p>In our Player B study, there were six comprehension questions, all of which were presented before our observability manipulation. Moreover, our analyses of Player Bs are withinsubject analyses of subjects in just one of our two observability conditions, and do not concern the causal effect of any between-subjects manipulation. Thus, in our analyses of Player Bs, following Jordan et al., 2016 and our CloudResearch replication pre-registration, we restrict to subjects who answered all six comprehension questions correctly-a restriction that does not threaten causal inference. Similarly, our analyses investigating whether uncalculating cooperation actually is a signal of trustworthiness, in which we analyze the association between looking and Trust Game returning among Player As, are correlational and do not concern the causal effect of our observability manipulation. Thus, following Jordan et al., 2016, when conducting these analyses among high comprehenders, we restrict on the basis of all seven comprehension questions in our Player A study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure for Player As</head><p>Player As first participate in the Helping Game (HG), and then participate in the Trust Game (TG). These subjects first read that they will participate in two different interactive games with other MTurk workers. They then read instructions describing the rules of the HG and view a decision tree illustrating their choices in the game (instructions use neutral language to label the different players and games; see OSF page for Qualtrics survey files that show full instructions). After subjects read the instructions, they answer three comprehension questions to ensure that they understand that helping is costly for them and beneficial for the recipient, and that they have two choices: whether to find out the exact cost of helping, and whether to help the recipient.</p><p>Next, we inform subjects that they will participate in the next game, the TG, with another player (Player B) who did not participate in the HG. We provide instructions describing the rules of the TG. Then, subjects answer three more comprehension questions to ensure that they understand that (i) Player B's payoff-maximizing decision depends on how much they decide to return to Player B; (ii) their payoff-maximizing decision is always to return nothing; and (iii) Player B did not participate in the HG.</p><p>Next, we tell subjects about the information that Player Bs can base their TG sending decisions on. In the process hidden condition, we explain that Player Bs can base their TG sending decisions on subjects' HG helping decisions (but not their HG looking decisions). In the process observable condition, we explain that Player Bs can base their TG sending decisions on subjects' HG helping and looking decision. Then, subjects answer another comprehension question to ensure that they understand what information Player Bs can base their TG sending decisions on.</p><p>Next, subjects make their looking decisions. Before deciding, they are reminded that (i) all they currently know is that helping entails paying somewhere between 0 and 20 cents to deliver twice as much to the recipient; (ii) the other players are real; and (iii) they really do have a chance to find out the precise cost of helping. Player As in the process observable condition, but not the process hidden condition, are also reminded that (iv) Player Bs really will get to base their TG sending decisions on whether they decide to find out the precise cost. They then make a binary looking decision, and afterwards, subjects who decide to look are informed that the precise cost of helping is 10 cents.</p><p>Next, subjects make their helping decisions. Before deciding, they are reminded (i) of the parameters of the helping decision (in which the cost is labeled as 10 cents only for subjects who decided to look); (ii) that the other players are real; (iii) that they really do have a chance to help the recipient; and (iv) that Player Bs really will get to base their TG sending decisions on whether they decide to help. They then make a binary helping decision.</p><p>Next, subjects make their TG returning decisions. Before deciding, they are reminded (i) of the parameters of the returning decision (in which they are told to decide what percentage to return of the amount Player B will send); (ii) that the other players are real; and (iii) that they really do have a chance to decide how much to return. They make a continuous returning decision, indicating the percentage (in 10-cent increments) they would like to return. Finally, Player As receive a post-experimental questionnaire.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure for Player Bs</head><p>The procedure for Player Bs is identical to the procedure for Player As, with the following exceptions. Player Bs do not participate in the HG, but do participate in the TG. When describing the HG, we thus tell subjects that they will not participate, but that we want them to understand the game. When describing the TG, we tell subjects that they will play with a Player A who previously played the HG.</p><p>When subjects make their TG decisions, we explain, according to condition, what information they can base their sending decisions on. Thus, we tell subjects in the process hidden condition that they can only base their sending on whether Player A helped in the HG, and we tell subjects in the process observable condition that they can base their sending both on whether Player A helped, and whether Player A looked at the precise cost of helping. We then explain that they will make multiple sending decisions that correspond to different possible Player A behaviors in the HG, and that the decision that matches the behavior of the actual Player A they are matched with will determine their earnings (the "strategy method"). Then, subjects decide how much to send (in 5-cent increments) to each possible type of Player A (helpers and nonhelpers in the process hidden condition; helpers who looked, helpers who did not look, nonhelpers who looked, and non-helpers who did not look in the process observable condition) in a random order, with each decision on a separate page.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure for HG Recipients</head><p>Because HG Recipients do not make any decisions, we do not require them to read the rules or answer comprehension questions. Instead, for every Player A who chooses to help the recipient, we give a bonus of 20 cents to a randomly selected Mturk worker (picked from our database of Mturk worker IDs who have previously participated in our studies) who thus functions as the Recipient.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>HiddenFigure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Observable = 0.40, OR = 1.30 [1.07,1.57], z = 2.66, p = .008, n = 1799 Hidden = 0.34, Observable = 0.40, b = 0.06 [0.02,0.11], t = 2.67, p = .008, n = 1799 Hidden = 0.40, Observable = 0.47, OR = 1.34 [0.97,1.86], z = 1.76, p = .079, n = 591 Hidden = 0.40, Observable = 0.47, b = 0.07 [-0.01,0.15], t = 1.76, p = .079, n = 591 Meta analysis with all Holzmeister et al., 2024 data 2 studies, total n = 5454 Overall OR = 1.17 [1.03,1.33], z = 2.45, p = .014, n = 5454 Overall effect = 0.03 [0.00,0.05], z = 2.40, p = .016, n = 5454 Overall OR = 1.56 [1.09,2.25], z = 2.41, p = .016, n = 1028 Overall effect = 0.11 [0.02,0.20], z = 2.32, p = .020, comprehension questions Effects of observability on looking, analyzed using… (A) Uncalculating cooperation is perceived as a signal of trustworthiness.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>looking and helping on returning</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>No look = 21.74, b = -15.66 [-20.82, -10.49], t = -5.95, p &lt; .001, n = 612 Look = 57.18, No look = 48.25, b</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>z = -3.20, p = .001, n = 880 Overall effect = -9.49 [-11.27, -7.72], z = -10.46, p &lt; .001, n = 4574 Overall effect = 12.27 [0.57, 23.97], z = 2.06, p = .04, n = 5454 Overall effect = -9.15 [-20.57, 2.27], z = -1.57, p = .12, z = 3.98, p &lt; .001, n = 755 Overall effect = 12.61 [6.02, 19.20], z = 3.75, p &lt; .001, n = 936 Meta analysis with all data besides original published study 3 studies, total n = 7253 Overall effect = -18.22 [-27.75, -8.69], z = -3.75, p &lt; .001, n = 1228 Overall effect = -5.49 [-14.24, 3.27], z = -1.23, p = .22, n = 6025 Overall effect = 12.65 [6.08, 19.21], z = 3.78, p &lt; .001, n = 7253 Overall effect = -9.32 [-15.64, -3.01], z = -2.89, p &lt; .001, n = 281 Overall effect = 6.03 [3.73, 8.32], z = 5.15, p &lt; .001, n = 1214 Overall effect = 14.57 [9.37, 19.78], z = 5.49, p &lt; .001, n = 1495 Meta analysis with all data 4 studies, total n = 7988 Overall effect = -14.52 [-23.69, -5.36], z = -3.11, p = .002, n = 1368 Overall effect = -1.94 [-10.74, 6.87], z = -0.43, p = .67, n = 6620 Overall effect = 12.15 [7.04, 17.27], z = 4.65, p &lt; .001, n = 7988 Overall effect = -8.64 [-13.21, -4.07], z = -3.71, p &lt; .001, n = 315 Overall effect = 7.57 [3.69, 11.44], z = 3.83, p &lt; .001, n = 1395 Overall effect = 15.86 [10.88, 20.84], z = 6.24, p &lt; .001, n = 1710 Analyses of all subjects Analyses of subjects who passed all comprehension questions</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Effect of observability All subjects High comprehenders</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.3</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>.25</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>.2</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>.15</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>.1</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>.05</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>-.05</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Jordan et al., 2016</cell><cell>All Holzmeister et al., 2024 data</cell></row><row><cell>Holzmeister et al., 2024 Batch 1</cell><cell>All data except Jordan et al., 2016</cell></row><row><cell>Holzmeister et al., 2024 Batch 2</cell><cell>All data</cell></row><row><cell>CloudResearch Replication</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>investigate these patterns for each data sourceamong all subjects, and subjects who correctly answered all comprehension questions.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>…logistic regression</cell><cell>…linear regression</cell><cell>…logistic regression</cell><cell>…linear regression</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Hidden = 0.30,</cell><cell>Hidden = 0.30,</cell><cell>Hidden = 0.29,</cell><cell>Hidden = 0.29,</cell></row><row><cell>Our published study</cell><cell>Observable = 0.41,</cell><cell>Observable = 0.41,</cell><cell>Observable = 0.35,</cell><cell>Observable = 0.35,</cell></row><row><cell>Open MTurk, 2015</cell><cell>OR = 1.63 [1.20,2.20],</cell><cell>b = 0.11 [0.04,0.18],</cell><cell>OR = 1.30 [0.75,2.25],</cell><cell>b = 0.06 [-0.06,0.18],</cell></row><row><cell>n = 735</cell><cell>z = 3.12, p = .002,</cell><cell>t = 3.15, p = .002,</cell><cell>z = 0.93, p = .354,</cell><cell>t = 0.92, p = .356,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>n = 735</cell><cell>n = 735</cell><cell>n = 233</cell><cell>n = 233</cell></row><row><cell>Holzmeister et al., 2024 batch 1 Open MTurk, 2023 n = 3628</cell><cell>Hidden = 0.23, Observable = 0.26, OR = 1.19 [1.02,1.38], z = 2.22, p = .026, n = 3628</cell><cell>Hidden = 0.23, Observable = 0.26, b = 0.03 [0.00,0.06], t = 2.22, p = .026, n = 3628</cell><cell>Hidden = 0.36, Observable = 0.44, OR = 1.38 [1.04,1.82], z = 2.22, p = .027, n = 813</cell><cell>Hidden = 0.36, Observable = 0.44, b = 0.08 [0.01,0.14], t = 2.22, p = .026, n = 813</cell></row><row><cell>Holzmeister et al., 2024 batch 2 Open MTurk, 2023 n = 1826</cell><cell>Hidden = 0.17, Observable = 0.19, OR = 1.14 [0.90,1.45], z = 1.06, p = .288, n = 1826</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Is uncalculating cooperation perceived as a signal of trustworthiness? Is uncalculating cooperation actually a signal of trustworthiness? A B</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>.3</cell></row><row><cell>Effect of observability</cell><cell>0 .05 .1 .15 .2 .25</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-.05</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>All subjects</cell><cell>High comprehenders</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Jordan et al., 2016</cell><cell>All Holzmeister et al., 2024 data</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Holzmeister et al., 2024 Batch 1</cell><cell>All data except Jordan et al., 2016</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Holzmeister et al., 2024 Batch 2</cell><cell>All data</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CloudResearch Replication</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Analyses of all subjects Analyses of subjects who passed all comprehension questions</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Effects of not looking on sending…</cell><cell>Interaction between</cell><cell cols="2">Effects of not looking on sending…</cell><cell>Interaction between</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>not looking and</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>not looking and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>...to non-helpers</cell><cell>…to helpers</cell><cell>helping on sending</cell><cell>…to non-helpers</cell><cell>…to helpers</cell><cell>helping on sending</cell></row><row><cell>Our published study Open MTurk, 2015 n = 361</cell><cell>Look = 21.13, No look = 19.07, b = -2.06 [-4.37, 0.25], t = -1.75, p = .080, n = 361</cell><cell>Look = 49.11, No look = 54.78, b = 5.67 [3.26, 8.08], t = 4.62, p &lt; .001, n = 361</cell><cell>b = 7.73 [4.44, 11.01], t = 4.63, p &lt; .001, n = 361</cell><cell>Look = 15.35, No look = 12.53, b = -2.82 [-6.48, 0.83], t = -1.53, p = .129, n = 157</cell><cell>Look = 50.42, No look = 59.79, b = 9.36 [5.32, 13.41], t = 4.57, p &lt; .001, n = 157</cell><cell>b = 12.19 [6.80, 17.58], t = 4.47, p &lt; .001, n = 157</cell></row><row><cell>Holzmeister et al., 2024 batch 2 Open MTurk, 2023 n = 933</cell><cell>Look = 34.05, No look = 32.97, b = -1.08 [-2.38, 0.22], t = -1.63, p = .103, n = 933</cell><cell>Look = 52.47, No look = 54.86, b = 2.39 [1.14, 3.64], t = 3.74, p &lt; .001, n = 933</cell><cell>b = 3.47 [1.60, 5.34], t = 3.64, p &lt; .001, n = 933</cell><cell>Look = 22.55, No look = 19.49, b = -3.06 [-5.82, -0.30], t = -2.19, p = .030, n = 195</cell><cell>Look = 63.25, No look = 70.89, b = 7.64 [4.66, 10.62], t = 5.05, p &lt; .001, n = 195</cell><cell>b = 10.70 [6.31, 15.09], t = 4.81, p &lt; .001, n = 195</cell></row><row><cell>Our replication CloudResearch, 2023 n = 451</cell><cell>Look = 27.15, No look = 26.28, b = -0.86 [-2.74, 1.01], t = -0.91, p = .366, n = 451</cell><cell>Look = 57.62, No look = 61.37, b = 3.75 [1.84, 5.67], t = 3.86, p &lt; .001, n = 451</cell><cell>b = 4.62 [1.96, 7.28], t = 3.41, p = .001, n = 451</cell><cell>Look = 21.60, No look = 19.11, b = -2.50 [-5.54, 0.55], t = -1.62, p = .107, n = 179</cell><cell>Look = 61.36, No look = 68.88, b = 7.52 [4.06, 10.98], t = 4.29, p &lt; .001, n = 179</cell><cell>b = 10.02 [5.52, 14.52], t = 4.39, p &lt; .001, n = 179</cell></row><row><cell>Meta analysis with</cell><cell>Overall effect =</cell><cell>Overall effect =</cell><cell>Overall effect =</cell><cell>Overall effect =</cell><cell>Overall effect =</cell><cell>Overall effect =</cell></row><row><cell>all data besides original</cell><cell>-1.01 [-2.08, 0.06],</cell><cell>2.88 [1.60, 4.16],</cell><cell>3.85 [2.32, 5.38],</cell><cell>-2.81 [-4.84, -0.78],</cell><cell>7.59 [5.35, 9.84],</cell><cell>10.37 [7.25, 13.49],</cell></row><row><cell>published study</cell><cell>z = -1.86, p = .063,</cell><cell>z = 4.40, p &lt; .001,</cell><cell>z = 4.94, p &lt; .001,</cell><cell>z = -2.71, p = .007,</cell><cell>z = 6.63, p &lt; .001,</cell><cell>z = 6.51, p &lt; .001,</cell></row><row><cell>2 studies, total n = 1384</cell><cell>n = 1384</cell><cell>n = 1384</cell><cell>n = 1384</cell><cell>n = 374</cell><cell>n = 374</cell><cell>n = 374</cell></row><row><cell>Meta analysis with all data 3 studies, total n = 1745</cell><cell>Overall effect = -1.20 [-2.16, -0.23], z = -2.42, p = .016, n = 1745</cell><cell>Overall effect = 3.71 [1.90, 5.52], z = 4.02, p &lt; .001, n = 1745</cell><cell>Overall effect = 4.97 [2.66, 7.27], z = 4.22, p &lt; .001, n = 1745</cell><cell>Overall effect = -2.81 [-4.58, -1.04], z = -3.11, p = .002, n = 531</cell><cell>Overall effect = 8.01 [6.05, 9.97], z = 8.02, p &lt; .001, n = 531</cell><cell>Overall effect = 10.83 [8.13, 13.53], z = 7.88, p &lt; .001, n = 531</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We gratefully acknowledge Anoushka Kiyawat for helpful research assistance.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncalculating Cooperation is used to Signal of Trustworthiness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nowak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8658" to="8663" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Examining the replicability of online experiments selected by a decision market</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Holzmeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Representativeness Versus Attentiveness: A Comparison Across Nine Online Survey Samples</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Stagnaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Druckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Arechar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Willer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Conditioning on Posttreatment Variables Can Ruin Your Experiment and What to Do about It</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nyhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Torres</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American J Political Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="760" to="775" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
