<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiaying</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<email>jiayingz@psych.ubc.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute for Resources</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Environment and Sustainability</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology Institute for Resources, Environment and Sustainability University of British Columbia Vancouver</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>V6T 1Z4</postCode>
									<region>B.C., Canada</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:43+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>decision making</term>
					<term>cognition</term>
					<term>behavior change</term>
					<term>polarization</term>
					<term>debias</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We propose a framework that outlines several predominant cognitive biases of climate change, identifies potential causes, and proposes debiasing tools, with the ultimate goal of depolarizing climate beliefs and promoting actions to mitigate climate change.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Climate change is an urgent crisis facing humanity. To effectively combat climate change, we need concerted efforts not only from policymakers and industry leaders to institute top-down structural changes (e.g., policies, infrastructure) but also from individuals and communities to instigate bottom-up behavior changes to collectively reduce greenhouse gas emissions. To this end, psychology has offered useful insights on what motivates people to act on climate change, from social psychology investigating the underlying beliefs and attitudes of climate change, to cognitive psychology uncovering the attentional, perceptual, and decision processes of climate actions, and more recently neuroscience pinpointing the neural circuitry on motivated cognition. Insights gained from these fields have started to generate interventions to shift beliefs and promote behavior change to mitigate climate change.</p><p>In the search for behavioral climate solutions, a stubborn challenge remains. That is, a sizeable portion of the public still hold disbelief on climate change and refuse to take actions, despite the fact that the vast majority of climate scientists have reached a consensus on anthropogenic causes of climate change. In fact, public opinion on climate change has polarized along party lines in North America over the last few decades. According to a recent poll by the Pew Research Center in 2021, 40% of Republicans remain skeptical about the role of human activities in climate change, where most Democrats have reached an agreement on the anthropogenic causes.</p><p>To address climate hesitancy and polarization, it is essential to understand the cognitive biases that distort the mental representation of climate change and subsequently lead to faulty climate beliefs and prevent climate actions. Here, we propose a framework that first outlines the predominant cognitive biases that can give rise to disbelief and skepticism on climate change and 4 perpetuate polarization, then identifies the causes of the biases, and proposes debiasing tools to mitigate the biases, reshape climate beliefs, and promote climate actions (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1: A framework on cognitive biases of climate change</head><p>We illustrate this framework with an example. An attentional bias away from climate change evidence among conservative individuals can be driven by motivated cognition stemming from prior beliefs, and this bias can attenuate their concerns about climate change and fortify the resistance to reduce carbon emissions. The reduced concern and inaction can further reinforce motivated cognition, forming a positive feedback loop. A potential debiasing tool to address the attentional bias is to visualize global temperature in relation to greenhouse gas emissions from human activities as opposed to natural causes (e.g., solar activities). This tool can draw attention to the human contributions to climate change relative to natural factors, highlighting the need to reduce human-caused carbon emissions. In the following sections, we discuss the cognitive 5 biases, potential causes, and debiasing tools in detail (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>). Most biases identified so far involve an under-representation of the urgency and severity of climate change, while a few involve an over-representation (e.g., heightened attention to climate change) that can lead to ecoanxiety and sense of hopelessness (e.g., pseudoinefficacy). A decision bias that presents another barrier for climate mitigation is present bias, which is the tendency to prioritize objectives or tasks that are temporally and spatially closer over the ones that are more distant <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Weber, 2017)</ref>. A consequence of this bias is that people tend to overvalue the immediate costs of climate mitigation policies (e.g., carbon tax) and undervalue the future benefits (e.g., greenhouse gas emission reductions). For individual climate actions, this bias can deter people from purchasing energy efficient appliances due to the high upfront cost despite equally high (if not higher) future energy savings. A related decision bias is the status quo bias, which suggests that people prefer to stick with the status quo rather than choosing a new option to minimize effort and uncertainty associated with the change. This bias hinders efforts to promote climate actions that require changes to people's current lifestyles even though the changes are beneficial over the long term.</p><p>Another prominent decision bias is pseudoinefficacy, which is a false sense of inefficacy of individual actions that are perceived to be not making an appreciable contribution to solving a large overall problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(V채stfj채ll et al., 2015</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Causes of bias</head><p>Most research to date has focused on identifying the biases of climate change, but relatively less work has examined the causes of the bias. In order to minimize cognitive biases, it 9 is critical to understand the underlying driving forces. In this section, we offer some hypotheses on the potential factors that can contribute to the cognitive biases.</p><p>A primary cause of the biases is motivated cognition, which is that prior motivations (e.g., personal goals, needs) can influence information processing at multiple stages, resulting in attentional, perceptual, recall, and confirmation biases. For example, motivations to identify with and belong to a certain political group can determine how an individual processes climate change information depending on whether the information is consistent with the group's ideologies, although such causal evidence is still lacking (most evidence so far is correlational). Another factor driving motivated cognition could be prior beliefs that serve to maintain consistency in opinions rather than protecting partisan identities. Recent neuroscience studies have shown that motives can modulate neural systems associated with attentional control and low-level perception by shifting attention and perception toward motivationally consistent information and away from inconsistent ones <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Hughes and Zaki, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>In addition to motivated cognition, cognitive rigidity can be a driver of some biases.</p><p>Cognitive rigidity is defined as a cognitive trait characterized by an inability to adapt to a new environment or respond dynamically to neuropsychological tasks and is suggested to correlate with extreme political actions and more ideological and dogmatic worldviews <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Zmigrod and Goldenberg, 2021)</ref>. Conservatives often adopt the view that climate change is caused by natural factors instead of human activities, and this incorrect assumption can contribute to confirmation bias and pseudoinefficacy. Moreover, people tend to underestimate the carbon emissions associated with daily individual actions regardless of their political orientations and climate concerns <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Camilleri et al., 2019)</ref>. This underestimation can cause pseudoinefficacy by minimizing the climate impact of their own actions, and also present bias by devaluing the carbon savings of switching to climate friendlier alternatives. Finally, the single action bias can be caused by the temporary alleviation of negative affect after performing one climate action <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Truelove et al., 2014)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Debiasing tools</head><p>Identify potential causes of the bias can inform the design of debiasing tools to increase the acceptance of anthropogenic climate change and the adoption of climate change mitigation behaviors. In this section, we propose several debiasing tools to address the underlying causes. understanding of the occurrence, causes, and consequences of climate change <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Goldberg et al., 2021)</ref>. Another tool is to reconstruct an accurate representation of the social norms of the group by exposing people to the actual views on in-group and out-group members on climate change, or by encouraging people to communicate with more in-group and out-group members to get a representative view of the group. A third tool is observational learning which is a process of acquiring beliefs, norms, and facts by observing the behavior of others or watching videos.</p><p>To address cognitive rigidity, forward-looking techniques can be used that involve generating arguments for forward-looking options or considering the legacy for future generations. This tool can evoke personal reflections on how they want to be remembered by future generations <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Weber, 2017)</ref>. Another tool is to use default which involves making climatefriendly options the status quo, which reduces the effort and scrutinization of potential risks during the decision process.</p><p>One tool to increase the knowledge of climate change and to correct the incorrect assumptions is to use visualization techniques to highlight human contributions to climate change as opposed to natural causes over a long timescale. We should note that highlighting climate change evidence alone may backfire, as in a previous study conservatives were less likely to take climate actions when the rising phase of the global temperature curve was made salient <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Luo and Zhao, 2021)</ref>. Visualization thus must target the specific assumption that was incorrect or information of climate change that was not known before, rather than reiterating what is already known, to avoid possible backfiring. Visualizing existing and future damages caused by climate change can increase the awareness of the urgency and severity of climate change. To solve the underestimation problem of carbon footprint, visualization techniques can be used to present accurate and digestible carbon footprint information of individual actions (e.g., one roundtrip from New York to London) to rebuild an accurate understanding of the climate impact of individual actions. This information can also help people decide which actions to take to mitigate climate change <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Camilleri et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>The lack of knowledge and awareness of climate change also makes people susceptible to misinformation. A meta-analysis showed that interventions that induced skepticism on climate change had a stronger effect on attitudes than those that aimed to increase belief, suggesting that belief in climate change is harder to build but easier to demolish <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Rode et al., 2021)</ref>. To combat misinformation, inoculation can be used by first exposeing people to warnings of false claims and then preemptively refuting these claims to protect them from misinformation. For example, after seeing a message of scientific consensus on climate change, participants were first warned about a false claim in a misinformation campaign, and then read a statement that refuted the false claim with a reiteration of the consensus among climate scientists. These participants maintained positive views toward the consensus after being exposed to misinformation but not those who were not inoculated against misinformation <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(van der Linden et al., 2017)</ref>.</p><p>Lastly, a debiasing tool for the single action bias is reinforcing the connection between climate actions and a person's identity or values by reflecing on the how the behavior is related</p><p>to their values, identity, or views on how people in society should behave. Such intervention has been shown to increase the adotption of subsequent climate actions <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Sparkman et al., 2021)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A call for future research</head><p>The current framework is only a start of identifying cognitive biases, the causes, and the debiasing tools. It is far from a comprehensive list. We call for future research in (1) discovering 13 cognitive biases of climate change, (2) identifying the root causes of the biases, (3) developing the corresponding debiasing tools, (4) testing the tools in randomized field experiments, and <ref type="formula">5</ref>tracking both short-term and long-term impact on the bias and the downstream changes in climate beliefs (e.g., personal importance and concerns) and climate actions (e.g., reducing carbon emissions, voting). While this framework heavily focuses on the contributions from social and cognitive psychology, more research on the underlying neural mechanisms of the cognitive biases and debiasing tools is needed. We urge cognitive, behavioral, and</p><p>neuroscientists to enrich the current framework to collectively discover the remedy for cognitive biases of climate change, with the ultimate goal of depolarizing beliefs and promoting actions to conquer the climate crisis.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Cognitive rigidity can also cause a failure to update prior beliefs given new information. In the case of climate change, cognitively rigid individuals may fail to change their beliefs when presented with climate change evidence, giving rise to confirmation bias or status quo bias. They may also experience problems adapting to climate change as adaptation requires changes in their environment (e.g., moving to a new location with a lower risk of flooding). Other causes include lack of awareness of the urgency and severity of climate change, lack of knowledge of the drivers or consequences of climate change or what actions to take, incorrect assumptions of what causes climate change, and misperceptions of the carbon footprint associated with individual actions. The lack of awareness of the urgent need to mitigate climatechange can contribute to present bias and status quo bias due to a false sense of contentment. The lack of knowledge has been shown to correlate with less concern about climate change, which can contribute to status quo bias.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A summary of the cognitive biases, causes, and debiasing tools This section describes several key cognitive biases on climate change discovered in prior literature, provides examples associated with each bias, and explains the downstream consequences of the biases on climate beliefs and actions. Recent studies revealed an attentional bias of climate change, where people attend to climate information differently depending on their political orientation or prior beliefs about Attention away from climate information in conservatives can reinforce their climate disbelief and inaction, while attention toward climate information in liberals or the concerned can elevate their belief and level of concern of climate change, thus contributing to polarization.In addition to selective attention, a perceptual bias arises from selective perception where people misperceive in-group and out-group norms by overweighing the voices and views from a few members of in-group or out-group members. This selective perception exaggerates the degree of support for a given climate policy from in-group members or the degree of opposition from out-group members, thus creating a false sense of polarization. A related memory bias is when people falsely recall the severity of climate change, and those who recall climate change to be less severe tend to show stronger skepticism and disbelief of climate change. The motivated recall can serve to protect and justify the previously held skepticism and disbelief. Apart from selective perception, another perceptual bias is the negative footprint illusion where people perceive a lower carbon footprint of a combination of conventional items and environmentally friendly items than the carbon footprint of the conventional items alone.A well-known cognitive bias is confirmation bias, which is the tendency to actively seek information that confirms prior beliefs (e.g., reading news articles that challenge climate change among conservatives), or to discount information that contradicts prior beliefs. This bias creates a barrier for shifting conservatives' position on climate change when the intervention only presents pro-climate change information. A recent paper revealed the neural mechanism of this</figDesc><table><row><cell>Cognitive biases</cell><cell>Causes of bias</cell><cell>Debiasing tools</cell></row><row><cell>Attentional bias</cell><cell>Motivated cognition</cell><cell>Framing</cell></row><row><cell>-attending to climate change</cell><cell>-information processing</cell><cell>-aligning climate communication</cell></row><row><cell>information differently depending on</cell><cell>being shaped by personal</cell><cell>with peoples' ideologies and values</cell></row><row><cell>political orientations</cell><cell>goals and needs</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Perceptual bias</cell><cell>Cognitive rigidity</cell><cell>Reconstruction</cell></row><row><cell>-inaccurate perceptions of ingroup</cell><cell>-inability to adapt to a new</cell><cell>-reconstructing accurate</cell></row><row><cell>norms and outgroup norms</cell><cell>environment or update prior</cell><cell>representations of social norms</cell></row><row><cell>-negative footprint illusion</cell><cell>beliefs given new information</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Recall bias</cell><cell>Lack of awareness</cell><cell>Observational learning</cell></row><row><cell>-falsely recalling climate change to be</cell><cell>-no awareness of the</cell><cell>-acquiring attitudes, norms, and facts</cell></row><row><cell>less serious, which is associated with</cell><cell>urgency and severity of</cell><cell>by observing the behavior of others or</cell></row><row><cell>higher skepticism of climate change</cell><cell>climate change</cell><cell>watching videos</cell></row><row><cell>Confirmation bias</cell><cell>Lack of knowledge</cell><cell>Forward-looking</cell></row><row><cell>-seeking information that confirms</cell><cell>-no knowledge about the</cell><cell>-generating arguments for forward-</cell></row><row><cell>prior beliefs, or discounting</cell><cell>causes or consequences of</cell><cell>looking options or considering the</cell></row><row><cell>information that contradicts prior</cell><cell>climate change, or what</cell><cell>legacy for future generations</cell></row><row><cell>beliefs</cell><cell>actions to take</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Present bias</cell><cell>Incorrect assumptions</cell><cell>Default</cell></row><row><cell>-priority given to people and</cell><cell>-inaccurate understandings</cell><cell>-making climate-friendly options the</cell></row><row><cell>objectives that are close in terms of</cell><cell>of the drivers of climate</cell><cell>default</cell></row><row><cell>time and space than more distant ones</cell><cell>change</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Status quo bias</cell><cell>Misperceptions</cell><cell>Visualization</cell></row><row><cell>-unwillingness to change the status</cell><cell>-underestimations of carbon</cell><cell>-highlighting human contributions to</cell></row><row><cell>quo because any change involves effort</cell><cell>footprints associated with</cell><cell>climate change as opposed to natural</cell></row><row><cell>and uncertainty</cell><cell>individual actions</cell><cell>causes</cell></row><row><cell>Pseudoinefficacy</cell><cell>Negative affect</cell><cell>Inoculation</cell></row><row><cell>-a false sense of inefficacy of</cell><cell>-reduced negative emotion</cell><cell>-exposing people to forewarning and</cell></row><row><cell>individual actions not making an</cell><cell>after taking one climate</cell><cell>using preemptive refutation to protect</cell></row><row><cell>appreciable contribution to solving a</cell><cell>action</cell><cell>them from misinformation</cell></row><row><cell>large overall problem</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Single action bias</cell><cell></cell><cell>Identity or value reinforcement</cell></row><row><cell>-perceiving a reduced risk of climate</cell><cell></cell><cell>-reinforcing one's identity and values</cell></row><row><cell>change after taking one climate action</cell><cell></cell><cell>to promote subsequent climate actions</cell></row></table><note>climate change (Luo and Zhao, 2021). In a series of eye-tracking studies, people who self- identified as more liberal focused more on the rising phase of a global temperature curve relative to the flatter phase of the curve, while those who self-identified as more conservative focused more on the flatter phase. This selective attention is also shown in other studies using an attentional blink paradigm and an attention cueing paradigm, where people who had greater concerns about climate change prioritized their attention toward climate-related words (e.g., carbon) or images (e.g., melting ice) over neutral ones.bias, which suggests that the neural representation of information strength is weakened when others' opinions oppose one's own (Kappes et al., 2020). In other words, during information processing the brain tends to disregard the strength of opposing evidence but incorporates the strength of confirming evidence. This bias provides one explanation of how some people remain skeptical about anthropogenic climate change despite overwhelming evidence by ignoring the strength of the scientific consensus on climate change.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>There are a number of tools to address motivated cognition. A commonly used tool is framing, which involves aligning climate communication with peoples' ideologies and values.For example, religious leaders (e.g., Pope Francis) who are concerned about climate change can promote environmental actions among conservatives via shared religious faith. A recent field experiment showed that Republican elites associating their concerns of climate change with economy, national security, faith, and conservative values, increased Republican individuals'</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Nigel Deans and two anonymous reviewers for providing helpful comments.</p><p>This work was supported by the Canada Research Chairs program (to JZ) and Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council Doctoral Fellowship (to YL).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Declaration of Interests</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumers underestimate the emissions associated with food but are aided by labels</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Camilleri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Larrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Patino-Echeverri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Clim. Chang</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shifting Republican views on climate change through targeted advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gustafson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leiserowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Clim. Chang</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neuroscience of motivated cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confirmation bias in the utilization of others&apos; opinion strength</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kappes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Harvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lohrenz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Montague</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sharot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inoculating the Public against Misinformation about Climate Change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leiserowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Maibach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Glob. Challenges</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1600008</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attentional and perceptual biases of climate change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Behav. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Dent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Benedict</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Brosnahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ditto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influencing Climate Change Attitudes in the United States: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Environ. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">101623</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moderating spillover: Focusing on personal sustainable behavior rarely hinders and can boost climate policy support</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sparkman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Attari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Res. Soc. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102150</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Truelove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Carrico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Raimi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Vandenbergh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Positive and negative spillover of pro-environmental behavior: An integrative review and theoretical framework</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Glob. Environ. Chang</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="138" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pseudoinecacy and the Arithmetic of Compassion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>V채stfj채ll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mayorga</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Numbers and Nerves: Information, Emotion, and Meaning in a World of</title>
		<editor>Data., S. Slovic, and P. Slovic</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oregon State University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="52" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Breaking cognitive barriers to a sustainable future</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognition and Emotion in Extreme Political Action: Individual Differences and Dynamic Interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zmigrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Dir. Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="218" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
