<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">CALIBRATING EXPLORE-EXPLOIT DECISIONS</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilona</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
							<email>ibass@fas.harvard.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elise</forename><surname>Mahaffey</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Arizona State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Bonawitz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">CALIBRATING EXPLORE-EXPLOIT DECISIONS</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:44+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>explore-exploit, pedagogical model Object Naming Matching Games Teacher Forms Representation New Games &amp; Rank Ordering A</term>
					<term>B</term>
					<term>C</term>
					<term>D</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Models of the explore-exploit problem have explained how children&apos;s decision making is weighed by a bias for information (directed exploration), randomness, and generalization. These behaviors are often tested in domains where a choice to explore (or exploit) is guaranteed to reveal an outcome. An often overlooked but critical component of the assessment of explore-exploit decisions lies in the expected success of taking actions in the first place-and, crucially, how such decisions might be carried out when learning from others. Here we examine how children consider an informal teacher&apos;s beliefs about the child&apos;s competence when deciding how difficult a task they want to pursue. We present a simple model of this problem that predicts that while learners should follow the recommendation of an accurate teacher, they should exploit easier games when a teacher overestimates their abilities, and explore harder games when she underestimates them. We tested these predictions in two experiments with adults (Experiment 1) and six-to eight-year-old children (Experiment 2). In our task, participants&apos; performance on a picture-matching game was either overestimated, underestimated, or accurately represented by a confederate (the &quot;Teacher&quot;), who then presented three new matching games of varying assessed difficulty (too easy, too hard, just right) at varying potential reward (low, medium, high). In line with our model&apos;s predictions, we found that both adults and children calibrated their choices to the Teacher&apos;s representation of their competence. That is, to maximize expected reward, when she underestimated them, participants chose games the Teacher evaluated as being too hard for them; when she overestimated them, they chose games she evaluated as being too easy; and when she was accurate, they chose games she assessed as being just right. This work provides insight into the early-emerging ability to calibrate explore-exploit decisions to others&apos; knowledge when learning in informal pedagogical contexts.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Children Use Teachers' Beliefs About Their Abilities to Calibrate</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Explore-Exploit Decisions</head><p>Children learn about the world through their own exploration <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Piaget, 1929;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Xu, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Xu &amp; Kushnir, 2013)</ref>, and past work has shown how children leverage playful exploration to gather evidence for themselves in ways that could facilitate learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bonawitz, van Schijndel, Friel, &amp; Schulz, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Sim &amp; Xu, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Singer, Golinkoff, &amp; Hirsh-Pasek, 2006)</ref>. When learning about the world, children are implicitly faced with decisions about whether to explore something new and unknown, or exploit a known outcome. Should they squeeze the fun squeaker they already know works on a toy, or expend energy trying to figure out if it does something even more exciting? (See e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Gopnik, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Schulz, Wu, Ruggeri, &amp; Meder, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Wilson, Bonawitz, Costa, &amp; Ebitz, 2021.)</ref> Of course, the explore-exploit problem is not unique to children, or even to humans.</p><p>Models of this problem have been used to explain behavior across a variety of species and contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Kaelbling, Littman, &amp; Moore, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sutton &amp; Barto, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Critically, however, human children also have access to a mode of learning that may be much less widespread: the existing knowledge of other people. Our ability to learn about the world through informal pedagogy allows humans to build up and pass down knowledge in a uniquely efficient and powerful way, and young children appear to be uniquely prepared to learn from the information provided by others <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csibra &amp; Gergely, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Koenig, Clément, &amp; Harris, 2004</ref>). Yet, we know relatively little about how explore-exploit decisions may be shaped by the people around us, their knowledge, and what they decide to teach us. Here we ask: How might children consider others' beliefs about what we're capable of when making decisions about whether to explore or exploit?</p><p>Formal models of pedagogical reasoning <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bonawitz &amp; Shafto, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Shafto &amp; Goodman, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Shafto, Goodman, &amp; Griffiths, 2014)</ref> provide the foundation for understanding why children might calibrate explore-exploit decisions to the beliefs of the person teaching them. Under these models, pedagogy is understood as a set of recursive, mutually dependent inferences: Good teachers should present the evidence they believe will maximize the learner's belief in the target hypothesis; and the learner updates their belief in that most likely hypothesis, assuming that the teacher sampled the evidence in this intentional, helpful way. And indeed, a growing body of literature has shown how even young children appear to bring these assumptions to bear when learning from others in pedagogical contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bonawitz et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Gweon, Pelton, Konopka, &amp; Schulz, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Shneidman, Gweon, Schulz, &amp; Woodward, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Yu, Landrum, Bonawitz, &amp; Shafto, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Children thus expect good teachers to present the evidence that would be most likely to lead the learner to the correct solution. But what that "optimal" set of exemplars actually is should hinge not only on the learner's beliefs and background knowledge, but in cases when the teacher provides scaffolding for child-directed activities, it should also depend on the learner's expected level of competence. To illustrate, consider a fifth grader asking their teacher for recommendations of books to read. A level-appropriate selection of books for the teacher to present to this child might include titles such as Charlotte's Web, Holes, or A Wrinkle in Time. But if the teacher has overestimated the child's abilities, they might present options like Of Mice and Men or Moby Dick that are simply too advanced; and a teacher who has underestimated their student's reading level might instead present choices that aren't nearly challenging enough, such as Amelia Bedelia or Dr. Seuss. Indeed, teachers' sensitivity to the Zone of Proxmial Development <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Vygotsky, 1978</ref>) is a key factor in successfully setting the stage for effective child-driven learning.</p><p>Importantly, however, past work also tells us that young learners are quite flexible, and may engage in compensatory actions to maximize learning despite sub-optimal teaching (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Gweon et al., 2014)</ref>. So, perhaps if that fifth grader detected that their competence was being overestimated, they could try to compensate by looking for the easiest book in the bunch. On the other hand, if the student's competence was clearly being underestimated, they could do the opposite by finding the most challenging book of those available. That is, in this paper, we want to investigate the intuition that mental state miscalibrations in pedagogical contexts could influence children's choices about whether to explore a potentially difficult task, versus exploit the more certain success associated with attempting a relatively easy task.</p><p>Some past work provides preliminary evidence for this hypothesis. In one study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bonawitz et al. (2011)</ref>, preschool-aged children observed an experimenter pedagogically demonstrate one function on a novel toy (which actually had four functions) in one of three conditions: they were either directly shown this demonstration by the experimenter; or they observed the experimenter provide this demonstration to another child; or they observed this same demonstration provided to an adult. Children then explored the toy themselves. When they were the direct recipients of pedagogy, children were more likely to restrict their exploration to the demonstrated function -which is in line with the predictions of the pedagogical model. Patterns of play were similar when children observed pedagogy provided to another child. But, when children observed pedagogy provided to an adult, they were more likely to explore non-demonstrated features of the toy <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bonawitz et al., 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Why might we see this selective interpretation of pedagogical sampling? One explanation is that children understood that the evidence the teacher would select for another child might be similar to what she would select for the participant; however, this assumption would not extend to sampling for an adult, given the vast differences in their prior knowledge and competence. Therefore, children may attend to whether a teacher's demonstration is likely to be relevant to them. However, these effects raise questions about how exactly children's inferences and explore-exploit decisions are shaped by what they believe a teacher knows about their abilities -which has yet to be directly empirically tested.</p><p>The current work asks whether young learners use information about the correctness of their teacher's beliefs about them to contextualize pedagogical actions and optimize their own choices. In particular, here we investigate how a teacher's representation of the learner's competence could shape learners' decisions about attempted task difficulty. This is in some ways different from the concept and causal learning research in which investigations of the pedagogical model are often situated. However, competence and knowledge may be tightly related in the context of pedagogy. For instance, past work has found that when acting as teachers themselves, preschoolers calibrate their own pedagogical demonstrations to their learner's competence <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Gweon &amp; Schulz, 2019)</ref>, similarly to how they do so in light of a learner's beliefs <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bass et al., 2019)</ref>. Further, just as instruction can constrain exploration in the context of novel toy exploration tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bonawitz et al., 2011)</ref>, 18-month-olds have been shown to rationally integrate information about their own abilities with adult-provided feedback about task difficulty, constraining their decisions about when to deploy physical effort accordingly <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lucca, Horton, &amp; Sommerville, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Tamis-LeMonda et al., 2008)</ref>. Moreover, notions of competence are necessarily connected to the explore-exploit problem, as agents require an understanding of their own ability level in order to decide whether to try something new, or stick with the safer, more certain outcome (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Sutton &amp; Barto, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>We suggest that if a teacher underestimates a learner's competence, that learner will be more likely to explore a potentially difficult task that could yield a higher reward.</p><p>Conversely, this kind of challenge-seeking might be curbed if a teacher instead overestimates that learner's abilities, leading to more decisions to exploit a more certain (albeit smaller) reward associated with completing a relatively easy task. We present a computational model that formalizes these intuitions. Leveraging a formal model of this decision-making process allows us not only to ground our predictions in a causal explanatory theory, but also to understand more precisely how and why these mental models may change with development.</p><p>In two pre-registered behavioral experiments, each with three between-subjects conditions, we test our predictions with adults (Experiment 1) and six-to eight-year-old children (Experiment 2). Although it is possible that children as young as four might be sensitive to subtle cues about others' knowledge in pedagogy <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bass et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bonawitz et al., 2011)</ref>, our task may prove difficult for younger children for two main reasons. First, explicit second-order false belief reasoning abilities -which may be recruited when considering another's false belief about one's own mental state -are still developing through the later preschool years <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Wellman, Cross, &amp; Watson, 2001</ref>). Second, we suspected that the added attentional demands associated with running this task remotely via Zoom due to the COVID-19 pandemic, as opposed to in-person as we originally planned, might make this task more difficult for a younger sample. Therefore, our investigation in this paper focused on 6-to 8-year-olds.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>This study was approved by the Rutgers University -Newark Institutional Review Board, protocol Pro2020000399. Informed consent was obtained from participants (Experiment 1) or their parents (Experiment 2) before the study was administered. Sample sizes, methods, and analysis plans for both experiments were pre-registered through AsPredicted.org. Sample sizes were determined based on effect sizes from pilot data, with the goal of reaching 80% power. 1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure.</head><p>This task was administered over Zoom, with stimuli displayed to participants using Open Broadcaster Software (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kominsky et al., 2021</ref> for an overview of this methodological approach). The same procedure was used for both experiments. See <ref type="figure">Figure   1</ref> for a schematic of the procedure used in this task. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>A schematic of the procedure used in our two experiments. A. The Teacher first labeled two novel objects. She either labeled one object correctly and one incorrectly (in the Overestimate and Underestimate conditions), or she labeled both objects incorrectly (in the Accurate condition). B. Then, the participant played two matching games with the Experimenter. This task was controlled such that all participants found all matches on the first "easy" game, but no matches on the second "hard" game. C. The Experimenter pulled up a display of the participant's performance on the two matching games. This display was either an overestimation, an underestimation, or an accurate display of the participant's performance (between subjects). The teacher saw this display and formed a representation of the participant's performance. D. The Teacher brought three new matching games for the participant to choose from, one of which she assessed as "not hard enough" for the participant (matches worth 3 points each), one "much too hard" (matches worth 5 points each), and one "just right" (matches worth 4 points each). The participant then ranked their preferences for which games they would most want to play.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction to Teacher.</head><p>After signing onto the call with the Experimenter, participants were introduced to the "Teacher" -who, they were told, would be joining the call periodically throughout the activity. Unbeknownst to participants, the Teacher was actually a pre-recorded video. To explain away the Teacher's inability to interact with the participant, it was established that she was experiencing a technical glitch such that she could hear the Experimenter, but not the participant. The Teacher then (temporarily) signed off the call.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Novel Object Naming.</head><p>Because the task would later involve the Teacher either accurately representing the learner's abilities (in the Accurate condition), or inaccurately representing the learner's abilities (in the Overestimate and Underestimate conditions), we wanted to avoid the possibility that participants would be more likely to follow the Teacher's recommendation in the Accurate condition simply because she was a more reliable teacher. To control for this, the Experimenter familiarized the participant with the names of two novel objects; then, she invited the Teacher back into the call, and asked her to name the objects. In the conditions in which the Teacher would later overestimate or underestimate the participant's abilities, she correctly labeled one of the two novel objects. In the Accurate condition, she incorrectly labeled both objects. Thus, in all three conditions, the Teacher was correct on one of three total judgments throughout the task. It is important to note that in all conditions, the Teacher professed some uncertainty about her ability to correctly identify these objects before doing so ("Hmm, well I've never seen these exact toys before, but I think that one is called..."). This provided a plausible explanation for the Teacher's inaccuracy other than her being generally unreliable or unknowledgeable, in order to help ensure that participants would not be unwilling to follow her recommendation later in the task simply due to her prior inaccuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimenter's Matching Games.</head><p>With the Teacher off the call again, participants were then shown how to play the matching game task. This was a simple memory matching game: Participants were shown a target picture and an array of cards with different colored shapes on them. This array of cards was then briefly flipped over, revealing pictures on their undersides. After the array had flipped back over (shape side up, picture side down), participants indicated the color and shape of the card they thought the match was under. Once the correct location for the match had been identified, the experimenter moved the target picture to a "counter", which tracked the matches the participant was able to complete.</p><p>After playing a practice game and displaying sufficient understanding of the task, participants were told they would be playing the Experimenter's two matching games: first an easy set, and then a hard set. Their goal would be to find as many matches as they could before time was up. In all conditions, the matching game task was controlled such that all participants finished the easy set, and no participant was able to complete any matches on the hard set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Teacher Forms Representation.</head><p>The Experimenter then pulled up a display of participants' results on the screen. In the Accurate condition, this display correctly showed 1/2 matching sets completed. In the Overestimate condition, the Experimenter "accidentally went to the answers screen", and the display showed 2/2 sets completed. In the Underestimate condition, the Experimenter "accidentally reset the counter", and the display showed 0/2 sets completed. The Teacher then re-entered the call and saw the display; she said she was about to pick out some new matching games to play, and would keep the participant's performance in mind when picking these new games. Due to the Teacher's previously established inability to hear the participant, participants were not able to correct the Teacher if she saw an inaccurate display (although some tried; see our exploratory analyses in Experiment 2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>New Games &amp; Rank Ordering.</head><p>The Teacher then returned with three new matching games, each of which would be worth a different number of points. Based on her purported understanding of the participant's performance on the Experimenter's matching games, the Teacher thought one of these games would be "just right" for the participant, and each correct match would be worth 4 points. Correct matches on the game that she thought "might not be hard enough" would be worth 3 points each; and for the game that she thought would be "much too hard", matches would be worth 5 points each. Participants were made aware that the Teacher would return later to see how many points they had earned. With the Teacher again off the call, the Experimenter then asked the participant which game they wanted to play, given that they would only have time to play one of the Teacher's new games. After participants made their initial choice, the experimenter feigned an inability to open the game and asked what their next choice would be if she couldn't get their first choice to work. By doing this, the experimenter elicited a natural ranked choice of the participant's game preferences. (Ultimately, the experimenter was able to open participants' first choice of game; unbeknownst to the participant, this game was actually the same for all participants, regardless of which game they selected as their first choice.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Comprehension Checks.</head><p>After playing this final matching game with the Experimenter, and then saying goodbye to the Teacher, participants were asked to recall: 1) how many of the Experimenter's matching sets the Teacher thought they were able to complete; and 2) how many of the novel objects the Teacher correctly named. Data from participants who were not able to answer these questions correctly after two attempts and a forced-choice follow-up were dropped and replaced prior to analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Coding.</head><p>Game choices were assigned different values (too easy = 1, just right = 2, too hard = 3), and rankings were assigned different weights (first choice = 2, second choice = 1, third choice = 0). From this, we calculated a "difficulty score", which was simply the weighted rank-ordering of participants' choices (e.g., a first choice of the "just right" game and a second choice of the "too hard" game implies a difficulty score of (2(2) + 1(3))/3 = 2.33). We computed this more continuous score as opposed to simply looking at first choices to allow for more sensitivity in our measure; we suspected from past work on epistemic trust that participants might have an initial bias to follow the teacher's recommendation across conditions (a pattern that was also supported by pilot data). 2</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model</head><p>Here we talk through the qualitative intuitions of the model to provide clarity on the general form of the expected response patterns. For detailed description of the quantitative predictions and fit to behavioral data, please see the Supplemental Materials.</p><p>We formalized our predictions by first considering the problem participants are solving in this task. When choosing to play one of the three presented games, participants likely computed something akin to the expected value of playing each of the three games.</p><p>This can be thought of simply as the maximum number of points (or reward, R) that could be earned by playing a particular game, weighted by the participant's belief p(S g ) that they will be able to successfully complete that particular matching game g:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">E(g) = R g p(S g )<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Because we used a point system in which harder games would be worth more points, the value of R g is known to the learner; but critically, p(S g ) is not. How might the probability of success be estimated? In addition to being influenced by participants' beliefs about their own competence (which we hold constant as their actual performance on the Experimenter's matching games), the probability of success will depend on the actual game difficulty -which, like p(S g ), is also unobserved. To infer this, participants must look to the available evidence: namely, the Teacher's statement about how difficult she thinks the game will be for the learner; and critically, the Teacher's beliefs about the learner's competence.</p><p>In our model (see <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>), the actual difficulty of each game (which, in theory, the Teacher knows) and the Teacher's beliefs about the learner's competence will mutually inform the statement the Teacher makes about how difficult she believes each game will be ("too easy", "too hard", or "just right"). In particular, if the actual game difficulty is if a participant chose the "too hard" game and did not make a second choice, their difficulty score would be 3). The one-way ANOVAs on difficulty scores were re-run excluding these participants, and the pattern of results was un-changed (Experiment 1: F (2, 49) = 4.2, p = .021, η 2 = .0146; Experiment 2: F (2, 50) = 9.45, p = 0.0003, η 2 = 0.274).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2</head><p>A causal graphical model of the inference problem in our experimental task. In order to estimate the probability of success on a particular game, the learner must infer the true level of game difficulty that would be most likely to lead to the Teacher's evaluation of how difficult that game would be for the learner, given her beliefs about the learner's competence.</p><p>about equal to the Teacher's subjective appraisal of the learner's abilities, the Teacher will assess that game as being "just right". On the other hand, if the actual game difficulty exceeds what the Teacher thinks the learner is capable of, she will say the game is "much too hard"; conversely, if the actual game difficulty level is lower than the what the Teacher has represented as the learner's competence, she will instead judge that game to be "not hard enough". Thus, learners can use the Teacher's statement to reverse-infer what the actual difficulty of the game is, based on how competent the Teacher thinks they are. If the Teacher is accurate, then the learner can take her statements about game difficulty at face value, and trust that the game she says is "just right" probably will be. If the Teacher overestimated or underestimated the learner's abilities, then her statement that a game is "not hard enough" or "much too hard" suggests that the actual difficulty of that game (respectively) might be closer to the learner's actual ability level. In this way, the learner "compensates" for pedagogy that was generated using an inaccurate representation of their abilities. Together, the model thus predicts that learners should choose games that the **</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3</head><p>The average difficulty scores for adults' selected games across conditions in Experiment 1. Participants preferred easier games when the Teacher overestimated their knowledge, and harder games when she underestimated their knowledge, while those in the Accurate condition fell in between. **p &lt; 0.01. Error bars represent (+/-) the standard error.</p><p>In line with our pre-registered analysis plan, we first conducted a one-way ANOVA on the difficulty score for participants' preferred games. This ANOVA was significant:</p><p>F (2, 57) = 4.91, p = 0.011, η 2 = 0.147. Bonferroni-corrected pairwise comparisons revealed significant differences between the Overestimate and Underestimate conditions (p &lt; 0.01):</p><p>When the Teacher had overestimated participants' abilities, they opted to play games she thought would be easier for them (M = 1.77, SD = 0.41) than when the Teacher had underestimated their performance (M = 2.17, SD = 0.44). Although scores in the Accurate condition (M = 1.93, SD = 0.37) were not significantly different from the other two, the general pattern of results is well-supported by our model's predictions; see <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We also discretely analyzed participants' first choice of game across conditions. A 3x3 Fisher's exact test on these choices was significant (p = 0.031). To follow up on this result, we compared the modal response in each condition to chance (1/3) by exact binomial test. Interestingly, the most common first choice in all three conditions was the "just right" game (Overestimate: 12/20, one-tailed p = 0.013; Accurate: 17/20, one-tailed p &lt; 0.0001; Underestimate: 14/20, one-tailed p = 0.0008). In the Overestimate condition, 7/20 participants chose the predicted "too easy" game; and in the Underestimate condition, 5/20 participants chose the predicted "too hard" game; but neither of these proportions differed from chance (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>). Our computed difficulty score measure was thus able to capture more subtle differences in participants' preferences, despite an overall tendency to choose the recommended game.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4</head><p>Adults' first and second choices of games in Experiment 1, split by experimental condition. The 3x3 Fisher's exact test on adults' first choices was significant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>While adults generally wanted to attempt the game recommended by the Teacher across conditions (as we suspected might be the case), their rank-ordering of all three games revealed preferences that aligned with the predictions of our model. If the Teacher overestimated their knowledge, adults compensated by choosing games that she thought might not be challenging enough for them. In contrast, when she underestimated them, participants instead preferred games that she thought would be too difficult.</p><p>These findings lead to questions about whether children might also be able to use what a teacher believes about them when making decisions about whether to attempt relatively easier or more difficult tasks. This capacity may depend on a relatively mature Theory of Mind -and although children typically pass explicit false belief tasks around age 5, tasks that require higher-order false belief reasoning abilities (i.e., "I know that you know that I know...") may be difficult even for older children <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Wellman et al., 2001)</ref>. Therefore, it is unclear whether children will be as sensitive to the teacher's knowledge as adults were, and thus whether they will calibrate their explore-exploit decisions in a similar manner.</p><p>We investigate this possibility in Experiment 2 with a group of 6-to 8-year-old children.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Following the same analysis plan described in our pre-registration and in Experiment 1, we first ran a one-way ANOVA on difficulty scores for children's chosen games across conditions. This ANOVA was significant (F (2, 57) = 13.02, p &lt; 0.0001, η 2 = 0.314), and follow-up Bonferroni-corrected pairwise comparisons between conditions further revealed significant differences between the Overestimate condition and the other two conditions. Specifically, when the Teacher overestimated their competence, children selected easier games (M = 1.58, SD = 0.40) than when she had been accurate (M = 1.97, SD = 0.42; p &lt; 0.05) or when she had underestimated their abilities (M = 2.3, SD = 0.51; p &lt; 0.01). Therefore, like adults, children's choices in this task were in line with our model's predictions, such that the Teacher's beliefs about their abilities rationally shaped their decisions about attempted task difficulty; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 5</ref>.</p><p>A 3x3 Fisher's exact test on children's first choices across conditions was significant (p = 0.0001), so we again followed up with binomial tests comparing the modal response in each condition to chance (1/3). A majority of children in the Accurate condition chose the "just right" (16/20, one-tailed p &lt; 0.0001). In the Overestimate condition, 10/20 children picked the "just right" game (one-tailed p = 0.092); this was closely followed by the</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 6</head><p>Children's first and second choices of games in Experiment 2, split by experimental condition. The 3x3 Fisher's exact test on children's first choices was significant.</p><p>predicted "too easy" game (9/20), although this latter proportion did not differ from chance. In contrast, the most common choice in the Underestimate condition was the "too hard" game (11/20, one-tailed p = 0.038). See <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> for a summary of these results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory Analyses</head><p>We conducted two sets of post-hoc exploratory analyses that were not included in our original pre-registration. First, we investigated possible effects of age on children's choices by correlating age with difficulty scores separately for each of the three conditions.</p><p>(There were no differences in the average age of children across conditions; p = 0.878.)</p><p>These correlations were non-significant in the Overestimate and Accurate conditions (ps ≥ 0.59). However, age was significantly and positively related to the difficulty of games that children chose in the Underestimate condition (r(18) = 0.57, p = 0.009; significant at our adjusted α = 0.017; see <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>). Thus, when the Teacher underestimated their abilities, older children were more likely than younger children to compensate by choosing the game the Teacher thought would be too difficult.</p><p>Our second set of exploratory analyses was motivated by anecdotal reports from our experimenters that several children in this task spontaneously "protested" at various points on the call when the Teacher was forming or had recently referred to her beliefs about the child's competence. We wanted to know whether the frequency and degree of such protests  differed across our three conditions. We pre-registered these analyses after completing our original pre-registered analysis plan, but before coding or analyzing protest behaviors.</p><p>We coded the degree of protest at three key points: When the Teacher initially formed her belief about the participant's competence; when the Teacher presented the three new games for the child to choose from; and when the Teacher returned at the end of the call to see how well the participant did with their selected game. 4 At each of these three time points, protests were coded on a scale of 0-5, where 0 = no protest, and 5 = the most vehement protest observed in our sample. To assess vehemence of protest, coders considered factors including emotional valence and repetition and volume of speech. (Two coders who were naïve to the hypotheses of our study were in high agreement about protest behaviors at all three time points, r ≥ 0.91.) We computed the mean of these three scores to produce an average protest score for each participant. One child in the Overestimate <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We recognize that protests at the third time point may have been motivated by different factors than the first two, because these protests necessarily occurred after the teacher had made her game selection and the child had successfully completed that game. In fact, as we note in the pre-registration, this is precisely why we decided to code protest at this third time point: These protests may have reflected a desire for reputation management rather than an attempt to correct the teacher's knowledge in order to calibrate her subsequent evidence selection. However, there were only a total of 3 instances of protest at this time point in our entire sample of 60 children, making it impossible to statistically compare the frequency of these protests across conditions. The patterns of results reported below do not change when examining the frequency of protest across conditions (all 3 children who protested at the third time point also protested at one of the other 2), nor when protests at the third time point were omitted in the calculation of average degree of protest (F (2, 36) = 3.52, p = 0.036, η 2 = 0.112).</p><p>condition, whose overall protest score fell more than 2 standard deviations above the mean for that condition, was excluded from analyses involving average protest scores.</p><p>First, we simply looked at the number of children who protested across the three conditions. A 2x3 Fisher's exact test was significant (p = 0.023) -as expected, children</p><p>were more likely to protest in the two conditions in which the Teacher held inaccurate beliefs (Overestimate: 7/20; Underestimate: 8/20) than in the Accurate condition (1/20).</p><p>See <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>, left panel.</p><p>We also compared the average degree of protest across conditions. A one-way ANOVA was significant (F (2, 56) = 3.93, p = 0.025, η 2 = 0.123) and post-hoc</p><p>Bonferroni-corrected pairwise comparisons found that protests in the Underestimate condition were more vehement than in the Accurate condition (p &lt; .05). Extending past work on children's pedagogical reasoning and Theory of Mind, these findings suggest that young children not only understand that teachers may have false beliefs about them, but also recognize that these beliefs need to be corrected if the teacher is to provide appropriate evidence. Left Panel: Children were more likely to protest in the two conditions in which the teacher held a false belief than in the Accurate condition. Right Panel: Children's protest were more vehement in the Underestimate condition than in the Accurate condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Experiment 2 shows that children use a teacher's beliefs about their abilities to directionally adjust their learning from that teacher's future demonstrations. Although sixto eight-year-olds are relatively proficient at reasoning explicitly about others' minds, these findings are nonetheless impressive. Adult-like performance on our task required an understanding of how exactly the Teacher's (false) beliefs would influence her pedagogical sampling and, critically, what kinds of actions they as learners could take in order to compensate for such conceptual misalignments and preserve the highest chance of success.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Learners are constantly faced with decisions about whether to exploit known outcomes, or face uncertainty and explore the unknown. But we know relatively little about how explore-exploit decisions might be carried out in social learning contextsspecifically, how such decisions reflect a teacher's beliefs about the learner's competence. If teachers are to select helpful evidence, they must consider what exactly their learner already knows; and for learners to be able to interpret the meaning of that evidence, they must consider whether their teacher is sampling appropriately for them. Do learners use a teacher's beliefs about their competence to calibrate explore-exploit decisions? Our results suggest that they do, even in early childhood. When a teacher correctly understood their competence, adults and six-to eight-year-olds were happy to play a game that the teacher thought would be about right for them. However, if she overestimated their knowledge, participants compensated by choosing to play games that the teacher thought might not be challenging enough for them; in contrast, when she underestimated them, participants instead preferred games that she thought would be too difficult. Thus, beyond a mere sensitivity to an informant's beliefs about them, learners used this information to rationally adjust their choices when making decisions about the expected success of taking actions in the first place. This work provides exciting new evidence about the development of pedagogical reasoning that follows naturally from existing formal models <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bonawitz &amp; Shafto, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Shafto &amp; Goodman, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Shafto et al., 2014)</ref>. Namely, even young learners appear to understand that: (1) Good teaching requires the teacher to have an accurate understanding of the learner's abilities; (2) If a teacher holds an inaccurate belief about a learner, the evidence she selects for them may be inappropriate; and (3) If faced with a teacher with inaccurate beliefs about them, learners can help mitigate breakdowns in learning by making decisions that would directionally compensate for the teacher's inaccurate beliefs.</p><p>That children were more likely to spontaneously protest when the teacher held a false belief about them suggests that children understood how they could take action to try to correct the teacher's beliefs and prevent misleading pedagogy; and despite the futility of these efforts, children nonetheless then proceeded to make decisions about how to explore or exploit the options that were available to them in a way that would maximize their chance of success. These results demonstrate highly sophisticated recursive mental state reasoning in pedagogical contexts, and raise exciting questions about the cognitive developmental capacities that underlie such reasoning. It could be fruitful to ask whether even younger children (e.g., toddlers and preschoolers) are able to consider a teacher's beliefs about them when learning from their future demonstrations, and to directly correlate performance on this task with independent measures of false belief reasoning abilities. Testing younger children could also elucidate the extent to which experience with formal schooling and structured classroom learning might have facilitated reasoning in our current experiments.</p><p>Further, what exactly children believed the Teacher was inferring about them in this task is open to interpretation. Did they think her judgment of their performance was limited to this particular matching game task? Or might they have taken this to be an evaluation of their competence in general? Answers to these questions could inform our understanding of how the current findings might extend to more formal pedagogical contexts, such as classroom settings. Student-teacher rapport is a key factor in predicting students' academic success (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Wentzel, 2009</ref> for a review). For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Skinner and Belmont (1993)</ref> found that teachers' support of individual students' autonomy predicted children's motivation in grades three through five; and correlations have been found between student-instructor relationships and student achievement orientations even in samples of college students <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Creasey, Jarvis, &amp; Gadke, 2009)</ref>. While rapport is a rich and complex construct that likely comprises a multitude of mutually dependent social judgments that extend beyond the confines of one specific task (e.g., general liking of one another), it is possible that one component of rapport is this sense that a teacher is providing evidence at the appropriate level for the learner. In order to connect this work to applications in formal education, it will be critical to investigate how children believe teachers' judgments of their competence generalize across domains, tasks, and time.</p><p>One potential limitation of these results lies in our use of the novel object naming pretrials. We included these pretrials in order to ensure that the number of correct epistemic judgments the Teacher made was matched across conditions. One possible concern with this task is that the Teacher was established as slightly more reliable in the Underestimate and Overestimate conditions (1/2 correct labels) than in the Accurate condition (0/2 correct labels) in the pretrials. If it were the case that observing more inaccurate labels in the pretrial events should cause children to believe that the Teacher was generally unreliable or unknowledgeable, then we should have seen behaviors that work against our hypothesis and findings: namely, children in the Accurate condition (where the Teacher showed greatest pretrial inaccuracy) should have shown a relatively "flat" distribution of final choices (not trusting the Teachers' labels about the game difficulty), making it less likely to detect effects comparing to the other conditions. Instead, we saw that 16/20 children in the Accurate condition chose the predicted "just right" game, allowing us to rule out this concern. Another possible concern is that the nature of the pretrial labeling inaccuracy differs qualitatively from the within-task inaccuracy about the child's competence to some extent. In future versions of this task, we might consider using a control in which the Teacher was always initially miscalibrated, but the Experimenter corrected them either before they selected the new games, or after. In this case, the Teacher always spends the same amount of time with a false belief about the participant's competence, and is always corrected -but only in one case would the Teacher's beliefs be accurate when she was selecting the new task. 5 Of course, there are numerous contextual factors that might have shifted our results around quantitatively. Our primary goal was to demonstrate whether learners use teachers' beliefs about their abilities to calibrate explore-exploit decisions at all (rather than to quantify the precise extent of such a reactiveness, as the extent would also be sensitive to other contextual factors). We believe the current study provides clear evidence of the role of such social calibrations on choice.</p><p>In both experiments, there were patterns in our data that could be worth exploring further in future work. For instance, we observed a first-choice bias for the game that the Teacher thought would be "just right" for the participant across conditions in both experiments, particularly with adults in Experiment 1 (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>). This pattern may reflect a "regression towards the mean" with respect to attempted task difficulty when learning from pedagogy. A general bias to trust teachers' testimony may be rational given the assumptions underlying models of pedagogy <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Jaswal, Croft, Setia, &amp; Cole, 2010</ref>; see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Buchsbaum, Gopnik, Griffiths, &amp; Shafto, 2011)</ref>. Further, under the framework of our presented causal model, the degree to which the Teacher's statement about game difficulty is quantitatively related to inferences about actual game difficulty is not specified. Thus, a "just right" bias may suggest that participants interpreted the Teacher's subjective appraisal of "not hard enough" in the Overestimate condition (for instance) as indicating an actual game difficulty that was even lower than the Teacher's perception of their competence.</p><p>We also saw that a majority of children's first choices in the Underestimate condition was the predicted "too hard" game, while in the Overestimate condition, more children opted for the "just right" game (although of these children, almost all of them chose the predicted "too easy" game as their second choice). There are several possible (non-mutually exclusive) explanations for this asymmetry in our results. First, it could be that children were simply overly confident in their own abilities relative to adults. This would not only be consistent with past work finding that children tend to overestimate their own abilities across a variety of domains <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Plumert, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Yussen &amp; Levy, 1975)</ref>, but also ties into the predictions of our computational model. In our model, we suggest that learners may gauge the probability of succeeding at a task using both the difficulty of that task and their own perceived competence. We held this latter variable constant in the current work by controlling participants' performance on the Experimenter's matching games; future work could instead test the converse by holding the Teacher's beliefs constant, but manipulating the participant's ability to complete the task. This might illuminate the role that confidence plays in learners' decisions about attempted task difficulty during pedagogy. With adults in Experiment 1, we assessed the role of challenge-seeking and Need for Cognition on choices in this task -which, while not a direct measure of confidence per se, could nonetheless be related to the degree to which learners think they might be able to complete difficult tasks. Although we did not find an effect of these individual differences in our adult sample (see Supplemental Materials), we did find a relationship between age and attempted task difficulty within the Underestimate condition in Experiment 2. While it is possible that this result simply reflects greater sensitivity to our experimental manipulation in older children, we find this unlikely, given that we did not find age effects in the other two conditions. Rather, age might be something of a proxy measure for confidence here, making the "too hard" game a more rational choice for these children in their computations of the probability of success for each game. The notion of confidence may also be tied to children's propensity to protest in an attempt to correct the teacher's beliefs, and there is likely high variability in the degree to which children feel confident or empowered to speak up and correct a teacher if they detect a conceptual misalignment (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Kleitman, Stankov, Allwood, Young, &amp; Mak, 2013)</ref>. Again, as we think about how these findings may be able to be connected to rapport and learning in the classroom, it will be important to consider when and why different children might be more or less likely to attempt to correct their teacher's beliefs, and how this could differentially impact the evidence they receive as a result.</p><p>Second, it is possible that this asymmetry reflects something about the trade-off between p(S G ) and R g in the computation of the expected value for each game across conditions. More children first opted for the "just right" game in the Overestimate condition, which could indicate that the prospect of earning more points was worth the risk of this game possibly being too hard for them; but of these children, almost all of them chose the predicted "too easy" game as their second choice, driving difficulty scores down and leading to detectable differences between conditions. This is in contrast to the Underestimate condition, in which most children's first choice was the predicted "too hard" game; but those who did choose the "just right" game first were then split in their second choices, such that some children might have been quite certain that they would not be able to complete the game the teacher thought would be too hard for them. Understanding individual differences in the relative weights on p(S G ) and R g , and how these might be related to different decision-making strategies in these and related tasks, would be an exciting direction for future work.</p><p>Third, it is possible that children were particularly motivated to demonstrate their true abilities to the Teacher when she had underestimated them. Past work has found that children begin managing their reputation with others starting early in development <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Aloise-Young, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Silver &amp; Shaw, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Zhao, Heyman, Chen, &amp; Lee, 2018)</ref>, and act so as to clarify potential misrepresentations of their own competence <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Asaba &amp; Gweon, 2022)</ref>.</p><p>Indeed, a subtle but important aspect of our method was that children knew that the Teacher would return at the end of the task to see how many points they had earned.</p><p>Perhaps children had a stronger desire to correct negative misconceptions about them (in the Underestimate condition) than positive misconceptions about them (in the Overestimate condition). This notion is also supported by our quantitative computational modeling results, in which children (particularly older children) selected the "too hard" game in the Underestimate condition much more often than our model predicted (see Supplemental Materials). Thus, social communicative pressures that were not accounted for by our model may have influenced children's decision-making in this task. Future work could explore whether the asymmetry in our results persists when children do not expect the teacher to observe their final performance.</p><p>Finally, it is worth noting that our approach to the explore-exploit problem does not fall along traditional clean boundaries as previously examined in the literature. In our matching game task, all options involved some degree of exploration (as there was uncertainty about what exactly the task would be), as well as a known potential maximum reward. We defined "exploiting" as selecting a game that would be less challenging, thus making it more certain that the participant would be able to attain the maximum possible reward given this choice. On the other hand, "exploring" was defined as choosing to attempt a task that might be more challenging, such that the maximum possible reward was higher, but there was less certainty about whether that maximum reward was attainable. This operationalization follows naturally from past work on the role of expected values and utilities in decision-making (see e.g., Jara-Ettinger, <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Gweon, Schulz, &amp; Tenenbaum, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Lieder &amp; Griffiths, 2020)</ref>. Importantly, defining explore-exploit decisions in this way allowed us to control for our variables of interest and identify how exactly children take teachers' beliefs into account when making such decisions. Further, whether a decision constitutes exploring or exploiting may not always be clearly defined, as the decision-maker may have some knowledge both about the reward landscape and the underlying utilities. However, future work might examine how trade-offs between social information and children's beliefs about their own competence interact in more traditional explore-exploit paradigms.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Families were recruited to participate online through advertisements on social media and via ChildrenHelpingScience.com. As in Experiment 1, we recruited 20 participants per condition such that our final sample included 60 children (M (SD) age = 88.1(9.58) months, range = 72 − 108 months; N = 29 female). A total of three children were dropped and replaced prior to analysis for failure to pass the built-in check questions (N = 2) or terminating the study early (N = 1).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>The average difficulty scores for children's selected games across conditions in Experiment 2. Mirroring the results from adults in Experiment 1, children preferred easier games when the Teacher overestimated their knowledge, and harder games when she underestimated their knowledge, while those in the Accurate condition fell in between. * p &lt; 0.05; **p &lt; 0.01. Error bars represent (+/-) the standard error.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 8 Left Panel: Children were more likely to protest in the two conditions in which the teacher held a false belief than in the Accurate condition. Right Panel: Children's protest were more vehement in the Underestimate condition than in the Accurate condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Teacher assessed as being more difficult in the Underestimate condition, and less difficult in the Overestimate condition, with the Accurate condition falling in between.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Experiment 1: Adults</cell></row><row><cell>Participants.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Adults were recruited using the Rutgers University -Newark psychology subject</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">pool and were compensated with course credit. Our final sample consisted of 60 adults</cell></row><row><cell>(M (SD) Results</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Experiment 1 (Adults)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>3</cell></row><row><cell>Difficulty Score for</cell><cell>Chosen Games</cell><cell>1.5 2 2.5</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Overestimate</cell><cell>Accurate</cell><cell>Underestimate</cell></row></table><note>age = 22.16(4.96) years, range = 18 − 44 years; N = 46 female). Data from an additional 7 participants were dropped and replaced due to failure to pass the built-in check questions described above.</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">In our pre-registration, we neglected to re-run our power analysis after changing our primary dependent measure from a categorical variable to a continuous variable. Therefore, although the pre-registration denotes our intention to run 30 participants in each condition, this was in error; 20 participants per condition is sufficient for our anticipated effect sizes.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Some participants did not make a second choice, either because they opted not to provide one (N=1 child in Experiment 2), or because they were run in an early version of the task in which second choices were not solicited (N=8 adults in Experiment 1, N=6 children in Experiment 2; seeFigures 4 and 6). For these participants, difficulty scores were simply treated as the unweighted value of the first game they chose (e.g.,</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Because our adult sample was drawn from the psychology subject pool, these participants had previously completed a "prescreener survey" that included measures of challenge-seeking and Need for Cognition (NFC). In a post-hoc exploratory regression model, we asked whether individual differences in participants' challenge-seeking and NFC might have contributed to variance in our results. However, experimental condition was the sole significant predictor of the difficulty scores for participants' chosen games. See Supplemental Materials for additional details.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">We thank an anonymous reviewer for this suggestion.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Taisha Blanc and Sugandhi Yerram Reddy for assistance with coding.</p><p>Thanks also to our participating families and to ChildrenHelpingScience.com. This work was funded in part by an American Fellowship from AAUW to IB, and by support from the McDonnell Foundation to EB.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This work demonstrates how even young learners may capitalize on subtle information about others' beliefs about them to make rational inferences during informal pedagogy. We find novel evidence that young children and adults alike consider their own competence in deciding how difficult a task they want to take on. This work connects to and extends prior work on explore-exploit decisions and inferences from pedagogical situations, showing that from a young age, learners deftly reason both about evidence, and the people providing that evidence, to make rational decisions even from imperfect teaching. Although many open questions remain, we hope that we have neither overestimated nor underestimated the potential implications of the current work.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The development of self-presentation: Self-promotion in 6-to 10-year-old children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aloise-Young</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1521/soco.1993.11.2.201</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="222" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Young children infer and manage what others think about them</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Asaba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2105642119</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">32</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Children&apos;s developing theory of mind and pedagogical evidence selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gopnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ramarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shafto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wellman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonawitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dev0000642</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="286" to="302" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Computational models of development, social influences. Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonawitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shafto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cobeha.2015.12.008</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="100" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonawitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shafto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Spelke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The double-edged sword of pedagogy: Instruction limits spontaneous exploration and discovery</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2010.10.001</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Children balance theories and evidence in exploration, explanation, and learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonawitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J P</forename><surname>Van Schijndel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Friel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2011.12.002</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="234" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Children&apos;s imitation of causal action sequences is influenced by statistical and pedagogical evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Buchsbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gopnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shafto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2010.12.001</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="331" to="340" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Student attachment stances, instructor immediacy, and student-instructor relationships as predictors of achievement expectancies in college students</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Creasey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Jarvis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gadke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1353/csd.0.0082</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of College Student Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="372" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural pedagogy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Csibra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gergely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2009.01.005</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Childhood as a solution to explore-exploit tensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gopnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2019.0502</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20190502</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1803" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sins of omission: Children selectively explore when teachers are under-informative</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pelton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Konopka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2014.04.013</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">132</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="341" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From exploration to instruction: Children learn from exploration and tailor their demonstrations to observers&apos; goals and competence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/cdev.13059</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="148" to="164" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The naïve utility calculus: Computational principles underlying commonsense psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jara-Ettinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TiCS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="589" to="604" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Young children have a specific, highly robust bias to trust testimony</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Jaswal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Setia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797610383438</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1541" to="1547" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement learning: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kaelbling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Littman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1613/jair.301</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of artificial intelligence research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kleitman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Stankov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">K L</forename><surname>Mak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Self-directed learning oriented assessments in the asia-pacific</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-94-007-4507-0_8</idno>
		<editor>M. M. C. Mok</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="153" />
			<pubPlace>Dordrecht; Netherlands</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Metacognitive self-confidence in school-aged children</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust in testimony: Children&apos;s use of true and false statements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Koenig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Clément</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.0956-7976.2004.00742.x</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="694" to="698" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organizing the methodological toolbox: Lessons learned from implementing developmental methods online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Kominsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Begus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Colantonio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Leonard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mackey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonawitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.702710</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resource-rational analysis: Understanding human cognition as the optimal use of limited computational resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X1900061X</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Infants rationally decide when and how to deploy effort</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lucca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Horton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sommerville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-019-0814-0</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="372" to="379" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The child&apos;s conception of the world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Piaget</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1929" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY: Harcort, Brace</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relations between children&apos;s overestimation of their physical abilities and accident proneness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Plumert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0012-1649.31.5.866</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="866" to="876" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Searching for rewards like a child means less generalization and more directed exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ruggeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797619863663</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1561" to="1572" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teaching games: Statistical sampling assumptions for learning in pedagogical situations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shafto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the 30th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A rational account of pedagogical reasoning: Teaching by, and learning from, examples</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shafto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2013.12.004</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning from others and spontaneous exploration: A cross-cultural investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Shneidman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Woodward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/cdev.12502</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="723" to="735" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pint-sized public relations: The development of reputation management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Silver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2018.01.006</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="279" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning higher-order generalizations through free play: Evidence from 2-and 3-year-old children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dev0000278</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="642" to="651" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Play = learning: How play motivates and enhances children&apos;s cognitive and social-emotional growth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Golinkoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hirsh-Pasek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivation in the classroom: Reciprocal effects of teacher behavior and student engagement across the school year</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Skinner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Belmont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-0663.85.4.571</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Educational Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="571" to="581" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reinforcement learning: An introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>MIT press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When infants take mothers&apos; advice: 18-month-olds integrate perceptual and social information to guide motor action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tamis-Lemonda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Adolph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lobo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Karasik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ishak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Dimitropoulou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0012-1649.44.3.734</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="734" to="746" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mind in society</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Vygotsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Meta-analysis of theory-of-mind development: The truth about false belief</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wellman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1467-8624.00304</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="684" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Students&apos; relationships with teachers as motivational contexts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wentzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of motivation at school</title>
		<editor>K. R. Wentzel &amp; A. Wigfield</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="322" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Balancing exploration and exploitation with information and randomization. Current opinion in behavioral sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonawitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Costa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Ebitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards a rational constructivist theory of cognitive development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000153</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">126</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="841" to="864" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Infants are rational constructivist learners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kushnir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0963721412469396</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Questioning supports effective transmission of knowledge and increased exploratory learning in pre-kindergarten children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Landrum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonawitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Shafto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/desc.12696</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developmental changes in predicting one&apos;s own span of short-term memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Yussen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0022-0965(75</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Child Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">90079</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Telling young children they have a reputation for being smart promotes cheating</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Heyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/desc.12585</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12585</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
