<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Transcranial direct current stimulation above the medial prefrontal cortex facilitates decision-making following periods of low outcome controllability</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gábor</forename><surname>Csifcsák</surname></persName>
							<email>gabor.csifcsak@uit.no</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UiT The Arctic University of Norway</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9037</postCode>
									<settlement>Tromsø</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jorunn</forename><surname>Bjørkøy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UiT The Arctic University of Norway</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9037</postCode>
									<settlement>Tromsø</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sarjo</forename><surname>Kuyateh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UiT The Arctic University of Norway</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9037</postCode>
									<settlement>Tromsø</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haakon</forename><surname>Reithe</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UiT The Arctic University of Norway</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9037</postCode>
									<settlement>Tromsø</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Mittner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UiT The Arctic University of Norway</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9037</postCode>
									<settlement>Tromsø</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">UiT The Arctic</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Norway</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Huginbakken 32</addrLine>
									<postCode>9037</postCode>
									<settlement>Tromsø</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Transcranial direct current stimulation above the medial prefrontal cortex facilitates decision-making following periods of low outcome controllability</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:46+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>learned helplessness</term>
					<term>medial prefrontal cortex</term>
					<term>reinforcement learning</term>
					<term>tDCS</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent studies suggest that choice behavior in reinforcement learning tasks is shaped by the level of outcome controllability. In particular, &quot;Pavlovian bias&quot; (PB) seems to be enhanced under low levels of control, manifesting in approach tendencies towards rewards and response inhibition when facing potential losses. PB has also been associated with learned helplessness (LH), raising the possibility that motor passivity and poor coping capabilities in clinical conditions with LH are due to exaggerated PB in decision-making. The medial prefrontal cortex (mPFC) has been implicated both in evaluating outcome controllability and in the development of LH. The current study tested if high-definition transcranial direct current stimulation (HD-tDCS) above the mPFC of healthy humans can influence PB, and counteract the previously documented, deleterious behavioral effects of low outcome controllability during reinforcement learning. In a pre-registered, between-group, doubleblind study (N = 103 adults, both sexes), we tested the interaction between controllability and HD-tDCS on parameters of choice behavior in a Go/NoGo task. Relative to sham stimulation, active HD-tDCS resulted in more robust performance improvement following reduced control, an effect that was more pronounced in appetitive trials. In addition, we found evidence for weaker PB when active HD-tDCS was administered during low controllability over outcomes. Computational modeling revealed that parameter estimates of learning rate and choice randomness were modulated by controllability, HD-tDCS and their interaction. Overall, these results highlight the potential of our HD-tDCS protocol for interfering with choice arbitration under low levels of control, resulting in more adaptive behavior.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Value-based decision-making is essential for guiding actions towards influencing external events in our favor. Recently, it has been suggested that deliberation strategies can be adjusted to the perceived level of controllability of the environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Dorfman &amp; Gershman, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Ly et al., 2019)</ref>. When uncertainty around action outcomes is increased, a commonly utilized heuristic is to rely more heavily on a "Pavlovian bias" (PB), manifesting in tendencies for approaching reward-predictive cues, and motor inhibition when facing potential punishment <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Dayan and Berridge, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Rangel et al., 2008)</ref>. A possible explanation for this phenomenon is that the instrumental system relies on more effortful calculation of stimulus-action/action-outcome associations that does not pay off when outcomes are independent of actions. Conversely, Pavlovian stimulus-outcome learning may provide more precise predictions about upcoming events in the absence of response-feedback contingency, which in turn can optimize behavior more cost-effectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Dayan et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Dorfman and Gershman, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Rangel et al., 2008)</ref>.</p><p>In extreme cases, the absence of control over aversive events can induce learned helplessness (LH), characterized by anxiety, motor passivity and impaired decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Maier &amp; Seligman, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Pryce et al., 2011)</ref>. Once established, LH can also hinder problem solving in new situations with regained control, leading to persistent maladaptive coping.</p><p>Intriguingly, inaction that is elicited by negative outcomes is a Pavlovian-type response <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Dayan and Berridge, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Rangel et al., 2008)</ref>, raising the possibility that LH is an excessive manifestation of PB in decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Maier &amp; Seligman, 2016)</ref>. On the neural level, perceived controllability has been associated with the medial prefrontal cortex (mPFC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Diener et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Kerr et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Ly et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Maier &amp; Seligman, 2016)</ref>, which regulates activity in subcortical structures as a function of outcome controllability <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Amat et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Kerr et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Maier &amp; Seligman, 2016)</ref>. In the case of LH, low perceived controllability of negative events can lead to weaker top-down suppression from mPFC towards the dorsal raphe nucleus and the amygdala, both of which have been implicated in defensive behavior and pathological responses to threat <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Amat et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Kerr et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">LeDoux &amp; Daw, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Maier &amp; Seligman, 2016;</ref>.</p><p>The mPFC also seems to be crucial for mediating the balance between Pavlovian and instrumental responses. This is apparent under "Pavlovian conflict", when Pavlovian and instrumental systems promote opposing action policies. For instance, avoiding an appetitive stimulus or approaching large losses can be difficult, since goal-directed aims are in conflict with Pavlovian response tendencies <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Guitart-Masip et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hershberger, 1986;</ref>. In these situations, cognitive control (CC) linked to the dorsal anterior cingulate cortex (dACC) was proposed as a mechanism for suppressing maladaptive PB, and consequently, to optimize behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cavanagh et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Cavanagh and Frank, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Swart et al., 2018)</ref>. A recent study provided a more direct link between PB, controllability and dACC activity, by showing that intermittent absence of control over rewards and losses during reinforcement learning enhanced PB, and interfered with the neurophysiological correlate of CC, arising from dACC <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020)</ref>. The authors concluded that manipulation of controllability levels can influence the magnitude of CC over PB in action selection.</p><p>The aims of the current study were twofold. First, using a new controllability manipulation, we wished to extend knowledge on the effect of low outcome controllability on PB and response accuracy during reinforcement learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Dorfman and Gershman, 2019)</ref>. We hypothesized that, relative to a control condition, low controllability of outcomes would result in stronger PB and worse performance on Pavlovian-conflict trials. We anticipated that these effects, if sufficiently strong, would outlast the period of controllability manipulation, and manifest in a transfer to the subsequent block, where control over rewards and losses is restored.</p><p>Our second aim was to test if high-definition transcranial direct current stimulation (HD-tDCS) above the mPFC reverses the behavioral consequences of low controllability ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure   1A</ref>). Whereas conventional tDCS montages use large electrodes that are placed further apart from each other, HD-tDCS consists of several, closely arranged small electrodes that provide more focal stimulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Datta et al., 2009)</ref>. We selected a "4x1" HD-tDCS protocol that provides, according to simulation studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Csifcsák et al., 2018)</ref>, relatively circumscribed and predominantly excitatory stimulation in the mPFC, potentially even reaching the dACC ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure   1B</ref>). Overview of our study design (A), the spatial distribution and magnitude of the normal components of HD-tDCS-induced electric fields, representing currents either entering or leaving the cerebral cortex (depicted with positive and negative values, respectively), averaged across 18 head models of healthy adults (B), trial structure (C) and card types with feedback values (D).</p><p>To investigate the interaction between controllability and HD-tDCS, we adopted a double-blind, between-group design following a pre-registered protocol (https://osf.io/h45ju).</p><p>Concerning our hypothesis about the effect of HD-tDCS, we predicted that, relative to the sham protocol, active stimulation of the mPFC/dACC would enhance CC, resulting in weaker PB and improved response accuracy both during and following active stimulation. In this respect, we postulated that HD-tDCS would counteract the deleterious effects of low outcome controllability on task performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials &amp; Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Human subjects were recruited via public advertisements in Tromsø, Norway. Based on our a priori power analysis (repeated-measures analysis of variance, Cohen's f = 0.2 for the within-between factor interaction for block x group, 1-β = .9, α = .05, minimum required sample size = 96), 104 healthy adults from both sexes signed the informed consent and were randomized to one of four groups differing in the level of outcome controllability (control: high vs. manipulated: low) and HD-tDCS (active vs. sham). Data from one participant was discarded due to technical errors, yielding 103 participants (Control-Active: N = 26, Control-Sham: N = 26, Manipulated-Active: N = 27, Manipulated-Sham: N = 24; 64 females). We had to deviate from our pre-specified exclusion criteria (i.e., excluding participants not producing at least one Go and one NoGo response to all four card types in both blocks) because an impractically high number of participants (N = 50, evenly distributed across groups) had to be excluded from further analysis using this criterion. This change was made before any formal data-analysis took place and should therefore not compromise our pre-registered analyses. A possible explanation for the high number of subjects not producing both response options to all cards in each block may be that 14 participants showed excessive PB (predominantly in block 1), whereas another 19 individuals could very successfully suppress their PB (mainly in block 2), leading to ceiling/floor effects in terms of response accuracy for some cards.</p><p>However, we note that all participants in the final sample produced at least one Go and one NoGo response in both blocks. The groups did not differ in age (M = 23.3 years, SD = 2.7, F(3,99) = 0.61, p = .606) or sex (H(3) = 2.08, p = .555). Participants received gift cards worth approximately 22.5 USD. The study protocol complied with the Declaration of Helsinki and was approved by the Institutional Ethics Committee. All data and study materials are available at https://osf.io/d6eqk/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study design</head><p>First, a local anesthetic cream containing lidocaine/prilocaine ("EMLA") was distributed at electrode locations to ensure proper blinding. Next, we collected data on mood in the past month (PANAS-Past) and at the moment (PANAS-Present-Before) <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Watson et al., 1988)</ref>, personality attributes of motivated behavior (BIS/BAS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Carver and White, 1994</ref>) and predisposition to develop hopelessness (BHS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Beck et al., 1974)</ref>. Participants read task instructions (framed as a card game), performed a short practice session, and completed a quiz to ensure they understood all important aspects of the game. Quiz items with wrong answers were re-visited and discussed. Subsequently, we placed the electrode cap with electrodes and a small amount of conductive gel on the head of participants, and made sure that impedances were below 10 kOhm.</p><p>The task consisted of two task blocks with a response-feedback contingency of 70/30%, except for block 1 in participants in the manipulated groups. Active or sham HD-tDCS was also delivered during block 1, using a pre-specified double-blinded protocol. After each block, participants rated their perceived levels of success and control using two visual analogue scales (data missing for one participant). At the end of the session, participants had to guess whether they received active or sham stimulation, which was followed by assessing momentary mood scores (PANAS-Present-After) and a working memory task (OSPAN) <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Turner and Engle, 1989)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task and controllability manipulation</head><p>We used the modified version of the orthogonalized Go/NoGo task that was designed to investigate the neural correlates of Pavlovian bias during instrumental learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cavanagh et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Guitart-Masip et al., 2012)</ref>. Participants had to collect points by learning whether to respond (Go: "pick up") or not (NoGo: "leave on the table") to each card. They were informed that there would be "winning" and "losing" cards, and that Win cards would either provide a reward (10 points) or zero outcome, whereas Avoid cards could result in a loss (-10 points) or the absence thereof. Participants were also aware that favorable vs. unfavorable outcomes were determined by correct vs. incorrect responses, albeit in a probabilistic manner, with occasional "misleading outcomes". Outcomes were penalized by a "Go-cost" (-1 point) if they were preceded by a Go response. Therefore, following an active response, win, no win/no loss and loss outcomes were modified to 9, -1 and -11 points, respectively. The Gocost was framed as the cost/effort of exploring by action, mimicking real-life situations <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Teodorescu and Erev, 2014)</ref>. The task consisted of two experimental blocks consisting of 160 trials each (4 cards x 40 repetitions).</p><p>For running the task, we used a desktop computer with Windows XP Professional operating system, Intel (R) Core(TM)2 Duo CPU, 2.33 GHz, 1.96 GB RAM, and a 19-inch Sony Trinitron CRT monitor with 1024 x 768 resolution and 100 Hz refresh rate. Stimuli were presented and responses were collected using PsychoPy 1.83.04 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Peirce, 2007)</ref>. Trials started with a central fixation sign, followed by a custom-made card, the response screen, a short delay and the outcome ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1C</ref>). Participants were asked to respond only when the question mark appeared on the screen, which always occurred 1 second after cue-onset. Thus, the current task design did not enable assessing reaction times. In each block, 4 new cards were shown ("Go-to-Win", "NoGo-to-Avoid", "Go-to-Avoid", "NoGo-to-Win"), depending on their valence (reward vs. loss) and action requirement (Go vs. NoGo) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1D</ref>). Given that the Pavlovian system promotes approach towards rewards and inhibits response tendencies for losses, "Go-to-Win" and "NoGo-to-Avoid" cards were Pavlovian-congruent, whereas "Goto-Avoid" and "NoGo-to-Win" cards were associated with Pavlovian conflict.</p><p>We aimed to induce helplessness by manipulating action-outcome contingency in the manipulated groups. Unbeknownst to the participants, each manipulated individual was paired with a control participant. Control-manipulated pairs were created by counterbalancing HD-tDCS conditions. For each control participant, we recorded the outcomes from block 1 for the 4 card types separately, but removing the effect of the Go-cost when appropriate. These outcomes were shown in a random order, but in a card-specific manner to the corresponding paired subject in the manipulated group. That is, outcomes for a control participant's Go-to-Win card were presented to the matched participant from the manipulated group for the card that was also labeled as Go-to-Win. Our manipulation ensured that controllability over rewards and losses was absent in this block (except for the Go-cost), while matching reward/loss frequency between groups. Importantly, manipulated outcomes were penalized by a Go-cost based on manipulated participants' own responses, leading to a possible discrepancy in reward/loss magnitude between control and manipulated groups. For instance, a Go-associated reward (9 points) for a control participant could be modified to 10 points if the same outcome was presented following a manipulated participant's NoGo response (or vice versa). By keeping the Go-cost during controllability manipulation we aimed for promoting behavioral passivity and limiting active exploration, which are key features of helplessness <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Maier and Seligman, 1976;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Teodorescu and Erev, 2014)</ref>. However, it is important to note that the Go-cost provided some level of outcome controllability in block 1 to the manipulated groups, by reducing each outcome upon active responding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>HD-tDCS</head><p>Brain stimulation was delivered with a Starstim device, using neoprene headcaps, conductive gel (SignaGel) and Ag/AgCl electrodes with a diameter of 12mm (Neuroelectrics, Barcelona, Spain). Electrodes were placed at scalp positions Fpz, Fz, Cz, F3 and F4, with Fz serving as anode (2mA) and the surrounding four electrodes as returns (0.5mA each). The choice of the electrode montage was based on our simulations of HD-tDCS-induced electric fields, using 18 realistic head models of healthy adults, downloaded from a freely available database (https://osf.io/exbd5/, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Boayue et al., 2018)</ref>. Simulations were performed with the freely available SimNIBS software <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Thielscher et al., 2015)</ref>. We chose to evaluate the spatial distribution and magnitude of the normal component of electric fields, since it represents currents either entering or leaving the pial surface of the cortex, associated with predominantly excitatory or inhibitory effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Rahman et al., 2013)</ref>. Our montage yielded facilitatory currents in the superior-lateral and medial surfaces of the prefrontal cortex in both hemispheres, possibly even reaching the dACC ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1B</ref>).</p><p>Active stimulation consisted of 30s ramp-up, 15min stimulation and 30s ramp-down, whereas the sham session only contained two 30s ramp-up/ramp-down periods at the beginning and end of a 16min period, with no stimulation in-between. Neither the experimenters, nor the participants were aware of group assignment (double-blind protocols), and the percentage of participants guessing that they received active stimulation was comparable across groups, indicating proper blinding (Control-Active: 34.6%, Control-Sham: 50.0%, Manipulated-Active: 55.5%, Manipulated-Sham: 60.8%; H(3) = 3.84, p = .279).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pre-registered analysis</head><p>Our primary focus was the change in PB across experimental blocks and groups.</p><p>Therefore, we calculated the Pavlovian performance index (PPI) as the mean of two measures, "Reward-based invigoration" (the ratio of Go responses on win trials/total number of Go) and "Punishment-based suppression" (the number of NoGo responses on avoid trials/total number of NoGo). These indices represent the likelihood to initiate actions towards rewards and inhibit responses when facing potential loss, respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cavanagh et al., 2013)</ref>. We also calculated response accuracy as the ratio of correct responses for each block and card type.</p><p>PPI and accuracy were entered into repeated-measures analysis of variance (rmANOVA) with Group as between-subject and Block as within-subject factors, and additional within-subject factors of card Congruency and Valence for accuracy. Main effects and interactions were interpreted as significant at p &lt; .05. Estimates of effect size (η p 2 ) are also reported. Furthermore, Cumming estimation plots were used to illustrate effect sizes for pairwise comparison of conditions, whenever appropriate <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Ho et al., 2019)</ref>. We note, however, that Cumming estimation plots were not included in our pre-registered analysis pipeline, and we used them to verify and/or extend results from rmANOVA. We chose estimation statistics because they provide robust estimates about the underlying effect sizes with resampling-based confidence intervals. Thus, this approach avoids pitfalls of dichotomous significance testing by focusing on the magnitude of effects, while also accounting for the precision of the estimation method using bias-corrected and accelerated bootstrapping <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Ho et al., 2019)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational modeling</head><p>To gain a more nuanced view on the effects of our interventions on latent processes of reinforcement learning and decision-making, we also implemented a computational model to our behavioral data. Previous studies on Pavlovian-instrumental interactions have successfully applied such models to extract various parameters of choice behavior, and showed that this approach unravels hidden associations that cannot be captured by more conventional data analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cavanagh et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Csifcsák et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Guitart-Masip et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Swart et al., 2018)</ref>. For computational modeling, we used a Precision 7920 Rack computer, Debian GNU/Linux 9.9 operating system, 2x Intel Gold 6152, 2.1 GHz, 22 cores, and 512 GB RAM. Our primary interest was to look for potential group differences in the temporal evolution of the PB parameter π, but we also extracted parameters representing randomness of choice (temperature; β), learning rate (α) and the general tendency to initiate actions (Gobias; b go ). This approach was very similar to those used in previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cavanagh et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Csifcsák et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Swart et al., 2018)</ref>, with the exception that our model did not incorporate single-trial EEG data. All four parameters capture choice behavior from a different perspective. Changes in the Pavlovian parameter (π) were expected to corroborate findings on PPI, with higher values in manipulated participants receiving sham stimulation, but a reduction during/following active HD-tDCS. With respect to randomness of choice (β), learning rate (α) and Go-bias (b go ), our analysis was more exploratory, aiming at providing supportive evidence to a study <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020)</ref> reporting increased values for all three parameters during manipulated outcome controllability.</p><p>Action choices (Go vs. NoGo) for subject in trial of block for stimulus were modelled with the Bernoulli-experiment with probabilities Go and NoGo 1 Go</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">as Go| , , | , , / , | , , / , | , , / ,<label>[1]</label></formula><p>where is response weight (Go vs. NoGo) of the stimulus, and temperature parameter , determines how biased the decisions are in favor of the higher-weighted option. For a given stimulus value ,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">| , , Go| , ,<label>, , , , if Go</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">NoGo| , , if NoGo. [2]</formula><p>where parameter , codes for a general Go-bias, and , is our crucial Pavlovian bias parameter that scales learnt stimulus value , , in a way that it favors action/inaction for win/avoid cards. The value of stimulus , , is cumulated as</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">, ,<label>, , , , , , , [3]</label></formula><p>where , is the learning rate and , , is the reward (feedback). The final bit of the model is a standard -learning mechanism where stimulus/action pairs receive a value | , , that are updated to the standard rule</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">| , , | , ,<label>, , , | , , . [4]</label></formula><p>We model the data from all subject and sessions in the framework of hierarchical Bayesian modeling. We refer the reader to <ref type="bibr">Gelman et al. (2013)</ref> for in-depth coverage of the advantages of this approach. All models where implemented using Hamiltonian Monte-Carlo algorithms <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Hoffman and Gelman, 2014)</ref> implemented in Stan <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Carpenter et al., 2017)</ref>. We used six parallel chains with warm-up period of a 1000 samples each such that 6000 samples were drawn from the converged chains. Traceplots for all variables were manually screened for convergence. In addition, we calculated the Gelman-Rubin diagnostic <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Gelman and Rubin, 1992)</ref> to ensure that all 1.05.</p><p>The dependency of each model parameter on Block, Manipulation of controllability, HD-tDCS and their interactions were included at the group-level in the hierarchical model directly. Posterior densities for the estimated coefficients were calculated and regarded as relevant if their 95% highest density interval (HDI) excluded zero. When reporting regression coefficients, we report posterior mean b, 95% HDI and the evidence ratio (ER) in favor of a positive (ER + ) or a negative effect (ER -). ER can be interpreted as an odds-ratio, calculated as the ratio of two probabilities: The probability of the effect being positive, P(b&gt;0), divided by the inverse probability of the effect being zero or negative, 1-P(b&gt;0), for ER + or its inverse for ER -. For example, the statement b = 0.09 [0.01, 0.18], ER + = 27.0 indicates that it is 27 times as likely that the effect is positive than that it is zero or negative. In this analysis, P-values represent posterior probabilities that values are either below or above zero, and are not to be confused with frequentist p-values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Code Accessibility</head><p>The code/software described in the paper is freely available online at https://osf.io/d6eqk/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pre-registered analysis</head><p>Statistical analysis of questionnaire data and working memory performance collected at baseline are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. Experimental groups did not differ in their past mood (PANAS-Past), hopelessness (BHS), personality traits (BIS/BAS) or working memory capacity (OSPAN). Statistical results concerning repeated measurements of momentary mood ratings (PANAS-Present) revealed reduced scores by the end of the session, but no Group differences were found <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table 2)</ref>. Subjective ratings of perceived success increased by block 2, but scores were statistically comparable across groups (Table 2; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2A</ref>). As for perceived outcome controllability, no main effects or interactions were found (Table 2; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2B</ref>).  With respect to our Pavlovian bias measure, PPI, a significant reduction in block 2 confirmed that participants gradually learned to suppress their PB (Block: F(1,99) = 3.99, p = .048, η p 2 = .039). However, PPI was not influenced by group membership, despite showing lower values in the crucial Manipulated-Active group (Group: F(3,99) = 2.11, p = .104, η p 2 = .060; Block x Group: F(3,99) = 0.14, p = .937, η p 2 = .004; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3A</ref>). Paired data from all individuals along with the effect size estimates (bootstrapped 95% confidence intervals; 95% CI) for changes in PPI from block 1 to block 2 are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3B</ref>). A similar trend was observed in block 2, even though the 95% CI did not exclude zero (-0.52 [-1.09, 0.05]; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3C</ref>). comparisons, mean effect size estimates were substantially weaker (between -0.27 and -0.04), and 95% CIs always included zero. Overall, these findings provide some evidence for the efficacy of HD-tDCS in reducing Pavlovian bias when mPFC stimulation occurs simultaneously with the absence of control over rewards and losses.</p><p>Analysis of response accuracy revealed significant main effects for Congruency (F(1,99) = 16.60, p &lt; .001, η p 2 = .144), Block (F(1,99) = 5.72, p = .019, η p 2 = .055) and Group (F(3,99) = 4.52, p = .005, η p 2 = .120). Importantly, the significant Block x Group interaction (F(3,99) = 9.60, p &lt; .001, η p 2 = .225) was due to significantly improved responding from block 1 to block 2 in the Manipulated-Active group only (p Bonferroni &lt; .001; p Bonferroni &gt; .068 for other groups; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure   4A</ref>), with only this group showing increased mean response accuracies by block 2 for all four card types <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 4-1)</ref>. As a result of low controllability, both manipulated groups produced significantly worse response accuracies in block 1 relative to control groups (p Bonferroni &lt; .023 for all comparisons; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4A</ref>). When comparing changes in response accuracy between blocks using Cumming estimation plots, we found effect size estimates with the 95% CI  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4A</ref>). This effect was robust against removing one participant from the Manipulated-Active group, who was the only one in the whole sample producing accuracy scores of both &lt; 0.3 and &gt; 0.7 in the two blocks, resulting in an extremely large difference score (Cohen's d for the comparison of manipulated groups after exclusion: 0.56 [0.003, 1.06]). Mean differences are presented as black dots, along with the corresponding bootstrap sampling distributions (5000 samples) and the bias-corrected and accelerated 95% confidence intervals (black bars). Raw data and Cumming estimation plots related to changes from block 1 to block 2 for each group are presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref>-2. Changes in response accuracy (means and standard errors) corresponding to the four groups and Pavlovianconflict vs. Pavlovian-congruent cards are plotted separately for Avoid and Win cards (C). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref>-3 shows the same interaction between card valence, Pavlovian congruency and group, plotted separately for the two blocks. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref>-4 shows the percentage of Go responses (PercGo) separately for each card, group and experimental block. The pre-registered rmANOVA also indicated a significant Congruency x Valence x Group interaction (F(3,99) = 3.49, p = .019, η p 2 = .096; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4C</ref>). Here, all groups responded more accurately to Pavlovian-congruent cards in the loss domain (NoGo-to-Avoid &gt; Go-to-Avoid; p Bonferroni &lt; .003), an effect that was consistent across both blocks <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 4-3)</ref>. For rewarding cards, however, no clear effect of congruency was found (p Bonferroni &gt; .099), except for the Manipulated-Active group, where performance was surprisingly worse for Pavloviancongruent Go-to-Win vs. conflicting NoGo-to-Win cards (p Bonferroni = .008). Consequently, accuracy was comparable between groups for all Avoid cards as well as in conflicting NoGoto-Win trials (p Bonferroni &gt; .074), but for Pavlovian-congruent Go-to-Win cards, the Manipulated-Active group's performance was worse than that of Control-Active (p Bonferroni = .009) and</p><p>Control-Sham participants (p Bonferroni = .002). The paradoxical effect of improved responding to Pavlovian-conflict Win cards in manipulated participants was most pronounced in Manipulated-Active participants in both blocks <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 4-3)</ref>. While in block 2, this was due to improved responding to conflict NoGo-to-Win cards, in block 1, the effect was driven by reduced accuracy for congruent Go-to-Win cards.  Response accuracy for Pavlovian-congruent and conflict cards, plotted separately for Win and Avoid cards for block 1 (A) and block 2 (B). Please note that the concept of Pavlovian congruency cannot be interpreted in block 1 for the manipulated groups, as it just reflects the arbitrary labeling of the two Win cards as "Go-to-Win" and "NoGo-to-Win", without underlying response-feedback contingency that could drive cue-response learning. Percentage of Go responses (PercGo) for Pavlovian-congruent and conflict cards, plotted separately for Win and Avoid cards for block 1 (A) and block 2 (B). Please note that the concept of Pavlovian congruency cannot be interpreted in block 1 for the manipulated groups, as it just reflects the arbitrary labeling of the two Win cards as "Go-to-Win" and "NoGo-to-Win", without underlying response-feedback contingency that could drive cue-response learning.</p><p>Given that controllability manipulation in the first block invalidates the concept of Pavlovian congruency (out of the two Win and two Avoid cards, one is arbitrarily labeled as Go and one as NoGo, but these attributes cannot be learned in the absence of action-outcome contingency), the number of Go responses must necessarily be similar for congruent vs. conflict cards in this block. To verify this, we also calculated the percentage of Go responses (PercGo) for each card type and block. Indeed, the main effect of Congruency was not significant for block 1 in manipulated groups either for Win or Avoid cards (F &lt; 1.43, p &gt; .237), while it was significant for control groups in block 1 and all four groups in block 2, in both the gain and loss domains (all F &gt; 12.75, p &lt; .001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4-4)</ref>.</p><p>Finally, the significant Congruency x Valence x Block interaction for response accuracy (F(1,99) = 8.89, p = .004, η p 2 = .082) was due to improved performance from block 1 to block 2 for NoGo cards only (NoGo-to-Avoid: p Bonferroni &lt; .001, NoGo-to-Win: p Bonferroni = .036, Go-to-Avoid: p Bonf = .074, Go-to-Win: p Bonf = .055), albeit this effect was independent of group (fourway interaction: F(3,99) = 0.29, p = .833, η p 2 = .009).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational modeling</head><p>Modeling in this study was not pre-registered, and thus, it should be regarded as exploratory. We extracted four latent parameters of learning and decision-making: Pavlovian bias (π), learning rate (α), temperature (β) and Go-bias (b go ).  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 5A</ref>) provided evidence for our hypothesis that controllability interfered with reductions in PB throughout the task (i.e., changes in PB from block 1 to block 2 were weaker in manipulated groups). Lastly, we found some support for the interaction between controllability and HD-tDCS (i.e., weaker PB in the Manipulated-Active group; b = -0.58 <ref type="bibr">[-1.37, 0</ref>.17], P(b&lt;0) = .927, ER -= 12.7). Even though the result indicated that posterior estimates for the Manipulation x HD-tDCS interaction were 12.7-times more likely to be in the negative range than being either positive or zero (in line with <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3B-C)</ref>, the effect was not compelling since the 95% HDI included zero.</p><p>Next, we looked at the learning rate parameter α resembling the degree to which participants updated their stimulus-action values on a trial-by-trial basis. Group-level coefficients were in a similar range as observed in previous reports (α = 0.20, [0.09, 0.34]).   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 5D</ref>), indicating improved response accuracy from block 1 to block 2 in NoGo trials (see also: <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 4-1)</ref>. We found strong evidence for the general reduction in Go-bias in manipulated groups (Manipulation: b = -1.48 <ref type="bibr">[-2.35, -0.46]</ref>, P(b&lt;0) = .999, ER -= 665.7), mirroring motor passivity in animal studies of LH <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Maier and Seligman, 2016)</ref>. Importantly, this effect was much stronger in block 1 (Block x Manipulation: b = 0.92 [0.61, 1.23], P(b&gt;0) &gt; .999, ER + = ∞), pointing towards weak transfer from controllability manipulation to block 2, where control over outcomes was regained.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>With respect to our first study aim, we expected to observe enhanced Pavlovian bias during and following low outcome controllability under sham stimulation. We postulated that such a result would (1) support earlier findings of similar nature <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Dorfman and Gershman, 2019)</ref>, and (2) pinpoint our controllability manipulation protocol as a potent experimental intervention for inducing decision-making strategies resembling LH in healthy adults. However, we could only find partial support for this hypothesis: While pre-registered analyses revealed comparable PPI values for the Control-Sham and Manipulated-Sham groups, the Pavlovian bias parameter from the computational model was modulated in the expected direction (i.e., controllability manipulation attenuated the reduction of PB from block 1 to block 2). The discrepancy between results from the model-free PPI analysis and the model-derived Pavlovian parameter was also reported by another study <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020)</ref>,</p><p>indicating that the two measures differ in their sensitivities to changes in PB under low controllability. While PPI is an aggregated measure that simply reflects the propensity of initiating Go responses exclusively in appetitive trials and withholding actions specifically when facing aversive cues, the Pavlovian parameter takes into account the dynamic learning process, i.e., how card values are learnt from trial-to-trial, and the degree to which this valence-specific knowledge contributes to subsequent choices. Overall, our study supports the view that the model-derived Pavlovian parameter is a more sensitive measure to manipulations of controllability in experimental setting. However, given the present results, we cannot state that our protocol for manipulating outcome controllability is potent in inducing decision-making patterns resembling LH. This conclusion is also supported by the absence of a transfer effect regarding response accuracy from the block 1 to block 2 (i.e., comparable values for manipulated vs. control groups in the final block), and by the similar levels of perceived controllability across groups.</p><p>Our manipulation schedule was not optimal for several reasons. First, by keeping the Go-cost during the controllability manipulation, participants could exert some level of control over outcomes, which most probably contributed to their "illusion of control" <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Ly et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>The Go-cost also led to imperfect matching in reward/loss magnitude between control and manipulated groups. Second, reduced control over rewards and losses increased uncertainty around action consequences, and thus, controllability was confounded with predictability <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Ligneul, 2021)</ref>. In this regard, neither our protocol, nor those previously described in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Dorfman and Gershman, 2019)</ref>, including the seminal animal studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Maier and Seligman, 1976)</ref>, offer a "clean method" of controllability manipulations, with appropriately accounting for changes in outcome predictability. However, a new experimental setting has been introduced recently, that enables manipulations of controllability without confounding it with uncertainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Ligneul et al., 2020)</ref>. The authors show that an information-theoretic measure, transfer entropy, can efficiently capture environmental controllability, being dynamically inferred by the agent during the task. Future work could test whether other controllability manipulation schedules (similar to the one described by <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Ligneul et al., 2020)</ref> are more effective in inducing LH-like choice behavior in healthy adults.</p><p>The second aim of our study was to investigate how HD-tDCS above the mPFC influenced task performance under controllable vs. largely uncontrollable response-outcome relationships. Our most striking result is that following low controllability, improvement in response accuracy was stronger in participants receiving active HD-tDCS relative to those undergoing sham stimulation. This implies that stimulation above the mPFC/dACC led to more efficient adjustments in decision-making strategies following low controllability, when control over rewards and losses was regained. Even though our simulations indicate that HD-tDCSinduced electric fields might have reached the dACC, these modeling results have not been validated by intracranial recordings, and therefore, they should be interpreted with caution.</p><p>Nevertheless, the mPFC (and dACC in particular) has been associated with conditions of low controllability in the context of LH <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bauer et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Diener et al., 2010)</ref>, but also with tracking changes in environmental volatility <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Behrens et al., 2007)</ref> and the implementation of CC during various cognitive tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Cavanagh and Frank, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Shenhav et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Interestingly, a recent study found evidence for trial-by-trial correspondence between frontal midline theta power (an electrophysiological correlate of dACC activity, associated with the implementation of CC), and subjectively inferred controllability in a very similar Go/NoGo task <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Gershman et al., 2021)</ref>. Moreover, anodal tDCS above the rostromedial PFC enhanced gathering information about one's sense of being in control in a social context <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Ligneul et al., 2016)</ref>. Based on these findings, a possible mechanism for the observed effect in our study is that active HD-tDCS improved the precision of controllability estimations rather than affecting PB per se. Following that interpretation, the Manipulated-Active group could more effectively adjust decision-making strategies to environmental constraints in both blocks. This is apparent in their lower number of Go responses for Win cards in the first block, a behavior that has been associated with reduced exploration tendencies <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Teodorescu and Erev, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Withholding Go tendencies was adaptive in this context, since active responses reduced the magnitude of outcomes by the Go-cost, without directly influencing reward/loss frequency.</p><p>Conversely, in block 2, the Manipulated-Active group adjusted their choices in Pavlovianconflict trials only, a response pattern that has been associated with increased cognitive effort <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cavanagh et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Swart et al., 2018)</ref>. Thus, we conclude that active HD-tDCS above the mPFC facilitated manipulated participants' task performance in an adaptive way, possibly via improving their assessment of environmental controllability.</p><p>The interaction between controllability and HD-tDCS was most striking in Win trials, resulting in better accuracy for conflicting NoGo-to-Win vs. congruent Go-to-Win cards in the Manipulated-Active group. Moreover, this group was the only one to show improved responding to Go-to-Win cards from block 1 to block 2. These observations suggest that only Manipulated-Active participants could successfully suppress maladaptive PB in conflicting NoGo-to-Win trials by the end of the task, without overcompensating this strategy at the expense of congruent Go-to-Win cards. Such a selective overcompensation of NoGo response tendencies in Win trials (resulting in a reversal of the congruency effect) was also reported in another study, albeit only for participants with higher levels of outcome controllability <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020)</ref>. A possible reason for this discrepancy is that control-manipulated participants in the study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Csifcsák et al. (2020)</ref> were initially exposed to a controllable version of the task, whereas in the current task, they immediately started the task with the manipulated block. Therefore, we propose that prior exposure to controllable outcomes plays a key role in how uncontrollable task-contexts shape decision-making. It remains puzzling, though, why we found stronger HD-tDCS effects for reward-predictive trials. While explanation for this phenomenon awaits future investigation, it is noteworthy that a recent neuroimaging study reported valence-action mappings during the processing of preparatory cues in the ACC for win (but not loss) trials, as well as increased ACC activity during target stimulus presentation for both approach vs. avoid and win vs. loss stimuli <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Hoofs et al., 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Therefore, we speculate that this region is more sensitive to evolutionary dominant action requirements in the appetitive domain.</p><p>Recent studies suggest that PB during reinforcement learning is regulated by top-down CC mechanisms <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cavanagh et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Csifcsák et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Swart et al., 2018</ref>). An alternative explanation for the observed effect concerning the interaction between HD-tDCS and controllability is that, rather than influencing estimations of one's controllability over the environment, active stimulation directly facilitated the implementation of CC in Pavlovianconflict trials. Conflict-associated CC has been successfully modulated via transcranial electric stimulation above midline frontal areas in a Stroop task <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(To et al., 2018)</ref>, and in a similar orthogonalized Go/NoGo task <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Turi et al., 2020)</ref>. Thus, it is feasible that the combined effect of low controllability and HD-tDCS on response accuracy in our study is related to enhanced CC and the consequential suppression of PB. In line with this argument, we found improved accuracies for both NoGo-to-Win and Go-to-Avoid cards in block 2 for Manipulated-Active vs.</p><p>Manipulated-Sham participants. Moreover, Cumming estimation plots provided some evidence for weaker PB in the Manipulated-Active group, predominantly in block 1. However, it should be noted that results from the pre-registered PPI analysis and the computational modeling approach were not compelling, so this conclusion based on exploratory analyses should be treated with caution.</p><p>One could argue that instead of reducing PB for Win cards, HD-tDCS might have promoted NoGo tendencies globally in Manipulated-Active participants. While the modelderived Go-bias parameter is inconclusive for the Manipulation x HD-tDCS interaction, our results from PPI and accuracy analyses argue against this interpretation. First, a possible general facilitation of NoGo responding should have influenced the two PB sub-measures (reward-based invigoration and punishment-based suppression) in the opposite direction, but this effect was not present in our results. More specifically, the predisposition for NoGo responses in the Manipulated-Active group was not present in Avoid trials (producing even more Go responses in Go-to-Avoid trials in block 2, compared to Manipulated-Sham participants) which points towards the specificity of NoGo-enhancement to Win trials. In line with the PB account, Ly and colleagues have reported reduced "affective biasing" of instrumental responding following cathodal tDCS above the frontopolar cortex <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Ly et al., 2016)</ref>. In that study, approach primed by emotional stimuli (roughly equivalent to our Go trials) was faster for appetitive vs. aversive cues during sham stimulation, but this effect was reversed in the cathodal condition. Given the diffuse cortical distribution of tDCS-induced electric fields in that protocol (with the return electrode placed above the occipital area), it is possible that the similar finding of weaker PB following tDCS in the two studies was mediated by excitability changes in overlapping cortical areas.</p><p>The fact that HD-tDCS did not influence response accuracy in control participants is a surprising finding, as we expected that the Control-Active group would show more efficient CC and improved task performance in Pavlovian-conflict trials. It is possible that our controllability manipulation changed neural excitability in target regions so that they became more susceptible to HD-tDCS-induced electric fields. Indeed, behavioral consequences of tDCS are sensitive to dynamic fluctuations in neural activity during stimulation ("statedependency") <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Dubreuil-Vall et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Tremblay et al., 2014)</ref>, and a recent study implementing a similar low controllability protocol reported altered neurophysiological responses arising from the mPFC/dACC in manipulated subjects <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020)</ref>. Based on these results, we speculate that HD-tDCS in our study was not potent enough to influence task performance in participants with sufficient levels of outcome controllability, whereas controllability manipulation might have lowered the threshold for HD-tDCS effects to develop.</p><p>Computational modeling revealed two additional latent processes that were influenced by our interventions. While earlier work reported stronger reliance on immediate feedback (i.e., increased learning rates) under reduced outcome controllability <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020)</ref>, we found such an effect only when controllability was combined with active HD-tDCS.</p><p>Similarly, there was no conclusive evidence for increased exploration/randomness during choice selection in the manipulated groups, which is in contrast with previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Csifcsák et al., 2020)</ref>. However, controllability and HD-tDCS exerted opposite (intensifying and attenuating) effects on the reduction of both parameters from block 1 to block 2. Although we hesitate to provide an interpretation for these interactions as they stem from an exploratory analysis, the results suggest that evaluation of outcome controllability converges with both the rate of feedback learning and randomness of choice in the mPFC/dACC.</p><p>Our key finding is that HD-tDCS facilitated task performance in the manipulated group only, an effect that was stronger in the appetitive domain, and possibly related to more precise estimations of controllability and/or to enhanced cognitive control over Pavlovian response tendencies. Moreover, controllability and HD-tDCS showed interactive effects in the gradual accumulation of stimulus-action values and in the tendency to act randomly rather than to rely on reinforcement history. Overall, these results highlight the potential of our protocol for interfering with choice arbitration under low controllability of environmental events, resulting in more adaptive behavior. Further work is necessary to consolidate these findings and to test if our experimental paradigm can improve suboptimal decision-making in patients with symptoms of learned helplessness.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Overview of our study design (A), the spatial distribution and magnitude of the normal components of HD-tDCS-induced electric fields, representing currents either entering or leaving the cerebral cortex (depicted with positive and negative values, respectively), averaged across 18 head models of healthy adults (B), trial structure (C) and card types with feedback values (D).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Ratings (means and standard errors) of perceived success (A) and outcome controllability (B) following each block.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Changes in the magnitude of the Pavlovian performance index (PPI; means and standard errors) across the two blocks and four experimental groups (A), and Cumming estimation plots showing effect size estimates (Cohen's d) for 3 comparisons against a shared control condition (Control-Sham group) for block 1 (B) and block 2 (C). Mean differences are presented as black dots, along with the corresponding bootstrap sampling distributions (5000 samples) and the bias-corrected and accelerated 95% confidence intervals (black bars). Raw data and Cumming estimation plots related to changes from block 1 to block 2 for each group are presented inFigure 3-1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>-1, indicating comparable Block-effects across the four groups. Crucially, Cumming estimation plots for the effect size (Cohen's d) obtained for the comparison of PPI values from the three groups receiving experimental interventions (Control-Active, Manipulated-Sham, Manipulated-Active) against a shared control (Control-Sham) showed reduced PPI only in the Manipulated-Active group in block 1, quantified by a medium mean effect size (mean = -0.63, 95% CI = [-1.13, -0.01];</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 - 1 .</head><label>31</label><figDesc>Raw data(upper panel)  showing changes in the Pavlovian performance index (PPI) from block 1 to block 2 for each participant, and Cumming estimation plots (lower panel) representing effect size estimates (Cohen's d) for the change in response accuracy from block 1 to block 2, plotted separately for the four groups. Mean differences are presented as dots, along with the corresponding bootstrap sampling distributions (5000 samples) and the bias-corrected and accelerated 95% confidence intervals.Finally, we assessed if the two sub-measures of PPI, reward-based invigoration(RBI)    and punishment-based suppression (PBS) were similarly influenced by our interventions. Thisanalysis yielded largely similar results to PPI (estimates for Cohen's d for the Manipulated-Active vs. Control-Sham comparison: RBI block 1: -0.59 [-1.1, -0.06], PBS block 1: -0.62 [-1.12, -0.09], RBI block 2: -0.48 [-1.02, 0.08], PBS block 2: -0.55 [-1.1, 0.05]). For all other</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>excluding zero for both manipulated groups (Control-Sham: -0.27 [-0.75, 0.09], Control-Active: -0.16 [-0.42, 0.06], Manipulated-Sham: 0.55 [0.14, 0.94], Manipulated-Active: 1.17 [0.73, 1.61]; Figure 4-2). To verify that this effect was larger in the Manipulated-Active than in the Manipulated-Sham group, we calculated block 2 minus block 1 difference scores, and estimated effect sizes for the active vs. sham HD-tDCS comparison, separately in the control and manipulated conditions (Figure 4B). This analysis revealed negligible effect for HD-tDCS in the control groups (0.15 [-0.39, 0.65]), but a medium mean effect size in the Manipulated-Active vs. Manipulated-Sham comparison (0.63 [0.10, 1.06]), confirming results from rmANOVA (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Response accuracy (means and standard errors) in each block and experimental group (A). Data corresponding to accuracy for each card type, block and group are presented inFigure 4-1. Cumming estimation plots representing effect size estimates (Cohen's d) for the pairwise comparison of block-effects between groups receiving active vs. sham HD-tDCS, calculated separately for control and manipulated groups are shown in (B).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 4 - 1 .</head><label>41</label><figDesc>Response accuracy (means and standard errors) across the two blocks and four experimental groups, plotted separately for the four card types.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 4 - 2 .</head><label>42</label><figDesc>Raw data(upper panel)  showing changes in response accuracy from block 1 to block 2 for each participant, and Cumming estimation plots (lower panel) representing effect size estimates (Cohen's d) for the change in response accuracy from block 1 to block 2, plotted separately for the four groups. Mean differences are presented as dots, along with the corresponding bootstrap sampling distributions (5000 samples) and the bias-corrected and accelerated 95% confidence intervals.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4-3. Response accuracy for Pavlovian-congruent and conflict cards, plotted separately for Win and Avoid cards for block 1 (A) and block 2 (B). Please note that the concept of Pavlovian congruency cannot be interpreted in block 1 for the manipulated groups, as it just reflects the arbitrary labeling of the two Win cards as "Go-to-Win" and "NoGo-to-Win", without underlying response-feedback contingency that could drive cue-response learning.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4-4. Percentage of Go responses (PercGo) for Pavlovian-congruent and conflict cards, plotted separately for Win and Avoid cards for block 1 (A) and block 2 (B). Please note that the concept of Pavlovian congruency cannot be interpreted in block 1 for the manipulated groups, as it just reflects the arbitrary labeling of the two Win cards as "Go-to-Win" and "NoGo-to-Win", without underlying response-feedback contingency that could drive cue-response learning.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Posterior distributions for the group-level distribution of the Pavlovian parameter were in the positive range (π = 0.59, [0.20, 0.99]), confirming that learned stimulus valence biased decisions in the expected manner (action/inaction for positive/negative values, respectively). The estimated 95% HDI for the Block coefficient on the Pavlovian bias was negative (b = -0.08 [-0.15, -0.01], P(b&lt;0) = .993, ER -= 135.3), in line with results from rmANOVA that Pavlovian bias was partially learnt away by block 2. Moreover, predominantly positive values for the Block x Manipulation interaction (0.14 [-0.01, 0.29], P(b&gt;0) = .974, ER + = 33.3;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Again, we found negative values for the Block coefficient, indicating reduced learning rates by block 2 (b = -0.40 [-0.52, -0.28], P(b&lt;0) &gt; .999, ER -= ∞; Figure 5B). This effect was modulated by controllability and HD-tDCS in the opposite manner, with stronger reduction in manipulated participants (Block x Manipulation: b = -0.43 [-0.62, -0.24], P(b&lt;0) &gt; .999, ER -= ∞), but weaker change following active stimulation (Block x HD-tDCS: b = 1.03 [0.86, 1.20], P(b&gt;0) &gt; .999, ER + = ∞). While the main effect of HD-tDCS was negative (b = -1.05 [-1.69, -0.43], P(b&lt;0) = .999, ER -= 749.0), positive values for the Manipulation x HD-tDCS interaction coefficient implied that stimulation of mPFC was less effective in reducing learning rates when combined with low controllability (b = 1.05 [0.17, 1.93], P(b&gt;0) = .991, ER + = 100).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results from computational modeling. Posterior densities for estimates for the regression coefficients for Pavlovian bias (parameter π; A), learning rate (parameter α; B), temperature/randomness of choice (parameter β; C) and Go-bias (parameter b go ; D).Posterior distributions for the temperature parameter (β = 2.71 [1.75, 3.99]) revealed a negative Block-effect (b = -0.58 [-0.71, -0.45], P(b&lt;0) &gt; .999, ER -= ∞; Figure 5C), which can be interpreted as stronger reliance on learned action weights during response selection in block 2. Similarly to parameter α, low controllability intensified (Block x Manipulation: b = -0.32 [-0.55, -0.11], P(b&lt;0) = .998, ER -= 544.4), while HD-tDCS attenuated this effect (Block x HD-tDCS: b = 0.71 [0.50, 0.91], P(b&gt;0) &gt; .999, ER + = ∞). Importantly, participants acted less randomly in block 2 when low controllability was combined with HD-tDCS (Block x Manipulation x HD-tDCS: b = -0.39 [-0.71, -0.10], P(b&lt;0) = .994, ER -= 170.4). We also found some support for a general reduction in β values in both active HD-tDCS groups, even though the 95% HDI did not exclude zero (HD-tDCS: b = -0.48 [-1.07, 0.09], P(b&lt;0) = .948, ER -= 18.2). The fourth parameter, , represented Go-bias, the tendency to initiate actions irrespective of learned stimulus value. As expected, value estimates were mostly positive ( = 0.30, [-0.40, 0.99]), though associated with high uncertainty. The coefficient for Block was negative (b = -0.53 [-0.78, -0.30], P(b&lt;0) &gt; .999, ER -= ∞;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Statistical results for the comparison of questionnaire data and cognitive tests between the four experimental groups. Behavioral Inhibition/Approach System; BHS: Beck Hopelessness Scale; OSPAN: Operation Span task; PANAS-Pa-Neg: negative past mood scores on the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule; PANAS-Pa-Pos: positive past mood scores on the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Baseline measures</cell><cell>Group effect</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>F</cell><cell>d f</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>η p 2</cell></row><row><cell>PANAS-Pa-Pos</cell><cell>0.43</cell><cell>3,99</cell><cell>0.731</cell><cell>0.013</cell></row><row><cell>PANAS-Pa-Neg</cell><cell>0.17</cell><cell>3,99</cell><cell>0.916</cell><cell>0.005</cell></row><row><cell>BIS/BAS</cell><cell>0.49</cell><cell>3,99</cell><cell>0.691</cell><cell>0.015</cell></row><row><cell>BHS</cell><cell>0.46</cell><cell>3,99</cell><cell>0.710</cell><cell>0.014</cell></row><row><cell>OSPAN</cell><cell>0.14</cell><cell>3,96</cell><cell>0.933</cell><cell>0.004</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Abbreviations: BIS/BAS:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Statistical results for the comparison of questionnaire data and subjective ratings between the four experimental groups and the repeated measurements. Neg: negative momentary mood scores on the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule; PANAS-Pr-Pos: positive momentary mood scores on the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Group effect</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Block effect</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Block x Group interaction</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>F</cell><cell>df</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>η p 2</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>df</cell><cell>P</cell><cell>η p 2</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>df</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>η p 2</cell></row><row><cell>PANAS-Pr-Pos</cell><cell cols="12">0.37 3,98 0.820 0.009 23.99 1,98 &lt;0.001 0.197 1.75 3,98 0.162 0.05</cell></row><row><cell>PANAS-Pr-Neg</cell><cell cols="12">0.61 3,98 0.611 0.018 10.99 1,98 0.001 0.101 1.33 3,98 0.267 0.04</cell></row><row><cell>Success rating</cell><cell cols="12">0.12 3,98 0.949 0.004 12.27 1,98 &lt;0.001 0.111 2.39 3,98 0.073 0.07</cell></row><row><cell>Control rating</cell><cell cols="12">0.81 3,98 0.488 0.024 0.80 1,98 0.373 0.008 0.81 3,98 0.492 0.024</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Abbreviations: PANAS-Pr-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Medial prefrontal cortex determines how stressor controllability affects behavior and dorsal raphe nucleus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Amat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Baratta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Paul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Watkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Functional neuroanatomy of learned helplessness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pripfl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lamm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Prainsack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="927" to="939" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The measurement of pessimism: the hopelessness scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Weissman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Trexler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Consult Clin Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="861" to="865" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning the value of information in an uncertain world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Woolrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Walton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Rushworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1214" to="1221" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Head models of healthy and depressed adults for simulating the effects of non-invasive brain stimulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Boayue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Csifcsák</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Puonti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Thielscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mittner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">704</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>version 2; referees: 2 approved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stan: A probabilistic programming language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Betancourt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brubaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Riddell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Stat Softw</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral inhibition, behavioral activation, and affective responses to impending reward and punishment: the BIS/BAS scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Pers Soc Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="333" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontal theta overrides pavlovian learning biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Eisenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Guitart-Masip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Huys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8541" to="8548" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontal theta as a mechanism for cognitive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="414" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of transcranial direct current stimulation for treating depression: A modeling study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Csifcsák</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Boayue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Puonti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Thielscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mittner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Affective Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">234</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="164" to="173" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intermittent absence of control during reinforcement learning interferes with Pavlovian bias in action selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Csifcsák</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Melsaeter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mittner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="646" to="663" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gyri-precise head model of transcranial direct current stimulation: improved spatial focality using a ring electrode versus conventional rectangular pad</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Datta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Diaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bikson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain stimulation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="207" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-based and model-free Pavlovian reward learning: Revaluation, revision, and revelation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Berridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn Affect Behav Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="492" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The misbehavior of value and the discipline of the will</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Niv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Seymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1153" to="1160" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loss of control during instrumental learning: a source localization study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Diener</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kuehner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Flor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="717" to="726" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Controllability governs the balance between Pavlovian and instrumental action selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dorfman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">tDCS to the left DLPFC modulates cognitive and physiological correlates of executive function in a statedependent manner</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Dubreuil-Vall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ruffini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Widge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Camprodon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain Stimulation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1456" to="1463" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Carlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">/CRC Texts in Statistical Science)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Chapman &amp; Hall</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Inference from iterative simulation using multiple sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="472" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural signatures of arbitration between Pavlovian and instrumental action selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Guitart-Masip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1008553</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Go and no-go learning in reward and punishment: interactions between affect and effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Guitart-Masip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Huys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fuentemilla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Duzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="166" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An approach through the looking-glass</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hershberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Learning &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moving beyond P values: data analysis with estimation graphics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tumkaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aryal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Claridge-Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="565" to="566" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The No-U-turn sampler: adaptively setting path lengths in Hamiltonian Monte Carlo</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Mach Learn Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1593" to="1623" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural underpinnings of valence-action interactions triggered by cues and targets in a rewarded approach/avoidance task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Hoofs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Vermeylen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Boehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Krebs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bonsai trees in your head: how the Pavlovian system sculpts goal-directed choices by pruning decision trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Huys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Eshel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>O'nions</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Sheridan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Comput Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1002410</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Controllability modulates the anticipatory response in the human ventromedial prefrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Kerr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Mclaren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mathy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Nitschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">557</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surviving threats: neural circuit and computational implications of a new taxonomy of defensive behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ledoux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">269</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prediction or Causation? Towards a Redefinition of Task Controllability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ligneul</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stress-sensitive inference of task controllability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ligneul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Mainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Ly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cools</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>bioRxiv 2020.11.19.390393</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamical representation of dominance relationships in the human rostromedial prefrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ligneul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Obeso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J-C</forename><surname>Dreher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3107" to="3115" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reduced Affective Biasing of Instrumental Action With tDCS Over the Prefrontal Cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Ly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Bergmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gladwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Volman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Usberti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cools</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Roelofs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain stimulation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="380" to="387" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A reward-based framework of perceived control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Ly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bhanji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Delgado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">65</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learned helplessness: Theory and evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Seligman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Exp Psychol Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learned helplessness at fifty: Insights from neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mep</forename><surname>Seligman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="367" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stressor controllability and learned helplessness: the roles of the dorsal raphe nucleus, serotonin, and corticotropin-releasing factor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Watkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="829" to="841" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PsychoPy-psychophysics software in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Peirce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">162</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Helplessness: a systematic translational review of theory and evidence for its relevance to understanding and treating depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Pryce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Azzinnari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Spinelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Seifritz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tegethoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Meinlschmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pharmacol Ther</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">132</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="242" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cellular effects of acute direct current stimulation: somatic and synaptic terminal effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rahman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Arlotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gasca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Datta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Parra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bikson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Physiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">591</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2563" to="2578" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for studying the neurobiology of value-based decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Montague</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="556" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The expected value of control: an integrative theory of anterior cingulate cortex function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="240" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontal network dynamics reflect neurocomputational mechanisms for reducing maladaptive biases in motivated action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Swart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Määttä</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Jensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cools</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Den Ouden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2005979</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learned helplessness and learned prevalence: Exploring the causal relations among perceived controllability, reward prevalence, and exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1861" to="1869" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Field modeling for transcranial magnetic stimulation: A useful tool to understand the physiological effects of TMS?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Thielscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Antunes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Saturnino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE EMBS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="225" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring the effects of anodal and cathodal high definition transcranial direct current stimulation targeting the dorsal anterior cingulate cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>To</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Eroh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vanneste</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The uncertain outcome of prefrontal tDCS</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tremblay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Lepage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Latulipe-Loiselle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Fregni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pascual-Leone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Théoret</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain Stimulation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="783" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Theta-Gamma Cross-Frequency Transcranial Alternating Current Stimulation over the Trough Impairs Cognitive Control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Turi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mittner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Bürger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Antal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Paulus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is working memory capacity task dependent?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Engle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Mem Lang</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="154" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development and validation of brief measures of positive and negative affect: the PANAS scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tellegen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Pers Soc Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1063" to="1070" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
