<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Standard Relationship Between Choice Frequency and Choice Time is Violated in Multi-Attribute Preferential Choice</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guy</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Newcastle</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gavin</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Newcastle</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon-Paul</forename><surname>Cavallaro</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Newcastle</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Standard Relationship Between Choice Frequency and Choice Time is Violated in Multi-Attribute Preferential Choice</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:51+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Preference</term>
					<term>Multi-attribute</term>
					<term>Choice</term>
					<term>Response time</term>
					<term>Cognitive model</term>
					<term>Sequential sampling model</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Many decision making theories assume a principle of sequentially sampling decision-relevant evidence from the stimulus environment, where sampled evidence is dynamically accumulated toward a threshold to trigger a decision in favour of the threshold-crossing option. A core prediction of sequential sampling models is that options more likely to be chosen are chosen more quickly. This result has been empirically supported hundreds of times for low-level speeded perceptual decisions-the traditional domain of sequential sampling models. More recently, sequential sampling models have been generalised and applied to higher-level preferential, or value-based, decisions-decisions for which there is no objectively correct option. Preferential options are typically composed of multiple attributes, like a phone defined by its price, camera quality, memory capacity, and so on. Here, we show that decisions for such multi-attribute preferential options with defined features violate the core prediction of sequential sampling models: options more likely to be chosen are not chosen more quickly. We find this invariance across 4 data sets spanning multi-attribute choices made in unconstrained conditions, under time pressure, and for multi-attribute options with artificial or marketplace compositions. The result remains whether the relationship between choice frequency and choice time is inspected at the lower level of component attributes or the higher level of whole options. Our finding places critical constraints on the capacity to generalise sequential sampling models from low-level perceptual decisions to high-level multi-attribute preferential choice.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Many theories of preferential choice assume a latent valuation function drives a decision process that terminates upon meeting a decision rule. This surprisingly simple description encompasses many perspectives that cut across psychology, behavioural economics, marketing, and neuroscience. Take, for instance -in the spirit of Prof Tony Marley -random utility theory. The latent valuation function in random utility theory assumes the agent has a subjective value they place on each option in a set of available options. The utility of any of those options, at any moment in time, is a combination of its specific subjective value and unknown random factors. The decision rule in random utility theory compares the utility of all options, at the moment of choice, and selects the option with greatest utility.</p><p>A subset of models derived from this broader class of 'latent valuation function' theories are based on sequentially sampling decision-relevant information from the stimulus environment (for reviews, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Forstmann, Ratcliff, &amp; Wagenmakers, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Ratcliff, Smith, Brown, &amp; McKoon, 2016)</ref>. The principle of sequential sampling theories is that pieces of decision-relevant information are sampled from the environment, where each piece of information may favour one or another response. This process is repeated sequentially, over time, until we have collected, or accumulated, enough pieces of information, or evidence, to inform a choice. The theories naturally predict the choice (which option had more evidence?) and the choice time (how many samples were collected?). Viewed this way, sequential sampling theories such as random walk and diffusion models generalise static signal detection theory (which predicts choices) into the time domain (to predict the joint distribution of choices and choice times).</p><p>Sequential sampling theories are most often studied in the domain of 'objective' or veridical choice, where one response option is objectively more closely aligned with the target stimulus quality, such as detecting coherent motion or judging line lengths. Sequential sampling models have been studied in great detail for such 'low-level' decisions -for example, those pertaining to perceptual and memory-based representations (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Ratcliff &amp; McKoon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Shadlen &amp; Shohamy, 2016)</ref>. This has advanced psychological theorising by decomposing observed choices and latencies into latent components of processing including the speed of information processing, cautiousness, and biases, among others. A critical aspect of the use of sequential sampling models is the application of these theories to choice and response time data. Many of these components of processing cannot be decomposed on the basis of choice data alone.</p><p>More recently, the principle of sequentially sampling decision-relevant information has been applied to 'higher-level' decisions -those pertaining to attitudinal and preferential options -often referred to as value-based decisions. One can think of this as generalising</p><p>We thank Tony Marley for discussions that led to this manuscript, at the Annual Meeting of the Society for Mathematical Psychology 2018, and at the University of Newcastle in 2018 and 2019. This work was supported by: Australian Research Council (ARC) Discovery Early Career Researcher Award <ref type="bibr">(Hawkins, DE170100177)</ref> and ARC Discovery Project <ref type="bibr">(Hawkins, DP180103613)</ref>. The funding sources had no role in the study design; in the collection, analysis and interpretation of data; in the writing of the report; and in the decision to submit the article for publication. Declarations of interest: none. random utility theory (which predicts choices) into the time domain, which leads to a set of sequential sampling models known as 'race' models, where each response option is represented with a different node or 'accumulator' (to predict the joint distribution of choices and choice times, for N ≥ 2 options). Tony Marley, in collaboration with Hans Colonius, formalised the link between the choice and time domains in random utility theory (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Marley, 1989</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">, Marley &amp; Colonius, 1992</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">, Colonius &amp; Marley, 2015</ref>; for more recent treatments see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Webb, 2019)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preferential Choices and the Time Taken to Make Them</head><p>Generalising the theories to new domains of decision making has been fruitful in many ways. Theoretically, it permits testing the principle of sequential sampling as a foundational unit of the decision process -units that can be pieced together much like atoms making up a molecule. Such work aims to provide a deeper understanding of the decision processes involved in higher-level decisions, working toward theoretical consensus on the principles driving decisions under different conditions and contexts.</p><p>To this end, sequential sampling models have been studied in 'simple' value-based or preferential decisions in considerable detail. 'Simple' in this context pertains to the stimulus structure: choices for value-based options that implicitly have multiple features or attributes but the stimulus structure doesn't specify values for those attributes. For example, a choice between crisps and a chocolate bar, where information about the options is communicated with images that do not explicitly describe features such as the price, weight, caloric content, and so on. In this context, the primary predictions of the models are borne out in data (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Fisher, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Gluth, Kern, Kortmann, &amp; Vitali, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Krajbich, Armel, &amp; Rangel, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">and Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2018</ref>; for review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Clithero, 2018)</ref>. This supports the hypothesis that sequential sampling may be a principle underlying foundational unit of the decision process.</p><p>Value-based decisions are also widely studied with explicit multi-attribute structures, where the available options have specified values for a set of product attributes (for reference sources, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Louviere, Flynn, &amp; Marley, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Louviere, Hensher, &amp; Swait, 2000)</ref>. For instance, a choice between a chocolate bar that costs $2.20, weighs 50g and contains 780kj of energy and a bag of crisps that cost $2.60, weighs 60g and contains 1400kj of energy. Throughout the manuscript, we refer to the class of multi-attribute stimuli with explicitly specified attribute values as multi-attribute options with defined features.</p><p>Many existing theories of choice between value-based options with defined features either have no role for choice times (e.g., standard DCE analytic techniques, such as the family of logit and probit models derived from random utility theory; <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Train, 2009)</ref> or they have a role for choice times though they are rarely used to test model adequacy (e.g., sequential sampling models; Otter et al., 2008 -see below for some exceptions). Such sequential sampling models naturally accommodate options with defined features, and can generate predictions for observed patterns of choices marginalised over the predicted distribution of choice times. This permits a test of the models' predictive scope -the capacity to explain observed choices for options with defined features. This has been a useful test because latency data are rarely collected in multi-attribute preferential choice contexts, and when they are collected they are less frequently analysed and modelled. When they have been collected, there are typically far fewer trials than are considered in conventional applications of sequential sampling models in 'low-level' decision contexts, or even simple value-based decisions, which reduces the information value of the choice times, at least to some extent.</p><p>Nevertheless, applying sequential sampling models to choice data (without response times) is a limited test of the theories. The models predict a joint distribution of choice outcomes and choice times, so a test of the models based on just one dimension of the joint distribution has limited capacity to discriminate between competing theories. It is also possible the class of models mispredicts important features of the observed choice times, which has the potential to falsify the class of models as a proposed psychological process for preferential decision making.</p><p>Exceptions exist, of course, and sequential sampling models have been evaluated against choice frequency and choice times for preferential options with defined features (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Cataldo &amp; Cohen, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Cohen, Kang, &amp; Leise, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Evans, Holmes, &amp; Trueblood, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hawkins et al., 2014a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Jones, Hawkins, &amp; Brown, 2015)</ref>; we restrict our focus to consumer-like decisions and do not consider further other types of preferential options, such as those studied in paradigms of risky gambles or delay discounting. While the two outcome measures have been jointly used to constrain the theories (i.e., estimate parameters) in previous studies, models have tended to be evaluated against marginal distributions of choice outcomes and choice times (i.e., for measures of goodness of fit to data). For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Evans et al. (2019)</ref> compared choice frequency and choice time predictions between four of the major cognitive process models of multi-attribute choice: multi-alternative decision field theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Roe, Busemeyer, &amp; Townsend, 2001)</ref>, the multi-attribute linear ballistic accumulator <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Trueblood, Brown, &amp; Heathcote, 2014)</ref>, the leaky competing accumulator <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Usher &amp; McClelland, 2004)</ref>, and the associative accumulation model <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bhatia, 2013)</ref>. They found that analysing the models against the joint distribution of choices and choice times led to different model preference compared to analyses that only assessed the models against the choice outcomes, such as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Trueblood et al. (2014)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Turner, Schley, Muller, and Tsetsos (2018)</ref>.</p><p>It is rare to consider the joint distribution of choice frequency and choice times in multi-attribute choice for options with defined features -evaluating choice times as a function of choice outcomes, or vice versa. This is commonplace in low-level decisions, for instance, with visualisation including latency-probability and quantile-probability (QP) plots, or defective CDFs (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Donkin &amp; Brown, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>. When the joint distribution of multi-attribute preferential choice frequency and choice times are inspected in this way an interesting pattern emerges that, to our knowledge, has not previously been documented. The pattern is important as it places critical constraints on the capacity of sequential sampling models to explain the cognitive processes driving multi-attribute preferential choice.</p><p>Here, we study a pattern in multi-attribute choice frequency and choice time data, for options with defined features, that violates a qualitative trend observed in countless studies of choices and times in speeded low-level decisions (for reviews, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Forstmann et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Ratcliff &amp; McKoon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>. In low-level decisions, we almost always observe a monotonically decreasing relationship between choice frequency and choice times, conditioned on a given threshold/boundary. That is, as a stimulus dimension becomes more discriminable (e.g., increasing brightness in a brightness discrimination task) it is increasingly likely to be chosen and those choices are made more rapidly. This trend is typically observed in simple value-based decisions, too (for review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Clithero, 2018)</ref>. In the value-based context, option discriminability refers to the difference in value of the available options: there is lower discriminability when the set of available options are of similar value and higher discriminability when the set of options differ markedly in value.</p><p>Sequential sampling models predict this relationship with a change in the parameter corresponding to the rate of accumulation -the drift rate. As decision-relevant information is acquired more rapidly (greater drift rate), the decision process reaches threshold sooner (faster response) with increasing likelihood (greater choice probability). This relationship is conditioned on a given value of the threshold/boundary parameter -the standard assumption in the decision making literature when pre-stimulus information about the upcoming decision context is not available. We maintain this standard fixed-threshold assumption throughout.</p><p>We show that the negative monotonic relationship between choice frequency and choice time is violated for decisions between multi-attribute preferential stimuli with defined features -there is an invariance between the two outcome measures. Further, this trend holds even when a set of options merely contains better attribute values -one doesn't need to consider value differences, as is the norm in value-based decisions without defined features. This result places a critical constraint on the generalisability of the principle of sequential sampling from low-level to high-level decisions -at least for options with defined features.</p><p>To our knowledge, two previous results hint at this finding. First, Cohen et al. (2017) report a moderate-to-strong positive correlation between choice proportions observed (in people) and predicted (by the multi-attribute linear ballistic accumulator) in preferential and risky choice contexts, yet a very low correlation between observed and predicted choice times. Given the model predicts a negative monotonic relationship between choice frequency and choice times, and the correlation between observed data and model predictions differed markedly for choice frequency and times, one might conclude the data violate some feature of the predicted relationship. Second, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Cataldo and Cohen (2021)</ref> found that of the multiattribute context effects, faster responses tend to be associated with a stronger similarity effect while slower responses tend to be associated with stronger attraction and compromise effects. This empirical result demonstrates choice frequency can depend on choice time, marginalised across stimulus values. We address an orthogonal question: conditioned on stimulus value, what is the relationship between choice frequency and choice time?</p><p>In the remainder of the paper, we document experimental evidence for our claim, along with preliminary evidence from standard sequential sampling models. We start with an overview of the generic paradigm studied in much of the decision literature: the discrete choice experiment (DCE).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discrete Choice Experiments (DCE)</head><p>Many studies of multi-attribute preferential choice with defined features involve a DCE. A multi-attribute DCE presents a set of two or more options that vary across two or more features or attributes, and asks the respondent to select their most preferred option. For instance, when choosing between candidate fast food options, would you prefer an expensive meal that arrives quickly or a cheaper meal with a longer wait time? By manipulating the levels of the attributes, like cheap vs expensive meal and fast vs slow delivery time, the DCE requires participants to make tradeoffs between the multiple attributes that make up an option. By selecting one option over another the respondent reveals information about the psychological weight they place on the attributes of the chosen option relative to the unchosen option/s. Through repeated choices between sets of options with different combinations of attributes and levels, the analyst learns increasingly precise information about the psychological weight a decision maker assigns to the component attributes.</p><p>Multi-attribute DCEs in the applied choice field are typically analysed with random utility models. Random utility models share many similarities with standard sequential sampling models: the existence of a latent valuation function, sampling some number of times from the valuation function on presentation of a stimulus, and selecting an option based on some function of the sampled values. Indeed, there is close correspondence between random utility and sequential sampling models formally (e.g., see <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Colonius &amp; Marley, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Marley &amp; Colonius, 1992)</ref> and empirically (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hawkins et al., 2014b)</ref>. Given similarities in the standard analysis approaches applied across disciplines, one might expect similar relationships to hold in data -such as the joint distribution of choice outcomes and choice times. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The specific question we address here is whether value-based options in a multiattribute DCE that are chosen more often are also chosen more quickly. One can address this question at two levels: choosing options (a collection of attribute levels -like a cheap meal with fast delivery) or component attributes of options (the attribute levels considered independently -like cheap meals, or fast delivery). At the level of options, one can map all unique combinations of attribute levels permitted in the experimental design, where some will naturally be more desirable -a cheap meal delivered quickly is better than a slow and expensive meal. We ask if the former is chosen more rapidly than the latter. At the level of attributes, we examine the relationship between the choice frequency for options with a specified attribute level marginalised over all other attributes and options, and how quickly those options are chosen. To continue the earlier example, a negative monotonic relationship at the level of attributes would be that cheap fast food meals are chosen more often and more quickly than expensive fast food meals -independent of the speed of delivery. AS another example, and to foreshadow the DCE studied in Experiment 1, we would expect phones that cost $250 are chosen more often and more quickly than phones that cost $500, which in turn would be chosen more often and more quickly than phones that cost $750independent of the values of the 4 other attributes that comprise the DCE stimulus. The latter is a powerful test of an effect because it doesn't rely on specific collections of attribute levels to emerge.</p><p>We present evidence for our argument using a common multi-attribute DCE context</p><p>1 As an aside, we note the well-documented violations of random utility axioms for multi-attribute preferences -the 'context effects' -are orthogonal to our argument. Many sequential sampling models that explain the multi-attribute context effects also violate the choice frequency and choice time prediction we document here. This is because the violation concerns the dynamic accumulation process of sequential sampling models and not the composition of the latent valuation function that provides inputs to the sampling process; the latter has been the target for most cognitive theories of decisions that violate the context effects, not the former. This applies to major cognitive theories of the context effects including multi-alternative decision field theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Roe et al., 2001)</ref>, the multi-attribute linear ballistic accumulator <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Trueblood et al., 2014)</ref>, the leaky competing accumulator <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Usher &amp; McClelland, 2004)</ref>, and the associative accumulation model <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bhatia, 2013)</ref>; see formalisation in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Evans et al. (2019)</ref> that demonstrates the common underlying structure.</p><p>across four experiments: preferences for mobile (cell) phones. In each experiment, participants were presented with 2 or 3 phones per choice set (trial), where each phone was described by different values for each of 4 or 5 attributes. Participants were asked to select their most preferred phone in each choice set. Across studies we assessed 'free' choice, the impact of time pressure, whether the attribute structure of the options was correlated or not, and whether the analysis focus was at the level of component attributes or options. Regardless of the study differences, the same pattern emerged in data: the standard relationship between choice frequency and choice time is violated for multi-attribute preferential choice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1: Multi-Attribute Preferential Choices</head><p>Experiment 1 reports data previously published in Experiment 2 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hawkins et al. (2014a)</ref>. Twenty six participants selected their most preferred phone from each of 150 choice sets, presented one at a time. 2 Each choice set presented 3 phones that varied across 5 attributes -price, camera resolution, memory capacity, battery life, video capabilitywhere each attribute could take on one of 3 levels; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. For each choice set and option, the level of each attribute was randomly sampled from the set of 3 levels. In Experiments 1-3 we summarise the data at the level of attributes by calculating attribute-level choice proportions and attribute-level response times. In all experiments, we calculated each summary statistic independently for each participant and then averaged across participants for visualisation. To calculate attribute-level choice proportions, we tallied the number of choice sets in which an attribute level was present in at least 1 of the 3 options (call this n), and then counted the number of times the attribute level was in the option that was selected (call this c, where c ≤ n). The attribute-level choice proportion is the ratio c/n, calculated separately for each level of each attribute. This generates 3 (levels) × 5 (attributes) = 15 attribute-level choice proportions per participant.</p><p>To calculate attribute-level response times, we subset to the choice sets where an attribute level was in the selected option (i.e., the subset of choice sets included in c from the choice proportion calculations) and then computed summary statistics based on those response times. In Experiment 1, we summarised the attribute-level response time distributions with 5 quantiles: .1, .3, .5 (i.e., median), .7, and .9. This generates 5 response times for each attribute level, for a total of 5 (response time quantiles) × 3 (levels) × 5 (attributes) = 75 response times per participant. Note that each choice contributes response time information for 5 attribute levels, because the chosen option is composed of 1 level from each of the 5 attributes. Our data summaries are at the attribute level rather than the option level because the stimulus structure was randomly generated: the attribute level for each option was randomly selected from the possible levels for that attribute. With this stimulus structure, participants selected between the set of 3 5 = 243 unique phones, across trials; each choice set was composed of a random sample of 3 options from the set of 243 options. This stimulus space is too large to summarise at the level of options (i.e., computing choice frequency and response time distributions for 243 unique stimuli, for each participant). In Experiment 4 we studied a restricted stimulus space (fewer unique options) so we could summarise the data at the level of options, confirming that our attribute level analysis approach does not impact our conclusion. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> summarises attribute-level choice proportion and response time data in quantile-probability (QP) plots. For each attribute, symbols falling from smaller to larger values along the x-axis represent more desirable attribute levels -levels that were more frequently in the selected option. For example, when 1 of the available phones was the most expensive of the 3 possible prices ($750), that phone was chosen 28% of the time on average (leftmost points on the price panel). Similarly, when 1 of the available phones was the cheapest of the 3 possible prices ($250), that phone was chosen 66% of the time on average (rightmost points on the price panel). Attributes bearing greater impact on choices span a larger range on the choice proportion axis (x-axis); changes in the levels of those attributes generated larger changes in patterns of stated preferences. Price had the greatest impact (range 28% to 66%) and memory had the smallest impact (range 38% to 55%). A range of 0% would represent chance-level responding: the features of that attribute had no impact on choice. In such a case, the expected choice proportion is ∼.47, given the randomly generated stimulus structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The most striking feature in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> is that response times do not change as a function of choice proportion. This observation holds for measures of central tendency, such as the median (middle horizontal line), and for the full response time distributions, representing both fast and slow decisions (lower and upper horizontal lines, respectively). For all attributes, levels that were in options more frequently chosen were not chosen more rapidly; there was no relationship with the speed of the choice. All standard sequential sampling models predict that options chosen more frequently will be chosen more quickly, conditioned on a fixed threshold. This is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> with posterior predictive data of an exemplar sequential sampling model -the Linear Ballistic Accumulator (LBA; <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Brown &amp; Heathcote, 2008)</ref> model -applied to the data. The model specification follows standard assumptions, originally described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hawkins et al. (2014a)</ref>; complete modelling details are given in Appendix A.</p><p>A core feature of the model's predictions is the monotonically decreasing relationship between attribute-level choice proportions and attribute-level response times. This relationship holds across the entire response time distribution, for the fastest through to the slowest decisions. It also holds for all attributes, even attributes with relatively little impact (i.e., small range in choice proportion).</p><p>The model clearly misfits the data. It under-predicts choice proportions and overpredicts response times. By only varying drift rates across choice sets -that is, sensitivity to, or utility of, the attribute-level information -the model cannot capture the observed data. The model is capable of predicting more extreme attribute-level choice proportions (i.e., a larger range on the x-axes) such that it would more closely match the observed choice data. However, in doing so the model must predict an even larger range in response times between the least and most desirable levels of an attribute, thus misfitting the response time data to an even greater degree than it already does. The predictions in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> are those that maximise the posterior likelihood of the joint distribution of choices and response times; the 'best' the model can do, given its (standard) specification for multi-attribute preferential choices.</p><p>To ensure the model predictions weren't idiosyncratic to the particular sequential sampling model we chose, we repeated the modelling analysis with a second sequential sampling model -the racing diffusion model (RDM; Tillman, Van Zandt, &amp; Logan, 2020); for complete modelling details see Appendix A. All conclusions were identical (data not shown). Thus, the preceding discussion applies equally to both models, and demonstrates the qualitative pattern of the model predictions generalises to at least two standard sequential sampling models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Quantifying the Relationship Between Choices and Times for Observed and Predicted Data</head><p>The conclusions thus far were based on visual inspection of group-averaged data. We aimed to confirm that trends in the observed and predicted data followed qualitatively different trends via statistical analysis. The aim of our analysis was to test whether a linear regression predicting response time as a function of choice proportion has a slope coefficient of 0. A coefficient of 0, or a coefficient that does not statistically differ to 0, is evidence for no relationship between choice frequency and choice times.</p><p>We started with the observed data and conducted independent regressions for response time quantile i ∈ {.1, .3, .5, .7, .9} and attribute j ∈ {price, camera, memory, battery, video}, for a total of 25 linear regressions. While there are limitations to this analysis approach, it is a useful proxy to complement the 'by eye' tests of the visual trends, and supports our broader thesis. We interpret the overall direction (sign) of the trends across the set of regression models without a focus on particular quantiles or attributes; if our argument is supported then it ought to hold across the set of 25 regressions. Furthermore, while sequential sampling models predict a negative monotonic relationship and not the stricter assumption of a negative linear relationship we test here, we believe that the linear test strikes the right balance between answering the research question and interpretability of the analysis outputs, relative to arguably more appropriate analytic approaches (e.g., ordinal/monotonic regression) whose coefficients are less straightforward to interpret, at least for our purposes.</p><p>In each regression, we predicted response time y for quantile i and attribute j, y ij , as a function of the 3 choice proportions for attribute j, x j ; bold notation indicates x j is a vector, which has length 3. We assumed a random effects structure, so participant k had their own intercept (α) and slope (β) coefficients in each regression:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">y ijk ∼ α ijk + β ijk • x jk + N (0, k ),<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where k is a participant-specific variance term. The models were estimated in a Bayesian framework. We assumed random effects were sampled from group-level normal distributions, and non-informative hyperpriors sampled from uniform distributions with settings selected to span the range of response times observed across participants:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">α ijk ∼ N (α µ ij , α σ ij ) α µ ij ∼ U (0, 40) α σ ij ∼ U (0, 20) β ijk ∼ N (β µ ij , β σ ij ) β µ ij ∼ U (−20, 20) β σ ij ∼ U (0, 20).<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The participant-specific noise term had no hierarchical structure; k ∼ U (0, 10). The left panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows the estimated group-level slope coefficients (β µ ). For all 25 regressions -5 response time quantiles crossed with 5 attributes -the 95% credible interval of the slope coefficient includes 0: there is evidence of no (linear) relationship between choice proportion and response time, aggregated across participants. The result was remarkably consistent across the full distribution of response times, indicating the effect is not isolated to fast or slow decisions.</p><p>We repeated the set of regression analyses on the posterior predictive data of the sequential sampling model (i.e., the predictions shown in blue in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). Our aim was to confirm that the sequential sampling model does indeed predict the expected negative relationship between choice frequency and choice times, and that it can be detected with this analysis approach. To this end, we substituted outcome y ijk and predictor x jk in Equation 1 with each participant's posterior predictive data of the sequential sampling model; outcome y ijk and predictor x jk . 3 The middle panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows the slope coefficients of the linear regressions estimated from the predictions of the sequential sampling model. The 95% credible intervals exclude 0 in all cases, bar 1 which marginally crossed 0. This confirms the sequential sampling model predicts the expected negative relationship between choices and times. Of note, the sequential sampling model predicts a consistent trend where the strength of the relationship increases for slower decisions (i.e., slope coefficient becomes more negative). The right panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows the difference in estimated slope coefficients between the regressions applied to the observed data and the regressions applied to the sequential sampling model's predictions. Values larger than 0 indicate the sequential sampling model predicts a more negative relationship between choice frequency and choice times. For all quantiles, the mean difference in slope coefficients is positive, indicating a more negative relationship between the two variables for the sequential sampling model. This effect grew in magnitude from the fastest decisions (.1 quantile) through to the slowest (.9 quantile).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2: Preferential Choices Under Time Pressure</head><p>We aimed to test whether the findings of Experiment 1 generalised to a context where decision makers modulate their decision threshold -the evidence required to commit to a decision. It is well known that people adaptively set thresholds based on relevant information at the time of making a decision; for instance, environmental cues encouraging speedy or careful actions. And while we assume throughout that thresholds do not vary as a function of the target stimulus (i.e., the content of the DCE), it's important to confirm whether we still observe no relationship between choice frequency and choice times when pre-stimulus information (e.g., a cue) positions the decision maker along different parts of the speed-accuracy tradeoff function. That is, do we still observe no relationship conditioning on different thresholds?</p><p>Experiment 2 reports data previously published in Experiment 2b of <ref type="bibr">Cavallaro and Hawkins (submitted)</ref>, where 45 participants selected their most preferred phone from each of 250 choice sets. The structure closely followed Experiment 1 with two primary exceptions. First, participants were cued to emphasise speedy or careful decisions. The emphasis was randomised across trials and implemented with a pre-trial cue to "be speedy" or "be careful". Second, the stimulus was composed of 4 attributes each with 3 levels; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> displays the attribute-level choice proportion and response time data in the same format as <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, separately for speedy and careful decisions. We observed similar qualitative patterns to Experiment 1 for most attributes. When given instructions to be speedy, there was no relationship between choice frequency and choice time for most quantiles and attributes, with some suggestion of a negative-going relationship for the price and camera attributes for faster decisions (lower quantiles). When given instructions to be careful, there was a general tendency toward a negative relationship for faster decisions for the price and memory attributes, and the battery attribute though to a lesser extent. Overall, there was a greater range in decision behaviour in Experiment 2, over which the relationship between choice frequency and choice times was still mostly absent, although unlike Experiment 1 there were some indications the relationship may be present.</p><p>As in Experiment 1, we compared the observed data to predictions of the LBA model -see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> -and predictions of the RDM (data not shown); complete modelling details are given in Appendix A. We focus on two main results. First, the two models misfit the Experiment 2 data in the same qualitative way; under-predicting choice proportions and over-predicting response times. This again demonstrates the modelling result in Experiment 1 is not idiosyncratic to a specific sequential sampling model. Second, as reported in <ref type="bibr">Cavallaro and Hawkins (submitted)</ref>, the only parameter difference that emerged between the speedy and careful conditions was in the decision thresholds -for both models -such that participants accumulated more decision-relevant information when instructed to make careful compared to speedy decisions; in the LBA, there was also a smaller range in the start-point distribution for the speedy condition than the careful condition. The model specification permitted separate utility coefficients (drift rate parameters) for each attribute and emphasis condition, though the estimated utility coefficients did not differ between the speedy and careful conditions. This suggests our finding of no relationship between attribute-level choice proportions and response times is not dependent on a particular response speed or 'mode' of decision making. Rather, it generalises across (at least some of the) speed-accuracy tradeoff settings that people may adopt when making multi-attribute preferential choices. We repeated the regression analyses from Experiment 1 with two main changes: the regressions were conducted independently for the speedy and careful instruction conditions, and there were only 4 attributes in the DCE. This led to a total of 5 (response time quantiles) × 4 (attributes) × 2 (instruction conditions) = 40 regressions, for observed and predicted data. The modified regression model includes instruction emphasis condition m ∈ {speedy, careful}:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">y ijkm ∼ α ijkm + β ijkm • x jkm + N (0, k ),<label>(3)</label></formula><p>All other details were as described in Experiment 1, including the random effects structure and hyperprior settings. The left column of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> shows the estimated group-level slope coefficients (β µ ) for the observed data. For many of the quantile-attribute regressions in the speedy condition, the 95% credible interval includes 0. In contrast, many of the quantile-attribute regressions in the careful condition have coefficients that are small yet reliably below 0 (i.e., 95% credible interval excludes 0). Interestingly, the relationship between choice frequency and choice times was weakest -and in fact non-existent -for the slowest decisions, whose credible interval included 0 for all attributes.</p><p>The middle column of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> shows the slope coefficients estimated from the predictions of the sequential sampling model. As in Experiment 1, the 95% credible interval  excludes 0 for all quantiles and attributes, and new in Experiment 2, this generalised to speedy and careful decisions. As in Experiment 1, the model predicts the magnitude of the relationship increases (i.e., β µ becomes increasingly negative) for slower decisions. The right column of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> shows the difference in estimated slope coefficients between the observed data and predictions of the sequential sampling model. For all 40 regressions, the 95% credible interval excludes 0. This is strong evidence that the relationship between choice frequency and choice times differs between how people make multi-attribute decisions and how a standard model proposes people make those decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3: Preferential Choices with Correlated and Uncorrelated Attribute Structures: Attribute-Level Analysis</head><p>Experiments 1 and 2 used a standard principle of DCE design: uncorrelated attribute structure. The attribute structure is uncorrelated when, for a given option, the level of one attribute has no bearing on the levels of the other attributes. Experiments 1 and 2 imposed an uncorrelated attribute structure by randomly sampling the level of each attribute from the set of potential levels. Many DCEs, particularly in the applied choice literature, specify uncorrelated attribute structures with carefully balanced orthogonal designs such that the attribute levels composing each option are assigned in a manner that makes the options in a choice set maximally different. On the whole, uncorrelated attribute structures are highly efficient for statistical estimation, and hence identifying the attributes of greatest importance to consumers from minimal trial counts.</p><p>However, uncorrelated attribute structures introduce a level of artificiality to the preferential choice scenario relative to multi-attribute choices as they occur in the marketplace. Real-world preferential choice occurs in a context of correlated attribute structures, where knowing something about the level of one attribute generally provides some information about potential levels of other attributes. For instance, one generally expects a $1000 phone to contain better features (camera, memory, etc.) than a $100 phone. It's not only a price 'heuristic', however. Having some content knowledge also allows the decision maker to draw inferences about likely attribute correlations. For instance, a phone with a low screen resolution is unlikely to have a high resolution camera, because photos taken with the high resolution camera cannot be clearly viewed on a low resolution screen.</p><p>It's possible that the lack of association between choices and response times observed in Experiments 1 and 2 was due to the artificiality introduced by uncorrelated attribute structures. For instance, with information about attribute correlations unavailable, it's possible that participants drew upon different cognitive mechanisms to make decisions about the novel stimuli.</p><p>In Experiment 3, we tested whether the same (lack of) relationship between choice frequency and choice time was observed when multi-attribute preferential options were generated with correlated attribute structures. To ensure the correlation structure of our stimuli mirrored the magnitude and direction of the attribute correlations observed in the marketplace, we sampled our stimuli from all mobile phones for sale at a prominent consumer hifi store in Australia during Summer 2020. We extracted the product descriptions for all the phones and selected 5 attributes for our DCE that were routinely specified in the product description for almost all phones; price, camera, memory, screen size, and screen resolution. We extracted the levels for these 5 attributes for all available phones and removed duplicates from the database, which were predominantly phones that differed on attributes we didn't investigate, like colour. The final database contained 101 unique phones. The Appendix provides evidence of the correlated attribute structure of the phone database and a complete listing of options in the database is available at osf.io/kdyp5. Experiment 3 manipulated the attribute structure between subjects in two conditions. Both conditions made choices between sets of 3 phones. The correlated attributes condition had choice sets derived directly from the phone database, where each choice set was generated from a random sample, without replacement, from the set of 101 phones. This ensured that, across trials and on average, participants would experience the magnitude and direction of the attribute correlations as they appear in the marketplace. The uncorrelated attributes condition had choice sets indirectly derived from the phone database. Separately for each choice set and option, we randomly sampled a level for each attribute from the set of available attribute levels across the 101 phones in the database. This stimulus-generation procedure balanced the range of attribute levels participants experienced across both conditions, on average, though it removed the correlated attributes structure inherent in the phone database. One-hundred and two participants were randomly allocated to the correlated (N = 49) or uncorrelated (N = 53) condition. Each participant completed 245 choice sets. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref> displays mean attribute-level response times as a function of attributelevel choice proportions. We display the mean rather than quantiles of the distribution of attribute-level response times in Experiment 3 (and 4, next) owing to the sparser attributelevel data in this experimental design. This is a consequence of the correlated attribute structure: to generate attribute correlations we require many data points (i.e., attribute levels). This means the volume of choice and response time data per attribute level per participant decreases markedly, and to a degree where it is no longer feasible to generate reliable participant-by attribute-level response time distributions.</p><p>Experiment 3 replicated the primary finding of Experiments 1 and 2. Mean response times did not vary as a function of choice proportion for any attribute or for correlated or uncorrelated attribute structures. We rely on visual inspection for this conclusion because we do not think it reasonable to conduct the regression-based analyses from the earlier experiments in Experiment 3 or 4 owing to the sparsity of participant-level data. This sparsity causes particular problems for individual-participant regression, because there are very uneven quantities of data contributing to the different summary data points in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref>. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We note that a more complete analyses of these data would model the joint distribution, ideally with a plausible generative cognitive model. Our aim in this paper is not to propose such a model but rather to note empirical trends in the joint distribution of choice frequency and choice time that place critical constraints on such a theory.</p><p>As a side point, the choice proportion data in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref> highlight the importance of uncorrelated attribute structures when one's aim is to identify the impact of attributes on preferential choices. For the uncorrelated attribute structure, some attributes had little impact on product selection (i.e., small range in choice proportion; e.g., screen size, screen resolution). In contrast, other attributes had a larger impact (e.g., price, memory capacity). The attributes that had little impact on choice in the uncorrelated attributes condition appear to have a large impact on choice in the correlated attributes condition. However, this is a consequence of those attributes (screen size, resolution) co-varying with the attributes that participants actually do value highly (price, memory), thus artificially inflating the apparent impact of those attributes on choice. Taken together, for both natural (correlated) and artificial (uncorrelated) attribute structures, we still observe no reliable relationship between attribute-level response times and choice proportions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 4: Preferential Choices with Correlated and Uncorrelated Attribute Structures: Option-Level Analysis</head><p>In Experiment 4 we confirm that our findings from the previous experiments were not due to summary statistics defined on attribute levels rather than options. While the attribute-level summaries we reported above are informative and standard in the applied choice literature, they also mismatch the actual decision made by participants; participants choose options, not attributes or levels. It may be that options chosen more frequently are indeed chosen more quickly.</p><p>In Experiment 4 we generated a subset of 15 phones from the database of 98 phones in Experiment 3. 5 The set size of 15 phones was selected to be small enough so that all options could be presented with all other options yet large enough to calculate summary statistics (mean response times, choice proportions) for individual options, and for the study to run in the available participant time. We selected the subset of phones for the correlated attributes condition through a simulation-based search that maximised the correlation between attributes of the subset. To this end, we randomly sampled 15 phones without replacement from the database of 98 phones, calculated the absolute value of the pairwise correlation between all attributes of the options in the subset, and computed the average over these values. We repeated this procedure 1,000,000 times and selected the subset of 15 phones with the largest average (absolute value of) pairwise attribute correlation. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> shows the stimulus set, which had mean pairwise attribute correlation = 0.806 and range across attribute pairs of 0.703 to 0.961. represent the data. This wasn't a concern in Experiments 1 and 2 as the choice proportions for 'disfavoured' attribute levels were sufficiently greater than 0 that we could estimate distributions of response times for individual participants.</p><p>5 For Experiment 4 we removed 3 phones from the Experiment 3 database of 101 phones because they had extreme values on at least one dimension. These extreme attribute levels had the capacity to skew the stimulus generation procedure of Experiment 4. The 3 phones that were removed were: a phone with double the memory capacity of the next-highest memory capacity phone, a phone that was 3× cheaper than the second cheapest phone, and a phone with screen size almost half the size of the next-smallest screen size. We generated stimuli for the uncorrelated attributes condition from the set of 15 phones shown in the upper half of <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. We shuffled the levels assigned to each attribute of each option without replacement. This generated a new set of 15 phones that matched the attribute level composition of the original set of 15 phones (i.e., each attribute had the same mean, variance and range across options) though removed (some of) the attribute structure across options. We repeated this procedure 1,000,000 times and selected the set of 15 phones with the smallest average (absolute value of) pairwise attribute correlation. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> shows the stimulus set, which had mean pairwise attribute correlation = 0.034 and range across attribute pairs of 0.005 to 0.192.</p><p>Given the stimulus structure, we confirmed the set of 15 (artificial) phones in the  <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> . Experiment 4: Option-level mean response times (y-axes) as a function of optionlevel choice proportions (x-axes) for each attribute structure condition (panels). Symbols represent the mean across participants and uncertainty bars represent ± standard error of the mean. uncorrelated attributes condition weren't deemed less psychologically plausible than the set of 15 (real) phones in the correlated attributes condition. We asked 3 participants naive to the stimulus structure to rate whether they believed each of the 30 phones (randomised order) was plausible. We operationalised plausible as 'I believe this could be a legitimate phone sold in the marketplace', and participants made a yes/no response. Chi-square tests indicated no significant difference in plausibility (yes/no) ratings between the two sets of phones (correlated, uncorrelated), χ 2 (1) = 3.4, p = .06.</p><p>One hundred and seven participants were randomly allocated to the correlated (N = 52) or uncorrelated (N = 55) attribute structure conditions. Participants made 105 binary choices, where the set of 105 trials was the exhaustive set of all pairs of options from the stimulus set of the participant's attribute structure condition. (i.e., 15 × (15 − 1)/2 = 105). Trial order was randomised across participants. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> shows option-level mean response times as a function of option-level choice proportions. Option-level summary statistics were calculated in the expected manner, first for individual participants and then averaged for visualisation. We first tallied the number of choice sets in which an option was present (n), counted the number of times the option was chosen (c, where c ≤ n), and operationalised the option-level choice proportion as the ratio c/n. For option-level mean response times, we subsetted to the choice sets where an option was chosen (the subset of choice sets in c) and then calculated the mean response time from those choices.</p><p>When summary statistics were calculated for options, we still observed no consistent relationship between choice frequency and choice time. This result held even though the range of option attractiveness was quite substantial; choice proportions ranged from .2 to .8 for uncorrelated attributes, with a marginally smaller range for correlated attributes. Whether attributes had a correlated or uncorrelated structure had no impact on the relationship between the two variables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>We have demonstrated there is no relationship between how often people choose an item from a set of preferential options with defined features and how quickly they choose from the set. Our evidence for this invariance in multi-attribute preferential / value-based judgements came from four experimental contexts that were unconstrained (Experiment 1), imposed time pressure (Experiment 2), and contained artificial and real-life compositions of options (Experiments 3 and 4). The invariance held when data were inspected at the 'higher' level of overall options (Experiment 4) and the 'lower' level of the component attributes of options (Experiments 1-3).</p><p>Our findings lend support to a critical constraint on the relationship between choice frequency and choice times: a lack of relationship. Such an invariance is powerful because the dominant theories that have choices and times within their predictive scope -sequential sampling models -all naturally predict a negative monotonic relationship. Our results therefore place new constraints on theories of multi-attribute choice.</p><p>Before considering implications, there are some limitations to our conclusion to bear in mind. First, choosing between multi-alternative and multi-attribute options may include longer or multiple components of processing that are unrelated to evidence accumulation. If this is the case, then the expected relationship between choice time and choice frequency would be attenuated. For instance, compared to perceptual decisions, value-based decisions may require more time searching for decision relevant information (e.g., attribute values) relative to evidence accumulation (for review, see <ref type="bibr">Mormann et al., 2020)</ref>. Second, our findings relate to value-based decisions with defined features -explicitly specified attributes and levels, such as a choice between one phone that cost $30/month with a 12MP camera and 32GB memory capacity and another phone that cost $45/month with an 8MP camera and 64GB memory capacity. This differs to research that has investigated value-based decisions for options that implicitly have multiple attributes but the stimulus structure doesn't specify values for those attributes -such as a choice between crisps and a chocolate bar, most often displayed as images without a feature description. There is considerable research demonstrating that value-based decisions without explicit attributes observe the expected negative monotonic relationship between choice time and choice frequency (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Fisher, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Gluth et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">and Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2018</ref>; for review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Clithero, 2018)</ref>. We recommend that future research further investigates this difference between implicit and explicit attribute structures for value-based decisions.</p><p>Given the behavioural differences, we argue that our findings have implications for theories of multi-attribute preferential choice -for options with implicitly and explicitly defined features. This is because our findings for options with defined features must be reconciled with choice frequency and choice time effects observed for options without defined features. We suggest the first steps along this path might incorporate different psychological mechanisms into existing sequential sampling theories of multi-attribute choice, and empirically test them against data. The goal of such work will be to determine whether the new mechanisms for different stimulus setups are (a) psychologically reasonable and (b) sufficient to explain patterns in observed data.</p><p>As a starting point for such work, we suggest the lack of relationship between the two outcome measures could be incorporated into existing theories of multi-attribute preferential choice. For instance, with complex displays of defined features (e.g., features defined in rows of a table, and available options in columns), the decision process may involve a dynamic attention-switching mechanism that discounts information that is not currently attended. For instance, Yang and Krajbich (in press) investigated value-based decisions between two options each with two defined features, and found that attention switching (eye movements) led to discounted weights (lower utility) for the non-fixated attribute and non-fixated option.</p><p>Discounted weights for non-attended information will attenuate the relationship between choice frequency and choice time.</p><p>Another perspective is that preference may dynamically accumulate until a quantity of information is accrued or a self-imposed (i.e., internal) deadline terminates the process -a deadline on the amount of time one is willing to commit to a decision. A strict interpretation of such 'deadline' models suggest all choices should have the same choice time, though modern approaches suggest a distribution of internal times could terminate the process (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bhatia &amp; Mullett, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hawkins &amp; Heathcote, 2021)</ref>. Internal deadline models truncate decisions with slower-than-average preference accumulation, and thus attenuate the relationship between choice frequency and choice times. One possibility is that internal deadlines may be used more often for choices between options with defined features because the deliberation process is (or is more likely to be) more taxing to the cognitive system than choices between options with undefined features.</p><p>Alternatively, our results might hark back to earlier work generalising random utility theory into the time domain (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Marley, 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Marley &amp; Colonius, 1992)</ref>. This work showed that classic random utility models applied to choice data can be generalised to 'horse race' random utility models applied to choice and response time data. The resulting generalisations were considered inadequate because they predicted distributions of choice times that were independent of the choice outcomes. This prediction was considered to be inconsistent with data showing choice time depends on choice frequency -data predominantly from 'low-level' decisions. Our work shows that the rejection of the class of 'horse race' random utility models may need to be re-considered, given choice frequency and choice times appear to be independent, or almost independent, for the types of 'high-level' multiattribute preferential choices where random utility models are most often studied -options with defined features.</p><p>To take a broader perspective, in the domain of value-based decisions between options with defined features, choice data is by far the most common outcome measure used to test theories and generate predictions of marketplace behaviour. This is clearly the most natural approach when we have a goal of enhancing market share; that is, in applied contexts what people choose to purchase is ultimately the most important outcome. Nevertheless, to accurately predict choices we need good theories. We argue that a focus on choice outcomes is a 'first step' metric in identifying and developing good theories. For more accurate predictions we ought to incorporate more choice-relevant metrics into the choice theories. This is not to say that other metrics haven't been investigated with an eye to improving prediction, including eye movements, neuroimaging (e.g., EEG, fMRI), confidence ratings, and indeed response times. Rather, our perspective is that these various outcome measures provide a lens on a single generative process. As such, we ought to consider latent cognitive processes as a single 'model' capable of generating a joint distribution over outcome measures, only some of which we observe (i.e., measure) on a given occasion -like the joint distribution of choices frequency and choice times we examined here.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure B1</ref> . Experiment 3: Attribute correlations for the 101 options in the phone database derived from marketplace data. Scatterplots in the upper right panels show the association between the row-named and column-named attributes. Each point represents one phone from the database. The lower left panels show the Spearman correlation coefficient for the association between the row-named and column-named attributes. The resolution attribute was converted to total pixels in the display (i.e., pixel width x pixel height).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Price</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Experiment 1: Attribute-level response times (y-axes) displayed as a function of attribute-level choice proportions (x-axes) separately for each attribute (panel). Observed data are shown in black and mean posterior predictive data of the model are shown in blue. Quantiles of the response time distributions are stacked vertically where the .1, .3, .5 (i.e., median), .7 and .9 quantiles are shown as the lowest through to highest symbols. Uncertainty bars on data points represent ± standard error of the mean along both axes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Experiment 1: Estimated slope coefficients (y-axes) displayed as a function of the 5 response time quantiles (x-axes) separately for data (left) and model (middle), and the difference in estimated slope coefficients between data and model (right). Attributes are shown in different colours. Posterior mean and 95% credible intervals of the estimated coefficients are shown with dots and bars, respectively. Horizontal lines indicate the coefficient value representing no relationship between choice frequency and choice times (left, middle), and the point of no difference between data and model (right).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Experiment 2: Attribute-level response times (y-axes) displayed as a function of attribute-level choice proportions (x-axes) separately for each attribute (columns) and speed-accuracy tradeoff emphasis (rows). Observed data are shown in black and mean posterior predictive data of the model are shown in blue. Quantiles of the response time distributions are stacked vertically where the .1, .3, .5 (i.e., median), .7 and .9 quantiles are shown as the lowest through to highest symbols. Uncertainty bars on data points represent ± standard error of the mean along both axes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Experiment 2: Estimated slope coefficients (y-axes) displayed as a function of the 5 response time quantiles (x-axes) separately for speedy or careful decisions (rows), for data (left) and model (middle), and the difference in estimated slope coefficients between data and model (right). Attributes are shown in different colours. Posterior mean and 95% credible intervals of the estimated coefficients are shown with dots and bars, respectively. Horizontal lines indicate the coefficient value representing no relationship between choice frequency and choice times (left, middle), and the point of no difference between data and model (right).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Experiment 3: Attribute-level mean response times (y-axes) as a function of attribute-level choice proportions (x-axes) for each attribute (columns) and attribute structure condition (rows). Symbols represent the mean across participants and uncertainty bars represent ± standard error of the mean.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Experiment 1: The 5 attributes and their combined 15 levels.</figDesc><table><row><cell>capability</cell></row></table><note>Price Camera resolution Memory capacity Battery life (talk time) Video</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Experiment 2: The 4 attributes and their combined 12 levels.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Price per month Camera resolution Memory capacity Battery life (talk time)</cell></row><row><cell>$30</cell><cell>8MP</cell><cell>16GB</cell><cell>10hrs</cell></row><row><cell>$45</cell><cell>12MP</cell><cell>32GB</cell><cell>16hrs</cell></row><row><cell>$60</cell><cell>16MP</cell><cell>64GB</cell><cell>24hrs</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Experiment 4: The 15 options in the correlated and uncorrelated conditions.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Condition</cell><cell>Price</cell><cell cols="3">Camera Memory Size</cell><cell>Resolution</cell></row><row><cell>Correlated</cell><cell>$134</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>16Gb</cell><cell>5"</cell><cell>1280 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$179</cell><cell>8MP</cell><cell>8Gb</cell><cell>5"</cell><cell>1280 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$199</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>16Gb</cell><cell cols="2">5.71" 1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$229</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>32Gb</cell><cell cols="2">6.26" 1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$239</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>64Gb</cell><cell>6.2"</cell><cell>1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$279</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>64Gb</cell><cell>6.2"</cell><cell>1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$299</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>32Gb</cell><cell cols="2">5.71" 1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$399</cell><cell>16MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>2340 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$399</cell><cell>16MP</cell><cell>64Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>2280 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$549</cell><cell>48MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>2280 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$599</cell><cell>48MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>6.5"</cell><cell>2340 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$599</cell><cell>48MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>6.4"</cell><cell>2340 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">$1,199 16MP</cell><cell>512Gb</cell><cell>6.1"</cell><cell>3040 x 1440</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">$1,279 16MP</cell><cell>64Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>3040 x 1440</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">$1,429 16MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>3040 x 1440</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Uncorrelated $134</cell><cell>16MP</cell><cell>64Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$179</cell><cell>16MP</cell><cell>32Gb</cell><cell>6.1"</cell><cell>1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$199</cell><cell>8MP</cell><cell>64Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>3040 x 1440</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$229</cell><cell>16MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>5"</cell><cell>1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$239</cell><cell>48MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>5"</cell><cell>3040 x 1440</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$279</cell><cell>16MP</cell><cell>64Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>2340 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$299</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>32Gb</cell><cell>6.4"</cell><cell>1280 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$399</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$399</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>64Gb</cell><cell>6.3"</cell><cell>2340 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$549</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>16Gb</cell><cell>6.2"</cell><cell>3040 x 1440</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$599</cell><cell>48MP</cell><cell>512Gb</cell><cell>6.5"</cell><cell>2280 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>$599</cell><cell>13MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell cols="2">5.71" 1280 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">$1,199 16MP</cell><cell>16Gb</cell><cell cols="2">5.71" 1520 x 720</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">$1,279 48MP</cell><cell>8Gb</cell><cell cols="2">6.26" 2280 x 1080</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">$1,429 13MP</cell><cell>128Gb</cell><cell>6.2"</cell><cell>2340 x 1080</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">We restrict our focus to 1 of the 3 between-subject conditions studied in Experiment 2 of<ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hawkins et al. (2014a)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">To simplify the analysis, y ijk and x jk are the mean of each participant's posterior predictive distribution.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Specifically, with so few responses for 'disfavoured' attribute levels (high price, low resolution camera, etc.) there are necessarily very few response times, so some participants' attribute-level mean response time estimates are highly variable (e.g., some participants chose a phone with a given attribute level just once). As a result, participant-level mean response times at the 'left' of each panel inFigure 5are much noisier than those at the 'right' of each panel. Since the regression analyses would use these empirical estimates of participants' mean response times and choice proportions as inputs, the resulting analyses cannot faithfully</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A Model Description and Estimation</head><p>We applied the Linear Ballistic Accumulator (LBA; <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Brown &amp; Heathcote, 2008)</ref> and the Racing Diffusion Model (RDM; <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Tillman et al., 2020)</ref> to the data of Experiments 1 and 2. These two models were chosen for two primary reasons. First, they are natural extensions of random utility theory -the most common model applied to value-based multi-attribute choices for options with defined features. Second, they are simple models from the class of race models that naturally generalise to decisions between more than 2 options.</p><p>The primary feature of both models is an additive utility representation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Marley &amp; Pihlens, 2012)</ref>. We assume the level of each attribute has a utility, and the overall utility of an option is the sum of the component attribute-level utilities of the option. That is, if each multi-attribute option has m attributes, then there are utility scales u i , i = 1, ..., m, such that if z = (z 1 , ..., z m ), with z i the attribute level for z on attribute i, then</p><p>with a separate u(z) for each option in the choice set. We assume the utility of each attribute level is a linear function of the attribute's levels. That is,</p><p>and we freely estimate β i for i = 1, ..., m attributes. The utility of an option is transformed to a positive-only drift rate, d(z), with a logarithmic relationship: d(z) = exp(u(z)); see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Colonius and Marley (2015)</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hawkins et al. (2014b)</ref>.</p><p>Alternative utility scales (u i for i = 1, ..., m) are, of course, possible, such as a concave utility function for price, or even independent utilities for each u i (z i ) subject to some identifiability constraints (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Marley &amp; Pihlens, 2012)</ref>. Nevertheless, all such transformations of the utility scales still generate the prediction described in the main text, given the additive utility representation of an option: larger utility (drift rate) predicts faster responses with greater certainty (larger choice proportion). For this reason we don't investigate alternative specifications of the utility scales here.</p><p>The remaining parameters of the LBA and RDM were specified in standard ways. In Experiment 1, for the LBA, we freely estimated from data the start-point of evidence accumulation (A), the response threshold (b), and the non-decision time (t 0 ). We set the across-trial variability in drift rate to s = 1 to satisfy the scaling condition of the model. For the RDM, we freely estimated from data the response threshold (α) and the non-decision time (τ ), setting the within-trial variability in drift to σ = 1 to satisfy the scaling condition.</p><p>In Experiment 2, the models were specified as described in Experiment 1 with two exceptions. First, we estimated an independent set of β i for i = 1, ..., m for the speed and accuracy emphasis conditions, resulting in 8 utility scales (4 attributes × 2 conditions). Second, we estimated independent response thresholds for the speed and accuracy emphasis conditions; for the LBA we also estimated an independent start-point for the two conditions.</p><p>All models were estimated in a hierarchical Bayesian framework using the Particle Metropolis within Gibbs (PMWG) algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Cooper et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gunawan, Hawkins, Tran, Kohn, &amp; Brown, 2020)</ref>. Participant-level utility parameters (β) were estimated on the real line, response thresholds, non-decision times and start points (for the LBA) were log transformed and estimated on the real line. Prior distributions for the group-level mean parameters were multivariate normal distributed with mean vector set to 0 for the β parameters, 0 for non-decision times, 1 for the start-point and response threshold parameters in the LBA, and 2 for the response threshold parameters in the RDM; the start-point / thresholds had different prior means such that the total height of the models' thresholds were equal (in the prior), since the LBA threshold is defined as A + b, where we estimate b − A, above. The covariance matrix for the prior on the group-level mean parameters was set to 1 for the diagonal elements and off-diagonal elements set to 0. The group-level variance-covariance matrix was set to the marginally non-informative prior distribution of <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Huang and Wand (2013)</ref>.</p><p>The three stages of the PMwG algorithm were specified as follows, for both models and both experiments; for further details see <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gunawan et al. (2020)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Cooper et al. (2021)</ref>. The burnin stage used 100 particles and ran for 1000 iterations. The adaptation stage used 100 particles and was set to for a maximum of 5000 iterations and terminated early once the adaptive proposal distribution was obtained for all participants. The sampling stage used 25 particles and ran for 10000 iterations. We scaled the variance-covariance matrix of the proposal distribution by a factor of = .3. Convergence was monitored by visual inspection.</p><p>To demonstrate the descriptive adequacy of the models, we randomly sampled from the posterior predictive distribution for each participant. Each posterior predictive sample -that is, each simulated data set for N participants in the experiment -was summarised with identical methods as described in the manuscript for the observed data, and then averaged across the posterior predictive samples for visualisation. <ref type="figure">Figure B1</ref> shows all pairwise correlations between the 5 attributes that compose the options in the Experiment 3 phone database. As expected, many attributes are positively correlated. A notable exception is the association between price and camera, which is negative. This is because a particular brand that shall remain unnamed tended to sell many phones with relatively low camera resolution (compared to competitor options) at a relatively high price point (again, compared to competitor options).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix B Experimemnt 3: Attribute Correlations</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Associations and the accumulation of preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">522</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dynamics of deferred decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mullett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2016.02.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2016.02.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="112" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The simplest complete model of choice response time: Linear ballistic accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2007.12.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2007.12.002" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling preference reversals in context effects over time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cataldo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Brain &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Psychological theories of preferential choices under time pressure are more consistent than descriptive theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-P</forename><surname>Cavallaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="psyarxiv.com/4b285" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>submitted</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response times in economics: Looking through the lens of sequential sampling models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clithero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-attribute, multi-alternative models of choice: Choice, reaction time, and process tracing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Leise</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision and choice: Random utility models of choice and response time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Colonius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International encyclopedia of the social &amp; behavioral sciences</title>
		<editor>J. D. Wright</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="901" to="905" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Innes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kuhne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-P</forename><surname>Cavallaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gunawan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=pmwg" />
		<title level="m">pmwg: Particle metropolis within gibbs</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Computer software manual. R package version 0.2.0)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response times and decision-making. Stevens&apos; Handbook of Experimental Psychology and Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Methodology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">349</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response-time data provide critical constraints on dynamic models of multi-alternative, multi-attribute choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="901" to="933" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multiattribute attentional drift diffusion model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">165</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="182" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential sampling models in cognitive neuroscience: Advantages, applications, and extensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="666" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value-based attention but not divisive normalization influences decisions with multiple alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kortmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Vitali</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="634" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New estimation approaches for the hierarchical linear ballistic accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gunawan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-N</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102368</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Racing against the clock: Evidence-based versus time-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The best of times and the worst of times are interchangeable. Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="192" to="214" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrating cognitive process and descriptive models of attitudes and preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="701" to="735" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple marginally noninformative prior distributions for covariance matrices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Wand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bayesian Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="439" to="452" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using best-worst scaling to improve psychological service delivery: An innovative tool for psychologists in organized care settings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Services</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual fixations and comparison of value in simple choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1298" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multi-alternative drift diffusion model predicts the relationship between visual fixations and choice in value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13852" to="13857" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Best-worst scaling: Theory, methods and applications</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stated choice methods: Analysis and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Louviere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hensher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Swait</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A random utility family that includes many of the &quot;classical&quot; models and has close form choice probabilities and choice reaction times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Mathematical and Statistical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The &quot;horse race&quot; random utility model for choice probabilities and reaction times, and its competing risks interpretation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Colonius</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models of best-worst choice and ranking among multiattribute options (profiles)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Marley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pihlens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Time to pay attention to attention: Using attention-based process traces to better understand consumer decision-making. Marketing Letters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mormann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Janiszewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aribarg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="392" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>others (2020)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential sampling models of choice: Some recent advances</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Otter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Allenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brazell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Diederich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diffusion decision model: Theory and data for two-choice decision tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="873" to="922" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion decision model: Current issues and history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2016.01.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2016.01.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-alternative decision field theory: A dynamic artificial neural network model of decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Roe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="370" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision making and sequential sampling from memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="927" to="939" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention and choice across domains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1810</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential sampling models without random between-trial variability: The racing diffusion model of speeded decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Van Zandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-020-01719-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-020-01719-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="911" to="936" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discrete choice methods with simulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Train</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The multi-attribute linear ballistic accumulator model of context effects in multi-alternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="205" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competing theories of multialternative, multiattribute preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Schley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">329</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loss aversion and inhibition in dynamical models of multialternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="757" to="769" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The (neural) dynamics of stochastic choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Webb</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="230" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic computational model of gaze and choice in multiattribute decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in press</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
