<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Why We Obey: From Animal Dominance to Affective Coherence</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>04 22, 2025</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Kleden</surname></persName>
							<email>ak@alankleden.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Why We Obey: From Animal Dominance to Affective Coherence</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">04 22, 2025</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/s7fge_v2</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:52+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>telotopic negentropy</term>
					<term>affective alignment</term>
					<term>obedience</term>
					<term>emotional coherence</term>
					<term>conative forces</term>
					<term>symbolic authority</term>
					<term>ethopraxie</term>
					<term>mémotions</term>
					<term>hierarchy</term>
					<term>affective decision-making</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>This article presents a novel affective-cognitive model of obedience based on telotopic negentropy, a measure of emotional alignment toward a situational telos. Departing from institutional or rationalchoice theories, we conceptualize obedience as the vectorial convergence of affective forces, including both approach-oriented (conative) and avoidance-oriented (inhibitory) dynamics. Drawing from ethology, symbolic violence theory, game theory, and affective neuroscience, we trace the evolution of obedience from animal hierarchies to human systems of internalized authority. Through repeated interactions and normative reinforcement, affective vectors become aligned with shared goals, generating a stable emotional field. The model formalizes this alignment using angular projections of emotional forces, quantified by their coherence with the telos. A simulation illustrates how varying degrees of affective alignment predict obedient behavior, ranging from mechanical compliance to genuine convergence. We discuss implications for political theory, social cohesion, and artificial systems of command. Obedience, we argue, emerges not merely from power or rationality, but from affective structure-a coherent emotional orientation toward a legitimized directive.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction: From Pecking Orders to Emotional Structure</head><p>Obedience is one of the most enduring and paradoxical features of human social life. We stop at red lights even in the absence of enforcement, defer to flight attendants during takeoff, and silence our phones in cinemas-not always because we are watched, but because we have internalized affective expectations linked to social order. These micro-acts of compliance reveal a deeper question: why does it often feel more coherent to obey than to resist? Obedience pervades our institutions, from military and religious systems to families and schools, yet it resists simple explanation. While the classical sociological canon-from Weber to Durkheim-treated authority as a foundational mechanism of order, the affective and embodied dimensions of obedience have remained underexplored. Traditional models often rely on legal-rational legitimacy, cost-benefit calculations, or learned helplessness, offering only partial answers to the deeper question: Why do we obey, even when resistance is an option?</p><p>This article proposes that the answer lies neither in fear nor in blind conformity, but in the subtle mechanics of affective coherence. Drawing on insights from ethology, game theory, political philosophy, and affective modeling, we reinterpret obedience as a negentropic phenomenon-a process of emotional alignment that reduces internal tension within a group by stabilizing affective forces around a shared telos <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">1</ref> .</p><p>The point of departure is a long evolutionary arc that links dominance behavior in non-human animalssuch as the pecking order in chickens <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Schjelderup-Ebbe, 1921)</ref> or the coalitional politics of chimpanzees (de Waal)-to the symbolic hierarchies of human societies, where coercion is often replaced by ritualized submission and internalized norms. We argue that the transition from physical dominance to symbolic authority corresponds to a shift from direct threat to what we call telotopic organization: the affective structuring of obedience around an emotionally salient goal or telos.</p><p>To formalize this process, we introduce the concept of telotopic negentropy-a measure of emotional convergence toward a situational objective. Unlike entropy, which captures dispersion and uncertainty, this framework quantifies the affective coherence and directionality of conative (approach-oriented) and inhibitory (avoidance-oriented) emotional vectors within an interactional field. Obedience, in this framework, is not simply the result of pressure or passivity, but a situated decision to align one's emotional forces with those of a perceived authority whose telos appears stabilizing or desirable.</p><p>To support this hypothesis, the article proceeds as follows: We first examine the ethological roots of hierarchy and dominance (Section 2), before turning to the symbolic and affective modulation of obedience in human societies through violence, ritual, and ethopraxic regulation (Section 3). We then introduce insights from repeated games theory and evolutionary strategies (Section 4) to show how obedience may emerge through anticipatory alignment. Section 5 presents the telotopic model in formal terms, followed by a theoretical simulation in Section 6. The discussion (Section 7) considers broader implications, including reversed hierarchies and political ideologies of obedience, before concluding with potential applications and limitations of the model.</p><p>Through this interdisciplinary synthesis, we aim to offer a new lens on a fundamental question: we obey not only because we must, but because it often feels affectively coherent to do so.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Ethology and the Structural Necessity of Hierarchy</head><p>Long before the codification of political authority or the construction of institutional hierarchies, animals were already solving the problem of conflict through asymmetry. Thorleif Schjelderup-Ebbe's seminal study of chickens in the 1920s <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Schjelderup-Ebbe, 1921)</ref> introduced the concept of the pecking order, a linear ranking system where each bird knows its place through repeated agonistic encounters. The brilliance of this model lies not in its brutality but in its economy of violence: once the hierarchy is stabilized, aggression diminishes. This principle-conflict followed by predictability-forms the behavioral core of all stable group dynamics.</p><p>Across the animal kingdom, similar mechanisms regulate access to resources, mates, and influence. Frans de Waal's observations of chimpanzees <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(de Waal, 2000)</ref> in Arnhem have shown that primate hierarchies are neither fixed nor merely physical. They are fluid, negotiated, and emotionally charged. Alpha status is not simply imposed by strength, but maintained through strategic alliances, grooming, appeasement gestures, and symbolic gestures of deference. Power is not only seized-it must be sustained affectively.</p><p>This dynamic complexity illustrates a crucial point: Hierarchy serves not just as a tool of control, but as a shield against the mental and emotional exhaustion of constant negotiation. From an ethological perspective, hierarchies are cognitive shortcuts that simplify the problem of social uncertainty. They encode expectations, structure behavior, and reduce the emotional arousal associated with unpredictable outcomes. This perspective aligns with recent work in cognitive load theory and emotional regulation, suggesting that stable hierarchies function as entropy-reducing structures in social cognition.</p><p>As societies grow in complexity, the biological roots of dominance become increasingly mediated by symbolization. Yet, the structural logic remains: humans, like other primates, require a framework for orienting behavior, reducing conflict, and establishing collective direction. What changes, however, is the affective and symbolic encoding of that framework.</p><p>In humans, hierarchy becomes not only a question of force or rank, but of meaning. We obey not because we are physically subdued, but because we recognize-or misrecognize-the telos embedded in an order. This telos may be expressed through charisma, tradition, legality, ritual, or ideology. What matters is not the content of the authority, but its capacity to generate affective alignment.</p><p>As we shall see in the next section, this transition from biological dominance to symbolic hierarchy corresponds to a shift from external coercion to internalized regulation-a process facilitated by violence, shame, ritual, and what we term ethopraxie <ref type="bibr">(Kleden, Beyond Rational Choice : Modeling Political Behavior Through Axiological Distance and Emotional Dynamics, 2025)</ref>. In doing so, hierarchy ceases to be merely an adaptation to conflict; it becomes a negentropic attractor, shaping the emotional geometry of obedience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">From Physical Aggression to Symbolic Submission</head><p>In human societies, the continuity of dominance structures with the animal world is undeniable, yet the mode of enforcement undergoes a profound transformation. Where primates rely on threat displays, coalition building, or periodic contests, humans develop more durable and disembodied mechanisms of control. Chief among these is the symbolic codification of subordination, which renders obedience affectively internalized and socially routinized.</p><p>Pierre Bourdieu famously described this phenomenon as symbolic violence <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bourdieu, 1982)</ref>-the power to impose meaning in such a way that the dominated perceive their domination as legitimate or natural. This form of power operates below the threshold of awareness; it is not imposed, but recognized.</p><p>The pecking order becomes a cognitive schema; the alpha display becomes an institutional role. In this transformation, the body does not disappear, but its submission is woven into gestures, rituals, and protocols that encode respect, deference, or silence.</p><p>This transition is not merely cultural. It involves a deeper affective restructuring. Obedience becomes associated not with fear alone, but with more ambiguous emotions: shame, pride, trust, reverence, guilt. These affective configurations stabilize the hierarchy by making dissent emotionally costly and conformity emotionally coherent. The presence of ritual is particularly crucial here. As shown by both Durkheimian sociology and affective neuroscience, ritual synchronizes emotional states, channels arousal, and reinforces alignment with shared goals.</p><p>To conceptualize this emotional structuring, we introduce the notion of ethopraxie, defined here as the structuring process by which deep-seated dispositions (ethos) are aligned with socially reinforced behaviors (praxis). Ethopraxie stabilizes behavioral orientation by integrating emotional memory, ritual conformity, and implicit norms. It binds internal affective states to external social roles, forming the backbone of habitual obedience in stable social systems. One obeys not because one evaluates the command as justified, but because obedience "feels right"-emotionally appropriate within a shared norm.</p><p>Importantly, this process is not deterministic. Ethopraxic alignment can be contested, reversed, or fractured. But its existence explains how obedience can persist even in the absence of surveillance, and why resistance often requires a break not only with belief, but with affective memory.</p><p>From this perspective, the command is more than a linguistic act, just as obedience transcends mere behavior. Both are components of an affective field-a structured space of felt relations, oriented toward a perceived telos. This sets the stage for a formal rethinking of obedience not as a discrete act, but as a negentropic modulation of emotional forces. In what follows, we will explore how such modulation can emerge even without trust, empathy, or long-term affiliation, through repetition, feedback, and anticipatory logic-the domain of repeated interaction and game theory.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Repeated Games, Tit-for-Tat and the Internalization of Hierarchical Positioning</head><p>If hierarchy offers a structural solution to the problem of uncertainty in group dynamics, the question remains: how do individuals learn and sustain their position within it? In humans, as in many social animals, stable hierarchies are not solely imposed through violence or ritual, but emerge through repetition, anticipation, and feedback-hallmarks of interactive learning. This section explores how game-theoretic models, particularly repeated games and the celebrated strategy of Tit-for-Tat, shed light on the affective learning mechanisms behind obedience and subordination.</p><p>In classical game theory, the Prisoner's Dilemma presents a dilemma of cooperation under uncertainty. When repeated over time, it reveals how mutual adjustment and trust can arise, even in the absence of central enforcement. In his foundational work, Robert Axelrod demonstrated that the simple strategy of Tit-for-Tat-start by cooperating, then repeat whatever your partner did in the last round-outperformed more complex competitors across multiple computer tournaments <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Axelrod, 1984)</ref>. Its success lay in four properties: it was nice, retaliatory, forgiving, and clear.</p><p>Applied to hierarchy, Tit-for-Tat suggests that individuals test and adjust their behavior in relation to the expected responses of others. A subordinate may challenge a superior, observe the outcome (punishment, indifference, reward), and recalibrate future behavior accordingly. Over time, a pattern emerges that is functionally equivalent to obedience, even if no single command is issued. The result is a dynamic equilibrium of alignment, stabilized by memory and anticipation-a condition highly compatible with telotopic organization.</p><p>One crucial factor in this process is what Axelrod called the "shadow of the future": the longer the expected interaction, the more incentive there is to avoid betrayal and favor stable coordination. In hierarchical settings, this means that obedience is not just a response to a command, but an investment in relational predictability. The subordinate aligns affectively not because they are coerced, but because the cost of disalignment increases over time, both emotionally (shame, guilt, loss of trust) and structurally (isolation, demotion, retaliation).</p><p>In parallel, evolutionary game theory introduces the concept of costly signaling, whereby obedience or loyalty functions as a signal of allegiance precisely because it is costly-emotionally, socially, or materially. Acts of obedience thus become affective commitments: they stabilize a subject's position by signaling reliability, even at personal expense. The affective charge of such signals (e.g., submission, sacrifice, silence) reinforces the telos of the hierarchy, often without explicit deliberation.</p><p>In this light, hierarchical positioning can be understood as an emergent property of affective feedback loops, shaped by anticipation, mimicry, and emotional inertia. The resulting patterns are neither purely rational nor strictly habitual: they reflect telotopic convergence, where obedience maximizes emotional coherence over time. The model of telotopic negentropy formalizes this convergence as a vectorial alignment toward a situational attractor-the command, the leader, or the role expected to be fulfilled.</p><p>Thus, the repetition of interaction-structured by memory and felt consequence-lays the groundwork for the internalization of subordination. What begins as a pragmatic adjustment becomes an ethopraxic orientation, stabilized by affect and difficult to unravel without significant emotional or symbolic rupture. In the next section, we will formalize this intuition by introducing a mathematical model of affective forces oriented toward hierarchical teloi, and show how the stability of obedience can be quantified as a function of emotional alignment and directional coherence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Telotopic Negentropy as a Quantifier of Affective Hierarchy</head><p>To understand obedience not merely as behavioral compliance but as a form of affective coherence, we must formalize how emotions participate in the structuring of interaction. The telotopic model of negentropy provides such a framework, allowing us to measure how obedience emerges from the dynamic alignment of affective forces toward a shared directional goal or telos.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Affective Forces and Vectorial Structure</head><p>In this model, each agent's emotional disposition in a given context is represented by a set of affective vectors:</p><p>• Conative forces ( ⃗ ) : approach-oriented motivations (e.g., loyalty, admiration, desire to please).</p><p>• Inhibitory forces ( ⃗ ) : avoidance-oriented motivations (e.g., fear, shame, doubt, resentment).</p><p>Each vector is defined by two parameters:</p><p>• Intensity ( ∈ [0,1]) -representing the strength of the emotion.</p><p>• Orientation ( ∈ [0 ∘ , 180 ∘ ]) -indicating the direction of the emotional force relative to the telos of the interaction (e.g., a command to be followed).</p><p>These vectors are projected within a field of affective interaction, wherein the telos acts as an emotional attractor. The degree to which all forces align toward this telos determines the degree of telotopic negentropy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Defining Telotopic Negentropy</head><p>We define telotopic negentropy ( tel ) (Kleden, Affective Forces and the Structure of Interaction: A Telotopic Model of Negentropic Organization, 2025) as a function of:</p><p>• the angular dispersion between affective vectors and the telos;</p><p>• the balance between conative and inhibitory forces;</p><p>• and a primacy coefficient ( ) accounting for the dominant weight of emotionally salient vectors.</p><p>The simplified version of the equation is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">tel = ⋅ ∑ =1 ( ⋅ cos( − telos ))</formula><p>Where:</p><p>• is the intensity of the -th vector,</p><p>• is its direction,</p><p>• telos is the angular position of the goal, • and modulates the impact of strong emotions (typically &gt; 1 for affective dominance).</p><p>A high tel indicates a coherent alignment of emotional energies toward the command or role expectation. A low or negative value reflects divergence, ambivalence, or latent conflict within the emotional field.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Obedience as Convergent Emotional Geometry</head><p>In this framework, obedience is understood as the maximization of telotopic negentropy: a state where the emotional forces within an individual are not only strong, but directionally aligned toward the telos of a hierarchical interaction. Conversely, resistance, hesitation, or passive defection emerge from vectorial divergence, where inhibitory forces counteract the trajectory of conative alignment.</p><p>This formulation allows for distinctions between:</p><p>• affectively coherent obedience (high tel , low internal tension),</p><p>• obedience under constraint (high conative force, but misaligned inhibitory vectors),</p><p>• latent disobedience (inhibitory dominance with weak or misaligned conative components). Furthermore, the model accounts for emotional inertia: past alignments contribute to future expectations through memorized vector configurations known as mémotions-defined as affectively charged memory units that store emotionally salient experiences with medium-term inertia. Mémotions influence conative and inhibitory vectors during new interactions, reinforcing obedience over time if coherence is maintained.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Applications to Hierarchical Systems</head><p>In real-world structures-military units, corporate teams, political organizations-the telotopic alignment metric offers a quantitative metaphor for institutional cohesion:</p><p>• High tel indicates a group emotionally mobilized toward a shared command structure.</p><p>• Fluctuations in tel can anticipate breakdowns in discipline, ideological fragmentation, or the emergence of counter-hierarchies.</p><p>In the next section, we will illustrate this dynamic by modeling a simplified dyadic interaction between a superior and a subordinate, across two stages: one where affective vectors are divergent, and one where alignment is progressively achieved. This simulation will show how obedience can be visualized not as a binary outcome, but as a dynamic process of emotional realignment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Theoretical Simulation: Modeling Obedience in a Dyadic Interaction</head><p>To concretize the telotopic model of obedience, we simulate a dyadic interaction between two agents: a commander (Agent A) and a subordinate (Agent B). The goal is to observe how affective forces evolve over time and how obedience corresponds to changes in telotopic negentropy.</p><p>We explore two contrasting scenarios:</p><p>• Case I: Initial misalignment -latent conflict and affective divergence.</p><p>• Case II: Progressive realignment -affective convergence toward the telos.</p><p>Each case unfolds in two phases, with emotional vectors assigned to Agent B at each phase. The telos in both cases is represented by the explicit command issued by Agent A (e.g., "Execute task X").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Case I -Subordination Without Alignment Phase 1: Conflictual Tension</head><p>Agent is emotionally ambivalent. While they feel obliged to obey (due to institutional expectation), they also harbor resentment or fear.</p><p>• Conative vector:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">⃗ = (0.6, 40 ∘ )</formula><p>• Inhibitory vector:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">⃗ = (0.5, 200 ∘ )</formula><p>• Telos (command vector):</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">telos = 0 ∘</formula><p>The telotopic negentropy is calculated as: • ⃗ = (0.4, 90 ∘ ) tel (1) = 1.2 ⋅ (0.7 ⋅ cos(10 ∘ ) + 0.4 ⋅ cos(90 ∘ )) = 1.2 ⋅ (0.689 + 0) = 0.827</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">tel (1) = ⋅ [0.6 ⋅ cos(40 ∘ − 0 ∘ ) + 0.5 ⋅ cos(200 ∘ − 0 ∘ )] tel<label>(</label></formula><p>The subordinate is nearly aligned, with minimal emotional friction.</p><p>Phase 2: Full emotional convergence</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">• ⃗ = (0.8, 0 ∘ ) • ⃗ = (0.2, 180 ∘ ) tel (2) = 1.2 ⋅ (0.8 ⋅ 1 + 0.2 ⋅ (−1)) = 1.2 ⋅ (0.8 − 0.2) = 0.72</formula><p>Here, even though the inhibitory vector is opposed to the telos, its low intensity makes the overall alignment stable and coherent.  This table summarizes the values of tel calculated for each phase of the simulated interactions. It highlights the affective dynamics underlying obedience, from emotional conflict to stable alignment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Comparative Interpretation</head><p>This simulation illustrates that obedience is not binary, but rather a graded process of affective convergence. High negentropy signals not only behavioral compliance, but emotional readiness and motivational integration. Inversely, obedience under low or negative tel entails emotional cost, and may forecast eventual disengagement, passive resistance, or breakdown in hierarchical legitimacy.</p><p>To illustrate this dynamic in a real-world context, we can consider the Burger partial replication of Milgram's experiment <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Burger, 2009)</ref>. In Burger's version, participants were asked to administer increasingly intense electric shocks to a confederate, but the procedure was ethically modified to stop at 150 volts. While a majority still obeyed the command to continue, post-experiment interviews revealed varying degrees of emotional tension and moral discomfort.</p><p>Using the telotopic model, we can interpret these variations as differences in affective vector configurations. Participants who showed high obedience but expressed emotional distress likely had strong conative vectors (e.g., desire to comply with authority), but inhibitory vectors misaligned with the telos (e.g., moral aversion, fear of harming others). This would yield a moderate or low tel , indicating formal compliance but internal misalignment.</p><p>In contrast, a minority of participants who disobeyed early may have exhibited low conative intensity toward the experimental authority, combined with strong inhibitory vectors rooted in personal values or prior mémotions of injustice-resulting in a sharply negative tel that predicted early divergence from the command structure.</p><p>These patterns support the model's central claim: that obedience is not simply a matter of submission, but a function of affective geometry-and that emotional alignment can be quantitatively and qualitatively distinguished from behavioral output.</p><p>A second example can be drawn from the professional context of middle management, where employees are expected to execute directives that may conflict with internal values. Consider an employee instructed to terminate a long-time subcontractor for cost-efficiency reasons. While the directive is clear, the emotional configuration may be complex:</p><p>• Conative vector: high (loyalty to the company, desire to meet expectations);</p><p>• Inhibitory vector: moderate to strong (moral discomfort, empathic bond with the subcontractor);</p><p>• Telos: organizational efficiency and budget control.</p><p>In this scenario, the telotopic negentropy might remain positive but low, reflecting a form of obedience that is strategically aligned but emotionally costly. Over time, the repetition of such misaligned decisions may degrade internal coherence, leading to burnout, disengagement, or passive resistance-phenomena widely reported in studies of emotional labor and corporate conformity.</p><p>From a telotopic perspective, this illustrates how affective misalignment accumulates entropy, even in the absence of open dissent. It also highlights the potential of this model for detecting latent organizational dysfunction, by mapping not just task performance but emotional congruence with institutional teloi. This diagram illustrates the affective configuration of an employee executing a directive that conflicts with personal ethical concerns. The green arrow (Conative Force) represents alignment with the organizational telos (budget control), while the red arrow (Inhibitory Force) captures internal resistance (moral discomfort, empathic tension). The dashed black line indicates the direction of the telos (0°).</p><p>Despite behavioral compliance, the angular divergence between conative and inhibitory forces suggests low telotopic negentropy, indicating emotional misalignment. Repeated exposure to such configurations may contribute to burnout or passive disengagement.</p><p>In the next section, we will consider how this model illuminates broader political and ideological structures, including charismatic authority, symbolic obedience, and reversed hierarchies, through the lens of telotopic affective structuration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Discussion: From Biological Subordination to Political Ideology</head><p>The transition from animal hierarchy to human obedience does not merely involve increased cognitive sophistication. It marks a fundamental shift from external dominance to internalized normativity, where the stabilization of social order depends less on physical constraint than on affective coherence and symbolic legitimacy. In this section, we expand the telotopic model to explore how affective alignment supports not only momentary compliance but the formation of enduring political ideologies, systems of belief that justify obedience even in the absence of force.</p><p>As theorized by Julien Freund, the command-obedience relationship is not a peripheral function of the political-it is its very precondition. All political structures, whether authoritarian or democratic, presuppose mechanisms of asymmetry that make collective coordination possible. What varies is the affective and symbolic encoding of that asymmetry.</p><p>In the classical psychological tradition, obedience has often been interpreted through the lens of situational authority and submission, notably in Milgram's experiments on destructive obedience. However, recent research ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Burger, 2009)</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Reicher &amp; Haslam, 2020)</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Perry, 2013)</ref>) has challenged the simplicity of this narrative, emphasizing the roles of identification, belief alignment, and the moral framing of obedience. These findings suggest that obedience is not merely a passive act but a motivated response to perceived legitimacy and shared goals.</p><p>The telotopic model builds on this shift. It provides a formal framework to express how emotional alignment, rather than constraint, can drive stable obedience. Unlike the binary logic of submission or defiance, the telotopic approach accounts for graded convergence, measuring how affective vectors orient toward a telos through conative or inhibitory tension. This emotional structuration offers a complement to existing models, especially in contexts where authority is ambiguous, contested, or emergent.</p><p>The telotopic model sheds light on this process. When obedience is aligned with the individual's affective field-that is, when emotional vectors are coherently oriented toward a shared telos-it generates what the model defines as telotopic negentropy: a stable configuration of directional emotional coherence. This is the case in contexts of charismatic leadership, ideological cohesion, or moral consensus, where the command issued resonates deeply with internalized values (axiotypes: cf. in <ref type="bibr">(Kleden, Beyond Rational Choice : Modeling Political Behavior Through Axiological Distance and Emotional Dynamics, 2025)</ref> and stored mémotions. Obedience in such cases is experienced as dignified alignment, not subjugation.</p><p>By contrast, when affective vectors are misaligned-for example, when individuals obey out of fear, shame, or pragmatic resignation-telotopic negentropy is low, and the system is more fragile. The appearance of obedience masks an underlying tension, detectable in shifts in language, posture, withdrawal, or sarcasm. Such configurations are energy-expensive, often requiring surveillance, incentive structures, or ideological overcompensation to maintain apparent stability. Moreover, the model allows us to understand reversed hierarchies, where traditional power dynamics are subverted. As discussed in Appendix A, affective alignment can occur even when the nominal superior voluntarily relinquishes authority to the previously subordinate-as in egalitarian rituals, leaderless movements, or servant-leadership paradigms. In these cases, a new telos emerges, one organized around values such as justice, reparation, or shared vulnerability. The resulting obedience is not "obedience to power" but obedience to coherence-a deeper form of legitimacy grounded in emotional convergence.</p><p>This framework also accounts for ideological consolidation. Political ideologies often function as affective telescopes: they provide a directional focus for otherwise diffuse emotions, aligning conative and inhibitory forces toward symbolic figures (leaders, laws, flags) or imagined futures (utopias, national destinies). When this alignment is sustained, a telotopic field emerges that reinforces obedience as a moral act, not merely a strategic one. This explains the affective fervor of totalitarian regimes as well as the resilient loyalties observed in some democratic systems. Finally, the model reframes resistance and dissent not as anomalies but as reorientations of the affective field. When an individual or group ceases to perceive the telos as legitimate, their emotional vectors rotate, often rapidly and collectively. This shift decreases negentropy and opens the system to realignment, rupture, or revolution.</p><p>In sum, the telotopic model offers a unified way to interpret political obedience, not as a function of coercion or rational agreement, but as the emergent property of affective geometry. It locates the source of political legitimacy not only in institutions, but in the orientation and coherence of collective emotional forces.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Limitations and Future Work</head><p>While the telotopic model provides a novel conceptual framework for understanding obedience as a form of affective alignment, several limitations must be acknowledged-both to preserve theoretical integrity and to guide future refinements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.1">Conceptual Boundaries</head><p>First, the model presupposes the existence of a shared telos, or at least a dominant telos perceived by the agents involved in an interaction. However, in real-world political or organizational contexts, teloi are often ambiguous, plural, or contested. Obedience may be directed not toward a single telos but toward conflicting symbolic orders-e.g., tradition versus innovation, loyalty versus justice. The current model does not yet account for poly-telotopic dynamics, where multiple teloi compete for affective alignment within the same system.</p><p>Second, although the model benefits from its structural abstraction (vectors, angles, intensities), this abstraction risks obscuring the semantic dimension of obedience-namely, how obedience is interpreted, narrated, or contested by agents themselves. Future iterations may need to integrate narrative framing, symbolic capital, or rhetorical strategies as complementary mechanisms to affective geometry.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.2">Methodological Constraints</head><p>The measurement of telotopic negentropy remains theoretical. While the equations are internally consistent, they rely on the assignment of affective vectors (Fc and Fi) based on qualitative interpretations of emotional states. Without a structured protocol, the model cannot yet be implemented as a predictive or diagnostic tool.</p><p>To address this, we propose an experimental design combining real-time emotional tracking with telotopic vector assignment. Participants would be exposed to simulated hierarchical interactions-e.g., roleplay of command scenarios or leadership instructions-with continuous measurement of affective responses through facial expression analysis, voice modulation, and galvanic skin response. Post-task debriefings would assess subjective motivation and internal conflict, enabling the assignment of vectorial parameters ( , ) to conative and inhibitory forces.</p><p>The key hypothesis is that highly aligned participants (high tel ) will report greater clarity, agency, and satisfaction, while misaligned ones (low or negative tel ) will exhibit ambivalence, hesitation, or negative emotional residue. Additionally, hormonal markers (e.g., cortisol or oxytocin levels) may serve as biological correlates of affective orientation, supporting the neuroendocrine mapping suggested in Appendix A.</p><p>While still exploratory, such a protocol would offer an empirical basis for testing the predictive validity of telotopic alignment, and open a new avenue for the operationalization of affective geometry in social behavior.</p><p>Moreover, the distinction between intentional obedience and automatic emotional convergence may require tighter calibration. As Daniel Kahneman's work <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Kahneman, 2012)</ref> on dual-process cognition has shown, affective alignment can occur through system 1 pathways (fast, intuitive, unconscious), making it difficult to distinguish between obedience and affective entrainment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.3">Scope of Applicability</head><p>The telotopic model has been illustrated in dyadic or small-group interactions, but it has yet to be stresstested in complex social systems, such as bureaucracies, mass movements, or digital swarms. The model assumes a bounded affective field, but larger systems may involve multiple layers of mediation, delayed feedback, or artificial amplifiers (e.g., algorithms, propaganda, ritual broadcasts).</p><p>Future work should explore how network topology, information flow, and memetic resonance interact with telotopic dynamics. Can obedience be understood as a function of collective emotional fields? Can ruptures in alignment predict the emergence of dissent or institutional collapse?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Directions for Further Research</head><p>• Empirical Calibration: Development of experimental protocols for assigning vectorial values to emotional states in real-time group dynamics.</p><p>• Simulation Modeling: Implementation of telotopic dynamics in agent-based simulations to study convergence, drift, and rupture.</p><p>• Cultural Variation: Cross-cultural analysis of telotopic fields-are there culturally-specific configurations of conative alignment?</p><p>• Political Pathologies: Application of the model to analyze authoritarian drift, populist fervor, or ritualized subjugation (e.g., in military or theocratic regimes).</p><p>• Artificial Obedience: Extension of the model to human-machine interaction, particularly in robotics and AI ethics, where synthetic agents are designed to obey under simulated affective architectures.</p><p>By acknowledging these limitations, the telotopic model remains open, falsifiable, and extensible. Its value lies not in its finality but in its capacity to reorganize the question of obedience-away from binaries of freedom and submission, and toward a richer understanding of emotional coherence as a vector of collective action.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Conclusion</head><p>Obedience is too often reduced to a question of power, ideology, or fear. While each of these dimensions contributes to its manifestation, they fail to fully capture its emotional and structural dynamics. This article has proposed a shift in perspective: to understand obedience not merely as a behavioral response or an institutional mechanism, but as the vectorial alignment of affective forces within a dynamic social field.</p><p>Drawing on ethology, game theory, sociology, and neuroendocrinology, we have argued that the command-obedience relationship emerges from a process of telotopic organization, in which conative and inhibitory emotions orient themselves toward a situational telos. When this alignment is coherent, it generates a measurable reduction in affective dispersion, formalized as telotopic negentropy.</p><p>From the primal pecking order to modern institutions, from symbolic violence to mimetic convergence, obedience takes shape not only through constraint or calculation, but through a felt emotional geometry of belonging, legitimacy, and coherence. When affective alignment toward the telos is strong, obedience is experienced as meaningful. When this alignment deteriorates, it becomes hollow, mechanized, or contested-signs that the telotopic field has fractured.</p><p>This model does not seek to moralize obedience or justify hierarchy. It aims instead to explain why we obey when we do, and why we resist when we must-not solely in terms of will, but in terms of affective structure. In doing so, it invites a reevaluation of political legitimacy, social cohesion, and institutional failure-not as crises of rationality, but as ruptures in emotional convergence.</p><p>The telotopic approach to obedience reformulates our understanding of power-not as the capacity to impose, but as the capacity to attract alignment, to stabilize affective fields, and to maintain directionality in complexity.</p><p>In an age of ideological polarization, institutional erosion, and artificial authority, understanding the way in which emotions organize obedience may be one of the most consequential questions for social theory-and more specifically, within the framework of what we propose to call political homeostasis: that is, an emergent stability grounded in affective coherence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10">Glossary</head><p>Affect : An emotional process influencing perception and decision-making, represented as a vector in the telotopic model.</p><p>Affective Force : An emotionally driven activation oriented toward a telos. It is conative ( ⃗ ) when it supports the telos, or inhibitory ( ⃗ ) when it opposes it.</p><p>Affective Vector : A mathematical representation of an emotion, defined by its intensity ( , from 0 to 1 ) and orientation ( , angle relative to the telos).</p><p>Axiotype : A stable set of affective and ideological values stored in long-term memory. It shapes affective responses and underpins emotional alignment with perceived teloi.</p><p>Directional Coherence : The degree to which affective vectors converge toward a shared telos, typically measured through angular projection and used to quantify alignment.</p><p>Ethopraxy : A process linking ethos (deep-seated affective dispositions) and praxis (socially enacted behavior), through which conduct is stabilized by emotionally reinforced social patterns. Ethopraxic behavior does not result from rational deliberation or instinct alone, but from the internalization of affective norms corresponding to the system of dispositions called the axiotype-a stable, long-term configuration of values and emotional orientations. Ethopraxy serves as the interface between axiotypic structure and social expression. It does not alter the axiotype itself, but modulates its influence in response to situational cues. In the telotopic model, ethopraxy functions as a low-inertia regulatory mechanism, enabling rapid and fluid behavioral adaptation to the affective configuration of a social field, while preserving coherence with the individual's underlying axiotype. By organizing affective forces around socially validated patterns of behavior, ethopraxy supports the stabilization of hierarchy, normative conformity, and affective legitimacy-without the need for explicit enforcement.</p><p>Mémotion : A transient emotional imprint that bridges memory and motivational activation. It shapes context-sensitive affective decisions and contributes to the dynamic regulation of obedience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Telos (τ) :</head><p>A term from ancient Greek meaning "end," "goal," or "purpose." In general terms, a telos refers to an objective toward which a being or system is oriented. In the telotopic model, the telos is defined as an emotionally salient goal that acts as an affective attractor within an interactional field. It organizes the orientation of conative and inhibitory forces by aligning them toward a direction perceived as socially or subjectively legitimate. The telos may be explicit (e.g., a command or norm) or implicit (e.g., a shared expectation or diffuse objective), and it serves as the dynamic reference point for the computation of telotopic negentropy ( tel ).</p><p>Telotopic Negentropy ( tel ) : A measure of affective coherence toward a telos, calculated through the vectorial alignment of conative and inhibitory forces. Its value typically ranges from -1 (complete misalignment) to +1 (full coherence).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Telotopy :</head><p>The directional organization of affective forces within an interactional field, reflecting context-specific emotional mobilization around a telos.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11">Appendix A -Affective Angles, Emotional States, and Hormonal Cocktails</head><p>This annex presents a conceptual framework linking affective vector orientation (in degrees), emotionalcognitive experience, and the hormonal profiles likely to be mobilized in each configuration. It builds upon the principles developed in appetition and aversion <ref type="bibr">(Kleden, Appétition et aversion, 2021)</ref>, and in the broader theory of natural affective structuring.</p><p>The angles correspond to the directional projection of affective forces in the telotopic model. Each angular sector is associated with a dominant affective stance and a neurohormonal signature shaping the subject's conative orientation. Note: These associations reflect a theoretical mapping between affective geometry and endocrine response. They are not fixed but represent probabilistic tendencies based on current neuropsychological research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Angle</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Underlying Principles</head><p>• The telotopic angle reflects the alignment or divergence of a given affective force with the situational telos (defined at 0 ∘ ).</p><p>• Hormonal cocktails modulate emotional salience, decision latency, and action readiness (e.g., approach vs. avoidance).</p><p>• The more aligned the emotional vector is with the telos, the more efficient and energetically coherent the behavioral activation.</p><p>• Divergence increases neuroendocrine tension, potentially leading to conflictual decisionmaking or behavioral blockage.</p><p>This table is consistent with the axiotype-sensitive modulation of affect introduced in axiodynamic theory, in which hormonal signatures act as biological mediators of mémotions and ethopraxic regulation. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">1)</ref> ≈ ⋅ (0.459 − 0.469) = ⋅ (−0.01) With = 1.2, this yields a slightly negative negentropy, indicating affective disharmony despite formal obedience.Phase 2: Resignation or passive complianceInhibitory forces reduce slightly (habitual inhibition), but directional misalignment remains:Negentropy increases, but remains moderate, suggesting a compliant but emotionally ambivalent obedience.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Telotopic Negentropy and Affective Interpretation Across Cases.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Affective Vector Field -Managerial Compliance.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 1 . 9 Figure 2 .</head><label>192</label><figDesc>Telotopic Negentropy and Affective Interpretation Across Cases. .......................................... Affective Vector Field -Managerial Compliance. ................................................................ 10</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Terms marked in italics are defined in the glossary at the end of the article.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Evolution of Cooperation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Axelrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<publisher>Basic Books</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Langage et pouvoir symbolique</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bourdieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<publisher>Fayard</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Brillouin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Science and Information Theory</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2 ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Replicating Milgram: Would People Still Obey Today?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Burger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0010932</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Crowds and Power</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Canetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
			<publisher>Claassen Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hamburg</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Chimpanzee Politics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>De Waal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Johns Hopkins University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Baltimore</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Foucault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Surveiller et punir. Paris: Gallimard</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">L&apos;essence du politique</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<publisher>Dalloz</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Thinking, Fast and Slow</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<pubPlace>London: Penguin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Appétition et aversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kleden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">L&apos;Harmattan</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Paris</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affective Forces and the Structure of Interaction: A Telotopic Model of Negentropic Organization. Affective Forces and the Structure of Interaction: A Telotopic Model of Negentropic Organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kleden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/yef36_v1</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PsyArXiv</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Beyond Rational Choice : Modeling Political Behavior Through Axiological Distance and Emotional Dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kleden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/uex4f</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/uex4f" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025" />
			<pubPlace>Paris, France</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>04 08)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">La Méthode (Vols. 1-5)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Morin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
			<publisher>Éditions du Seuil</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Behind the Shock Machine: The Untold Story of the Notorious Milgram Psychology Experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Perry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>The New Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking the Psychology of Tyranny: The Role of Disobedience and Resistance in the Milgram Paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Reicher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Haslam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691619878251</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="40" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Strategy of Conflict</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schelling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beiträge zur Sozialpsychologie des Haushuhns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schjelderup-Ebbe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Zeitschrift für Psychologie</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="1921" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Économie et société. 1 : les catégories de la sociologie</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Plon</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Économie et société. 2 : L&apos;organisation et les puissances de la société dans leur rapport avec l&apos;économie</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Plon</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affective Neuroscience and Social Hierarchies: A New Framework for Studying Obedience and Power</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Wiese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hofmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17470919.2021.1877224</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="229" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrating Empathy and Interpersonal Emotion Regulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev-psych-010419-050830</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="540" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction: From Pecking Orders to Emotional Structure</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>2 2 Ethology and the Structural Necessity of Hierarchy</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">From Physical Aggression to Symbolic Submission</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tit-for-Tat and the Internalization of Hierarchical Positioning</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Repeated Games</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Telotopic Negentropy as a Quantifier of Affective Hierarchy</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Affective</forename><surname>Forces</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">............................................................................ 6</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Vectorial Structure</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">............................................................................ 6</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="middle">. .</forename><surname>Defining Telotopic Negentropy</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">........................................................................................... 6</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Applications</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">................................................................................. 7</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="middle">. .</forename><surname>Systems</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">................................................................................. 7</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Theoretical Simulation: Modeling Obedience in a Dyadic Interaction</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I -</forename><surname>Case</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">Subordination Without Alignment ............................................................................. 8</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ii -Affective Realignment</forename><surname>Case</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">..................................................... 9</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Toward The Command</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">..................................................... 9</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discussion: From Biological Subordination to Political Ideology</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Future</forename><surname>Limitations</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">.................................................................................................... 14 8.1</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="middle">. .</forename><surname>Work</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">.................................................................................................... 14 8.1</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Conceptual</forename><forename type="middle">. . .</forename><surname>Boundaries</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">................................................................................................... 14</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="middle">. . .</forename><surname>Methodological Constraints</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">............................................................................................ 14</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="middle">. .</forename><surname>Scope Of Applicability</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">...................................................................................................... 14</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="middle">. . . . .</forename><surname>Conclusion</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">.......................................................................................................................... 16</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="middle">. . . . .</forename><surname>Glossary</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">.......................................................................................................................... 17</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
