<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Expertise Determines the Frequency and Accuracy of Contributions in Sequential Collaboration</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maren</forename><surname>Mayer</surname></persName>
							<email>maren.mayer@iwm-tuebingen.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Leibniz-Institut für Wissensmedien (Knowledge Media Research Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tübingen</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Heidelberg Academy of Sciences and Humanities</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Leibniz-Institut für Wissensmedien (Knowledge Media Research Center)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tübingen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcel</forename><surname>Broß</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Marburg</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Heck</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Marburg</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Marburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Marburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Schleichstraße 6</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>72076</postCode>
									<settlement>Tübingen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Expertise Determines the Frequency and Accuracy of Contributions in Sequential Collaboration</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:52+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Maren Mayer: Conceptualization, Investigation, Methodology, Formal Analysis, Writing -Original Draft, Writing -Review &amp; Editing</term>
					<term>Marcel Broß: Conceptualization, Investigation, Writing -Review &amp; Editing</term>
					<term>Daniel W. Heck: Conceptualization, Methodology, Formal Analysis, Writing -Review &amp; Editing wisdom of crowds, group decision making, mass collaboration, team work</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Many collaborative online projects such as Wikipedia and OpenStreetMap organize collaboration among their contributors sequentially. In sequential collaboration, one contributor creates an entry which is then consecutively encountered by other contributors who decide whether to adjust or maintain the presented entry. For numeric and geographical judgments, sequential collaboration yields improved judgments over the course of a sequential chain and results in accurate final estimates. We hypothesize that these benefits emerge since contributors adjust entries according to their expertise, implying that judgments of experts have a larger impact compared to those of novices. In three preregistered studies, we measured and manipulated expertise to investigate whether expertise leads to higher change probabilities and larger improvements in judgment accuracy. Moreover, we tested whether expertise results in an increase in accuracy over the course of a sequential chain. As expected, experts adjusted entries more frequently, made larger improvements, and contributed more to the final estimates of sequential chains. Overall, our findings suggest that the high accuracy of sequential collaboration is due to an implict weighting of judgments by expertise.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 4 Expertise Determines the Frequency and Accuracy of Contributions in</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sequential Collaboration</head><p>Online collaborative projects such as Wikipedia and OpenStreetMap have become increasingly important sources of information over the last two decades and are frequently used by many people. Prior research showed that Wikipedia yields highly accurate information both in general <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Giles, 2005)</ref> and for specific topics <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Kräenbring et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Leithner et al., 2010)</ref>. Also, OpenStreetMap provides geographic information with a similar accuracy as commercial map services and governmental data <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Ciepłuch et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Haklay, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Zhang &amp; Malczewski, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Zielstra &amp; Zipf, 2010)</ref>. To gather information, both Wikipedia and OpenStreetMap build on a sequential process referred to as sequential collaboration <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2022)</ref>. In this process, one contributor creates an entry which is then sequentially adjusted or maintained by the following contributors. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mayer and Heck (2022)</ref> showed that sequential collaboration represents a successful way of eliciting group judgments. In three online studies, participants either answered general-knowledge questions or located European cities on geographic maps.</p><p>Participants were randomly assigned to sequential chains of four or six contributors. Each chain started with a contributor providing an independent judgment. Next, other contributors encountered the latest version of the judgment and could then decide whether to adjust or maintain it. For instance, the first individual may start by locating Rome on a map of Italy without additional information. The second contributor may then maintain the location, whereas the third contributor may move the location more to the south. Participants were unaware of their position in the sequential chain, the change history of judgments, and how often a judgment had already been adjusted.</p><p>In the three studies by <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mayer and Heck (2022)</ref>, change probability and change magnitude decreased over the course of a sequential chain, whereas judgment accuracy improved. Observing an incremental increase in judgment accuracy over the course of a sequential chain represents a rather weak benchmark of performance since it lacks a comparison standard for the accuracy of the final judgments. As a remedy, one can also EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 5 compare the accuracy of sequential collaboration against a stronger benchmark. In fact, the studies by <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mayer and Heck (2022)</ref> provided preliminary evidence that the final judgments of sequential chains were similarly accurate, and in some cases even more accurate, than unweighted averaging, that is, computing the mean of independent individual judgments for the same number of participants. Similar results were reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Miller and Steyvers (2011)</ref> for a more complex ordering task. This is an important finding given that unweighted averaging is known to yield highly accurate estimates in various contexts and tasks, a phenomenon known as wisdom of crowds <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Hueffer et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Larrick &amp; Soll, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Steyvers et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Surowiecki, 2004)</ref>.</p><p>Even though these initial results are promising, the mechanisms contributing to the increase in accuracy of sequential judgments are still unclear. In the present paper, we investigate whether the expertise of contributors affects both the probability of adjusting a presented judgment and the accuracy of revised judgments. We hypothesize that individuals with higher expertise are better at distinguishing between presented judgments they can improve and those they cannot improve. This would lead to a systematic opt-out mechanism: experts provide new, more accurate judgments when possible, but otherwise maintain a presented judgment <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2022)</ref>. Sequential collaboration would thus facilitate an implicit weighting of judgments by expertise, in turn leading to increasingly accurate judgments over the course of a sequential chain.</p><p>In the following, we first define expertise and discuss its relevance for judgment accuracy in various contexts. Based on the literature on the role of expertise for individual judgments, we propose a theoretical framework of how individuals' expertise drives a differential opt-out mechanism that improves the accuracy of sequential judgments. We conducted three experimental studies using a city-location task and a random-dots estimation task. In each study, we either measured individuals' knowledge or manipulated their skill for the task at hand. Thereby, we examined whether expertise influences how frequently presented judgments in sequential collaboration are adjusted and how much they are improved. As expected, we found that contributors with higher EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 6 expertise adjust presented judgments more frequently and also provide larger improvements if adjustments are made. Furthermore, individuals with higher expertise have a larger impact on sequential chains than individuals with lower expertise, and this effect is more pronounced the later experts enter into the chain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Expertise in Judgment and Decision Making</head><p>Expertise is a concept for which many definitions have been proposed <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Herling, 2000)</ref>, with a focus on different facets depending on the research question of interest <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Baumann &amp; Bonner, 2013)</ref>. Typically, expertise is described as domain-specific <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Herling, 2000)</ref> and comprises task-related knowledge, skills, and abilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Schulze &amp; Krumm, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Stevens &amp; Campion, 1994)</ref>. This conceptualization is found in many research areas in judgment and decision making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kruger &amp; Dunning, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Martire et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Schunn &amp; Anderson, 1999)</ref>. In our studies on sequential collaboration, we adopt a knowledge definition of expertise in Experiment 1 and skill definition of expertise in Experiment 2. By ensuring that our conceptualization of expertise is highly task-related, it is plausible to assume a positive effect of expertise on task performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Kruger &amp; Dunning, 1999)</ref>.</p><p>Compared to novices, experts work on tasks in qualitatively different ways <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dubrovsky et al., 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Franz &amp; Larson, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Schunn &amp; Anderson, 1999)</ref> and usually show better performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Budescu &amp; Chen, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kruger &amp; Dunning, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Merkle et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Wang et al., 2021)</ref>. In group decision making, the more individuals are aware of the expertise of other group members, the more accurate group decisions become <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Baumann &amp; Bonner, 2013)</ref>. However, in such settings, it is crucial to explicitly communicate the expert status of group members before the discussion starts <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bonner et al., 2002)</ref>.</p><p>Moreover, when eliciting independent judgments from a group of individuals, weighting these judgments by expertise improves the accuracy of the aggregated estimates <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Budescu &amp; Chen, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Lin &amp; Cheng, 2009)</ref>. For this purpose, expertise can be estimated statistically based on the observed performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Merkle et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Merkle &amp; Steyvers, 2011)</ref> or measured empirically by asking participants to rate their EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 7 own, task-relevant knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Ungar et al., 2012)</ref>.</p><p>However, tasks need to have a certain level of "demonstrability" for expertise to have an impact on a group decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bonner et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Laughlin &amp; Ellis, 1986)</ref>. For a task to be demonstrable, team members completing the task need to rely on the same system of communication and require sufficient information to solve the task. Moreover, team members who cannot solve the task still need to recognize and accept a correct solution if it is proposed by others, whereas members who can solve the task need to have sufficient motivation, ability, and time to demonstrate the accuracy of their solution to others. Highly demonstrable tasks ("intellective tasks") can profit from group members' task-related expertise. In contrast, less demonstrable, highly subjective tasks ("judgmental tasks") may not profit from expertise in a similar way since forming, communicating, and recognizing a correct answer is less clear <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bonner et al., 2022)</ref>.</p><p>According to this theoretical framework, sequential collaboration requires a sufficient level of task demonstrability, and thus, we focus on intellective tasks in the following.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implicit Weighting of Judgments by Expertise</head><p>We hypothesize that sequential collaboration provides accurate outcomes because the process facilitates an implicit weighting of judgments by expertise. A weighting of judgments emerges due to the opportunity for contributors to opt out of providing a judgment. By opting out and maintaining the presented judgment, contributors assign more weight to the presented judgment <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2022)</ref>. In contrast, when opting in and adjusting a presented judgment, contributors give more weight to their own judgment compared to the presented judgment. Thus, if contributors show a differential opt-in and opt-out behavior depending on their expertise, judgments are implicitly weighted. This should in turn lead to increasingly accurate judgments over the course of a sequential chain since weighting by expertise improves aggregation of individual judgments (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Budescu &amp; Chen, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Mayer &amp; Heck, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Merkle et al., 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Such a process requires contributors to rely on task-related, metacognitive knowledge about their expertise. Metacognition describes contributors' "cognition about EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 8 cognitive phenomena" <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Flavell, 1979)</ref>. In the context of sequential collaboration, metacognitive knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Lai, 2011</ref>) about one's own expertise allows contributors to evaluate the accuracy of presented judgments and one's own capacity to provide improvements <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Kruger &amp; Dunning, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Laughlin &amp; Ellis, 1986)</ref>. Given that contributors decide whether to opt out of providing a judgment based on their metacognitive knowledge of their expertise <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bennett et al., 2018)</ref>, sequential collaboration does not require a particular mechanism for identifying experts. It is thus neither necessary to assign expert roles <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Baumann &amp; Bonner, 2013)</ref>, to directly assess individuals' expertise <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Ungar et al., 2012)</ref>, or to estimate expertise statistically <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Merkle et al., 2020)</ref>. Instead, contributors determine the weighting of judgments within sequential chains implicitly based on their metacognitive assessment of their expertise and the evaluation of the presented judgment. Achieving high accuracy only requires that some of the contributors have sufficient expertise to detect and improve inaccurate judgments by others.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Probability of Making Adjustments. Sequential collaboration requires a</head><p>two-stage response process in which contributors first decide whether to adjust a presented judgment (opt in) or whether to maintain it (opt out); only in the former case, they provide a new, revised judgment <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2022)</ref>. In the following, we derive predictions for the first stage in terms of the probability of adjusting a presented judgment. As discussed above, we expect that contributors with high expertise are better at distinguishing between presented judgments they can improve and those they cannot improve <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bennett et al., 2018)</ref>. <ref type="figure">Figure 1A</ref> illustrates our expectations of how the following two factors influence contributors' decision whether to adjust or maintain a presented judgment: First, contributors' expertise, and second, the deviation of the presented judgment from the correct answer (referred to as presented deviation in the following). Contributors high in expertise should be able to detect highly accurate judgments as being correct, and in turn refrain from adjusting such judgments. Moreover, they should be able to detect even small deviations of the presented judgment from the correct judgment and show a high probability of adjusting presented judgments that EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 9</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>Expected patterns for change probability and improvement. Note. In Panel B, a positive (negative) value of improvement indicates that a revised judgment is more (less) accuracte than the presented judgment.</p><p>differ considerably from the correct answer. In contrast, we assume that contributors with less expertise cannot reliably distinguish between presented judgments they can improve and those they cannot improve. Such contributors should show a substantial probability of (unnecessarily) adjusting already accurate judgments but a lower probability of adjusting inaccurate judgments compared to experts. Panel A of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows that the expected pattern implies an interaction, that is, a steeper slope of the change probability (as a function of the presented deviation) for contributors with higher than for those with lower expertise.</p><p>As long as contributors have sufficient task-relevant expertise, a positive relationship between presented deviation and change probability should emerge (i.e., a main effect), meaning that larger presented deviations are more likely to be detected and adjusted. Since we assume that contributors with higher expertise can detect even small EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 10 presented deviations and tend to adjust such judgments, we also expect an overall higher change probability for contributors with higher than for those with lower expertise.</p><p>However, since we expect a crossed interaction (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1)</ref>, this effect will only emerge when the range of presented deviations across items is sufficiently large.</p><p>Improvement of Presented Judgments. When deciding to adjust a presented judgment, contributors in sequential collaboration have to provide a new, revised judgment in the second stage of the response process. We assume that, similar to change probability, the amount of improvement of presented judgments also depends on the two factors expertise and presented deviation. As illustrated in Panel B of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, we expect a main effect of presented deviation, meaning that with increasing deviation, contributors improve presented judgments to a larger degree. We also expect that improvements increase with increasing expertise since contributors high in expertise can provide more accurate judgments compared to those low in expertise <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Merkle et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Ungar et al., 2012)</ref>. As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, we also assume an interaction of contributors' To test our predictions, we conducted three experiments. Experiment 1 and 2 focus on a single sequential step of sequential collaboration (i.e., at the level of individual contributions) which allows us to experimentally control the deviation of presented judgments. In contrast, Experiment 3 studies the effects of expertise and presented deviation in actual chains of sequential judgments to examine the role of contributors with varying expertise entering the sequential chain at different points.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1 Methods</head><p>In Experiment 1, we measured expertise in a city-location task and manipulated the presented deviation of judgments before letting participants decide whether to adjust or maintain location judgments with varying distances to the correct answer. To this end, we draw on the paradigm established by <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mayer and Heck (2022)</ref> to investigate sequential collaboration. In the original study, participants positioned 57 European cities on maps.</p><p>We modified the paradigm with some of these items serving as a baseline measure of individual expertise. Thereby, expertise was operationalized as knowledge acquired in the past <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Schunn &amp; Anderson, 1999)</ref>. The remaining items were used to examine how participants adjust judgments in terms of change probability and improvement. The study design, sample size, hypotheses, and planned analyses were preregistered at https://aspredicted.org/blind.php?x=JZ7_K2K. Materials, analysis scripts, and data are available at https://osf.io/z2cxv/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 290 participants who were compensated with 0.75€ for a median study duration of 9.63 minutes via a German panel provider. We excluded one participant who provided judgments that were on average more accurate than the mean accuracy of judgments found in a small test sample in which we instructed participants to look up the correct locations of each city before providing a judgment. Furthermore, we excluded 8 participants who positioned more than 10% of the cities outside the highlighted areas which marked the countries of interest. After these exclusions, the final Kingdom and Ireland, 6) Germany, and 7) Poland, Czech Republic, Hungary and Slovakia. All maps had a resolution of × 500 pixels and were scaled to 1:5,000,000.</p><p>Appendix A1 provides a list of all cities and the phase they were presented in. The 17 cities used for measuring expertise were selected based on the accuracy of independent location judgments for these cities collected in Experiment 3 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mayer and Heck (2022)</ref>.</p><p>Cities were selected to have a wide range of difficulty while ensuring that all seven European maps were represented.</p><p>In the first phase of Experiment 1, participants provided independent location judgments for the 17 cities which served as a measure of expertise. Each trial showed the instruction to place one city on the map as accurately as possible. Next, in the sequential phase, participants were instructed that each map already showed a location judgment of a previous participant and that they could decide whether to adjust or maintain the position. Again, only one of the remaining 40 cities was presented in each trial, but the map already contained a preselected location judgment. By clicking on the map, participants could adjust the presented judgment by providing a new position for the city, whereas clicking the button "continue" allowed them to maintain the presented judgment.</p><p>Participants were not provided with any additional information about the source of the judgment or the expertise of the previous contributor. were placed in the country or countries of interest colored in white. The seven maps and the corresponding cities were presented in block-randomized order (i.e., both the order of maps and of cities within maps were randomized).</p><p>Participants also provided demographic information and indicated their subjective knowledge concerning the locations of large European cities. Finally, they were debriefed and thanked for their participation.</p><p>Unknown to the participants, the locations presented in the sequential phase were Note. Each participant only saw one of the four preselected location judgments.</p><p>not provided by other participants. Instead, we manipulated the presented deviation by selecting locations with a certain Euclidean distance to the correct answer (0, 40, 80, or 120 pixels). The presented deviations were selected based on judgments obtained in <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mayer and Heck (2022)</ref> and pretested in a pilot study ensuring that participants were on average able to improve the presented distances. Moreover, in the supplementary materials (https://osf.io/z2cxv/), we show that the presented deviations correspond to plausible values from the empirical distribution of independent judgments of participants (which were collected for measuring expertise). The plots for all cities show that correct judgments as well as distances of 40, 80, or 120 pixels were inside the range of provided answers. For all 40 cities, one deviation was randomly selected such that each deviation was presented 10 times. For each map, the four levels of presented deviations were EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 15 duplicated as rarely as possible. To manipulate presented deviation, it was necessary to deceive participants about the presented locations allegedly being judgments of other participants. The study was reviewed and approved by the ethics committee of the University of Mannheim, and participants were debriefed after participation.</p><p>To ensure that participants complied to the instructions and completed the study without technical issues, the online study was accessible only for participants using a computer (but not for mobile devices). We prevented looking up correct answers by implementing a time limit of 40 seconds for each response. Moreover, we already excluded participants during participation if they left the browser tab more than five times despite repeated warnings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>We estimated participants' expertise based on the independent location judgments for the 17 cities that were shown without a previous judgment. As an operationalization of expertise, we computed the mean of the Euclidean distances between the location judgments and the correct positions for each participant. To ensure that larger values indicate higher expertise, we multiplied the average distances by −1. This measure of expertise was included as a continuous predictor in the analyses below. To assess the validity of this task-related expertise measure, we computed the correlation with the self-reported knowledge about the location of European cities. The large, positive correlation of r = 0.43 (t(279) = 7.91, p &lt; .001) indicates a satisfactory convergent validity.</p><p>We tested the effects of participants' expertise, presented deviation, and their interaction on change probability using a generalized linear mixed model. The model used a logistic link function to predict the decision whether to adjust (= 1) or maintain (= 0) a presented judgment. We standardized our expertise measure for all analyses.</p><p>Moreover, we applied a mean-centered linear contrast with values -1.5, -0.5, 0.5, and 1  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3A</ref> displays the average change probability for cities depending on participants' expertise and presented deviation. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 1 shows</ref>  However, contrary to our predictions, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3A</ref> shows that individuals with higher expertise changed correct judgments more frequently than individuals with lower expertise. The high change probability for accurate presented judgments may be due to demand effects. In fact, participants did not know that 25% of the presented judgments had a perfect accuracy. Hence, they may not have expected that optimal behavior required maintaining a substantial proportion of the presented judgments.</p><p>Next, we examined the effects of presented deviation, expertise, and their interaction on the improvement of presented judgments. As dependent variable, we computed the improvement by subtracting the accuracy of the presented judgments from that of the revised judgments. For this purpose, accuracy was defined as the Euclidean distance between a judgment and the correct position. For the presented judgments, accuracy is thus equivalent to the presented deviation (i.e., a distance of 0, 40, 80, or 120 pixels to the correct position). Positive (negative) values of the improvement measure imply that a revised judgment is more (less) accurate than the presented judgment. Since participants could decide whether to adjust or maintain presented judgments, we only Note. CI = confidence interval. All models included crossed random effects for participants and items.</p><p>The models for change probability (0 = no adjustment, 1 = adjustment) assumed a logistic link function.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 18</head><p>included trials in the analysis in which participants actually adjusted the presented judgments.</p><p>We used improvement as dependent variable in a linear mixed model with (standardized) expertise and presented deviation (linear contrast) as independent variables and added random intercepts for participants and items. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3B</ref> displays the average improvement in judgment accuracy whereas . In line with the expected pattern shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, the model also showed a significant interaction such that more knowledgeable participants showed a steeper increase in improvement than less knowledgeable participants (β = 3.819, CI = [2.930, 4.707]).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2</head><p>Experiment 1 allows only weak causal conclusions since expertise was merely measured rather than manipulated. As a remedy, we implemented a new study design in which expertise was operationalized as a skill or strategy. We manipulated the level of expertise in a random-dots estimation task <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Honda et al., 2022)</ref>   condition came up with any solution strategy themselves, which was not the case. The preliminary data were also used to calibrate the time limit per item and to define outliers.</p><p>Hypotheses, study design, sample size, and planned analyses were preregistered at https://aspredicted.org/DGV_R52. Materials, data and analysis scripts are available at https://osf.io/z2cxv/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 124 college students from the University of Marburg and a study exchange platform. Participants received course credit or the opportunity to take part in a gift-card lottery in exchange for participation. The median time to complete the study was 17.30 minutes. We excluded five participants from the analysis. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants were randomly assigned either to the expertise-manipulation condition (referred to as "experts" in the following) or the control condition ("novices").</p><p>Experts were introduced to raster scanning, a strategy for accurately estimating the number of objects on a presented image by mentally overlaying a 3 × 3 raster on top of the presented image. With the raster in mind, one can pick one of the nine areas with an approximately average number of dots and count the number of dots within this box.</p><p>Next, one simply multiplies the result by nine to obtain an estimate for the total number of dots in the image. To facilitate multiplication in one's head, we advised participants to multiply the number of dots by ten and then subtract the number of counted dots once.</p><p>Participants in the control condition only read an essay about the importance of accurate judgments. Afterwards, both groups answered four attention-check questions concerning the instructions.</p><p>As practice trials, all participants had to independently estimate the number of dots for five images. Only in the experimental condition, these five images were overlaid with a visible 3 × 3 raster to train raster scanning. Next, participants saw another set of five images, now always shown without a raster, and were again asked to provide independent judgments for the number of presented dots. The judgments in this phase served as a manipulation check. The following sequential phase was similar to the one in Experiment 1. In each trial, participants saw one of the 30 remaining images (20 test</p><p>3 Moreover, six participants in the experimental condition indicated that they did not apply the learned strategy. A robustness analysis in which we also excluded these participants led to similar results as the main analysis: For change probability, all tested effects were significant, whereas for improvement, only the v-shaped contrast for presented deviation, expertise, and their interaction were significant. Participants received no additional information about the (alleged) previous contributor.</p><p>After providing demographic information, participants in the experimental condition were asked whether they had actually used raster scanning, whereas participants in the control condition were asked whether they had used any particular strategy to estimate the number of dots. Finally, we asked whether they completed the study conscientiously and debriefed participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>We generated 30 images (600 × 600 pixels, see <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>) with white background depicting between 100 and 599 randomly-positioned, non-overlapping, colored dots using the R package ggplot2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Wickham, 2016)</ref>. Five of these images were used to train participants and five were used for the manipulation check. The remaining 20 images were shown jointly with an (alleged) judgment of the number of dots. These preselected values were either correct (deviation = 0%) or deviated by ±35% or ±70% from the correct answer. In contrast to Experiment 1, presented deviations were not randomly assigned to items but were fixed for all participants. Moreover, for motivational purposes, we also showed 10 additional images depicting only 10 to 59 dots which were displayed with a judgment that was either correct or deviated by ±20% or ±35% from the correct answer. For these items, a pilot study showed that participants in both conditions could easily detect whether the presented judgment was correct or not since the time limit allowed to simply count the small number of dots. We manipulated the deviation of EXPERTISE</p><note type="other">IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 22</note><p>presented judgments on five levels. Similar as in Experiment 1, it is thus in principle possible for participants to infer the manipulation if they knew the exact number of dots presented. However, since the deviation was not operationalized by a fixed additive error but rather by a multiplicative constant, it is unlikely that participants could detect the manipulation or acted differently than they would have when seeing actual judgments of previous participants. Moreover, the supplementary materials (https://osf.io/z2cxv/)</p><p>provides plots showing that the five levels of presented deviations fall within the empirical distribution of the independent judgments which were collected for the manipulation check.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4</head><p>Example images in the random-dots estimation taskpresented in Experiments 2 and 3.</p><p>Note. Both images show 379 dots. The left image was used in the training phase for the control condition. The right image displays the 3 × 3 raster overlaid during training in the expertise-manipulation condition. Images presented for the manipulation check and in the sequential phase resembled the left image.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>To test whether the manipulation was successful, we examined whether experts showed a higher accuracy than novices for the five items shown without a previous judgment. As a measure of accuracy, we computed the percentage error for each item, We first tested the expected patterns for change probability shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1A</ref>.</p><p>While expertise was coded with a dummy contrast (1 = expert condition, 0 = novice condition), we used two orthogonal, centered contrasts for presented deviation. Since the presented deviation includes both over-and underestimation of the correct answer, we used a centered, V-shaped contrast (values: 4, -1, -6, -1, 4) to test whether change probability is lowest for correct presented judgments but increases the more presented judgments deviate from the correct judgment. The regression coefficient of this contrast is positive for a V-shape, negative for an inverse V-shape, and zero in the absence of such an effect. Participants however may not equally often adjust over-and underestimated presented judgments. Hence, we also included a centered, linear contrast (values: 2, 1, 0, -1, -2) which tests whether the slope of the V-shaped contrast differs between these two cases. A value of zero indicates a symmetric V-shape whereas a positive (negative) coefficient indicates a steeper (less steep) slope for underestimated than for overestimated presented judgments.   <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 1</ref> shows the estimated regression coefficients. As expected, presented deviation had a significant V-shaped effect on improvement such that presented judgments were improved more the larger the deviation from the correct judgment was <ref type="bibr">(β = 6.782,</ref><ref type="bibr">CI = [6.323,</ref><ref type="bibr">7.240]</ref>). Compared to the novice condition, participants in the expert condition improved presented judgments more if there was room for improvement and also worsened correct judgments less <ref type="bibr">(β = 8.827,</ref><ref type="bibr">CI = [4.458,</ref><ref type="bibr">13.196]</ref>). Furthermore, the model showed a positive interaction between condition and the V-shaped contrast for Moreover, as outlined in the Introduction, the benefits of expertise on the accuracy of chains of sequential judgments should be especially pronounced for the final estimates.</p><p>To test these assumptions, we again relied on the random-dots estimation task using the raster-scanning strategy as a manipulation of expertise. However, we now implemented a sequential-collaboration paradigm in which participants actually encountered judgments made by previous participants <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2022)</ref>. The design allowed us to manipulate the number and position of experts and novices in a sequential chain. The hypotheses, study design, sample size, and planned analyses were preregistered at https://aspredicted.org/HZT_QW3. Materials, data, and analysis scripts can be found at https://osf.io/z2cxv/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and Procedure</head><p>We used the same experimental paradigm as in Experiment 2 while making some minor changes. In the expertise condition, we already excluded participants during participation if they did not answer at least three questions about the raster-scanning strategy correctly. Thereby, we avoided the necessity to exclude participants who subsequently contributed to the same sequential chains. We also generated five new items for the sequential-collaboration phase.</p><p>Participants were randomly assigned either to the expertise-manipulation or the control condition. We then built sequences of two participants which differed with respect to the status and order of contributors (i.e., novice-novice, expert-novice, novice-expert, and expert-expert). Similarly as in Experiment 2, the first participant in each chain saw EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 27 preselected judgments which were either correct or deviated by ±35% or ±70% from the correct number of dots. Again, the distribution of independent judgments obtained in the manipulation-check phase revealed that the manipulation for preselected judgments resembled actual judgments made by participants (see supplementary materials, https://osf.io/z2cxv/). If the first participant in a chain made an adjustment, the second participant saw the revised judgment; otherwise, the second participant merely saw the originally presented judgment. Overall, this procedure results in a mixed design with expertise and composition of dyads as between-subjects factors and presented deviation as within-subjects factor.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Using a German panel provider, we recruited 464 participants who were compensated by the panel provider for a median participation time of 18.30 minutes. We excluded one participant because they answered "1" to all items, which in turn made it necessary to remove another participant assigned to the same sequential chain. Moreover, we excluded five participants for technical reasons due to duplicate assignments to sequential chains. The final sample included 457 participants (46.80% female) with mean age of 46.16 (SD = 14.36) and heterogeneous educational background (college degree:</p><p>34.80%; high-school diploma: 26%; vocational education: 24.10%; lesser educational attainment: 15.10%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>We computed the same dependent measures as in Experiment 2. As a manipulation check, we fitted a linear mixed model to test whether the independent judgments for the five items during the manipulation-check phase were more accurate for experts than for novices. As expected, the expertise manipulation lead to a decrease in </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effects of One Step in Sequential Collaboration</head><p>Replicating the analyses of Experiment 2, we first tested the effects of presented deviation, expertise, and their interaction on change probability and improvement of presented judgments in a single sequential step. We analyzed change probabilities in the sequential phase by including only those participants who saw preselected judgments (but not those who saw the judgments of other participants). Similarly as in Experiment 2, we fitted a generalized linear mixed model to predict whether a presented judgment was changed using the same contrasts for presented deviation and condition. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 6A</ref> displays the average change probabilities in Experiment 3. As expected, the V-shaped effect of presented deviation emerged, with a steeper slope for underestimated than for overestimated judgments. In contrast to Experiment 2, the plot does not indicate a main effect of condition. These impressions were supported by the model-based analysis (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 1)</ref>   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure   6A</ref> illustrates the interaction of expertise and presented deviation on change probability.</p><p>In line with our expectations, experts adjusted presented judgments less often than novices if judgments were already correct, but more often if judgments deviated by ±70%</p><p>from the correct answer. In the mixed model, the corresponding interaction term of condition and the V-shaped contrast was significant (β = 0.075, CI = [0.040, 0.111]). As described in the Introduction, given that we predicted and found a crossed interaction (cf.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 6B</ref> displays the improvement of presented judgments which followed a V-shaped pattern, with already correct presented judgments being slightly worsened. We Moreover, the interaction between the linear slope for presented deviation and expertise was significant, indicating a steeper slope for the left than the right limb of the V-shape for experts compared to novices (β = −1.516, CI = [−2.745, −0.287]).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Robustness Analyses Using All Participants</head><p>As a robustness check, we also tested our predictions for a single sequential step Concerning the improvement of the presented judgments, results were again similar to analyzing only participants at the first chain position. We found a positive effect of the quadratic trend of deviation <ref type="bibr">(β = 12.333,</ref><ref type="bibr">CI = [11.530,</ref><ref type="bibr">13.135</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effects on Chains of Sequential Judgments</head><p>We tested the expected impact of experts at the chain level based on data of participants at the second chain position. We first fitted a generalized linear mixed model to predict whether change probability for the second contributor in a sequential chain differed between the four compositions of sequential chains (i.e., novice-novice, EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 31 expert-novice, novice-expert, or expert-expert). For this purpose, we implemented two contrasts: the first compared novice-novice chains against expert-novice chains whereas the second compared novice-expert chains against expert-expert chains. In line with our expectations, change probability was larger for experts correcting novices than for expert correcting other experts (β = 0.326, CI = [0.063, 0.588], z = 2.432, p = .015). In contrast, novices changed the entries of experts and novices similarly frequently (β = 0.136, CI = [−0.098, 0.370], z = 1.140, p = .254). These patterns are illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 7A</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 7</head><p>Change probability, improvement, and accuracy of judgments for the four compositions of sequential chains in Experiment 3. and implemented a linear mixed model with percentage improvement as dependent variable and composition of sequential chain as predictor. We additionally used Helmert contrasts to test our expectations concerning the improvement of each others' judgments by contrasting the novice-expert chain with all other chains, the expert-novice chain with the novice-novice and expert-expert chains, and, lastly, testing the novice-novice and expert-expert chains against each other. <ref type="figure">Figure 7B</ref>  judgment, the judgment entered by the first participant, or the judgment entered by the second participant. We used a linear contrast to test whether percentage error decreases, or equivalently, whether accuracy increases across chain compositions.</p><p>As expected, we found a significant linear trend between chain composition and accuracy of the final estimates <ref type="bibr">(β = 5.779,</ref><ref type="bibr">CI = [2.199,</ref><ref type="bibr">9.359]</ref>, t(216.79) = 3.164, p = .002). <ref type="figure">Figure 7C</ref> illustrates this pattern with the percentage error being largest for sequential chains with two novices and smallest for sequential chains with two experts.</p><p>Regarding mixed sequential chains which included both an expert and a novice, the percentage error was smaller when chains ended rather than started with an expert.</p><p>Overall, the more and the later experts enter sequential chains, the better the final estimates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>In three experiments, we studied when and how contributors with varying expertise adjust presented judgments in sequential collaboration. The results for individual contributions (i.e., a single sequential step) show that the probability of changing a judgment increases as the deviation to the correct answer increases and as participants' expertise increases. Most importantly, compared to novices, contributors with high expertise were better at distinguishing between accurate and inaccurate judgments as indicated by a steeper slope of the change probability. Core aspects of the predicted data pattern in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> were thus supported. However, the data did not consistently show that contributors with high expertise adjust perfectly accurate judgments less frequently than contributors with low expertise. Concerning the accuracy of revised judgments, the improvement of presented judgments increased for larger presented deviations and higher expertise in two of three experiments.</p><p>Expertise is thus an important predictor of change probability and the amount of improvement of judgments in sequential collaboration. This supports our theoretical assumption that contributors adjust and maintain judgments based on their expertise which in turn facilitates an implicit weighting of judgments. Even though this weighting EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 34 happens at the individual level within each sequential step, the increased accuracy due to overweighting judgments of contributors with higher expertise can be observed at the chain level <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2022)</ref>. The data provided evidence for an important prerequisite for such a weighting, namely, contributors with high expertise better differentiate between accurate and inaccurate judgments than contributors with low expertise. However, we found only mixed support for our prediction that contributors with high expertise have a lower change probability for perfectly accurate judgments than contributors with low expertise.</p><p>In Experiment 3, we also studied chains of two sequential judgments. As expected, experts adjusted judgments of novices more frequently than those of other experts, and experts improved judgments of novices most whereas novices tend to worsen judgments of experts. Moreover, the final estimates of sequential chains became more accurate the more and the later experts entered a sequential chain. This shows that the number of experts and the position in which they enter a sequential chain affects the accuracy of group estimates. Accurate judgments of experts at the beginning of a sequential chain may be obstructed by novices later, in turn resulting in reduced accuracy. In contrast, possibly inaccurate judgments by novices at the beginning can be corrected by experts later.</p><p>Our findings add to the literature on the wisdom of crowds, supporting the notion that weighting judgments by expertise increases accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Budescu &amp; Chen, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Mayer &amp; Heck, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Merkle et al., 2020)</ref>. In contrast to other experimental designs and statistical techniques, sequential collaboration does not require researchers to identify experts before or after the judgment task. Instead, sequential collaboration results in an implicit weighting of judgments by expertise. This is achieved by the contributors' metacognitive assessment of whether they can improve a presented judgment. Our results thus shed light into the mechanisms of why the aggregation of individual judgments in sequential collaboration results in high accuracy. Note, however, that the evidence for the high accuracy of sequential collaboration is still sparse <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Miller &amp; Steyvers, 2011)</ref>. Thus, further studies are necessary to test the robustness and performance of sequential collaboration in different tasks and populations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations and Future Research Directions</head><p>In all our experiments, we deceived participants about the source of the presented judgments. Both the presented city locations and the number of dots were not judgments of previous participants as stated in the instructions. Instead, we manipulated presented deviation experimentally by generating hypothetical judgments that closely resembled actual judgments. Even though the manipulation used only few levels of deviation, participants would require substantive knowledge about the correct answers for a considerable amount of items in order to become aware of the manipulation. Moreover, due to the design of the sequential-collaboration paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mayer &amp; Heck, 2022)</ref>, it is plausible that presented judgments were actually made by other participants previously.</p><p>This is also supported by the empirical distribution of independent judgments which were collected for measuring expertise (Experiment 1) and as a manipulation check (Experiments 2 and 3). For these items, the preselected deviations fall within the distribution of actual judgments, which provides evidence for their plausibility. In addition, a design presenting participants with authentic judgments by others was implemented in Experiment 3 in which participants formed sequential chains and encountered actual judgments of previous participants. Irrespective of the source of the presented judgments, all three studies provided converging evidence for the predicted data patterns. Overall, it thus seems unlikely that participants noticed the manipulation and acted differently towards the presented judgments than they would have when seeing actual judgments of previous participants.</p><p>We designed the tasks in our experiments to be highly demonstrable, meaning that contributors have the opportunity to demonstrate their expertise <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bonner et al., 2022)</ref>. However, demonstrability can still be low if participants are not sufficiently motivated to complete a task <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Laughlin &amp; Ellis, 1986)</ref>. If this was the case in our study, contributors with high expertise may have opted out more frequently than would be EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 36 beneficial for achieving a high accuracy. Also, contributors may have provided generally imprecise judgments and guesses to proceed more quickly. However, these appear to be minor concerns for the validity of our results. Moreover, in "natural" applied settings (e.g., online collaborative projects), the motivation of volunteers to provide demonstrable solutions should be very high.</p><p>Our studies show that expertise predicts change probability and improvement in chains of sequential judgments. However, it remains unclear whether the high accuracy of final estimates is due to the sequential-judgment process itself or due to the possibility to opt out of answering. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bennett et al. (2018)</ref> showed that merely providing an opportunity to opt out increases the accuracy of independent individual judgments. Essentially, individuals use their metacognitive knowledge to select those tasks that fit their individual expertise best. Regarding sequential collaboration, future research should thus disentangle the effects of the judgment-elicitation process (i.e., contributors building a chain of sequential judgments) and of the opportunity to opt out of providing a judgment.</p><p>Our three studies are also limited in their generalizability to online collaborative projects such as Wikipedia and OpenStreetMap since they differ in various features.</p><p>First, we examined the effect of expertise only in one sequential step of sequential collaboration and for short sequential chains of only two contributors even though sequential chains are typically much longer and complex in online collaborative projects.</p><p>Simplifying such a process into single steps is a typical approach in experimental research.</p><p>Nevertheless, we expect that the effects of expertise and deviation on change probability and improvement of judgments should similarly hold for longer sequential chains, given that participants are not aware of the number of contributors or previous judgments.</p><p>Moreover, tasks in our experiments considerably vary from tasks in online collaborative projects. Tasks in these projects are typically more judgmental and less demonstrable than providing numeric or geographical judgments with decisions on which, where, and how to include information while also providing more infrastructure for the contributions such as discussion forums and change logs. In contrast to scientific experiments, EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 37 contributors are not fully anonymous and typically volunteer for editing in these projects.</p><p>All these factors may influence whether contributors adjust or maintain Wikipedia articles or OpenStreetMap objects and how they contribute to these projects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Sequential collaboration is a key mechanism found in many large-scale, online collaborative projects. Our studies show that expertise is an important predictor of whether individuals adjust or maintain presented entries, how much they improve an entry, and how accurate the final estimates are. Thereby, we provide first evidence for the implicit-weighting of expertise in sequential collaboration, which can explain the high accuracy of online collaborative projects.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>displays the map of Italy with four preselected location judgments for Rome reflecting different distances from the correct location. All presented judgments</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Presented location judgments in Experiment for Rome with different distances to the correct position.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the estimated regression coefficients. As expected, the linear contrast of presented deviation was positive and significant (β = 0.444, CI = [0.392, 0.495]). The model also indicated a significant positive relationship between expertise and change probability (β = 0.622, CI = [0.202, 1.042]). Furthermore, we found a significant interaction between expertise and presented deviation (β = 0.218, CI = [0.165, 0.272]).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Change probability and improvement of presented judgments in Experiment 1. Points display empirical means with error bars showing the corresponding 99%between-subjects confidence intervals. Violin plots indicate the distribution of the dependent variable aggregated across items within each person. The plot for improvement only includes presented judgments that were adjusted by participants.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>images and 10 easy images for motivational purposes), each with an (alleged) judgment of a previous participant regarding the number of shown dots. They decided whether to adjust or maintain the presented judgment by clicking on respective buttons. Only if they decided to adjust the presented judgment, an open-text box appeared in which the new judgment could be entered. After indicating to maintain the judgment or providing a new judgment, participants continued to the next image. The images were shown in random order with a time limit of 60 seconds (including a warning after 40 seconds). Similar as in Experiment 1, presented judgments were not provided by previous participants but rather preselected to manipulate the deviation of presented judgments from the correct answer.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>5A illustrates the average change probability including 99% confidence intervals. Change probabilities followed the expected V-shape as a function of the presented deviation. Moreover, experts generally changed items more frequently than novices. This impression was confirmed by a significant, positive V-shaped contrast for EXPERTISEIN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION   24    presented deviation in the linear mixed model (β = 0.208, CI = [0.160, 0.256]) and a significant positive effect of condition (β = 0.570, CI = [0.169, 0.972])(Table 1).Moreover, we found a positive linear contrast indicating a smaller effect of presented deviation (i.e., a smaller slope of the V-shape) for underestimated than for overestimated judgments (β = 0.312, CI = [0.176, 0.448]). As expected, the interaction between condition and the V-shape contrast of the presented deviation was positive, meaning that experts better distinguished between accurate and inaccurate judgments (β = 0.056, CI = [−0.003, 0.114]). However, in contrast to our predictions, participants in the expert condition adjusted correct presented judgments more frequently than participants in the novice condition (Figure 5). Besides demand effects, this could be due to the raster-scanning strategy providing only an approximate estimate of the actual number of presented dots. While the approximation leads to improved judgments, it is still prone to errors. Hence, for already accurate presented judgments, participants may have adjusted the judgment even though it was already correct. Lastly, we found a significant interaction between condition and the linear contrast of presented deviation indicating that the V-shape was more symmetric (with respect to over-and underestimated judgments) for experts than for novices (β = −0.329, CI = [−0.503, −0.155]).Next, we tested whether expertise, presented deviation, and their interaction affect the improvement of presented judgment. Similar to Experiment 1, improvements were computed as the difference between the percentage errors of the presented and the revised judgment. Again, positive (negative) values indicate that presented judgments are improved (worsened). We used a linear mixed model to predict the improvement of presented judgments using the same contrasts for condition and presented deviation as in the model for change probability. Similar as in Experiment 1, we only included trials in which participants adjusted the presented judgment. 4Figure 5Bdisplays the mean</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Change probability and improvement of presented judgments for Experiment 2. Points display empirical means with error bars showing the corresponding 99% between-subjects confidence intervals. Violin plots show the distribution of the dependent variable for participants aggregated across items. The plot for improvement only includes trials in which presented judgments were adjusted by participants. improvement of presented judgments including 99% confidence intervals and violin plots;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>presented deviation(β = 0.647, CI = [0.191, 1.104]). These results are closely in line with the expected patterns derived from our theoretical framework (Figure @ref(fig: expected-patterns)).other effects were not significant). show that change probability and improvement of presented judgments depend on expertise, presented deviation, and their interaction. However, both studies implemented only a single incremental step in sequential collaboration using preselected values for the presented judgments. The same effects should hold if individuals encounter actual judgments of previous individuals rather than preselected judgments.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>showing a significant V-shaped contrast of presented deviation (β = 0.141, CI = [0.116, 0.167]), but no effect of experimental condition (β = 0.052, CI = [−0.297, 0.401]). The linear contrast of deviation was also significant, indicating a steeper slope for the left than the right limb of the V-shaped effect (β = 0.367, CI = [0.292, 0.441]). Most importantly for sequential collaboration,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 1), the absence of a main effect of expertise may simply be due to a limited range of presented deviations.Next, we tested the effect of expertise and presented deviation on the improvement of presented judgments. For this analysis, we only included participants at the first chain EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 29 Change probability, and percentage improvement of presented judgments for Experiment 3. Points display empirical means with error bars showing the corresponding 99% between-subjects confidence intervals. Violin plots show the distribution of the dependent variable for participants aggregated across items. The plot for improvement only includes trials in which presented judgments were adjusted by participants. position. 5</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>fitted a linear mixed model for the percentage improvement again using the same contrasts for condition and presented deviation. In line with our hypotheses, the modelshowed a V-shape effect of presented deviation, (β = 6.653, CI = [6.290, 7.016]), a main effect of condition, indicating more improvement of judgments provided by participants in the expertise than in the novice condition (β = 16.518, CI = [10.701, 22.336]), but no 5 Similar results were obtained when including judgments that were maintained with an improvement score of zero (V-shaped contrast of deviation: β = 4.871, CI = [4.596, 5.145], t(5, 599.39) = 34.822, p &lt; .001; linear contrast of deviation: β = 1.143, CI = [0.417, 1.870], t(5, 599.24) = 3.084, p = .002; condition: β = 12.784, CI = [7.998, 17.571], t(236.25) = 5.235, p &lt; .001; all other terms were not significant). interaction of condition and presented deviation (β = −0.024, CI = [−0.527, 0.479]).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>while including participants at both chain positions. The deviation of presented judgments thus becomes a continuous variable since participants at the second chain position may see revised judgments of participants at the first position. In the linear mixed models, we thus included the standardized deviation and the corresponding, quadratic trend as predictors. For change probability, the results were similar as when including only participants at the first chain position. The model showed a significant quadratic effect of presented deviation (β = 0.308, CI = [0.235, 0.381], z = 8.286, p &lt; .001) and, most importantly, a significant interaction with condition (β = −0.112, CI = [−0.204, −0.019], z = −2.371, p = .018). Again, the main effect of condition on change probability was not significant (β = 0.145, CI = [−0.111, 0.400], z = 1.108, p = .268).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>displays the empirical means for percentage improvement for all compositions of sequential chains. In line with this pattern, we found a significant Helmert contrast for the novice-expert sequential chain(β = 3.760, CI = [1.264, 6.256], t(215.08) = 2.952, p = .004). Furthermore, we found a significant contrast for the expert-novice chain (β = −3.852, CI = [−7.227, −0.477], t(221.47) = −2.237, p = .026). In fact,Figure 7shows that novices worsen judgments of experts. Lastly, we did not find a significant difference in improvement between expert-expert and novice-novice groups (β = −5.965, CI = [−12.137, 0.208], t(222.70) = −1.894, p = .060). Overall, these findings are in line with our expectations that experts improve judgments of novices most, novices worsen judgments of experts, and only little improvement can be found when novices correct novices and experts correct experts.Finally, we tested which composition of sequential chains lead to the most accurate estimates at the end of a sequential chain. We fitted a linear mixed model with percentage error of the final judgment in a sequential chain as dependent variable and chain composition as predictor. Depending on whether the two participants in each chain adjusted the presented judgment, the final judgment could either be the presented6 Similar results are obtained when maintained judgments are included with an improvement score of zero (β = 3.182, CI = [1.195, 5.169], t(214.61) = 3.139, p = .002 for comparing relative improvement of judgments of novice-expert chains to all other types of sequential chains, β = −2.985, CI = [−5.633, −0.336], t(214.50) = −2.209, p = .028 for comparing expert-novice chains to novice-novice and expert-expert chains, and β = −3.404, CI = [−8.161, 1.352], t(214.60) = −1.403, p = .162 for comparing expert-expert and novice-novice chains).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>sample comprised 281 participants who were on average 46.49 years old (SD = 15.33) with 48.80% of participants being female. Concerning educational background, 15.70% had a college degree, 15% held a high school diploma, 31.10% had vocational education, and 38.20% had a lesser educational attainment.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Materials</cell></row></table><note>and Procedure Participants had to locate 57 European cities on 7 different European maps, namely 1) Austria and Switzerland, 2) France, 3) Italy, 4) Spain and Portugal, 5) United EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 13</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>5for the four levels of deviation between presented and correct locations. Standardizing the expertise measure and applying a mean-centered contrast to the presented deviations EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 16 allows us to interpret the additive terms in the model as main effects and the multiplicative term as interaction. The model accounts for the nested data structure by including random intercepts for items and participants(Pinheiro &amp; Bates, 2000). 1</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fixed-effects coefficients of the fitted (generalized) linear mixed models.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Independent Variable</cell><cell>β</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell cols="2">95% CI</cell><cell>p</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>LL</cell><cell>UL</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Dependent variable: Change probability</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation</cell><cell cols="2">0.444 0.026</cell><cell>0.392</cell><cell cols="2">0.495 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment 1</cell><cell>Expertise</cell><cell cols="2">0.622 0.214</cell><cell>0.202</cell><cell>1.042</cell><cell>.004</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation × expertise</cell><cell cols="2">0.218 0.027</cell><cell>0.165</cell><cell cols="2">0.272 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (V-shaped contrast)</cell><cell cols="2">0.208 0.024</cell><cell>0.160</cell><cell cols="2">0.256 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (linear contrast)</cell><cell cols="2">0.312 0.069</cell><cell>0.176</cell><cell cols="2">0.448 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment 2</cell><cell>Expertise</cell><cell cols="2">0.570 0.205</cell><cell>0.169</cell><cell>0.972</cell><cell>.005</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (V-shape) × expertise</cell><cell cols="3">0.056 0.030 -0.003</cell><cell>0.114</cell><cell>.062</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (linear) × expertise</cell><cell cols="5">-0.329 0.089 -0.503 -0.155 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (V-shaped contrast)</cell><cell cols="2">0.141 0.013</cell><cell>0.116</cell><cell cols="2">0.167 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (linear contrast)</cell><cell cols="2">0.367 0.038</cell><cell>0.292</cell><cell cols="2">0.441 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment 3</cell><cell>Expertise</cell><cell cols="3">0.052 0.178 -0.297</cell><cell>0.401</cell><cell>.771</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (V-shape) × expertise</cell><cell cols="2">0.075 0.018</cell><cell>0.040</cell><cell cols="2">0.111 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (linear) × expertise</cell><cell cols="3">0.052 0.053 -0.051</cell><cell>0.156</cell><cell>.322</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Dependent variable: Improvement of presented judgments</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation</cell><cell cols="5">32.289 0.455 31.398 33.181 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment 1</cell><cell>Expertise</cell><cell cols="5">15.545 1.047 13.492 17.598 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation × expertise</cell><cell cols="2">3.819 0.453</cell><cell>2.930</cell><cell cols="2">4.707 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (V-shaped contrast)</cell><cell cols="2">6.782 0.234</cell><cell>6.323</cell><cell cols="2">7.240 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (linear contrast)</cell><cell cols="3">-0.593 0.579 -1.728</cell><cell>0.541</cell><cell>.315</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment 2</cell><cell>Expertise</cell><cell cols="2">8.827 2.229</cell><cell cols="3">4.458 13.196 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (V-shape) × expertise</cell><cell cols="2">0.647 0.233</cell><cell>0.191</cell><cell>1.104</cell><cell>.005</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (linear) × expertise</cell><cell cols="3">-0.069 0.546 -1.140</cell><cell>1.002</cell><cell>.899</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (V-shaped contrast)</cell><cell cols="2">6.653 0.185</cell><cell>6.290</cell><cell cols="2">7.016 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (linear contrast)</cell><cell cols="3">0.791 0.465 -0.122</cell><cell>1.703</cell><cell>.089</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment 3</cell><cell>Expertise</cell><cell cols="5">16.518 2.968 10.701 22.336 &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Presented deviation (V-shape) × expertise -0.024 0.257 -0.527</cell><cell>0.479</cell><cell>.925</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Presented deviation (linear) × expertise</cell><cell cols="4">-1.516 0.627 -2.745 -0.287</cell><cell>.016</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>shows the estimated</cell></row></table><note>CI = [13.492, 17.598])</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>in which participants had to estimate the number of randomly positioned, colored dots. Participants in the experimental group learned a strategy to provide accurate estimates for the number of presented points. Importantly for sequential collaboration, the same strategy can also be used to evaluate the accuracy of presented judgments. In contrast, participants in the control condition completed a control task and should thus have no advantage in providing and evaluating judgments. In a pilot study, we examined whether the manipulation of expertise was successful and whether participants in the control</figDesc><table /><note>2 The statistical analysis yielded similar results when including non-adjusted judgments (coded with an improvement score of zero) in the analysis (main effect of expertise: β = 12.200, CI = [10.523, 13.876], t(275.82) = 14.263, p &lt; .001; main effect of deviation: β = 21.932, CI = [21.291, 22.574], t(10, 861.76) = 66.979, p &lt; .001; interaction of expertise and deviation: β = 5.726, CI = [5.085, 6.367], t(10, 860.76) = 17.500, p &lt; .001).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>One participant did EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 20 not complete the study conscientiously, one vastly underestimated and another vastly overestimated the number of dots for most items, one almost always provided the perfectly exact number of dots, and one did not answer the attention-check questions about the instructions correctly. 3 The remaining 119 participants (69.70% female) had a mean age of 25.50 (SD = 9.94).</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 23 defined as the absolute difference between the judgment and the correct answer dividedby the correct answer and multiplied by 100. Using this measure allowed us to analyze average accuracy across items even though the number of dots varied from 100 to almost 600. Including only the independent judgments for the five items in the</figDesc><table><row><cell>manipulation-check phase, we fitted a linear mixed model with condition as independent</cell></row><row><cell>variable (dummy-coded with 1 = expert condition, 0 = novice condition). We found a</cell></row><row><cell>significant negative effect of condition on the percentage error (β = −16.214,</cell></row><row><cell>CI = [−23.645, −8.784], t(117.16) = −4.277, p &lt; .001). The effect of the manipulation of</cell></row><row><cell>expertise was large with novices showing a mean error of 35.81% and experts showing a</cell></row><row><cell>mean error of only 19.59%.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Including random slopes on items for presented deviation led to comparable results. For the sake of consistency with the models in Experiment 2 and 3, we only report the results of models which include random intercepts in Experiment 1.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Similar results were obtained when analyzing all trials while assigning an improvement score of zero to maintained judgments (condition: β = 8.659, CI = [4.804, 12.514], t(117.01) = 4.403, p &lt; .001; V-shaped contrast for presented deviation: β = 4.833, CI = [4.485, 5.181], t(39.41) = 27.225, p &lt; .001; interaction of condition and V-shaped contrast: β = 1.271, CI = [0.878, 1.663], t(2, 230.19) = 6.344, p &lt; .001; all</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head><p>Cities selected for different maps </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Member awareness of expertise, information sharing, information weighting, and group decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Baumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bonner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1046496413494415</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1046496413494415" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Small Group Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="532" to="562" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making a wiser crowd: Benefits of individual metacognitive control on crowd performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mistry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Brain &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s42113-018-0006-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s42113-018-0006-4" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of member expertise on group decision-making and performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bonner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Baumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Dalal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="719" to="736" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0749-5978(02)00010-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0749-5978(02" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="19" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The theory and measurement of expertise-based problem solving in organizational teams: Revisiting demonstrability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bonner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shannahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Coll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Meikle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/orsc.2021.1481</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.2021.1481" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organization Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1452" to="1469" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying expertise to extract the wisdom of crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Budescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="280" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.2014.1909</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1909" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparison of the accuracy of OpenStreetMap for ireland with google maps and bing maps</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ciepłuch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jacob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Winstanley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth International Symposium on Spatial Accuracy Assessment in Natural Resuorces and Enviromental Sciences 20-23rd</title>
		<meeting>the Ninth International Symposium on Spatial Accuracy Assessment in Natural Resuorces and Enviromental Sciences 20-23rd</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="340" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The equalization phenomenon: Status effects in computer-mediated and face-to-face decision-making groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dubrovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kiesler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Sethna</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15327051hci0602_2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327051hci0602_2" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognition and cognitive monitoring: A new area of cognitive-developmental inquiry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Flavell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="906" to="911" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0003-066X.34.10.906</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.34.10.906" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of experts on information sharing during group discussion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Small Group Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="411" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/104649640203300401</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/104649640203300401" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internet encyclopaedias go head to head</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Giles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/438900a</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/438900a" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">438</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="900" to="901" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How good is volunteered geographical information? A comparative study of OpenStreetMap and ordnance survey datasets. Environment and Planning B: Planning and Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Haklay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="682" to="703" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1068/b35097</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1068/b35097" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Operational definitions of expertise and competence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Herling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Developing Human Resources</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/152342230000200103</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/152342230000200103" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the round number bias and wisdom of crowds in different response formats for numerical estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Honda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shirasuna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-022-11900-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-11900-7" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wisdom of crowds: Predicting a weather and climate-related event</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hueffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fonseca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leiserowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accuracy and completeness of drug information in wikipedia: A comparison with standard textbooks of pharmacology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kräenbring</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Monzon Penza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gutmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Muehlich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Zolk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wojnowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Maas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Engelhardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sarikas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0106930</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0106930" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unskilled and unaware of it: How difficulties in recognizing one&apos;s own incompetence lead to inflated self-assessments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kruger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dunning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1121" to="1134" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Metacognition: A literature review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 40</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Pearson Research Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intuitions about combining opinions: Misappreciation of the averaging principle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Larrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Soll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.1050.0459</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.1050.0459" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="127" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demonstrability and social combination processes on mathematical intellective tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Laughlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0022-1031(86)90022-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-1031" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90022" to="90025" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wikipedia and osteosarcoma: A trustworthy patients&apos; information?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leithner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Maurer-Ertl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Glehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Friesenbichler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Leithner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Windhager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1136/jamia.2010.004507</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1136/jamia.2010.004507" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association : JAMIA</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="373" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The reliability of aggregated probability judgments obtained through cooke&apos;s classical model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/17465660910973961</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/17465660910973961" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Modelling in Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="161" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What do the experts know? Calibration, precision, and the wisdom of crowds among forensic handwriting experts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Martire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Growns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2346" to="2355" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-018-1448-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-018-1448-3" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sequential collaboration: The accuracy of dependent, incremental judgments. Decision, Advance online publication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Heck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dec0000193</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/dec0000193" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cultural consensus theory for two-dimensional location judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Heck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2022.102742</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmp.2022.102742" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102742</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beating the average forecast: Regularization based on forecaster attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Merkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Saw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Davis-Stober</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2020.102419</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmp.2020.102419" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102419</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A psychological model for aggregating EXPERTISE IN SEQUENTIAL COLLABORATION 41 judgments of magnitude</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Merkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-642-19656-0_34</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-19656-0_34" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Social computing, behavioral-cultural modeling and prediction</title>
		<editor>J. Salerno, S. J. Yang, D. Nau, &amp; S.-K. Chai</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="236" to="243" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wisdom of crowds with communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://escholarship.org/uc/item/4jt6q62c" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linear mixed-effects models: Basic concepts and examples</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mixed-effects models in S and S-PLUS</title>
		<editor>Pinheiro, J. C., &amp; Bates, D. M.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Springer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4419-0318-1_1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4419-0318-1_1" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The &quot;virtual team player&quot;: A review and initial model of knowledge, skills, abilities, and other characteristics for virtual collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schulze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Krumm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="95" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/2041386616675522</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/2041386616675522" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The generality/specificity of expertise in scientific reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Schunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="370" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15516709cog2303_3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15516709cog2303_3" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The knowledge, skill, and ability requirements for teamwork: Implications for human resource management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Campion</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="530" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/014920639402000210</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/014920639402000210" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wisdom of crowds in the recollection of order information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hemmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://proceedings.neurips.cc/paper/2009/file/4c27cea8526af8cfee3be5e183ac9605-Paper.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<editor>Y. Bengio, D. Schuurmans, J. Lafferty, C. Williams, &amp; A. Culotta</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Curran Associates, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1785" to="1793" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The wisdom of crowds (1. ed)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Surowiecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>Anchor Books</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The good judgment project: A large scale test of different methods of combining expert predictions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mellers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Satopää</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AAAI Fall Symposium Series</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forecast aggregation via peer prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing</title>
		<meeting>the AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">ggplot2: Elegant graphics for data analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wickham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://ggplot2.tidyverse.org" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accuracy evaluation of the canadian OpenStreetMap road networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Malczewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://ir.lib.uwo.ca/geographypub/347" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Geospatial and Environmental Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantitative studies on the data quality of OpenStreetMap in Germany</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Zielstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zipf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AGILE 2010. The 13th AGILE international conference on geographic information science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
