<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Stability of the Representativeness Heuristic: Further Evidence from Choices Between Lottery Tickets</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michał</forename><forename type="middle">Wiktor</forename><surname>Krawczyk</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joanna</forename><surname>Rachubik</surname></persName>
							<email>j.rachubik@uw.edu.pl</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Economic Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warsaw</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Economic Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warsaw</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>ul. Długa 44/50</addrLine>
									<postCode>00-241</postCode>
									<settlement>Warszawa</settlement>
									<country key="PL">Poland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Stability of the Representativeness Heuristic: Further Evidence from Choices Between Lottery Tickets</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dec0000188</idno>
					<note type="submission">Accepted for publication in Decision on 20/05/2022</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Decision making under risk</term>
					<term>Lottery choice</term>
					<term>Perception of randomness</term>
					<term>Number preferences in lotteries</term>
					<term>Representativeness heuristic</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The representativeness heuristic (RH) proposes that people expect even a small sample to have similar characteristics to its parent population. One domain in which it appears to operate is the preference for combinations of numbers on lottery tickets: most players seem to avoid very characteristic, &quot;unrepresentative&quot; combinations, e.g., only containing very low numbers. Likewise, many players may avoid betting on a recently drawn combination because it would seem particularly improbable that the same numbers would be drawn a second time. We confirmed both of these tendencies in a lab experiment and corroborated their external validity in two field experiments. However, we only found a weak link between these two choices: the same people do not necessarily exhibit the two biases. In this sense, there is little consistent manifestation of the RH across different tasks at the individual level. Nevertheless, there are some links related to rationality across the two choicespeople who are willing to forgo a monetary payment to get the preferred ticket in one task are also willing to do so in the other. We find such preferences to be related to the misperception of probabilities and the providing of intuitive, incorrect answers in the Cognitive Reflection Test. Our findings suggest that there are few individual differences in terms of the propensity to be impacted by the RHinstead, such occurrences are determined by circumstances and pure chance.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stability of the representativeness heuristic: Further evidence from choices between lottery tickets</head><p>The representativeness heuristic (RH; <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1972)</ref> is manifested when people erroneously believe that a sequence of random events, even a short sequence, should possess the essential characteristics of the process from which it was generated. As a result, people might expect that the new observations in the sequence will quickly correct any deviation. Such a misconception of chance appears to correctly organize several empirical findings. In the context of casino gambling, for example, people may believe that a win is "due" after several losses ("gambler's fallacy", <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Sundali &amp; Croson, 2006)</ref>. In Lotto, players seem to avoid both recently drawn combinations and very distinctive combinations, such as {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}, apparently (incorrectly) believing that they are less likely to be drawn; see <ref type="bibr">Krawczyk and Rachubik (2019, KR19</ref>) for a brief overview of the relevant evidence (which, with very few exceptions, happens to be either indirect or based on hypothetical choices made by small student samples). These tendencies appear naturally related; for example, one reason to perceive the {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6} as much less likely to be drawn than, say, <ref type="bibr">{8, 25, 32, 34, 41, 47}</ref> is that it seems nearly impossible that a very low number (e.g., a single-digit number) could be drawn six times in a row.</p><p>In this research project, we put these two lotto predictions through an explicit test in our three new experiments. Importantly, we looked at the link between these two choices: do individuals who prefer random combinations over "distinctive" combinations typically prefer random combinations over combinations that have been recently drawn? As hundreds of millions across the globe play lotteries every week, we believe it is important to understand how they do it and what individual characteristics might drive their behavior. But the importance of the issue goes beyond the case of gambling. When potential insurance clients mistakenly believe that a "hundredyear flood" in an area cannot happen again soon <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Jaspersen &amp; Aseervatham, 2017)</ref> and investors in an efficient market mistakenly believe that a stock that has gone up recently is now more likely to go down or that their gained returns predict future returns <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Chen et al., 2007)</ref>, they follow the representativeness heuristic. But in these complex environments, using pre-existing field data to successfully disentangle these effects from other factors that may cause underinsurance against catastrophic risks <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Holzheu &amp; Turner, 2018)</ref> and contrarian strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Boussaidi &amp; AlSaggaf, 2022</ref>) respectively is extremely difficult. The same is true in most applications; to name a few STABILITY OF THE REPRESENTATIVENESS HEURISTIC 4 recent examples, the RH has been investigated in the judgment-and decision-making of politicians <ref type="bibr">(Slotwijk &amp; Vis, 2021)</ref>, constructions workers <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Liu et al., 2022)</ref> and physicians <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Fernández-Aguilar et al., 2022)</ref>. Our study tackles the domain of lottery gambling, which is simpler in that probabilities are given. Moreover, the design yields control over confounding factors thanks to the experimental framework. This provides the best opportunity for clearly identifying the heuristic.</p><p>The question of the correlation of RH-driven behaviors across a task is also a question of the systematic individual differences in the susceptibility to the heuristic. This plays an important role in formal models of the RH. For example, in <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Rabin (2002)</ref>, an individual is assumed to perceive an independent sequence as if it was drawn with replacement from an "urn" with N "balls". In this model, in the case of a fair coin toss and N =2, the "urn" contains just one head and one tail. As a result, a head must be followed by a tail, because this is the only "ball" left in the "urn" at the moment; an extreme form of gambler's fallacy. The bias vanishes as approaches infinity, making N a natural candidate for the parameter of susceptibility to the RH characterizing an individual (whom the author, curiously, calls N-Freddy): low-N Freddies are more susceptible to it than high-N Freddies.</p><p>While it is not necessarily presented as a stable trait in psychological literature, individual differences in susceptibility to heuristics have already been suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Kahneman and Tversky (1972)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Nisbett et al. (1976)</ref>, among others. Subsequent studies linked the RH to several individual characteristics, confirming that some people are more prone to employ the RH than others. These characteristics included age <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Davidson, 1995)</ref>, statistical sophistication <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1983)</ref>, general intelligence <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Stanovich &amp; West, 2000)</ref>, and authoritarianism <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Kemmelmeier, 2010)</ref>, to name a few examples, although the reported correlations were often weak and sometimes counterintuitive.</p><p>There have also been some attempts to link the propensity to succumb to the RH with individual "thinking styles"; this is particularly true in reference to <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Epstein et al.'s (1996)</ref> distinction of the intuitive-experiential vs. analytical-rational styles. As the experiential system is rapid, automatic, crude, affective, and holistic, it may naturally be associated with the use of heuristics, in contrast to the slower, integrated, intentional, logical, and analytic rational system. Indeed, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Epstein et al. (1996)</ref> observed that people scoring high on the Faith in Intuition subscale of their Rational-Experiential Inventory (REI) (and, to a lesser extent, people scoring low on the Need for Cognition subscale) tended to display a "heuristic" mode of responding to vignette scenarios, e.g., falling for the near-miss and the sunk-cost bias. However, subsequent research found that the REI did not predict behavior in tasks for which RH was relevant <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Shiloh et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr">Sanchez et al., 2012)</ref>. Moreover, the correlation between (hypothetical) answers to problems aimed at identifying the RH was very low <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Shaham, 1992)</ref> or only observed in certain experimental conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Moore et al., 1997)</ref>, suggesting that the use of the RH is not stable within-subject, across tasks. To summarize, the existence of sizable individual differences in the propensity to fall for the RH remains unresolved.</p><p>It is also of importance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Gigerenzer (1991)</ref> argues, that to have a general theory or specific models of underlying cognitive processes, we need to be able to say more about how the mind adapts to the structure of a given environment. When such an adaptation occurs, is it stable, or does it only appear ad-hoc with a problem at hand? Although heuristics are often useful, they lead to systematic errors <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1974)</ref>; and here we wanted to test whether the use of RH is indeed systematic at the individual levelif it is the same people who are affected by the RH in two different tasks within the same domain.</p><p>While this research project was a direct follow-up of KR19 (in which we also investigated a preference for random-looking combinations of numbers and beliefs concerning the sequences of actually independent realizations), we sought to replicate the results in the more controlled environment of an economic laboratory with minimal face-to-face interactions between the subject and the experimenter. In doing so, we were in a position to ask many more questions to the same subject, thus deploying a more systematic manipulation of our core task of choosing a lottery ticket, along with the measures of RH used in previous literature; we could also offer more substantial incentives. We also introduced several methodological improvements in the two new field experiments in order to ensure that the results of KR19 hold after overcoming possible design shortcomings and the controlling for additional variables.</p><p>In the following section we focus on the laboratory experiment. Subsequently, we present the design and results of field experiments and close with a discussion and concluding remarks.</p><p>The data sets and Stata code used for the analyses, as well as the supplemental materials are available here: https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/RPXMG.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STABILITY OF THE REPRESENTATIVENESS HEURISTIC</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6</head><p>The laboratory experiment</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design</head><p>The experiment was conducted at the Laboratory of Experimental Economics, Faculty of Economic Sciences, University of Warsaw. The subjects were predominantly students, registered in the subject pool managed using ORSEE <ref type="bibr">(Greiner, 2012)</ref>. We ran four experimental sessions in October 2020 (when the COVID-19 restrictions were briefly lifted, making live sessions possible) during which we collected 165 observations. Females made up 55% of the subjects. Subjects' age varied between 18 and 76 years, with a mean of 35.8 years and a standard deviation of 15.1 years.</p><p>Their education structure was typical for a labwith highly educated subjects constituting 77%.</p><p>The detailed descriptive statistics of our sample are presented in Appendix B, <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table B1</ref>.</p><p>The subjects read instructions and provided responses on printed forms (see Appendix A1).</p><p>In Part 1, they made a series of choices between lottery tickets.</p><p>We used a popular Multi Multi game from Totalizator Sportowy (a state-owned monopolist in the field of number games and lotteries in Poland). With Multi Multi, twice a day, 20 numbers between 1-80 are randomly drawn, and players guess up to 10 numbers. The number of matches determines each player's payoff (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>). The prizes are guaranteed, generally meaning that every combination of, for example, ten numbers is as good as any other 1 and yields about 1 PLN in expectation, compared to the ticket price of 2.50 PLN. The task involved choices between two lottery sequences, each with ten numbers displayed in ascending order. We used four classes of sequences: Random, Distinctive, Previous and Distant Previous, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.  <ref type="bibr">,10,15,27,37,54,56,63,64,69} R4: {01,11,12,38,41,44,50,59,60,77} R2: {02,11,31,34,40,42,62,65,66,68} R5: {12,19,27,29,37,39,42,59,74,75} R3: {08,21,30,44,47,54,56,59,63,77} R6: {03,08,11,15,23,24,44,52,57,71}</ref> "Distinctive" sequences Numbers Distance 1 Distance 5</p><p>Low* L1: <ref type="bibr">{01,</ref><ref type="bibr">02,</ref><ref type="bibr">03,</ref><ref type="bibr">04,</ref><ref type="bibr">05,</ref><ref type="bibr">06,</ref><ref type="bibr">07,</ref><ref type="bibr">08,</ref><ref type="bibr">09,</ref><ref type="bibr">10} L5: {05,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">25,</ref><ref type="bibr">30,</ref><ref type="bibr">35,</ref><ref type="bibr">40,</ref><ref type="bibr">45,</ref><ref type="bibr">50} Medium M1: {01,</ref><ref type="bibr">02,</ref><ref type="bibr">03,</ref><ref type="bibr">04,</ref><ref type="bibr">05,</ref><ref type="bibr">76,</ref><ref type="bibr">77,</ref><ref type="bibr">78,</ref><ref type="bibr">79,</ref><ref type="bibr">80} M5: {05,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">25,</ref><ref type="bibr">60,</ref><ref type="bibr">65,</ref><ref type="bibr">70,</ref><ref type="bibr">75,</ref><ref type="bibr">80} High* H1: {71,</ref><ref type="bibr">72,</ref><ref type="bibr">73,</ref><ref type="bibr">74,</ref><ref type="bibr">75,</ref><ref type="bibr">76,</ref><ref type="bibr">77,</ref><ref type="bibr">78,</ref><ref type="bibr">79,</ref><ref type="bibr">80} H5: {35,</ref><ref type="bibr">40,</ref><ref type="bibr">45,</ref><ref type="bibr">50,</ref><ref type="bibr">55,</ref><ref type="bibr">60,</ref><ref type="bibr">65,</ref><ref type="bibr">70,</ref><ref type="bibr">75,</ref><ref type="bibr">80}</ref> * used in the field experiments only "Previous" (P) Ten numbers randomly selected from among the 20 that won in the drawing directly preceding a specific subject's choice. For example, if numbers <ref type="bibr">(02,</ref><ref type="bibr">07,</ref><ref type="bibr">11,</ref><ref type="bibr">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">18,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">21,</ref><ref type="bibr">23,</ref><ref type="bibr">25,</ref><ref type="bibr">31,</ref><ref type="bibr">32,</ref><ref type="bibr">38,</ref><ref type="bibr">46,</ref><ref type="bibr">48,</ref><ref type="bibr">51,</ref><ref type="bibr">55,</ref><ref type="bibr">71,</ref><ref type="bibr">77,</ref><ref type="bibr">79,</ref><ref type="bibr">80)</ref> showed up in the 2pm drawing, subjects making a choice later that day could see <ref type="bibr">(11,</ref><ref type="bibr">25,</ref><ref type="bibr">31,</ref><ref type="bibr">32,</ref><ref type="bibr">38,</ref><ref type="bibr">48,</ref><ref type="bibr">51,</ref><ref type="bibr">55,</ref><ref type="bibr">77,</ref><ref type="bibr">79)</ref> on their "Previous" ticket. "Distant Previous" (used in the lab experiment only) (DP) Numbers that were drawn on March 12, 2019, thus on an arbitrary day approximately a year and seven months before the experiment.</p><p>Unsurprisingly, the sequences used on the Random tickets were generated randomly; we used six different sequences, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>. Independently, we also randomized if the Random ticket was displayed on the left-or right-hand side of the form.</p><p>Distinctive tickets involved sequences with consecutive numbers or numbers ending in 0 or 5 only, as these can be easily identified as specific when printed out in a row (as they are on Multi Multi tickets). 2 In the lab experiment, we used two types of these Distinctive sequences: M1 and M5, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>Tickets in the Previous class contained ten numbers randomly selected from among the 20 that won in the drawing directly preceding the session. <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Wang et al. (2016)</ref> report that frequent players avoid winning numbers from recent draws, while occasional players tend to chase them.</p><p>We seek to verify this finding.</p><p>We used two different Previous sequences during each session. Additionally, to grasp whether the perceived improbability of the same numbers being again drawn reduces over time, we used a Distant Previous ticket type, containing numbers that were drawn on March 12, 2019, thus on an arbitrary day approximately a year and seven months before the experiment. Instructions informed the subjects where the numbers in the Previous and Distant Previous types came from.</p><p>There were six pairs of sequences, the subjects choosing their preferred one in each pair (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>), with the understanding that one of their six choices would be implemented.</p><p>Distinctive, Previous and Distant Previous were always matched with one of the Random sequences. The six pairs were fixed, e.g., R1 was always matched with M1. However, the order and thus the A/B labelling within each pair and the order of the six pairs were randomized at the individual level. Your choice: <ref type="bibr">10, 15, 27, 37, 54, 56, 63, 64, 69 01, 02, 03, 04, 05, 76, 77, 78, 79, 80</ref> 2. 2A: <ref type="bibr">08, 21, 30, 44, 47, 54, 56, 59, 63, 77 05, 10, 15, 20, 25, 60, 65, 70, 75, 80</ref> 3. 3A: <ref type="bibr">05, 10, 15, 20, 25, 60, 65, 70, 75, 80 02, 11, 31, 34, 40, 42, 62, 65, 66, 68</ref> 4. 4A (previous drawing): <ref type="bibr">05, 12, 14, 15, 19, 22, 32, 33, 38, 45 12, 19, 27, 29, 37, 39, 42, 59, 74, 75</ref> 5. 5A (drawing from 12.03.2019): <ref type="bibr">11, 17, 20, 21, 29, 45, 58, 68, 72, 79 03, 08, 11, 15, 23, 24, 44, 52, 57, 71</ref> 6. 6A: <ref type="bibr">11, 12, 38, 41, 44, 50, 59, 60, 77 21, 24, 25, 30, 32, 34, 38, 43, 46, 52</ref> The subjects were subsequently asked to rate each combination on a 1-7 scale with "1", meaning it would be "fully impossible" that this combination is obtained in the next drawing, and "7" meaning it would be "fully possible". We paid subjects a show-up fee of 10 PLN to reimburse them for their time and travel to the campus, and used "6x wager" tickets that sell at 15 PLN and pay up to 1.5 million PLN.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">1. 1A: [R1] 1B: [M1] A / B 01,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">[R3] 2B: [M5] A / B</formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">[M5] 3B: [R2] A / B</formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">[P1] 4B: [R5] A / B</formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">[DP] 5B: [R6] A / B</formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">[R4] 6B (previous drawing): [P2] A / B 01,</formula><p>In Part 2, we gave our subjects a number of puzzles previously used to measure susceptibility to the RH, such as the well-known Linda problem. Several minor changes were introduced to the original puzzles in order to fix features that were obsolete or exotic to the Polish sample, as well as to reduce the probability that subjects recognized the problem. Finally, the subjects reported a number of demographic characteristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Overall, Random was preferred over Distinctive (72%), Previous (69%), and Distant Previous (67%) (for more details, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table B2</ref> in App. B). The numbers were similar to those in comparable tasks of KR2019.</p><p>This pattern of choices was consistent with subjects' mean responses to the question of which combinations were "possible" or "impossible". Indeed, on average, the Random combinations were rated at 4.8, compared to 3.5 for Distinctive, 3.7 for Previous, and 4.2 for Distant Previous. The rating of Random combinations was thus much higher than that of any of the three remaining groups. Moreover, due to our within-subject design, we had the statistical power to reject the hypothesis of equality between any two groups, except Distinctive compared to Previous, at a 0.001 significance level (using Wilcoxon signed-rank tests treating each individual as one independent observation). The choices between lottery tickets were also predicted by "possibility" ratings at the individual level; in probit regressions (available in online supplemental materials S1), subjects rating R1 sequence as more "possible" and subjects rating M1 sequence as less "possible" were more likely to choose R over M1 and likewise for all the other pairs. In contrast to <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Wang et al. (2016)</ref>, the frequent players in our sample, compared to the occasional players, were more likely to choose Previous (correlation significant at p=0.055).</p><p>Looking across the tasks, we found significant positive correlations between choices involving Distinctive; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref>. By contrast, there were few correlations across other types of choices. It was only when we looked at the number of times that Random was preferred over Distinctive (0-3); and likewise the number of times that Random was preferred over (Distant)</p><p>Previous (0-3), that a weak but significant correlation surfaced (Spearman's rho = 0.20, p&lt;0.01). As for the hypothetical RH puzzles of Part 2, they were indeed puzzling, in accordance with the existing literature: incorrect answers (typically consistent with the RH) prevailed; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref>. To analyze the responses, we constructed dummy variables (with a suffix "_RH" in the code), taking a value of 1 if the response was consistent with the representativeness heuristics. In line with <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Shaham et al. (1992)</ref>, they clearly did not represent the same latent factor; for example, when these six _RH variables were mutually correlated, as many as seven out of 15 (=6*5/2) coefficients came out negative. *Unlike in the other puzzles, providing a precise answer in the Taxi problem requires the application of the Bayes theorem and some calculations. One thus has to decide as to the maximum error allowed. We took the most lenient approach and considered any guess larger than 20% and smaller than 85% (thus taking some account for both the prior and the evidence) as normatively correct.</p><p>However, the responses to the RH puzzles were hardly predictive of the lottery ticket choices. Specifically, only for the high school puzzle did those who solved it correctly tend to choose random less often, whereas the correlation was insignificant and often reversed for the remaining puzzles; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table B3</ref> in Appendix B.</p><p>We also investigated if demographics were correlated to ticket choices or responses in the RH puzzles (also because in such a case, some of the previously reported correlations or lack thereof could be spurious) <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">(Table B4</ref> and B5 in App. B). Overall, these effects were few; bettereducated respondents seem to prefer Random over Distinctive tickets more often, and those who gambled more had a weaker preference for Random over P1 (but not P2). Given the multiple comparisons, these effects, albeit significant at the 1% level, should be considered with caution.</p><p>Unsurprisingly, given the weak impact of demographic variables, controlling for them in regressions (available in online supplemental materials S2) generally confirmed the previously reported correlations (or lack thereof) between ticket choice tasks and the RH puzzles.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Field experiments</head><p>In the two field experiments, we sought to corroborate the external validity of the lab experiment. We thus addressed a much more diverse sample, in a more natural setting of the streets of Warsaw. We also wanted to replicate the field experiment of KR19, with substantial methodological improvements. First, in KR19 we had our subjects choose between a Random ticket and a Distinctive ticket and to be then asked whether they wanted to switch if we added a small monetary bonus to the initially unwanted ticket (replicating <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bar-Hillel and Neter, 1996)</ref>.</p><p>Thus, the fact that, in KR19, the majority of our sample stayed with their initial choice (did not switch) could reflect a clear preference; but was also consistent with a (near) indifference coupled with a status-quo bias. In the improved design, we wanted to unambiguously identify the effect of the RH. We thus employed other elicitation procedures, rendering status-quo bias irrelevant, thereby allowing us to establish a preference for Random (as postulated by the RH) cleanly.</p><p>Compared to the lab experiment which involved no bonuses, we offered a more stringent test for the preference for Random: we verified whether it prevails over monetary incentives.</p><p>Second, in KR19, we examined the potential correlations between the RH predictions for two different (but similar) tasks and failed to find any, perhaps because one of the tasks involved hypothetical choices (coin tosses). In the present experiments, we studied subjects' behavior under even more closely related, incentivized tasksboth were choices between tickets.</p><p>Third, we modified the question concerning subjects' justifications of choice, explicitly identifying if they believed that the random-looking tickets were more likely to win. Finally, in the new experiments, we added other dimensions characterizing subjects (education, religiosity, belief in superstition). We also included a question from the Cognitive Reflection Test (CRT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Frederick, 2005)</ref>, which, as suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Toplak et al. (2011)</ref>, may be predictive of the use of heuristics in decision-making.</p><p>We now describe the elements that are common to both field experiments. The subjects were random passers-by, approached in several locations in the city of Warsaw. They were greeted and asked whether they would agree to participate in a very brief study coordinated by the University of Warsaw, which would allow them to earn several pre-paid lottery tickets. The exact wording used in both experiments can be found in Appendix A2.</p><p>In both experiments, the main tasks involved choices between two lottery tickets. We used all six Random sequences <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table 2)</ref>. Independently, we also randomized in all tasks in both experiments if the Random ticket was displayed on the left-or right-hand side of the other ticket.</p><p>Also for Distinctive tickets, one of six particular combinations was always used; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>The Previous tickets, just as in the lab experiment, contained ten numbers randomly drawn from among the 20 that won in the drawing directly preceding a specific subject's choice. Subjects were explicitly told where the numbers came from. Because the experiment took place on different days, as many as 80 distinct combinations were used in the Previous class; they are therefore not shown here. We did not use Distant Previous tickets.</p><p>In both experiments, after the two main tasks, we asked our subjects a question adapted from the CRT:</p><p>A pencil and a pen together cost 1.10zł. The pen costs 1zł more than a pencil. How much does the pencil cost?</p><p>We then asked about subjects' age, education, gambling habits, superstitious behaviors, and religiosity. The experimenter also coded subjects' gender. Both experiments lasted five minutes per subject on average, and they involved a fully randomized between-subject design.</p><p>Both experiments had very similar demographic distributions. Roughly 52% of the subjects were female. Subjects' age varied between 18 and 81 years, with a mean of 39.1 years and a standard deviation of 15.3 years. These statistics are closer than those of the Lab Experiment to the national population 3 .</p><p>Our sample's education structure (66% of our subjects having a higher education)</p><p>resembles that of the city as a whole but is starkly different from that of the Polish nation 4 .</p><p>In <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 6</ref> see the summary of the possible choices in all four tasks. Field Experiment 1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design</head><p>In Task 1.1, we offered the subjects a choice between a Random and a Distinctive ticket, the latter being offered with a bonus of 1PLN (a distinctive amount close to the ticket's expected value). Thus, unlike in the KR19, choosing the ticket without a bonus could unambiguously be identified as the manifestation of a sufficiently strong preference (in favor of the Random ticket) rather than as a status-quo bias.</p><p>In Task 1.2, we asked the subjects to choose between a Random ticket and a Previous one.</p><p>Since we had predicted that there would be a general preference towards Random, we offered no bonuses to half of the subjects and a bonus of 1PLN for choosing Previous to the other half (no condition involving a bonus for choosing Random, which was typically preferred anyway). We then asked for a justification of their choice; in particular, we asked whether any of the tickets had a greater chance of being drawn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>In Task 1.1, Random vs. Distinctive, 60% of the 260 subjects chose the Random ticket, thus forgoing the bonus <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">(Table 7</ref>, Panel A), a replication of KR19 and the lab experiment. This pattern of outcomes suggests that it was primarily not due to a status quo bias that the subjects rejected the offer to switch, rather due to a strong preference for the random-looking sequences.</p><p>As for the preferences for each of the distinctive patterns, M5 was chosen relatively more often than other types (48% of the time), while L1 relatively less (33% of the time), as in KR19. offered with a bonus, but compared to the no-bonus benchmark, the difference was small and insignificant (74% vs. 80% choosing Random = 0.24, = 1.18). In this task, we also explicitly asked the subjects whether any of the tickets had a greater chance of being drawn. From Panel A of <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 8</ref>, we can see that Random (consistent with the gambler's fallacy) was indicated to be more likely by 74% of the subjects. Only 5% believed, conversely, that Previous was more likely to be drawn (consistent with the hot-hand fallacy). Nineteen percent said that they both had the same probability, and the answer was ambiguous for the remaining 3% of subjects. Panel A of <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 8</ref> also illustrates that the choices were entirely consistent with probability judgments; essentially, all the subjects picked the ticket they said was more likely to win, and the choices were split 43/57 when they said the chances were identical. One reason for this preference for Previous with a bonus not being more prevalent than without the bonus could be that some participants misrepresented their true beliefs. If someone knows that the "correct" answer is that "the chances are identical" but it does not feel this way at all, they may state that the chances are identical and yet choose R, even if P comes with cash.</p><p>Across the two tasks, we found no association (with a Chi-squared test) suggested by the RH; when no bonuses were offered in the R vs. P task, behavior in this task was unrelated to behavior in the R vs. D choice (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 7</ref>, Panel B1). However, among the subjects who had the chance to get the bonus in both tasks, we found the tendency to be rational (take the bonus) in either both or neither; see Panel B2. Since the bonus was associated with avoiding Random, we cannot be sure if this tendency was driven by either some people consistently going for the bonus (and others not doing so) or by some people consistently avoiding Random (while others consistently taking Random). If the latter effect were true, we should see the same tendency in Panel B1 of <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 7</ref>; yet we do not. In other words, we identified a consistent willingness to take cash across the two tasks, but no consistent willingness to go for the Random ticket.</p><p>CRT results are presented in Panel A of <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 9</ref>. Overall, only 15% gave the correct answer of 0.05, and among those who gave an incorrect answer, 93% gave the intuitive answer of 0.1.</p><p>Relating the choices in CRT to the choices of lottery tickets, we see that those choosing Random (rather than Distinctive with a bonus) was associated with giving an incorrect answer in the CRT; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 9</ref>, Panel A. These findings were confirmed in a probit regression (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table B6</ref> in Appendix B). 5 Choosing Random rather than Previous with a bonus was also associated with answering the CRT question incorrectly, but there was no link with the choice not involving a bonus, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 9</ref>, Panels B1 and B2. Thus, correct CRT answers appear to be predictive of a willingness to take cash, not of the preference for or against Random per se. These findings were confirmed when controlling for other variables (which by themselves had little systematic effect); see <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table B7</ref> in Appendix B.</p><p>The results were generally consistent with the findings reported in KR19 and the lab experiment. We confirmed that people have a strong preference for random-looking tickets and that the status quo bias does not cause this preference. Despite the tendency to choose Random, there was no consistent use of the RH in both tasks; however, we did determine that subjects tended to be rational (go for the bonus) either in both tasks or neither. We also found that going for the bonus was predicted by answering the CRT question correctly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Field Experiment 2</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design</head><p>One possible shortcoming of the design of Field Exp. 1 was that some subjects could treat the bonus immediately added to the Distinctive ticket as a signal of its inferiority. The possibility that a price is a signal of quality is often discussed in the marketing literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Gerstner, 1985)</ref>. An analogous signal of the inferiority of Previous could be perceived by (half) the subjects in Task 1.2 of Experiment 1. Hence, in Exp. 2, we wanted to remove the possibility of such an effect.</p><p>In Task 2.1, we applied the two-stage procedure of KR19 to the choice between a Random ticket and a Previous ticket. Once a subject indicated which one they liked better with no mention of the bonus, we added a bonus of 1 PLN to the unwanted ticket, and the subject could either stay with the initial decision or switch and encash the bonus. This procedure was thus not susceptible to the "price as a signal of quality" effect, previously described. This was because the bonus had been determined by the subject's choice, and not by the experimenter. However, it was susceptible to the status quo effect, as explored before; thus, running this condition gives a natural closure to the study's design, also allowing for an investigation of the status quo effect in the Random vs.</p><p>Previous choice. We would then ask how they made their decision, and if any of the tickets had a greater chance of being drawn.</p><p>The choice between Random and Distinctive (Task 2.2) was structured as follows. Before a subject could see the tickets, the experimenter tossed a coin, telling the subject that the outcome would determine to which ticket the bonus of 1 PLN would be added (we call it a Toss-the-Cointo-Determine-the-Bonus or TCDB procedure). As a result, it was clear that the bonus was not a valuable signal of quality. Once this was determined, the subject was asked to choose. We asked a second time how they made their choice and if either of the two tickets had a greater chance of being drawn.</p><p>The order of the tasks was reversed compared to the Field Experiment 1. The main reason for this is that subjects first exposed to the TCDB procedure could be inclined to ask about the bonus at the beginning of the subsequent two-stage procedure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>In both tasks, we once again may observe a clear preference for Random among our 199 subjects. From the results of the two-stage Random vs. Previous choice, it is evident that subjects preferred the Random ticket (87%), and the offer to switch with the bonus almost did not impact their decisionsonly 12% of these subjects decided to switch from their initial choice; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table   10</ref>, Panel A, suggesting a strong preference for R once again. We do see, however, that among those initially choosing Previous (13%), as much as 42% decided to switch when the bonus was</p><p>introduced, suggesting that this preference is often relatively weak.</p><p>The subjects were subsequently asked whether they thought that any of the tickets had a greater chance of being drawn. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 8</ref>, Panel B, the willingness to switch correlated very highly with the belief that both tickets had equal probability. We can stipulate that, consistent with our other results, the willingness to stay or switch did not come from a status-quo or other biases but from a strong belief that the chosen ticket had a greater probability of winning.</p><p>In the TCDB procedure applied to the choice between Random and Distinctive, we see that 77% chose Random if it came with a bonus, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 10</ref>, Panel B. Even if the bonus was, conversely, added to the Distinctive ticket, a slight majority -58 of 104 (56%)still chose Random. While the latter figure is not significantly different from the equal split, it also does not differ from the 60% choosing Random against Distinctive (with a bonus) in Experiment 1 ( = 0.7, = 0.48), suggesting that the bonus, added directly, without explicit randomization, did not cause the effect of perceived inferiority we had hypothesized. Further, the TCDB procedure did not allow for the status quo bias; despite this, more than half of the subjects still rejected the bonus, which again suggests a very strong preference towards Random. When inspecting the two tasks <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 10</ref>, Panel C), we observe again that those choosing Random against Previous were not necessarily the same subjects as those choosing Random against Distinctive. Choosing Random in one task but not in the other was so common that the choices in the two tasks appear unrelated. This is in accordance with all our previous findings: that the RH does not show up consistently across different tasks.</p><p>In the CRT only 21% (of N=199) were able to find the correct answer of 0.05 (additional 10% admitting they have seen the problem before), while 69% gave an incorrect answer, among whom 92% chose the intuitive option of 0.1.</p><p>Once again, we see a rationality across the tasks. Those giving a correct answer to CRT initially chose Previous more often (21% vs. 9%) and regardless of the initial choice switched to the bonus more often (31% vs. 9%); see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 11</ref>, Panel A. In the choice between the Random and Distinctive, if the bonus was associated with R, CRT-correct subjects chose Random particularly often (94%), while if the bonus was with Distinctive, we saw no dependence (52% chose Random); see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 11</ref>, Panels B1 and B2. Again, the fact that correct answers to the CRT were only associated with hunger for the bonus was confirmed by probit regression; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table B8</ref> in Appendix B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Tasks that predictably trigger non-normative performance do not necessarily have profound consequences for the underlying theoretical model. As proposed by <ref type="bibr">Stanovich &amp; West (2002)</ref>, "irrational" behaviors need not follow from the inherent irrationality of the human being; inspecting correlations across tasks can give us some hint as to which alternative explanation is the most plausible. Most importantly for our purposes, some deviations from the normative performance can simply be understood as performance errors, i.e., the "failure to apply a rule, strategy, or algorithm that is part of a person's competence because of a momentary and fairly random lapse in ancillary processes necessary to execute the strategy (lack of attention, temporary memory deactivation, distraction, etc.)." <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Stanovich &amp; West, 2000)</ref>. If that is the case, we expect a low correlation across tasks: all or the vast majority of the population is capable of applying the norm but they occasionally fail to do so. Our results seem to be largely consistent with this perspectivethe representativeness heuristic is sometimes used but does not altogether replace correct judgment. We believe it is a valuable contribution to the wider discussion on individual differences in susceptibility to cognitive biases <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bruine de Bruin et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Shiloh, Salton &amp; Sharabi, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Stanovich &amp; West, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Teovanović et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Vartanian et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Even more directly, our study contributes to the literature on lottery ticket preference.</p><p>Previous experiments <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bar-Hillel &amp; Neter 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Risen &amp; Gilovich, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr">KR19)</ref> established that people are reluctant to exchange the ticket they received first. This kind of endowment effect could be explained in terms of a loss aversion or a regret aversion. <ref type="bibr">6</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Risen and Gilovich (2007)</ref> further linked this reluctance to (regret-related) dwelling on the possibility that the ticket being given up may actually win, which leads people to overestimate the probability of such an occurrence. Our data can hardly be organized along these lines.</p><p>First, in the Field Experiment 1, the fraction of people willing to forgo a monetary payment to obtain the preferred ticket was just as high (60%) in the one-stage procedure as in the two-stage procedure in KR19 (59%), although only the latter involved tickets being relinquished; thus giving more scope for regret and (especially) the Risen-Gilovich effect. We thereby confirm that subjects choose Random due to their strong preference (and not due to a bias possibly partly driven by regret). Second, if anything, we would expect that people mostly regret turning down a Distinctive ticket because it is easy to remember its combination of numbers (and experience the pain of having discarded a winning ticket). Despite this, a preference for Distinctive is very rare. Third, among the people choosing Random over Previous when no bonus was offered in a one-stage procedure (Task 1.2 of the Field Experiment 1), 90.5% said that Random was more likely to win.</p><p>Among those who chose Random over Previous in the first stage <ref type="bibr">(Task 2.1,</ref><ref type="bibr">Field Experiment 2)</ref> and were subsequently offered the chance to switch (which some of them did), only 70.7% said that Random was more likely to win. Thus, offering an incentive to switch, if anything, shifted the belief against the ticket that could be given up, rather than in favor of ita reversed Risen-Gilovich effect.</p><p>One crucial difference between our set-up and those of previous studies, which could partly explain the lesser role of regret-related mechanisms that we observe, is that they had small lotteries run by the experimenter, with fellow students as participants. It could thus be natural to wonder who received the discarded ticket, etc. Strong regret/dwelling on the possibility that the relinquished ticket will win eventually in someone else's hands could thus be somewhat specific to these designs, with less bearing on the natural real-world stimuli that we are using.</p><p>While regret does not seem to play a role in our findings, we do find the RH to be quite relevant. Since tickets with Random sequences are generally preferred and held onto regardless of the task or the alternative ticket, RH prevails in our subjects' decisions. However, consistent with KR19, we find little correlation across tasks in this regard, which provides more evidence towards our previous finding that being affected by RH in one task does not predict its significance in a subsequent decision. This effect is also confirmed by the missing correlation with the answers to the classic puzzles used to illustrate RH that we administered in the Lab Experiment. In this sense, RH is not systematically observed across tasks. In other words, our findings suggest that there are few individual differences in the propensity to fall prey to RHinstead, such occurrences are determined by circumstances and pure chance. What does seem to differ between individuals is the willingness and ability to undertake cognitive reflection: correct answers to the CRT predict choosing tickets which come with a bonus, predict switching, and stating that the two tickets have the same probability of being drawn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Part 1</head><p>Multi Multi is a game offered by Totalizator Sportowy (which also offers, among others, the Lotto game). During this game (which happens twice daily at 14:00 and 21:50), out of numbers from 1 to 80, 20 numbers are drawn. In Multi Multi, one can bet on up to 10 numbers, and the prize depends on the quantity of drawn matching numbers. When betting on ten numbers (you will be choosing from such sequences here), a guaranteed prize (when all ten numbers are drawn) is one million five hundred thousand zlotys (1 500 000 zł). The lowest price (12 zł) is paid out for 4 matching drawn numbers.</p><p>In each row in the table below, choose the sequence you prefer to receive on your lottery ticket. At the end of the experiment, you will find out which of rows 1-6, as seen in the table below, we have drawn for you. You will receive a single ticket with the sequence of numbers that you have chosen as your preferred one in this row. This ticket will be for the next drawing, that is, today at 9.50 PM. Since you do not know which row will be drawn, it is in your best interest to consider them and in each pair (in each row), choose the sequence you prefer to receive on your ticket.</p><p>The following sequences differ only in their selected numbers. Each of them contains 10 numbers.</p><p>Sequences labelled as "previous drawing" contain only the numbers that won (i.e., were drawn) in the last draw, that is, today at 2 PM.</p><p>The sequence labelled as "drawing from 12.03.2019" contains only the numbers drawn in the draw of 12.03.2019 at 2 PM.</p><p>In each of the rows, choose one of the sequences A or B. Mark your choice in the rightmost column.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Available sequences:</head><p>Your choice: <ref type="bibr">10, 15, 27, 37, 54, 56, 63, 64, 69 01, 02, 03, 04, 05, 76, 77, 78, 79, 80</ref> 2. 2A: 2B: A / B 08, <ref type="bibr">21, 30, 44, 47, 54, 56, 59, 63, 77 05, 10, 15, 20, 25, 60, 65, 70, 75, 80</ref> 3. 3A: <ref type="bibr">05, 10, 15, 20, 25, 60, 65, 70, 75, 80 02, 11, 31, 34, 40, 42, 62, 65, 66, 68</ref> 4. 4A (previous drawing): <ref type="bibr">12, 14, 15, 19, 22, 32, 33, 38, 45 12, 19, 27, 29, 37, 39, 42, 59, 74, 75</ref> 5. 5A (drawing from 12.03.2019): <ref type="bibr">11, 17, 20, 21, 29, 45, 58, 68, 72, 79 03, 08, 11, 15, 23, 24, 44, 52, 57, 71</ref> 6. 6A: 6B (previous drawing): <ref type="bibr">A / B 01, 11, 12, 38, 41, 44, 50, 59, 60, 77 21, 24, 25, 30, 32, 34, 38, 43, 46, 52</ref> We would like to find out what motivated your choices. If you can, please briefly describe the motivations of at least some of them. When referring to a particular pair of sequences, indicate its number. ……… Now, for each sequence you have seen in this questionnaire, indicate how possible you think it is that it might be drawn in the next drawing (today at 9.50 PM) (mark one of the numbers 1-7 in each row).</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">1. 1A: 1B: A / B 01,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">3B: A / B</formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">4B: A / B 05,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">5B: A / B</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fully impossible</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fully possible</head><p>1A: <ref type="bibr">01,</ref><ref type="bibr">10,</ref><ref type="bibr">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">27,</ref><ref type="bibr">37,</ref><ref type="bibr">54,</ref><ref type="bibr">56,</ref><ref type="bibr">63,</ref><ref type="bibr">64,</ref><ref type="bibr">69</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p><p>1B: 01, 02, <ref type="bibr">03,</ref><ref type="bibr">04,</ref><ref type="bibr">05,</ref><ref type="bibr">76,</ref><ref type="bibr">77,</ref><ref type="bibr">78,</ref><ref type="bibr">79,</ref><ref type="bibr">80</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p><p>2A <ref type="bibr">: 08, 21, 30, 44, 47, 54, 56, 59, 63, 77</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 <ref type="bibr">: 05, 10, 15, 20, 25, 60, 65, 70, 75, 80</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2B</head><p>3A <ref type="bibr">: 05, 10, 15, 20, 25, 60, 65, 70, 75, 80</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p><p>3B <ref type="bibr">: 02, 11, 31, 34, 40, 42, 62, 65, 66, 68</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p><p>4A (previous drawing): <ref type="bibr">05,</ref><ref type="bibr">12,</ref><ref type="bibr">14,</ref><ref type="bibr">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">19,</ref><ref type="bibr">22,</ref><ref type="bibr">32,</ref><ref type="bibr">33,</ref><ref type="bibr">38,</ref><ref type="bibr">45</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 <ref type="bibr">: 05, 12, 14, 15, 19, 22, 32, 33, 38, 45</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4B</head><p>5A (drawing from 12.03.2019): <ref type="bibr">11,</ref><ref type="bibr">17,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">21,</ref><ref type="bibr">29,</ref><ref type="bibr">45,</ref><ref type="bibr">58,</ref><ref type="bibr">68,</ref><ref type="bibr">72,</ref><ref type="bibr">79</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 <ref type="bibr">: 03, 08, 11, 15, 23, 24, 44, 52, 57, 71</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5B</head><p>6A <ref type="bibr">: 01, 11, 12, 38, 41, 44, 50, 59, 60, 77</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p><p>6B (previous drawing): <ref type="bibr">21,</ref><ref type="bibr">24,</ref><ref type="bibr">25,</ref><ref type="bibr">30,</ref><ref type="bibr">32,</ref><ref type="bibr">34,</ref><ref type="bibr">38,</ref><ref type="bibr">43,</ref><ref type="bibr">46,</ref><ref type="bibr">52</ref> 1 2 3 4 5 6 7</p><p>Part 2</p><p>Please answer the following questions. In the questions where you write the answer yourself, we understand that you may not know the exact value or have to calculate it. However, we ask you to think for a moment and enter a specific numerical answer.</p><p>Each of the following open questions can be answered with a number.</p><p>1. Marta is 28 years old and is single. She is an open and intelligent person. She graduated in philosophy. As a student, she devoted a lot of time to the problems of social justice and discrimination, she used social media to defend evicted tenants. Choose what is more probable?</p><p>O Marta works in a bank O Marta works in a bank and is a feminist 2. A taxicab was involved in a hit-and-run accident at night. Only the Green and Blue cab companies operate in the city, where 85% of the cabs are Green, and 15% are Blue. A witness identified the cab as Blue, and when tested under similar conditions, was able to identify 80% of both Blue and Green cabs correctly. What is the probability that the cab involved in the accident was Blue?</p><p>Answer: ………% 3. A certain town is served by two hospitals. In the larger hospital, about 45 babies are born each day, and in the smaller hospital, about 15 babies are born each day. As you know, about 50% of all babies are boys. However, the exact percentage varies from day to day. Sometimes it may be higher than 50%, sometimes lower.</p><p>For a period of 1 year, each hospital recorded the days on which more than 60% of the babies born were boys. Which hospital do you think recorded more such days?</p><p>O The larger hospital O The smaller hospital O About the same (that is, within 5% of each other) 4. All families of six children in a city were surveyed. In 72 families, the exact order of births of boys and girls was GBGBBG.</p><p>What is your estimate of the number of families surveyed in which the exact order of births was BGBBBB?</p><p>Answer (number): ……… 5. There are two programmes in a high school. Boys are a majority (65%) in programme A and a minority (45%) in programme B. There is an equal number of classes in each of the two programmes.</p><p>You enter a class at random and observe that 55% of the students are boys. What is your best guessdoes the class belong to programme A or programme B?</p><p>Answer: A / B [subject choosing and receiving the ticket with/without the bonus]</p><p>Can you please tell me why you chose this one?</p><p>Do any of these have a greater chance of being drawn? <ref type="bibr">[TASK 2: Random vs. Distinctive]</ref>. Now I have one more choice for you. The two tickets differ only in the numbers chosen. I will show them to you in a second, but before that, we will toss a coin to determine to which one of them I will add 1zł. If it is heads, I will add it to the one on the right and if tails then to the one on the left. Is this clear?</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">[TCDB procedure]</formula><p>Okay, so to this one, I am adding a bonus. Please have a look at them, and you will receive whichever you choose.</p><p>[Subject choosing and receiving the ticket with/without the bonus]</p><p>Can you please tell me why you chose this one?</p><p>Do you think any of these has a greater chance of being drawn?</p><p>[CRT] As the last task, I have a riddle for you. I will read it out loud, but you can also see it for yourself printed here.</p><p>A pencil and a pen together cost one złoty and ten groszy <ref type="bibr">[1.10zł]</ref>. The pen costs one złoty more than a pencil. How much does the pencil cost?     </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Distribution of prizes in Multi Multi (when ten numbers are selected)</figDesc><table><row><cell># of matches</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>Prize in PLN</cell><cell>250,000</cell><cell>10,000</cell><cell>520</cell><cell>140</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Probability</cell><cell cols="7">1/8,911,711 1/163,381 1/7,384 1/621 1/87 1/19 1/8</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Types of Random and Distinctive sequences used</figDesc><table><row><cell>"Random" sequences</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Lab exp.: Table with lottery sequences (6 choices) as presented to the subjects [in square brackets are code-names of the sequences, which were not shown to the subjects]</figDesc><table><row><cell>Available sequences:</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Lab experiment: Correlation between lottery choices</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>R over</cell><cell>R over</cell><cell>R over</cell><cell>R over</cell><cell>R over</cell><cell>R over</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>D(M1)</cell><cell>D(M5)</cell><cell>D(M5)</cell><cell>P1</cell><cell>P2</cell><cell>DP</cell></row><row><cell>R over D(M1)</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>R over D(M5)</cell><cell>0.17**</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>R over D(M5)</cell><cell cols="2">0.25*** 0.24***</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>R over P1</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>-0.11</cell><cell>0.15</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>R over P2</cell><cell>0.18**</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell cols="2">0.19** 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>R over DP</cell><cell>0.14</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell cols="2">0.00 1.00</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">legend: ** p&lt;0.05; *** p&lt;0.01</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Lab experiment: Percent of correct (normative) answers to the puzzles (N=165)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Correct Consistent with RH</cell><cell>Other</cell></row><row><cell>Linda problem</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Taxi problem*</cell><cell>30</cell><cell>42</cell><cell>28</cell></row><row><cell>Hospitals</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>62</cell><cell>16</cell></row><row><cell>Families</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>65</cell><cell>10</cell></row><row><cell>High school</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>78</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Marbles</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>48</cell><cell>1</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Summary of the possible choices in all four tasks of the Field Experiments</figDesc><table><row><cell>Field Experiment 1</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Task 1.1</cell><cell>Random vs. Distinctive+bonus</cell></row><row><cell>Task 1.2</cell><cell>Random vs. Previous (50%+bonus; 50% no bonus)</cell></row><row><cell>Field Experiment 2</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>initial choice: Random vs. Previous</cell></row><row><cell>Task 2.1</cell><cell>bonus offered to the not chosen one</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>final choice: stay or switch</cell></row><row><cell>Task 2.2</cell><cell>toss the coin to determine to which one goes the bonus (TCDB) Random vs. Distinctive (either one might be with a bonus)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Field Exp. 1: Choices across the two tasks: joint and marginal proportionsSimilarly, in Task 1.2, in a choice between a Random and a Previous sequence, the vast majority of the 260 subjects, namely 77%, preferred the Random ticket(Table 7, Panel A), as in the lab experiment. Naturally, this tendency was weaker when the alternative (Previous) was</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Panel A: Decisions across the two tasks (in %)</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Task 1.1 \ Task 1.2 Random Previous</cell><cell cols="2">Total</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>60</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Distinctive +bonus 28</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>40</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>77</cell><cell>23</cell><cell cols="2">100 (N=260)</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Panel B1: R vs. D + bonus and R vs. P; subjects who were not</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">offered a bonus to P (in %)</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Task 1.1 \ Task 1.2 Random Previous</cell><cell cols="2">Total</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>57</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Distinctive +bonus 35</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>43</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>80</cell><cell>20</cell><cell cols="2">100 (N=130)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">2 (1) = 0.01;</cell><cell>= 0.93</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Panel B2: R vs. D + bonus and R vs. P; subjects who were</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">offered a bonus to P (in %)</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Task 1.1 \ Task 1.2 Random Previous</cell><cell cols="2">Total</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell>52</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>62</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Distinctive +bonus 22</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>38</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>74</cell><cell>26</cell><cell cols="2">100 (N=130)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">2 (1) = 11.36;</cell><cell>= 0.001</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Field Exp.1 and 2: Choices and beliefs about probability</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="7">Panel A: Field exp. 1: Choices in Random vs. Previous and beliefs about their</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">probability</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Which has a greater chance?</cell></row><row><cell>R vs. P</cell><cell cols="2">Random</cell><cell>Previous</cell><cell>Equal</cell><cell>Other</cell><cell>Total</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell>98</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>43</cell><cell>33</cell><cell>81</cell></row><row><cell>Previous</cell><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell>100</cell><cell>57</cell><cell>67</cell><cell>19</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Total</cell><cell>74</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>100 (N=198*)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>and beliefs</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">about the probability</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Which has a greater chance?</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Final choice Random</cell><cell>Previous</cell><cell>Equal</cell><cell>Other</cell><cell>Total</cell></row><row><cell>Stay</cell><cell>71</cell><cell></cell><cell>4</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>100 (N=167)</cell></row><row><cell>Switch</cell><cell>16</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>84</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>100 (N=32)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>62</cell><cell></cell><cell>3.5</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>2.5</cell><cell>100 (N=199)</cell></row></table><note>Note: *the first 62 subjects were not asked this question, hence the smaller sample size Panel B: Field exp. 2: Stay or switch choice in Random vs. Previous</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>CRT</cell><cell>Random</cell><cell>Distinctive + bonus</cell><cell>Total</cell></row><row><cell>Correct (15%)</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>62</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>Intuitive (79%)</cell><cell>62</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>Other (6%)</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>25</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Panel B1: Choice in R vs. P without bonus</cell></row><row><cell>CRT</cell><cell cols="2">Random Previous</cell><cell>Total</cell></row><row><cell>Correct (13%)</cell><cell>76</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>Intuitive (79%)</cell><cell>80</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>Other (8%)</cell><cell>90</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Panel B2: Choice in R vs. P with bonus</cell></row><row><cell>CRT</cell><cell>Random</cell><cell>Previous + bonus</cell><cell>Total</cell></row><row><cell>Correct (17%)</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>Intuitive (78%)</cell><cell>77</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>Other (5%)</cell><cell>83</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>100</cell></row></table><note>Field Experiment 1: Choices in Random vs. Distinctive with direct bonus and Random vs. Previous and CRT results Panel A: Choice in R vs. D (D always with a bonus)</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 10 .</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Field Experiment 2: Choices in Random vs. Previous, Random vs. Distinctive and across tasks</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">Panel A: Choices in Random vs. Previous</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Final Choice</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Initial preference</cell><cell>Stay</cell><cell>Switch</cell><cell>Total</cell></row><row><cell>Random (87%)</cell><cell>88</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>Previous (13%)</cell><cell>58</cell><cell>42</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>84</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>100 (N=199)</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Panel B: Choices in Random vs. Distinctive, depending on the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bonus</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Choice</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Bonus added to</cell><cell>Random</cell><cell>Distinctive</cell><cell>Total</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell>77</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>100 (N=95)</cell></row><row><cell>Distinctive</cell><cell>56</cell><cell>44</cell><cell>100 (N=104)</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>66</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>100 (N=199)</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Panel C: Choices across the initial choice in R vs. P and R vs. D</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Initial choice in R vs. P</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Choice in R vs. D</cell><cell>Random</cell><cell>Previous</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell>66</cell><cell>62</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Distinctive</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>38</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Total (N=199)</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Pearson 2 (1) = 0.2448; Pr = 0.621</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 11 .</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Field Experiment 2: Choices in Random vs. Distinctive and Random vs. Previous and CRT resultsPanel A: Choices in R vs. P and CRT responses (N=199)</figDesc><table><row><cell>CRT</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Are there people who often play games of chance among your close friends or family? Hello, I represent the University of Warsaw, where we are conducting a scientific study. Now I have one more choice for you. Once again, the two tickets differ only in the numbers chosen. You can choose this one[pointing at Random]  or this one [pointing at Previous], whereby this one [again pointing at Previous] contains only the numbers which have just won in the previous drawing today at 14:00/yesterday at 21:40 [depending on the time of experimentation].[If the experiment plan shows to add a bonus of 1zł to this subject, we add: To this one [again pointing at Previous] I will add 1zł in cash.] You will receive whichever you choose. As the last task, I have a riddle for you. I will read it out loud, but you can also see it for yourself printed here. Here, I have two lottery tickets for a Multi Multi game. In Multi Multi, out of numbers from 1 to 80, 20 numbers are drawn twice daily, and you can bet on up to 10 numbersas in the present case. On each of the tickets, ten numbers are already chosen, and the two tickets differ only in these numbers. Both of them are for the next drawing, and if all ten numbers are drawn, there is a guaranteed prize of 250,000 PLN; the fewer numbers match, the smaller the prize and all the prizes are guaranteed regardless of the numbers chosen by other players.You can choose this one[pointing at Random]  or this one [pointing at Previous], whereby this one [again pointing at Previous] contains only the numbers which have just won in the previous drawing today at 14:00/yesterday at 21:40 [depending on the time of experimentation]. Please have a look and indicate your choice.What if I add 1zł in cash to this one [indicating the one which they did not choose]. Will you choose this or this? You will receive whatever you choose.</figDesc><table><row><cell>O No A2. The wording of the Field experiment 1 Do you have primary, secondary, or higher education? [If higher, then we ask: What did you</cell></row><row><cell>study?]</cell></row><row><cell>3. O There are no such people [INTRO] May I take a couple of minutes of your time? In return, I have a pre-paid lottery ticket for you for Do you sometimes play the lottery, Lotto, or other games of chance?</cell></row><row><cell>a Multi Multi game from LOTTO. Do you sometimes knock on unpainted wood, blow on a found coin, or perform any activities of O There is one such person [If YES, then:] O There are several such people this type?</cell></row><row><cell>O There are many such people Do you consider yourself a believer?</cell></row><row><cell>[TASK 1: Random vs. Distinctive] Here, I have two lottery tickets for a Multi Multi game. In Multi</cell></row><row><cell>the two tickets differ only in these numbers. Both of them are for the next drawing, and if all ten this type? 10 numbers -as in the present case. On each of the tickets, ten numbers are already chosen, and 4. Do you sometimes knock on unpainted wood, blow on a found coin, or perform any activities of Multi, out of numbers from 1 to 80, 20 numbers are drawn twice daily, and you can bet on up to That is all; thank you. Have a nice day.</cell></row><row><cell>O Yes numbers are drawn, there is a guaranteed prize of 250,000 PLN; the fewer numbers match, the A3. The wording of the Field experiment 2</cell></row><row><cell>6. On each round of a game, 20 marbles are distributed at random among five children: Adaś, Boguś, O No smaller the prize and all the prizes are guaranteed regardless of the numbers chosen by other</cell></row><row><cell>Czarek, Daniel, and Edzio. Consider the following distributions: I II Adaś 4 Adaś 4 Boguś 4 Boguś players. [INTRO] Hello, I represent the University of Warsaw, where we are conducting a scientific study. 5. Do you consider yourself a religious person? May I take a couple of minutes of your time? In return, I have a pre-paid lottery ticket for you for You can choose either this one [pointing at Random] or this one [pointing at Distinctive], to which O Yes a Multi Multi game from LOTTO. I will add 1zł in cash. Please look at them and choose the one you prefer -you will receive it for 4 Czarek 5 Czarek 4 Daniel 4 Daniel O No free. [If YES, then:] 6. In what year were you born? …………………. 4 Edzio 3 Edzio 4 In many rounds of the game, will there be more results of type I or of type II? Answer: I / II Questionnaire 1. How often do you play other lotteries from Totalizator Sportowy (e.g., Lotto, scratch cards), bet on sports results, play cards for money, visit (online) casinos, or do similar things? 7. Gender: O male 8. What is your education level? O primary O secondary O higher or currently studying at a higher level ▪ field of study: ………………….…………………. [TASK 2: Random vs. Previous] Can you please tell me why you chose this one? O female [subject choosing and receiving the ticket with/without the bonus] [TASK 1: Random vs. Previous]</cell></row><row><cell>O Once a week or more 9. Which of the following terms best describes your household? [This question was added after the first 62 observations] Do any of these have a greater chance of O We live very poorly -we don't have enough for our basic needs being drawn? O Once, twice, or three times a month O We live modestly -we have to manage economically every day O Several times a year O Once or several times in my life O Never O We live on average -we have enough money for everyday living, but we have to save for major purchases O We live well -we can afford much without saving [CRT] A pencil and a pen together cost one złoty and ten groszy [1.10zł]. The pen costs one złoty</cell></row><row><cell>2. If you happen to play, do you sometimes do it together with friends or family? O We live very well -we can afford some luxury more than a pencil. How much does the pencil cost?</cell></row><row><cell>Now only a few demographic questions left, okay? O Yes If you have already answered all of the questions in this form, please go with it to the payout desk to receive remuneration. What is your age?</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Table B2</head><label>B2</label><figDesc>Lab exp.: Percent choosing Random over other types of sequences</figDesc><table><row><cell>R over Distinctive:</cell><cell>72%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">R over M1: 71%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">R over M5: 74%</cell></row><row><cell>R over Previous</cell><cell>69%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">R over Previous 1: 68%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">R over Previous 2: 71%</cell></row><row><cell>R over Distant</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Previous:</cell><cell>67%</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>Table B3</head><label>B3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="8">Lab exp.: Correlation between lottery choices (Choosing Random) and RH puzzles</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Choosing Random</cell><cell>Linda normative</cell><cell>Taxis normative</cell><cell>Hospitals normative</cell><cell>Families normative</cell><cell>High schools normative</cell><cell>Marbles normative</cell></row><row><cell>Choosing</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Linda</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>normative</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Taxis</cell><cell>-0.12</cell><cell>-0.07</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>normative</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell>0.35</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Hospitals</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.20</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>normative</cell><cell>0.25</cell><cell>0.21</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Families</cell><cell>0.15</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell>0.003</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>normative</cell><cell>0.06</cell><cell>0.25</cell><cell>0.96</cell><cell>0.15</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>High schools</cell><cell>-0.19</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell>0.06</cell><cell>-0.22</cell><cell>1.00</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>normative</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>0.86</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.46</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Marbles</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>-0.05</cell><cell>-0.01</cell><cell>0.24</cell><cell>-0.19</cell><cell>1.00</cell></row><row><cell>normative</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell>0.19</cell><cell>0.51</cell><cell>0.90</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head>Table B4</head><label>B4</label><figDesc>Lab exp.: Correlation between demographics and lottery choices</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">gambling habits education R over DP income</cell><cell cols="7">gambling habits 1.00 0.67 0.04 -0.10 gambling habits syndicate 0.17 0.02 gambling habits of others 0.32 superstitiou s 0.11 religious 0.02 0.14 0.05 0.04 0.12 1.00 0.60 0.21 0.07 0.54 0.61 0.13 0.24 1.00 0.00</cell><cell>age 0.00 1.00</cell><cell>female 1.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="9">gambling habits syndicate gambling habits Linda Table B5 normative Lab exp.: Correlation between demographics and RH puzzles 0.10 1.00 0.19 -0.14 -0.04 1.00 0.05 0.02 1.00 0.52 0.82 Taxis -0.02 -0.04 -0.07 1.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">of others superstitious normative religious Hospitals normative Families gambling habits normative age female education income R over Dist.(M1) R(1) over Dist.(M5) R(2) over Dist.(M5) R over P1 R over P2 R over DP Taxis normative Linda normative income education female age religious superstitious gambling habits syndicate High schools normative Marbles gambling habits of others normative</cell><cell cols="2">0.07 -0.10 0.77 0.20 -0.08 0.34 gambling habits 0.11 0.14 0.28 -0.19 1.00 0.00 0.01 0.14 0.08 0.18 0.02 0.04 0.59 0.07 0.41 0.16 0.04 0.05 0.57 0.04 0.62 0.13 0.10 0.07 0.36 0.82 0.02 0.88 0.01 0.59 0.04 0.02 0.18 0.08 0.14 0.01 -0.19 0.34 -0.08 0.20 -0.10 0.10 -0.08 0.32 0.19 -0.14 0.15 0.07 0.05</cell><cell cols="2">0.65 -0.07 0.65 0.38 -0.04 0.58 gambling habits syndicate 0.13 0.09 -0.01 0.22 0.86 0.01 0.04 0.63 -0.09 0.26 -0.04 0.62 -0.03 0.74 0.05 0.50 0.09 0.24 0.13 0.09 0.13 0.09 0.08 0.31 0.40 0.07 0.03 -0.17 0.62 -0.04 0.26 -0.09 0.63 0.04 0.01 0.22 0.58 -0.04 0.38 -0.07 0.07 1.00 0.39 -0.04 -0.13 0.65 0.11</cell><cell cols="3">0.20 0.01 0.11 0.17 gambling 0.35 habits of others 0.10 0.20 superstitiou 1.00 0.13 1.00 0.21 0.01 s 0.09 0.00 0.11 0.09 0.04 0.20 -0.06 1.00 religious 1.00 0.25 0.96 0.15 0.61 0.01 0.49 0.05 0.33 0.07 0.52 0.00 0.38 -0.13 -0.06 0.04 -0.28 1.00 0.12 0.13 0.10 0.47 0.60 0.00 0.02 -0.17 -0.20 -0.02 0.81 0.03 0.01 0.77 -0.05 -0.10 0.10 -0.08 0.54 0.21 0.21 0.31 0.08 -0.13 -0.02 -0.15 0.31 0.10 0.76 0.05 0.08 -0.10 0.06 -0.18 0.30 0.23 0.48 0.02 -0.17 0.03 0.10 0.03 0.03 0.75 0.21 0.70 -0.03 -0.13 0.01 0.01 0.66 0.11 0.95 0.88 0.08 -0.08 0.10 -0.02 0.33 0.32 0.21 0.84 0.54 0.69 0.81 0.05 0.03 -0.02 0.99 0.45 0.57 0.00 -0.06 0.04 -0.20 age 0.98 0.00 0.01 0.81 0.03 0.01 0.77 0.02 -0.17 -0.20 -0.02 0.10 0.47 0.60 0.00 -0.13 -0.06 0.04 -0.28 0.52 0.00 0.38 0.13 0.05 0.33 0.07 0.12 0.61 0.01 0.49 0.04 0.20 -0.05 1.00 0.17 0.09 0.11 0.13 1.00 0.01 0.20 1.00 0.01 0.13 0.06 -0.22 1.00 0.86 0.10 0.46 0.00 1.00 0.10 -0.05 -0.01 0.24 -0.19 -0.04 female 1.00 0.20 -0.10 -0.03 -0.16 -0.06 -0.13 0.03 0.44 0.06 0.74 0.78 0.02 0.10 0.65 -0.04 0.49 0.01 0.19 0.04 1.00 0.75 0.19 0.65 0.01 1.00 0.19 0.51 0.90 0.00 0.02</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">education income Hospitals 0.10 normative 0.18 education Families 0.09 1.00 normative 0.24</cell><cell cols="2">R over Dist.(M1) 0.07 0.34 -0.07 0.39</cell><cell cols="2">R(1) over Dist.(M5) -0.04 0.63 -0.10 0.22</cell><cell>R(2) over Dist.(M5) -0.09 0.26 -0.14 0.06</cell><cell>R over P1 R over P2 -0.14 -0.14 R over 0.07 0.07 DP 0.00 -0.19 0.99 0.02</cell><cell>-0.17 0.03 0.06 0.43</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">income High schools normative R over Dist.(M1) Marbles normative</cell><cell cols="3">0.24 -0.08 0.32 0.00 0.19 -0.03 1.00 0.02 0.69 0.13 0.10</cell><cell cols="2">-0.08 0.29 1.00 0.08 0.31</cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.02 0.78 -0.05 0.51</cell><cell>0.12 0.12 -0.15 0.05</cell><cell>-0.12 0.14 0.00 0.99</cell><cell>-0.01 0.92 -0.06 0.42</cell><cell>-0.08 0.33 -0.04 0.57</cell></row><row><cell>R(1) over</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.17</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.15</cell><cell cols="2">0.17</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Dist.(M5)</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.06</cell><cell cols="2">0.03</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>R(2) over Dist.(M5) R over P1</cell><cell cols="4">0.19 0.02 -0.01 0.94 education income 0.08 0.28 -0.12 0.13</cell><cell cols="3">0.25 0.00 0.10 0.19 Linda normative</cell><cell>0.24 0.00 -0.11 0.16 Taxis normative</cell><cell>1.00 0.15 0.06 Hospitals normative</cell><cell>1.00 Families normative</cell><cell>High schools normative</cell><cell>Marbles normativ e</cell></row><row><cell>R over P2</cell><cell cols="2">-0.03</cell><cell cols="2">-0.11</cell><cell cols="2">0.18</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell>0.19</cell><cell>1.00</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16"><head>Table B6</head><label>B6</label><figDesc>Field Exp. 1: Determinants of choosing R rather than D; probit analysis</figDesc><table><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>r0</cell><cell>r1</cell><cell>r2</cell><cell>r3</cell></row><row><cell>male</cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.07</cell><cell>-0.18</cell><cell>-0.13</cell></row><row><cell>male_exp</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.29</cell></row><row><cell>male_male_experimenter</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.11</cell></row><row><cell>age</cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.00</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>religious</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.20**</cell><cell>0.19**</cell><cell>0.18**</cell></row><row><cell>superstitious</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.17</cell><cell>0.19</cell><cell>0.19</cell></row><row><cell>only_high_school</cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.01</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.10</cell></row><row><cell>gambling_intensity</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>-0.01</cell><cell>-0.02</cell></row><row><cell>CRT_correct</cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.62**</cell><cell>-0.82**</cell><cell>-0.80**</cell></row><row><cell>Distinctive: medium</cell><cell>-0.23</cell><cell>-0.07</cell><cell>-0.18</cell><cell>-0.18</cell></row><row><cell>Distinctive: high</cell><cell>-0.20</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>-0.02</cell><cell>-0.03</cell></row><row><cell>Distinctive: distance 5</cell><cell>-0.14</cell><cell>-0.13</cell><cell>-0.24</cell><cell>-0.25</cell></row><row><cell>Random displayed on the right</cell><cell>0.19</cell><cell>0.30</cell><cell>0.38*</cell><cell>0.37*</cell></row><row><cell>Day of the week and Location dummies</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Note: legend: * p&lt;0.1; ** p&lt;0.05; *** p&lt;0.01</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">This is not true in games with a pari-mutuel format, such as Lotto, in which the jackpot, which is shared among the players who matched all the numbers, corresponds to a significant part of the expected payoff. This means that in expectation, the losses are larger if one bets on popular combinations, so that the jackpot, if won at all, will have to be shared with many other players.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Of course, multiples of 10 would have been even more prominent given our decimal system, but it would have been impossible to implement as there are only eight numbers ending with a zero in Multi Multi.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">In Poland: 52% female; population mean age 42, standard deviation 22 years.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">That fraction for Warsaw is 55% and 26% for Poland. The validity of this comparison is slightly limited by the fact that these official statistics are calculated for the population aged 15-64, whereas our subjects' ages ranged between 18 and 76.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">This analysis also suggests that more religious individuals are more likely to choose the Random ticket, foregoing the bonus.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">That said, in KR19 and in the two-stage choice between Random and Previous reported here, we tried to minimize such a possibility, in particular the subjects did not physically receive the ticket after their initial choice.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Appendix A: Wording of the Lab experiment (A1), and Field experiments 1 (A2), 2 (A3)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A1. The wording of the Lab experiment</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions</head><p>Welcome to the experiment. We ask you to turn off your mobile phones and not communicate with other participants in any way. If you have a question, raise your hand.</p><p>The experiment consists of two parts (and a questionnaire). You will receive 10 zł for participating in this study and a lottery ticket worth 15 zł for the Multi Multi lottery. When you answer all the questions that this form contains, approach the payout desk outside the room. The entire study is anonymous.  </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why are people reluctant to exchange lottery tickets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bar-Hillel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Neter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.70.1.17</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.70.1.17" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contrarian profits and representativeness heuristic in the MENA stock markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Boussaidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Alsaggaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.socec.2021.101820</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2021.101820" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual differences in adult decision-making competence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bruine De Bruin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fischhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.92.5.938</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.92.5.938" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="938" to="956" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trading performance, disposition effect, overconfidence, representativeness bias, and experience of emerging market investors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Nofsinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="425" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.561</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.561" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The representativeness heuristic and the conjunction fallacy effect in children&apos;s decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Merrill-Palmer Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="328" to="346" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual differences in intuitiveexperiential and analytical-rational thinking styles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pacini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Denes-Raj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Heier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.71.2.390</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.71.2.390" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="390" to="405" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fernández-Aguilar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Martín-Martín</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lorenzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fernández Ajuria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Use of heuristics during the clinical decision process from family care physicians in real conditions</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="141" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/jep.13608</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/jep.13608" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive reflection and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Frederick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1257/089533005775196732</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1257/089533005775196732" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do higher prices signal higher quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/002224378502200210</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/002224378502200210" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to make cognitive illusions disappear: Beyond &quot;heuristics and biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Review of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14792779143000033</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14792779143000033" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The natural catastrophe protection gap: Measurement, root causes and ways of addressing underinsurance for extreme events. The Geneva Papers on Risk and Insurance -Issues and Practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Holzheu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1057/s41288-017-0075-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1057/s41288-017-0075-y" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="71" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of affect on heuristic thinking in insurance demand</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Jaspersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Aseervatham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Insurance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/jori.12088</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/jori.12088" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective probability: A judgment of representativeness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0010-0285(72)90016-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0010-0285(72" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90016" to="90019" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Authoritarianism and its relationship with intuitive-experiential cognitive style and heuristic processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kemmelmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.paid.2009.08.012</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.paid.2009.08.012" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The representativeness heuristic and the choice of lottery tickets: A field experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Krawczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rachubik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Construction workers&apos; representativeness heuristic in decision making: The impact of demographic factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Xiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1061/(ASCE)CO.1943-7862.0002249</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)CO.1943-7862.0002249" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Construction Engineering and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">148</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality and judgment heuristics: Contextual and individual difference interactions in social judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gonzalez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167297231008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167297231008" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Popular induction: Information is not necessarily informative</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nisbett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Borgida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Crandall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Cognition and social behavior. Lawrence Erlbaum</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference by believers in the law of small numbers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/003355302760193896</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/003355302760193896" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="775" to="816" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Another look at why people are reluctant to exchange lottery tickets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Risen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.93.1.12</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.93.1.12" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring both systems of reasoning: A study of the predictive capacity of a new version of the Rational-Experiential Inventory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sánchez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Fernández-Berrocal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Alonso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tumau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.30552/ejep.v5i2.85</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.30552/ejep.v5i2.85" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Education and Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">121</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stability/instability of cognitive strategies across tasks determine whether stress will affect judgmental processes&apos;</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shaham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Schaeffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1559-1816.1992.tb00998.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1559-1816.1992.tb00998.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="713" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual differences in rational and intuitive thinking styles as predictors of heuristic responses and framing effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shiloh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sharabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0191-8869(01)00034-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0191-8869(01)00034-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Politicians, the representativeness heuristic and decision-making biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stolwijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Vis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11109-020-09594-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11109-020-09594-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1411" to="1432" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual differences in reasoning: Implications for the rationality debate?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stanovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="665" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X00003435</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X00003435" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the relative independence of thinking biases and cognitive ability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stanovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="672" to="695" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.94.4.672</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.94.4.672" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biases in casino betting: The hot hand and the gambler&apos;s fallacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sundali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Croson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual differences in cognitive biases: Evidence against one-factor theory of rationality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Teovanović</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Knežević</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Stankov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.intell.2015.02.008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intell.2015.02.008" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Cognitive Reflection Test as a predictor of performance on heuristics-and-biases tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Toplak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stanovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13421-011-0104-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-011-0104-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1275" to="1289" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgment under uncertainty: Heuristics and biases: Biases in judgments reveal some heuristics of thinking under uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.185.4157.1124</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.185.4157.1124" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">185</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1124" to="1131" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extensional versus intuitive reasoning: The conjunction fallacy in probability judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.90.4.293</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.90.4.293" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The reflective mind: Examining individual differences in susceptibility to base rate neglect with fMRI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Vartanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Beatty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Blackler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Lam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Forbes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>De Neys</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1011" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/jocn_a_01264</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn_a_01264" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Number preferences in lotteries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J D</forename><surname>Potter Van Loon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Den Assem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Dolder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.2657776</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2657776" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SSRN Electronic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
