<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Shoot or pass? Humans can prepare to move for different purposes in parallel</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsubasa</forename><surname>Wakatsuki</surname></persName>
							<email>t.wakatsuki1994@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Health and Sport Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chukyo University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toyota</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoya</forename><surname>Hibino</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Toyoda Gosei Scorpions</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Toyoda Gosei Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kiyosu</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takehito</forename><surname>Hirakawa</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">School of Physical Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Osaka University of Health and Sport Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Sennan</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norimasa</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">School of Health and Sport Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chukyo University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toyota</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<address>
									<addrLine>101 Tokodachi, Kaizu-cho</addrLine>
									<postCode>470-0393</postCode>
									<settlement>Toyota</settlement>
									<region>Aichi</region>
									<country key="JP">JAPAN</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Shoot or pass? Humans can prepare to move for different purposes in parallel</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:06+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Uncertainty</term>
					<term>Time constraint</term>
					<term>Dynamic decision-making</term>
					<term>Multistability</term>
					<term>Serial and parallel</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Just as Rubin&apos;s vase can appear to be a vase or two faces, multiple perceptual states can be present on a single time axis. However, it is difficult to understand how this theoretical concept can be applied to physical movements that eventually converge to a single state. We focused on the change in motion from shooting to passing during a jump shot in basketball and examined how far the shooter can respond to the change when the purpose, which was initially uncertain, is suddenly clarified. The timing of the visual stimuli presentation, which signifies the change in purpose to a pass, was strictly controlled, and 10 basketball players performed jump shots with the possibility of the purpose being changed to a pass. The shots maintained a high success rate regardless of the time at which the visual stimuli were turned on; furthermore, the success rate of the pass did not reach 0% until just before the ball was released (at least approximately 50 ms ago). These experimental results show that shooters can prepare to shoot and pass in parallel rather than in series. In a further validation experiment on kinematics during a possible change in purpose, strategies were observed in which individuals paused the elbow joint angle in mid-air and delayed the timing of the ball release. This is an example of how humans prepare to make multiple movements with different purposes in parallel, which can be transferred to either pattern if the movement is analogous to common motions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>In perceptual information processing, there are examples in which information is not handled by overlapping serial processing but by parallel processing (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Kelso, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Kienker et al., 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Livingstone &amp; Hubel, 1988)</ref>. When looking at an ambiguous figure, such as "Rubin's vase", at a given moment, only a vase (or two faces facing each other) comes to our attention; however, in the background, we also perceive two faces facing each other <ref type="bibr">(or a vase)</ref>. Depending on what is in the forefront of the conscious mind by self-organization, this single figure appears to be either a vase or a face <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Kelso, 1995)</ref>.</p><p>A graphical stimulus with that property is called a multistable stimulus <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Eagleman, 2001)</ref>, which indicates that there may be at least two perceptual states on a single time axis. The above are examples of figure perception, i.e., static images; however, if we focus on sports situations, we are also able to identify many examples of dynamic multistability. Taking baseball batting as an example, a batter waits for a fastball (or slow ball); however, when the time comes, batters are able to handle a slow ball (or fastball). The batter's swing is not a predetermined swing, which means that the batter has two possibilities, a fastball and a slow ball, and tries to respond to each. In recent years, this batter's strategy has received increasing attention, and the underlying mechanisms have been investigated using matching timing tasks, such as the subject's time estimation and prior distribution based on Bayesian estimation models <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Jazayeri &amp; Shadlen, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Miyazaki et al., 2005)</ref>, and identifying when the prior distribution is learned <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Roach et al., 2017)</ref>. However, these are only patterns identified based on experience and do not include the idea of parallel preparation of both movements in a common motion that can generate two movements with different purposes.</p><p>A concept that is helpful when considering this idea is the response to a target that changes during the execution of a movement <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Gutiérrez-Dávila et al., 2013a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, 2013b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, 2013c</ref>. In these studies, the participants, who were fencing attackers, performed by changing the direction of the sword tip in response to a target that suddenly moves from its initial position during the attack. Generalizing this situation corresponds to a response in which one must choose from several possibilities that could be presented as a stimulus, and a behavior tied to that stimulus must be generated. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gutiérrez-Dávila et al. (2013c)</ref>, the mean choice reaction time is 186 milliseconds (hereafter "ms") for one movement direction for a target and 243 ms for three movement directions for a target. However, this situation can be described as a response in which a person only changes direction within the same purpose; in actual sports, a more complex situation is observed in terms of cognitive aspects. For example, in basketball, if a shooter jumps for a shot but the defender attempts to a block shot, he must change his purpose to pass to a teammate and then control the direction in which he throws the ball. Shooting and passing have different purposes and therefore have different motions, for which the most significant differences were noted in the ball-releasing height and the angle of projection. In basic shooting, the ball is held over one's head <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Knudson, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr"></ref> 3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Krause &amp; Craig, 2018)</ref>, and the higher the releasing height is, the higher the success rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Tran &amp; Silverberg, 2008)</ref>. In contrast, the overhead pass <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Krause &amp; Craig, 2018)</ref> is the only way in which the ball is released from overhead, aside from basic shooting; however, there is a significant difference between the releasing height of an overhead pass and that of a jump shot because an overhead pass essentially does not involve jumping. The ideal angle of projection for shooting is 45 degrees or more <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Knudson, 2007)</ref>; basketball players in particular are known to shoot the ball at angles of 49 to 55 degrees <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Knudson, 1993)</ref>.</p><p>In contrast, the fastest and most commonly used of the many types of passes is the air pass (= chest pass) <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Krause &amp; Craig, 2018)</ref>; however, in this pass, the ball is released straight from the chest and has an extremely small angle of projection. Parabolic lob passes, such as a shot, are also used; however, the low velocity of these passes limits the situations in which they can be used, and they are not used frequently in real games <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Krause &amp; Craig, 2018)</ref>. Therefore, we can understand that although shooting and passing during jump-shooting begin with the common movement of holding the ball overhead and jumping up, there are clear differences in the characteristics of both movements. In other words, the decision to shoot or pass during a jump shot in basketball involves not only a simple change in direction but also a change in purpose. This is decision-making and would be one example of "dynamic decision-making (DDM)", where decisions are made in real time (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bakker et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brehmer, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Edwards, 1962;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Michalski et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Raßbach et al., 2021)</ref>. We therefore consider the idea of parallel preparation of two movements generated from a common motion, focusing on the change in purpose and motion from shooting to passing that is often observed during a basketball game.</p><p>Basketball players must determine and execute appropriate actions in a complex dynamic and time-constrained environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(van Maarseveen et al., 2018)</ref>, and creating a more advantageous situation in the smallest unit of interpersonal interaction, the 1-vs.-1 condition, can be an important factor in determining the outcome of a match <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Duarte et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Esteves et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Tsutsui et al., 2019)</ref>. One way to do this is to generate a spatial gap in the dueling process with the opponent. In basketball, in addition to the lateral gaps generated by dribbling skills, such as crossovers, and developing a way to catch the ball called "meeting the ball" <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Krause &amp; Craig, 2018)</ref>, players are able to create more advantageous situations by effectively utilizing the vertical gaps generated by jumping movements. A typical example of a jumping motion in basketball and a technique that directly leads to scoring is a jump shot. The jump shot is able to generate a greater vertical gap than other techniques since the ball is released at a higher position and is the most effective shooting skill in terms of accuracy, velocity, protection against opponents, and execution from several distances <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Okazaki et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>While the jump shot has many advantages, it also has a disadvantage: once the player moves into the shooting motion and both feet leave the ground, it is not ideal to land with the ball in hand. This action 4 would then be a travelling violation (FIBA (International Basketball Federation), 2020a); therefore, the ball must be removed from the hands in a short period of time between take-off and landing. For example, if the player judges that the execution of shooting is impossible due to interference by defenders, it is necessary to change the purpose from shooting to passing and must generate the corresponding behavior.</p><p>However, before that time, the purpose for the shooter is uncertain, since there is still a small possibility of passing the ball. If we compare this situation to the example of Rubin's vase described at the beginning, for the shooter, the shot is equivalent to the vase, and the pass is equivalent to the two faces (and vice versa). At any one point in time, the uncertain purpose becomes certain; at what point in time is the shooter able to respond accurately?</p><p>Up to this point, we have discussed the necessity of rapid movement changes during jump shots. <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Morya et al. (2003)</ref> examined the response of soccer players to sudden target changes based on rigorous simulated experiments. They conducted a laboratory simulation experiment using a paradigm in which the target changed during motion and provided basic insights by examining the kickers' strategies and temporal boundaries necessary to achieve a high probability of successful penalty kicks. However, van der <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Kamp (2006)</ref> pointed out that in Morya et al.'s experiment, which was constructed by computer simulation, the constraints imposed on both motor and perception are vastly different from those of a "reallife" penalty kick and reviewed their findings. van der Kamp (2006) provided a very interesting, but unintentional, insight in a field simulation experiment on penalty kicks. It is possible that the success rate is not 0% even if a stimulus is presented that influences the direction of the kick just before the foot contacts the ball. If we assume that right-to-left (or left-to-right) changes in direction are made by continuous rewriting of the motor program, i.e., that the information processing of movement is serial, the time needed to execute the movement will increase compared to the case with no change (theoretically, it would double). Furthermore, since the reaction time to choose a dynamic target <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Gutiérrez-Dávila et al., 2013a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, 2013b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, 2013c</ref> is also involved here, it would be natural to assume that after a certain point, the movement cannot be changed. However, considering the fact that there can be multiple perceptual states on a single time axis and that a baseball batter skillfully responds to a breaking ball while waiting for a fastball, it is quite possible that if the different movements begin with a common movement even if their purposes are different, such as kicking and batting, the movements can be prepared simultaneously (in parallel) and adjusted to fit the purpose as it becomes evident. This is exactly the relationship between shooting and passing during a jump shot. As mentioned above, since the change from shooting to passing is not a simple change in direction but also includes movement changes, it would therefore be meaningful and appropriate to attempt to examine the parallel preparation of the two movements using the change in purpose from shooting to passing during jump-shooting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5</head><p>Although van der <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Kamp (2006)</ref> made interesting suggestions, we would like to point out certain problems in the method of stimuli presentation and taking samples. He calculated a posteriori the severity of temporal pressure, i.e., the time it takes for the kicker's foot to contact the ball, by having the experimenter present the stimulus at various times. Although a posteriori classification of states may seem unproblematic at first glance, it leads to statistical ambiguity due to the lack of an aligned sample, as well as a situation where a class (= condition) for analysis with a small number of samples (close to zero extremely) is created. For example, if the number of samples between 100 ms and 200 ms is 0, the interval may need to be extended from 50 ms to 250 ms to ensure a certain number of samples. In fact, van der <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Kamp (2006)</ref> noted that only two types of data were obtained in trials in which the stimulus was presented just before the foot contacted the ball, i.e., trials in which time pressure was greatest. The possibility of a nonzero success rate even with greater temporal pressure, mentioned in the previous paragraph, also only alludes to these two trials, and its great importance is overlooked due to the small sample size. A methodical solution to this issue is to strictly control the timing of stimulus presentation beforehand through programming to ensure the same number of samples at all presentation timings. This method would not only help to maintain statistical reliability but also provide help explain how the delay of timing in clarifying the purpose of shot or pass affects the success rate of changes in motion.</p><p>In this study, we strictly controlled the timing of the stimulus, prior to its presentation, which directs the change in purpose from shooting to passing. This stimulus is separated by a fixed time interval from before take-off to just before the ball is released for a jump shot. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gutiérrez-Dávila et al. (2013a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, 2013b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, 2013c</ref> detected reaction times for choosing a course of action when the target changes during the movement, and although the intended movement is different, it is considered that these times are part of the necessary time for a motion change from shooting to passing. In other words, if the shooter is preparing simultaneously (in parallel) to shoot the ball, which is the base motion, and decides to pass, which requires a change in motion, the success rates of the passing trial are not zero until just before the ball is released, although the success rate of the shot is maintained, as if to ignore the minimum required reaction time to choose a course of action. On the other hand, if the success rate of the pass trial reaches zero at any point in time, the change in motion from shooting to passing is considered to have been made simply by continuous (serial) revision of the neural activity underlying motor behavior. By investigating the hypothesis above, we clarified the style of human information processing and motor control when individuals are deciding between the two possibilities. 6 2. Methods</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Participants</head><p>Ten skilled basketball players who were members of a university basketball team (experience = 11.2 ± 2.8 yrs [mean ± SD]) participated in this study. All participants were over 20 years old, right-handed, and had normal or corrected-to-normal vision. The experimental procedures were conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and were approved by the Human Subjects Committee at Chukyo University Graduate School of Health and Sport Sciences (approval number: 2018-12). Before conducting the experiment, the purpose of the study and experimental protocols were explained to the participants.</p><p>Written informed consent was obtained from all participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Protocol and apparatus</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1.">Experimental task</head><p>The participants dribbled a ball from the half-court line to the free throw line and attempted a jump shot. This is a basic movement and is defined as the shooting trial (without a change in purpose). On the other hand, a light-emitting diode (LED) was placed to the left and right of the participant, and if either LED illuminated, the participant must switch to make a jump pass to the receiver in that direction. Regardless of the direction, any trial in which either LED illuminated was defined as a passing trial (with a change in purpose). In other words, this change in direction task <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Morya et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">van der Kamp, 2006)</ref> has the characteristics of a Go/No-Go procedure <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Donders, 1969)</ref>; moreover, it is a task that includes a change in the movement itself, from shooting to passing, rather than a change in direction only as in a previous study <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(van der Kamp, 2006)</ref>. Each receiver and LED were placed on the extension of the vertical line forming the paint area, and the distance between the left and right receivers was approximately 4.9 meters (FIBA (International Basketball Federation), 2020a) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). The participant must shoot a basket if either LED does not light up; on the other hand, the participant must pass to a receiver waiting in that direction if the LED lights up.</p><p>In this experiment, the participants performed one shooting trial and two passing trials (once each on either side) for a total of three trials, five times each. The timing of the LED lighting used in the passing trials was determined and set from the premeasured hangtime of each participant (see below "Measurement of hangtime using a force plate"). The light timing was divided into eight conditions <ref type="bibr">(0, 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, and 70%)</ref> in increments of 10% from 0% to 70% when the time was normalized to 0% at the take-off time and 100% at the landing time for a total of nine conditions, including the before-jump condition (hereinafter the "BJ condition") in which the lights were turned on when both feet touched the ground ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). Therefore, the total number of trials performed by each participant was 135 (3 directions, 8 5 trials, and 9 conditions). To obtain a success rate for each condition not only in the passing trials in which the LED was lit but also in the shooting trials in which the LED was not lit, the experimenter informed the participants in advance of the condition to be implemented. The order of the type of trials and conditions were randomly determined by the experimenter and executed. Incidentally, the reason we included trials up to the 70% condition is that we confirmed in most of the preliminary experiments that the ball was already released at 80% of the hang time. The present experiment had a large physical stress in one trial, and it was necessary to eliminate useless trials as much as possible to avoid participant fatigue. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2.">Prior control of LED light timing by programming</head><p>One of the strong aspects of originality of this study is the strict control of the LED light timing. The experimental system was constructed by combining the graphic programming software LabVIEW (National Instruments, United States) and mat switch (Q'sfix, Japan). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3a</ref> shows the overall conceptual diagram of the experimental system, and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3b</ref> shows the conceptual diagram of the delay manipulation. The mat switch detects the participant's landing before the jump as ON and the take-off after the jump as OFF, and this electronic information is sent to LabVIEW.</p><p>Then, a delay manipulation of a preset time is performed within LabVIEW, and either the left or right 9 LED light is turned on. The BJ condition is programmed to light the LED at the moment the mat switch detects the ON condition, and the 0% condition is programmed to light the LED at the moment the mat switch detects the OFF condition afterward. Therefore, the ON/OFF information of the signal detected by the mat switch is used directly in these conditions (no delay manipulation). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3.">Measurement of the hang time and its within-individual error (preliminary experiment)</head><p>Before conducting the main experiment, two preliminary experiments were conducted to accurately control the timing at which the LEDs were lit (confirmation of experimental accuracy) and to examine the within-individual error in the hang time that determines the timing of LED lighting (confirmation of the inherent variability of human movement).</p><p>As mentioned above, the delay time was determined from the premeasured hang time of each participant for the seven conditions (except for the BJ and 0% conditions) in passing trials involving delay manipulation of LED illumination timing. A typical example of the ground reaction force (GRF) recorded in the first preliminary experiment conducted using a force plate (Bertec, United States, 1000 Hz) is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>. When the participants were instructed to jump as they would when making a jump shot after dribbling, which was done in the actual experiments, the mean hang time for all participants was 520 ms.</p><p>The illumination timing was controlled by sequentially importing the measured hang time of each participant into LabVIEW in each case. In other words, the ratio against the hang time was unified; however, the presentation timing was set differently for each participant. However, in the second 10 preliminary experiment in which the within-individual error in the hang time was confirmed by performing 10 jumps in which individuals assumed a jump shot was needed, an error of approximately 5.1% from the median value (positive direction: 2.3%, negative direction: 2.8%) was confirmed. Therefore, although the timing of the LED illumination was perfectly controlled, the experiment only slightly accounted for errors in human motor control. The flow of the experiment is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref>.  to measure the hang time and a main experiment using the data from the preliminary experiment. The participants were informed of the experimental conditions to be implemented before performing every time (3 and 7 in the figure). With this step, we were able to also obtain a success rate of shooting trials in which the LED was not lit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Data analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.1.">Success or failure in each trial</head><p>To make the experiment as close as possible to the actual game situation, two receivers were placed in front of the participants in the left and right directions (on the extension of the two vertical lines that make up the restricted area) as targets in the passing trials. Note that the receivers were volunteers and were not informed of the hypothesis of this study. As demonstrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, the receivers were instructed to hold both hands on their chest and not to extend their arms or step out to catch the ball themselves. The judgment criteria for the success or failure of passing trials were a circle with an approximate radius of 25 cm centered on the midpoint of the receiver's chest. A pass directly into this range was judged a success, while a pass that became dislodged from this range (including a shot) was judged to be a failure. The 25 cm radius circle was based on an inside diameter of 45 cm, which is the size of a basketball hoop (FIBA (International Basketball Federation), 2020b), and this range was equivalent to the range where the receiver could catch the ball without difficulty, as confirmed previously. An imaginary circle was used as one of the judgment criteria; however, since this experiment was based on a real situation, this was just a criterion for objectification, and we had the receivers report whether they could catch the pass without difficulty for each attempt. On the other hand, shooting trials were deemed successful if the ball passed through or the ball did not pass through the ring but hit the ring, and all other outcomes were judged as failures. In both the shooting and passing trials, landing with the ball in the hand was judged as a failure.</p><p>The receiver's hands, the target of the passing trials, were approximately 120 cm in height, and the ring, the target of the shooting trials, was 305 cm in height according to official rules (FIBA (International Basketball Federation), 2020b).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2.">Statistical comparison of success rates among conditions</head><p>The success or failure in each trial was judged based on the judgment criterion, and the success rate was calculated by dividing the number of successful trials by the number of target trials. Then, one-way ANOVA was used to detect the presence or absence of a main effect in shooting and passing trials, with a significance level of 0.05. The statistical analyses were performed using Mathematica 12 (Wolfram Research, United States). <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows the success rates for each participant. This table shows the success rates separately for shooting trials in which no LED was illuminated and for passing trials in which either the right or left LED was illuminated. In the shooting trials, no participant reached 0% in any condition, and half of the participants achieved 100% even in the 70% condition, where the time constraint was the strictest. On the other hand, in the passing trials, four out of ten participants did not reach 0% in any condition, and seven out of ten participants did not reach 0% in the 70% condition, where the time constraint was strictest.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">3  100   80  70  100  40  80  40  100  30  100  20  100  10  100  10  100  10   4  80  100  40  40  80  60  40  50  60  30  80  0  80  10  80  10  80  10   5  100   100  80  80  60  100  70  100  50  100  20  100  10  80  0  100  30   6  100   80  60  80  50  80  20  60  10  80  20  80  0  40  10  60  0   7  100   80  60  80  40  100  50  80  10  60  20  80  0  60  10  100  40   8  60   40  100  100  100  40  90  60  20  80  30  40  10  20  0  40  0   9  100   80  70  60  40  80  40  40  30  40  20  60  10  40  10  60  10   10  100  100  80  80  60  70  80  80  30  70  40  50  60  40  60  30  80  30   Mean  94   74  76  76  63  74  59  65  31  70  27  72  13  64  10  82</ref>  Note. The number of participants who did not reach a 0% success rate for passing trials in the 70% condition, which had the strictest time constraint, was 7 out of 10.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Success rates of trials with or without a change in purpose</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>13</head><p>Then, we confirmed the data depicted in the bar chart showing the mean and SD of the above results ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6</ref>). The success rates of shooting trials (without a change in purpose, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6a</ref>) and passing trials (with change in purpose, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6b</ref>) are shown separately, both with the horizontal axis representing the conditions and the vertical axis representing its success rates. To statistically examine these changes in success rates, we performed a one-way ANOVA for the nine conditions and found that shooting trials did not show a main effect (F 8,81 = 1.85, p = 0.08, η 2 = 0.15). On the other hand, pass trials did show a main effect (F 8,81 = 32.50, p &lt; 0.001, η 2 = 0.76). To statistically examine these changes in success rates, we performed a one-way ANOVA for the nine conditions and found that shooting trials did not show a main effect (F 8,81 = 1.85, p = 0.08, η 2 = 0.15). On the other hand, pass trials did show a main effect <ref type="bibr">(F 8,81</ref> = 32.50, p &lt; 0.001, η 2 = 0.76). However, for both trials, the success rate did not reach 0% even in the 70% condition just before ball release. The most important result of this study was that we were able to confirm that there were participants whose success rates did not reach 0% but did decrease as the time constraint became stricter. We were able to create a bar chart showing the data in which the average success rate did not reach 0% under any condition. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Preparing to shoot and pass in parallel</head><p>Jump shooters in basketball must make an appropriate decision and execute the shot or pass in the midair. In this study, through experiments in which the timing of LED illumination was strictly controlled, we successfully identified the success rate of changes in the purpose of nine conditions (seven of which were delayed conditions). However, it should be noted that the accuracy of the data in this study includes approximately 5.1% inherent error since preliminary experiments have shown that there is a 5.1% withinindividual error in human hang time.</p><p>The success rates of the shooting and passing trials ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6</ref>) showed that although the success rate of the shooting trials, which included a basic movement, was almost constant in all conditions (p = 0.08), the success rate of the passing trials, which required a change in movement, decreased as the delay time of the LED illumination timing increased (p &lt; 0.001). However, interestingly, the success rate of passing trials did not reach 0% even for the 70% condition, which corresponds to the time just before the ball was released (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). The result that success rates decreased as the strictness of time constraint increased is similar to the findings reported by van der <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Kamp (2006)</ref>, and since the authors also reported the possibility that the estimation for logistic approximation may not be zero, our results may represent a demonstration of their possibility. On the other hand, the temporal boundary may vary depending on the participant's proficiency level, as some participants reach a 0% success rate in any of the delay conditions.</p><p>In the present study, under the hypothesis derived in the introduction, whether the success rate of the passing trials reaches zero can determine whether the action was handled by serial processing or parallel processing. Then, we consider that the delay condition located immediately after the minimum reaction time required to make a choice during the execution of the movement to the delay condition just before the success rate reaches 0% is the interval in which parallel processing is used in the response, and after that delay condition is considered to be the temporal boundary for that participant. In the following, we provide an in-depth examination of the shooter's response to a sudden change in purpose from the perspective of information processing modes.</p><p>In general, information processing can be broadly classified into two modes: serial, in which processing of the previous object is completed before processing of the next object begins, and parallel, in which multiple objects or subsystems are processed simultaneously. The question of which processing mode humans use has long been a matter of debate <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Townsend, 1990)</ref>. Approaches to this question mainly rely on reaction time, such as the precuing paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Rosenbaum, 1980</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Rosenbaum, , 1983</ref>, which examines the relationship between the number of movement parameters to be determined and reaction time, and the psychological refractory period paradigm (= PRP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Telford, 1931)</ref>, which examines reaction times to two stimuli presented in succession. Although many studies have been conducted according to these paradigms, there is a mixture of studies that support serial processing (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bonnet et al., 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Kurata, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Larish &amp; Frekany, 1985)</ref>, support parallel processing (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Favilla et al., 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Jentzsch et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Zelaznik &amp; Hahn, 1985)</ref>, and show the coexistence of both modes <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Sigman &amp; Dehaene, 2008)</ref>, which means that no clear answer has been reached. However, considering that there are studies supporting parallel processing and the coexistence of both modes of processing and considering that the parallel distributed processing model (=PDP model) <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Rumelhart et al., 1986a)</ref>, which refers to the human brain nervous system rather than a general computer that performs serial processing around a CPU, has contributed to the basic concepts of today's neural network <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Rumelhart et al., 1986b)</ref>, it seems certain that humans make excellent use of parallel information processing, even if we cannot determine which theory is most accurate. Our hypothesis-testing study also showed results in favor of parallel processing.</p><p>There are sports science studies of fencing lunge attack movements in which participants performed the task of reacting to a sudden moving target during movement <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Gutiérrez-Dávila et al., 2013a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, 2013b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">, 2013c</ref>. Following the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gutiérrez-Dávila et al. (2013c)</ref>, the reaction time for making a decision in this study has two possibilities (pass in two directions) that differ from the initial target, i.e.,</p><p>shot; the reaction times were considered to be between 186 ms and 243 ms (temporarily 214 ms, just in between the other two values). Although the target movement differs from these previous studies, it is important to note that the concept of choosing a response when the objective changes for a movement that has already been initiated, rather than a response to generate a movement after receiving a stimulus as in the classical study conducted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hick (1952)</ref>, is consistent with these studies, which are very helpful in considering the present results.</p><p>Given that the average hang time of all participants in this study was 520 ms and that the 70% point of hang time was just before the ball was released, jump shots in this study should be completed at least 416 ms after ball release (80% point of hang time). Therefore, a change in purpose from shot to pass by continuous revision of the neural signals underlying motor activity (serial processing) is possible until approximately 202 ms (difference between 416 ms and 214 ms) after takeoff, after which serial processing is unlikely to be successful ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7)</ref>. The period of 202 ms after takeoff corresponds to the time between the 30% and 40% conditions in this experiment; however, in fact, the success rates did not reach 0% even after the 40% condition. In other words, the motor sequence for the passing during the jump shot is initiated in parallel with the motor behavior of shooting as the basic movement, and the process of deciding on one or the other is influenced by the clarification of the purpose. This phenomenon is thought to have made it possible to maintain a high shooting success rate while preparing to change the motion to a pass just before ball release. This interesting result goes beyond the specialized movement category of a jump shot by a basketball player and is an example of how humans are simultaneously preparing to make two movements generated from a common motion. As mentioned in the introduction, shooting and passing during a jump shot are different motions, although they involve a common movement. Furthermore, in this study, the target of the shot, the ring (305 cm high), and the target of the pass, the receiver's hands (approximately 17 possibility that the results obtained in this study may simply be a relatively commonplace result observed by changing the direction of the shooter's projectile. Since we were examining up to 70% of the hang time in this experiment and since some participants reached the temporal boundary before the 70% delay condition, it is possible that the limit may be reached at 71% depending on each participant's proficiency level; however, we considered that parallel processing was performed at least up to the delay condition where 0% was not reached, and the jump shooters could respond to the two purposes, that is, shooting and passing. which participants needed to make a choice during movement execution, the shooters were able to change the purpose of their movements through serial processing up to 202 ms after take-off. The obtained data support parallel processing.</p><p>As mentioned above, experimental studies that question whether human information processing is serial or parallel have been conducted mainly by comparing reaction times, with the precuing paradigm as a representative example. However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Goodman and Kelso (1980)</ref> suggested that this paradigm did not support the claim that any previous cues providing information merely reduce the number of stimulusresponse alternatives, thereby shortening the response selection stage before motoric processing. Because reaction time reflects human information processing in detail, it is extremely difficult to determine the stage in which the measured reaction time, for example, premotor time and motor time, occurred <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Botwinick &amp; Thompson, 1966)</ref>. In contrast, the task used in this study was examined under the distinct boundary of whether the success rate reaches 0%, which demonstrates the potential of parallel processing in a way that has never been done before.</p><p>Note that parallel processing occurred only in the preparatory phase of movement generation in the brain (information system). This is because, although the vase and the two faces in Rubin's vase can be replaced by shooting and passing in the jump shot, only one of the two motions can be performed by a single body in the dynamical system. In other words, the preparation of two motions involving only the information system reflects parallel processing, while the process involving the dynamical system from the preparation to the point where decisions are made, and motions are generated (the series of processes from a meta-perspective) is serial processing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Confirmation of parallel preparations from the aspect of movement (verification experiment)</head><p>From the result that the success rate of passing trials did not reach zero even when the clarification of purpose during the jump shot was delayed until just before the ball was released, we suggest that the shooter is preparing to make two motions with different purposes in parallel. Here, <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Kobayashi and Kimura (2022)</ref> reported, based on an experiment that simulated judging "Strike" or "Ball" in baseball, that batters improved their decision-making accuracy by slowing movement initiation. In other words, this means that there is a time period in which the person is in an uncertain state and able to perform several possible movements; this period can vary in duration, and this motor strategy attempts to extend this time as much as possible. If we were to apply this possibility to the present study, we would expect to have observed a motor phase that extended the uncertain state as much as possible, during which time the players would be able to change their motion to passing while using shooting as the base movement. Furthermore, for movement derived from the common initial movement shared by both shooting and passing, the kinematic characteristics should be evident in the elbow joint, the main joint that generates the arm movement. In the verification experiment, one participant was informed in advance that the purpose of movement would not change (=no change condition: NCC), and trials in which the possibility of a change in the purpose at the moment of take-off (corresponding to the 0% condition in the main experiment) was included (=change condition: CC). We confirmed the parallel preparation of movements from the difference in the extension pattern of the elbow joint, which is the last phase to be operated before the ball is released.</p><p>We tracked all trials from the right side of the shooter using one high-speed camera (CASIO, Japan, 300 Hz), and the coordination of the shoulder, elbow, and wrist joints (all on the right side) was digitized using a 2D DLT method to obtain the elbow joint angle of the shooter. All raw data were smoothed with a fourth-order Butterworth low-pass filter at a cutoff frequency of 30 Hz. Then, four characteristic time points were extracted to compare the elbow joint angle changes during a jump shot, which was defined as the time required for the three phases consisting of those temporal points. The time points were when both feet were on the ground before the jump (point A), the take-off (point B), when the highest point was reached (point C), and when the ball was released (point D).</p><p>Time series data of elbow joint angles in both conditions are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 8</ref> (left: NCC, right:</p><p>CC). The solid line in the middle of the three lines is the mean of all trials, the dashed line above is the +SD, and the dashed line below is the -SD. From this figure, we can understand that the angle increase has already started at point C for the NCC condition, while it has not yet started for the CC condition. This result means that in the NCC, elbow joint angle extension is initiated during the ascent of the center of gravity, whereas in the CC, elbow joint angle extension is initiated after the highest point and during descent. Paired t tests were performed for each temporal point to examine significant differences, and a significant difference was noted between the angles at point C (77.9 ± 18.7 vs. 55.1 ± 3.2 deg, p &lt; 0.05, d = 1.7) and point D (138.7 ± 4.8 vs. 146.8 ± 6.1 deg, p &lt; 0.05, d = 1.48). Next, the amount of elbow joint angle change in each phase is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 9a</ref>. One of the major characteristics is that the magnitude relation between the NCC and CC conditions is reversed from Phase 2 (from point B to point C) to Phase 3 (from point C to point D). Although no statistically significant difference was found, there was a trend toward greater values in the NCC condition than in the CC condition in Phase 2 <ref type="bibr">(29.4 ± 19.6 vs. 5.2 ± 5.4</ref> deg, p = 0.07, d = 1.69), whereas in Phase 3, values in the CC conditions were significantly greater than those in the NCC condition <ref type="bibr">(60.8 ± 19.0 vs. 91.7 ± 6.3 deg, p &lt; 0.05, d = 2.18)</ref>. Finally, the time required for each phase is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 9b</ref>. The sum time from Phases 1 to 3 is the total (hereafter "whole time"), and significant differences were found for the whole time (492 ± 24.2 vs. 555 ± 27.1 ms, p &lt; 0.05, d = 2.45) and for Phase 3 <ref type="bibr">(62.4 ± 20.8 vs. 134.4 ± 28.6 ms, p &lt; 0.05, d = 2.88)</ref>. Note that the individual hang time reflected in the delay time in the main experiment was from take-off to landing, which differed from the whole time (from grounding before jumping to releasing the ball) in the verification experiment. By subtracting Phase 1 from the whole time, the time from take-off to the point when the ball was released was calculated to be 275.4 ± 20.2 ms for the NCC condition and 343.8 ± 20.1 ms for the CC condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>20</head><p>This means that for the trials with these conditions, the ball was released after 53% and 66% of the hanging time.</p><p>From these results, the elbow joint angle was smoothly extended before reaching the highest point in the NCC condition with a predetermined purpose, whereas in the CC condition with an indeterminate purpose, the behavior of temporarily pausing the elbow joint angle extension in mid-air was observed.</p><p>Therefore, it can be said that the existence of a movement phase that maintains the ability to transition between two ways of movement with different purposes was demonstrated from the change in the elbow joint angle extension pattern.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Conceptual model of motor control against uncertainty</head><p>Through main and verification experiments using a jump shot in basketball, this study experimentally demonstrated parallel preparation to make two moves with different purposes and that there is a movement phase to allow one to transition to either of these movements in a situation when the person decides to execute one of two possibilities under strict time constraints. In this section, we provide an overview of the above two results in information systems and dynamical systems. <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Kugler and Turvey (1987)</ref>, who attempted to apply the mound-building model of African termites to human movements, divided human movements into motor information from sensory organs (information system) and actual movements (dynamical system) and skillfully reached the conclusion that these aspects interact through a unique experiment using a pendulum at which the moment of inertia can be freely changed. When modeling a complex subject, such as sports behaviors, the work often focuses only on either the information or the dynamical system to simplify the model; however, these aspects in fact interact with each other, so we considered that clearly distinguishing them first and then examining 22 how they interact with each other is an important way to propose a more realistic conceptual model. The authors of the aforementioned study also graphically described the termite mound-building process as a conceptual model using self-organization, providing tremendous suggestions and ideas for the subsequent development of self-organization research. In fact, the aforementioned research on the interaction between the information system and the dynamical system in individual physical movement is also based on this graphical abstract as a fundamental concept. Therefore, we describe the connection between the information system and the dynamical system in a single graphical abstract <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 10</ref>), although it has not yet been developed into a mathematical model as was done in previous studies. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>23</head><p>We first attempted to explain motor control in response to a choice under a time constraint (below in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref>, shot or pass) by contrasting it with the perception of ambiguous figures (above in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref>, vase or two faces). When looking at an ambiguous figure, the human information system is in a state of perceiving both A and B; that is, uncertainty and can come and go freely, and this state is a preparatory stage that makes it possible to bring either state to one's attention. Then, either the vase or the face rises to consciousness by self-organization. It is important here to note that perception is a process that can be established only by the information system, and there is no room for the dynamical system to intervene here. On the other hand, the case of motor control has two main characteristics that should be emphasized.</p><p>The first is that the time period in which the information system is in an uncertain state can increase or decrease, and the second is that not only the information system but also the dynamical system is involved, and these systems are interconnected. In the information system of motor control, similar to the information system of perception, parallel preparations are made for outcomes A and B. The difference from perception is that these outcomes are not self-organized but are determined by the individual's own decision-making process. At the time, the uncertain state in the information system is reflected in the "pausing" of the movement (extension of the elbow joint) in the dynamical system. What is important here is that, due to the involvement of a dynamical system that follows the arrow of time (unidirectionality), once decision-making is made and movement is initiated, inertia works in that direction and cannot be reversed. <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Kobayashi and Kimura (2022)</ref> reported that baseball batters use strategies to slow movement initiation or cancel movements once they have started and are able to determine whether a strike or a ball with high accuracy; however, the cancellation of movement in a jump shot corresponds to traveling, i.e., a violation. Therefore, jump shooters cannot afford to terminate their movement once it has been initiated.</p><p>These facts suggest that in decision-making during a jump shot, which is an aerial motion, the motor strategy of extending the time of the uncertain state, which is a state in which movement can be altered for two different purposes, was adopted to allow more time to make the best choice between two motor strategies. Not only that, however, a pausing motion in the mid-air during a jump shot means that the series of motions that have already begun are paused, unlike the slowing movement initiation from the stationary position of batters. In other words, this strategy is considered a new skill extracted from a jump shot with an aerial phase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Research limitation</head><p>A limitation of this study was that the judgment of the success/failure of the passing trials involved an element of the receiver's subjectivity. In this study, subjective judgments was used to make the experiment as close to the real situation as possible and to maintain the participant's concentration by speeding up the 24 feedback that participants received; however, if the target position of the ball was translated into coordinates, success/failure could be judged objectively. Furthermore, taking the study on baseball pitching as an example, since the hit position of the ball was represented by coordinates and the pitching accuracy and pitching characteristics were extracted from the variation <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Kawamura et al., 2017;</ref>, an objective judgment of success/failure and a deeper discussion on the effect of strict time constraints on ball control was possible. Despite the above limitations, the experimental results imply that humans are able to prepare several movements in parallel for different purposes, and the identification of the kinematic characteristics of these movements may be a fundamental approach to the connection between decision-making in information systems and motor generation in dynamical systems under the situation of strict time constraints.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>Using a task that entailed a change in purpose during a jump shot with strictly controlled LED illumination timing, we showed experimentally that the shooter is able to respond, albeit not perfectly, to the clarification of the purpose of the motion, either of the shot or pass from before take-off to just before releasing the ball (at a point corresponding to 70% of the hang time). This experimental result may have elucidated parallel human information processing that allows one to prepare to make two analogous movements with common motion. In addition, these findings may be deeply related to the skill of maintaining a state to be able to transition between two styles of movement with different purposes.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Experimental setup. The participant dribbles forward and attempts a jump shot on a mat switch.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Conceptual diagram of the nine conditions. This example is a scan of one of the shooting trials in the 10% condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Conceptual diagram of overall and delay manipulation. (a) Overall conceptual diagram of the experimental system. The case of the right LED lighting up. (b) Conceptual diagram of the delay manipulation by LabVIEW. The BJ and 0% conditions do not include this manipulation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Measuring the hang time from GRF data. Phase A involves the runup for jumping, phase B involves landing before jumping, point C is the take-off, and point D is the landing after jumping.Hangtime is defined as the time difference between point c and point D.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Flow of the experiment. This experiment was divided into two parts: a preliminary experiment</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Change in success rate in each trial. (a) Success rates for shooting trials (p = 0.08). (b) Success rates for passing trials (p &lt; 0.001).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Conceptual diagram of hypotheses and obtained results. Considering the reaction time in</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Time series data of elbow joint angles in successful shooting trials. The left part shows the without-change condition (control condition), and the right shows the condition with the possibility of a sudden change in purpose (in fact, the light was not illuminated). These trials were normalized to 0% at the grounding before the jump (point A) and 100% at the ball release (point D), while point B represents the take-off and point C represents the highest point that was reached. The solid line is the mean, the dashed line above it is the +SD, and the dashed line below it is the -SD.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Results of the verification experiment focusing on elbow joint extension patterns. (a) Amount of change in elbow joint angle for each phase. Black bars indicate trials in the without-change condition (control condition), and gray bars indicate trials with the possibility of a sudden change in purpose, both shown in absolute values; only a significant difference was found in Phase 3 (from point C to point D). (b) Required time for each phase. Black bars indicate trials in the without-change condition (control condition), and gray bars indicate trials with the possibility of a sudden change in purpose; the sum of Phases 1, 2, and 3 is the "Total", and significant differences were found for the Total and for Phase 3 (point C to point D).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 10 .</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Conceptual diagram of motor control against an uncertain purpose. The top depicts a case of simple perception, and the bottom shows a case of motor control. In the lower panel, the jump shooter perceives the defender at the moment the player jumps up to shoot and decides whether to shoot or pass the ball to a teammate. The time of uncertain information expands and contracts, and these characteristics are reflected in the dynamical system as a pause in movement (if there is no option, the movement is executed smoothly).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 . Success rate of each participant</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Shot Pass Shot Pass Shot Pass Shot Pass Shot Pass Shot Pass Shot Pass Shot Pass Shot Pass</figDesc><table><row><cell>Success rate (%)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions in motion: Passive body acceleration modulates hand choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bakker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H A</forename><surname>Weijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Beers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">P J</forename><surname>Selen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Medendorp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1152/jn.00022.2017</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00022.2017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2250" to="2261" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Specification of direction and extent in motor programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bonnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Requin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stelmach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bulletin of the Psychonomic Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03330031</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03330031" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Premotor and motor components of reaction time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Botwinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0022634</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0022634" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic decision making: Human control of complex systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Brehmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0001-6918(92)90019-A</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0001-6918(92)90019-A" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the speed of mental processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Donders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0001-6918(69</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0001-6918(69" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90065" to="90066" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpersonal coordination tendencies shape 1-vs-1 sub-phase performance outcomes in youth soccer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Duarte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Araújo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Davids</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Travassos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Gazimba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sampaio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02640414.2012.675081</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2012.675081" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Sports Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="871" to="877" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual illusions and neurobiology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Eagleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/35104092</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/35104092" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="920" to="926" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic decision theory and probabilistic information processings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/001872086200400201</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/001872086200400201" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Factors</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="1962" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpersonal dynamics and relative positioning to scoring target of performers in 1 vs. 1 sub-phases of team sports</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Esteves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Araújo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Davids</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Vilar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Travassos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Esteves</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Sports Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1285" to="1293" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02640414.2012.707327</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2012.707327" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trajectory control in targeted force impulses. VI. Independent specification of response amplitude and direction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Favilla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hening</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ghez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/bf00247934</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/bf00247934" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental Brain Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="280" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">FIBA (International Basketball Federation). (2020a)</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.fiba.basketball/documents/official-basketball-rules/2020.pdf" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Official basketball rules 2020</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">FIBA (International Basketball Federation). (2020b)</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.fiba.basketball/documents/official-basketball-rules/2020/equipment.pdf" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Official basketball rules 2020 basketball equipment</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are movements prepared in parts? Not under compatible (naturalized) conditions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kelso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="495" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037//0096-3445.109.4.475</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//0096-3445.109.4.475" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of uncertainty on the reaction response in fencing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gutiérrez-Dávila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Javier Rojas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Antonio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research Quarterly for Exercise and Sport</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02701367.2013.762286</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02701367.2013.762286" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response timing in the lunge and target change in elite versus medium-level fencers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gutiérrez-Dávila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Rojas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Antonio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17461391.2011.635704</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17461391.2011.635704" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Sport Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="364" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of target change during the simple attack in fencing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gutiérrez-Dávila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Rojas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Caletti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Antonio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Sport Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1100" to="1107" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02640414.2013.770908</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2013.770908" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the rate of gain of information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17470215208416600</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17470215208416600" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="1952" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal context calibrates interval timing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jazayeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.2590</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2590" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1020" to="1026" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beneficial effects of ambiguous precues: Parallel motor preparation or reduced premotoric processing time?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Jentzsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Leuthold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Ridderinkhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1469-8986.2004.00155.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-8986.2004.00155.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Baseball pitching accuracy: An examination of various parameters when evaluating pitch locations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kawamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shinya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kobayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Obata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kuwata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Nakazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14763141.2017.1332236</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14763141.2017.1332236" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sports Biomechanics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="410" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multistability and metastability: Understanding dynamic coordination in the brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kelso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="906" to="918" />
			<date type="published" when="1591" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2011.0351</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2011.0351" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dynamic patterns: The self-organization of brain and behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A S</forename><surname>Kelso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Separating figure from ground with a parallel network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kienker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sejnowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schumacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1068/p150197</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1068/p150197" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="197" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biomechanics of the basketball jump shot: Six key teaching points</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Knudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Physical Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Recreation &amp; Dance</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/07303084.1993.10606710</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/07303084.1993.10606710" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Knudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Fundamentals of biomechanics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compensative movement ameliorates reduced efficacy of rapidlyembodied decisions in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kobayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kimura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s42003-022-03232-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s42003-022-03232-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Basketball skills &amp; drills</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Craig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>Human Kinetics</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Information, natural law, and the self-assembly of rhythmic movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Kugler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Turvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Erlbaum</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Premotor cortex of monkeys: Set-and movement-related activity reflecting amplitude and direction of wrist movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kurata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1152/jn.1993.69.1.187</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.1993.69.1.187" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planning and preparing expected and unexpected movements: Reexamining the relationships of arm, direction, and extent of movement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Larish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Frekany</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00222895.1985.10735343</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/00222895.1985.10735343" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Motor Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="168" to="189" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Segregation of form, color, movement, and depth: Anatomy, physiology, and perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Livingstone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hubel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4853</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="740" to="749" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.3283936</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.3283936" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reaching decisions during ongoing movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michalski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cisek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1152/jn.00613.2019</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00613.2019" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1090" to="1102" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing Bayesian models of human coincidence timing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miyazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nozaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Nakajima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1152/jn.01168.2004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.01168.2004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="399" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamics of visual feedback in a laboratory simulation of a penalty kick</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Morya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ranvaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pinheiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Sports Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="95" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/0264041031000070840</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/0264041031000070840" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A review on the basketball jump shot</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Okazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rodacki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Satern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14763141.2015.1052541</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14763141.2015.1052541" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sports Biomechanics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="190" to="205" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deciding while moving: Cognitive interference biases value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Raßbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Grießbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cañal-Bruland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Herbort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.actpsy.2021.103449</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2021.103449" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">221</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103449</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalization of prior information for rapid Bayesian time estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Roach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Mcgraw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Whitaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Heron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PNAS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="412" to="417" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1610706114</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1610706114" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human movement initiation: Specification of arm, direction, and extent</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037//0096-3445.109.4.444</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//0096-3445.109.4.444" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="474" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The movement precuing technique: Assumptions, applications, and extensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0166-4115</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0166-4115" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">08</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61994" to="62003" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning representations by backpropagating errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rumelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/323533a0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/323533a0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">323</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6088</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="533" to="536" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Parallel distributed processing: Explorations in the microstructure of cognition: Foundations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rumelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pdp Research Group</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pitching form determines probabilistic structure of errors in pitch location</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shinya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tsuchiya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Nakazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Oda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02640414.2016.1258484</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2016.1258484" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Sports Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2142" to="2147" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brain mechanisms of serial and parallel processing during dual-task performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sigman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dehaene</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7585" to="7598" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/jneurosci.0948-08.2008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.0948-08.2008" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The refractory phase of voluntary and associative responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Telford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0073262</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0073262" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="1931" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Serial vs. Parallel processing: Sometimes they look like tweedledum and tweedledee but they can (and should) be distinguished</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-9280.1990.tb00067.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9280.1990.tb00067.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal release conditions for the free throw in men&apos;s basketball</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Silverberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Sport Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1147" to="1155" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02640410802004948</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02640410802004948" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spatiotemporal characteristics of an attacker&apos;s strategy to pass a defender effectively in a computer-based one-on-one task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsutsui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shinya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-019-54012-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-54012-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17260</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A field simulation study of the effectiveness of penalty kick strategies in soccer: Late alterations of kick direction increase errors and reduce accuracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Van Der Kamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02640410500190841</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02640410500190841" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Sports Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="477" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In situ examination of decision-making skills and gaze behaviour of basketball players</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J J</forename><surname>Van Maarseveen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J P</forename><surname>Savelsbergh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R D</forename><surname>Oudejans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.humov.2017.12.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.humov.2017.12.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Movement Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reaction time methods in the study of motor programming: The precuing of hand, digit, and duration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Zelaznik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Motor Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="190" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00222895.1985.10735344</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/00222895.1985.10735344" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
