<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Leveling up fun: Learning progress, expectations, and success influence enjoyment in video games</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>22/23</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franziska</forename><surname>Brändle</surname></persName>
							<email>franziska.braendle@tuebingen.mpg.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charley</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Human and Machine Cognition Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tübingen</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tübingen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Max Planck Institute for Biological Cybernetics</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tübingen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Max Planck Institute for Biological Cybernetics</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tübingen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Helmholtz Institute for Human-Centered AI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Helmholtz Center Munich</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<address>
									<addrLine>7,994 Levels 376,341 Votes 138,662 Levels 614, 770 Votes 115,032 Levels 795,313 Votes</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Leveling up fun: Learning progress, expectations, and success influence enjoyment in video games</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">22/23</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Puzzle game</term>
					<term>Robozzle Racing game</term>
					<term>Trackmania Platformer game</term>
					<term>Super Mario Maker</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>What factors influence how much fun people have when engaging in inherently enjoyable tasks? The theory of learning progress predicts that people will have the most fun in environments of intermediate difficulty because these environments offer the most progress in learning about the world. Past studies have frequently focused on simple experimental paradigms in which learning was still instrumental for later tasks. Here, we put the theory of learning progress to a test in three large and realistic video game data sets: a puzzle game (with 7,994 levels and 376,341 votes), a racing game (138,662 levels and 614,770 votes), and a platformer game (115,032 levels and 795,313 votes). As predicted, people preferred levels of intermediate difficulty in all games. Yet, additional factors influencing people&apos;s enjoyment also emerged: players preferred levels that matched closely with their prior expectations of difficulty and were also motivated by success. We further confirmed these factors in two precisely controlled experiments. Taken together, these results advance our understanding of the dynamics of fun in realistic environments and emphasize the importance of using both realistic, game-like environments and highly controlled experiments to refine theories of human learning and decision-making.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>People engage in many activities not only for material rewards or instrumental benefits but simply for the fun and enjoyment they offer. From playing a game, or taking in a movie, to making music, there are countless activities where behavior appears to be intrinsically motivated absent of instrumental benefits. With the high number of enjoyable options available at any time, it becomes crucial to understand which activities people prefer and continue to participate in purely for fun. What are the features influencing whether or not an ongoing activity is experienced as intrinsically rewarding and thus predicting continued engagement, especially in rich and realistic scenarios?</p><p>One way to formally describe "fun" -or more generally intrinsic reward -is based on an informational goal of learning progress <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> . A common technique used in robotics and machine learning is to assign intrinsic rewards to the active creation or discovery of surprising experiences, which allow intelligent agents to improve the predictions of their model of the world <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> . According to this approach, a subjective measure of "fun" or intrinsic reward can be defined as the degree to which the world model improves <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> . This produces an inverted U-shaped relationship between difficulty and intrinsic reward, with intrinsic reward being the highest in situations of intermediate difficulty (i.e. not too easy and not too hard) where learning progress is maximal <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1a)</ref>. When a task is too easy, people will not learn much, since they will have already possessed the necessary knowledge or skills to master it: for example, teaching an adult how to tie their shoes, or a skilled chess player how to move their pawns. On the other hand, when a task is too difficult, people might struggle to achieve any degree of traction, since they may fail miserably without any real lessons being learned: for example, teaching a 1-year-old to tie their shoes or a novice chess player how to play the Ruy Lopez opening.</p><p>An inverted U-shape between complexity and preference has been proposed in many related areas of research, such as curiosity <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> , boredom <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9</ref> , flow <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10</ref> , development <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11</ref> and game design <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12</ref> . From a normative perspective, robots learn faster when maximizing learning progress <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14</ref> and machine learning models using stochastic gradient-descent learn best when they are correct roughly 85% of the time <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15</ref> . Descriptively, learning progress has been linked to influential accounts of curiosity <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17</ref> and development <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18</ref> , with distinct neural responses encoding the anticipation of obtaining information compared to anticipations of reward <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref> . However, empirical evidence for human engagement being driven by learning progress has only recently emerged, often using free choice paradigms where task difficulty is related to learning outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22</ref> , engagement <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> , and subjective ratings <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25</ref> . A recent pre-registered study <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26</ref> provided additional support that learning progress rather than difficulty is a main driver of enjoyment. Using a "dynamic difficulty adjustment" system, learning progress was deliberately suppressed, with the <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Visualization of the tested theory and experimental setup. A: The learning progress theory. According to the theory, enjoyment increases with model improvement. As shown in multiple studies and our simulations, model improvement is highest in environments of intermediate difficulty. Therefore, enjoyment is predicted to be highest in environments of intermediate difficulty. B: Details on the three game data sets. We chose three pre-existing games of different genres, all including a large set of levels and player votes. C: Overview of our additional experimental setups. First, we investigated the additional component of difficulty-expectation disparity in a guessing game, where people had to guess numbers generated by different machines (for an enlarged version of the paradigm, refer to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3a</ref>). Second, we investigated the additional component of success in a grid exploration game, where people could open numerical tiles on a large grid.</p><p>outcome that the researchers failed to find a relationship between the difficulty-skill balance and enjoyment <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26</ref> .</p><p>In his seminal paper, Schmidhuber argues that making learning progress results in "fun" <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> . However, "fun" lacks a consistent definition in psychological literature and refers to a complex and subjective phenomenon <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29</ref> . Here, we will use the broader term "enjoyment" to describe the positive affect people experience when engaging in inherently "fun" tasks, such as games. While we believe that our paradigms capture the essence of fun and enjoyment, we adopt the term "intrinsic reward" to describe participants' positive experience elicited by learning progress -as proposed by Oudeyer et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> -to avoid unwarranted generalization. The term originates from the intrinsic motivation literature, which defines intrinsically motivated activities as those "for which there is no apparent reward except the activity itself" (REF <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30</ref> , p. 23). Traditionally, intrinsic motivation and rewards have been measured through behavioral measures, such as engagement <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30</ref> and choice behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22</ref> , or through self-report measures <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8</ref> . In our work, we use both engagement and players' level ratings to gain a more comprehensive understanding of learning progress.</p><p>While past studies have focused on simple experimental paradigms in which learning was still instrumental for later tasks, here we are interested in settings such as video games or other enjoyable diversions, where people play purely for fun or pleasure and can decide to quit at any moment <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> . In these settings, people can still gather knowledge about the structure or difficulty of the task, but instrumental learning is not the main focus of the activity <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32</ref> . In these inherently enjoyable scenarios, learning progress may not be the only motivational driver, since the link to a normative basis for improving future outcomes is made more tenuous. Thus, it is an open question whether learning progress can provide a good description of behavior in more real-world and inherently fun contexts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Goals and scope</head><p>To answer this question, we test the theory of intrinsic reward as learning progress <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">34</ref> in multiple large-scale game data sets, as well as two online experiments. Within three large-scale video game data sets ("Robozzle", "Trackmania", and "Super Mario Maker"; <ref type="figure">Fig. 1b</ref>), we used subjective ratings as an indicator of intrinsic reward, finding an inverted U-shaped relationship between difficulty and people's enjoyment <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 2)</ref>. However, other important factors also emerged. In particular, the Super Mario Maker data set revealed that players' ratings were also influenced by i) a "difficulty-expectation disparity" based on the mismatch between prior expectations about the difficulty of a level and our calculations of the underlying difficulty and ii) "success" from completing levels with low difficulty.</p><p>Having established that learning progress, along with the difficulty-expectation disparity and success, influences player's  . We plot the difference between the difficulty calculation -based on attempts and clears of the levels -and expected difficulty -given by categories assigned by the creators -in Super Mario Maker. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean.</p><p>ratings in complex and realistic video games, we conducted two controlled experiments ( <ref type="figure">Fig. 1c</ref>) to further corroborate our findings -measured through player engagement. In Experiment 1 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 3</ref>), we used a simple guessing game, where participants guessed numbers from Gaussian distributions with different levels of variance defining the difficulty. In both simulations and participant data, we found that learning progress and the difficulty-expectation disparity stemming from a mismatch between expectations about difficulty and true difficulty influenced players' engagement with each machine. In Experiment 2 ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 4</ref>),</p><p>we developed an open-ended exploration paradigm, in which participants explored different grids containing hidden points with varying degrees of spatial correlation. Through both simulations and participant data, we found that in tandem with increased engagement in levels with higher learning progress, participants also engaged more with landscapes with higher underlying point values. Taken together, these results advance our understanding of higher-order concepts in human motivation and intrinsic reward, by showing that multiple factors influence people's ratings and engagement behavior in inherently enjoyable, realistic, and rich environments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Game datasets</head><p>To investigate the theory of learning progress in inherently non-instrumental and enjoyable settings, we decided to use video games as a testbed. Games have a long history in psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref> . Video games bring the additional benefit that they provide a lot of data, as they are by design enjoyable and therefore attract more participants and generate more data per participant <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36</ref> . Video games are also more complex than traditional psychological paradigms, which brings them closer to the complexity of real-world environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> . In our analyses, we focused on three large-scale data sets of the popular video games Robozzle, Trackmania, and Super Mario Maker. All three games have in common that players can create and contribute levels, which other players can subsequently play and rate. These games, therefore, offer a great diversity in the complexity and difficulty of many different levels. To assess whether enjoyment was affected by learning progress, we compared different levels of difficulty within each game. As learning progress is predicted to be highest in tasks of intermediate difficulty, we expected to see an inverted U-shape between difficulty and enjoyment for each game. As the three data sets did not share the same data structures, we approximated enjoyment and difficulty measures for each game individually, based on the available data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Robozzle -Results</head><p>Robozzle is a puzzle game in which players need to write small, often recursive, programs with the help of building blocks to steer a spaceship to its goal. The data set consisted (after cleaning, see SI) of 7,994 levels and 376,341 votes. Players could rate the difficulty of each level between 1 and 5. For our analysis, we used the average rating for each level, which was displayed on the website as a value between 1 (very easy) and 5 (very hard) in steps of 0.01. Players could also up-and downvote levels, which we transformed into an enjoyment measure by dividing the upvotes by the total number of votes to get a like-ratio. Analyzing votes, we found that players seemed to prefer intermediate difficult levels over very easy or hard levels (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig.  2a</ref>). Additionally, we ran a regression analysis and found a significant negative quadratic effect of difficulty, indicating an inverted U-shape as predicted by the learning progress theory (linear: β = 0.09, z = 44.37, p &lt; .001, quadratic: β = −0.04, z = −22.98, p &lt; .001). Due to the size of the data set, standard model comparison methods were not appropriate. Instead, we looked at the model fit of different polynomial regression models. We observed that adding a quadratic term improved the model fit meaningfully, while adding a cubic term did not. For details on model comparison, refer to the SI. However, it is important to note that a difficulty measure based on players' ratings instead of their performance might lead to a tautological situation in which players rate the levels they enjoyed the most as intermediate difficult <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26</ref> . We avoid this confounding factor in the two upcoming datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trackmania -Results</head><p>Trackmania is a car racing game, in which players steer a racing car through different artificial-looking tracks. The data set consisted of 138,662 levels and 614,770 votes (here called awards). The difficulty of each level was given by the website as one of four categories: Beginner, Intermediate, Expert, and Lunatic. These difficulties were assigned by the creators of the levels. We mapped these difficulty categories to the values 1 -4. Players could give awards to levels, of which we used the absolute number per level as an enjoyment approximation. Again, players seemed to like intermediate difficult levels more than very easy or hard levels (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2b</ref>). In an additional regression analysis similar to the previous one, we again found a significant negative quadratic effect of difficulty as expected (linear: β = 1.10, z = 16.62, p &lt; .001, quadratic: β = −0.47, z = −10.63, p &lt; .001). We again observed that adding a quadratic term meaningfully improved the model fit, while adding a cubic term did not (see SI).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Super Mario Maker -Results</head><p>Super Mario is a platformer video game series, in which players have to move the main character to a goal by mainly jumping, running, and avoiding enemies. In Super Mario Maker, players can create their own Super Mario-style levels and then upload their levels for other players to play and rate them. We analyzed the data of 115,032 player-designed levels and 795,313 votes, which were based on a total of 32,665,615 attempts. As we had more detailed data per level, we did not have to rely on players' or creator's difficulty ratings. Instead, we approximated the difficulty of each level as 1 minus the ratio of how many players who attempted a level were able to finish it. Players could rate levels with stars. We defined our enjoyment measure as the proportion of players attempting a level, who also gave a star to this particular level. As in our previous experiments, we found an inverted U-shaped relation between our difficulty and our enjoyment measure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 2c</ref>). Again, players seemed to like intermediate difficult levels the most. As in our previous regression analyses, we found a significant negative quadratic effect of difficulty, as predicted (linear: β = 0.001, z = 3.62, p &lt; .001, quadratic: β = −0.002, z = −8.63, p &lt; .001). However, a closer look at the data suggests, that it does not follow a quadratic function and is better described by a third-degree polynomial (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2c</ref>). Indeed, we found that adding a cubic term improved the model fit (see SI). Therefore, while we found signatures of learning progress in all three data sets, the Super Mario Maker data set appeared to involve more than just learning progress. When only looking at the lower difficulties, it looked like players preferred simpler levels over more difficult ones. There are multiple possible explanations for this phenomenon:</p><p>First, players might have been influenced by their prior expectations about the difficulty of a level and how well it matched the actual difficulty. In the Super Mario Maker data set, each level was placed into one of four difficulty categories by the creator. These categories did not always match our difficulty calculations -defined by the number of players managing to clear the level (see SI). We looked at the discrepancy between these two difficulty assessments, by relating the difference between the calculated difficulty and the expected difficulty -defined by the difficulty category -to the average like rate (for more details, see SI). We observed an inverted-U shape with the peak at around 0 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2d</ref>). Players preferred levels in which their expectations matched our calculated difficulty measure. To assess this in more detail, we ran an additional regression analysis, including the difference between the two difficulty measures, and found a significant negative quadratic effect of the difference (linear: β = 0.00, z = −8.29, p &lt; .001, quadratic: β = −0.06, z = −40.12, p &lt; .001). As the linear effect is close to 0, the regression analysis confirmed that the peak of the inverted U-shape lies at a difference of 0 -where the expected difficulty matches the calculated difficulty measure.</p><p>A second possibility for the negative trend in the first half of the Super Mario Maker data set might be that players simply enjoy the feeling of success (e.g. solving a level or receiving higher rewards) on top of making progress in learning -thereby preferring the very easy over the slightly more difficult levels. The influence of rewards in video games on motivation has been shown in previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">37</ref> . However, with the data from the game data sets, we are not able to tease learning progress and a preference for success apart.</p><p>All of the above-mentioned data originated from three large-scale data sets of popular existing games. While this provided us with a large amount of data per level, we only had limited access to data per player. We were therefore not able to further study the additional hypotheses -i.e. the influence of the difficulty-expectation disparity or the influence of success. Instead, we decided to design two controlled and gamified experiments, in which we can collect all the necessary data, run more detailed analyses and precisely simulate learning progress. With the first experiment -a guessing game -we assessed learning progress including the relation of prior expectations of difficulty to the true difficulty. With the second experiment -a grid exploration game -we looked at the additional influence of success by letting players explore point values in grids.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1: A guessing game</head><p>To test the influence of learning progress on engagement in a simple setting, we developed a guessing game in which players guessed numbers from Gaussian distributions with different variances. This simple task has two main advantages over the above-analyzed game data sets: First, it allows us to implement a rational model and thereby derive more concrete predictions. Second, it minimizes the effect of the prior skill level of players, as the difficulty is defined by the randomness of the environment. While the task resembled classical psychological paradigms, we maintained the idea of using games as a research platform by giving players only a base pay and not compensating for performance. Additionally, we gave players the option to not engage with the task while still receiving their base compensation. Thereby, we still assessed enjoyment, rather than instrumental information gathering.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Paradigm</head><p>This experiment was inspired by the work of Geana et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9</ref> In one of their experiments, participants guessed numbers generated by a virtual machine in one of three conditions -"Certain", "Gaussian" and "Random" -while regularly reporting their boredom levels. Consistent with the learning progress theory, people's boredom levels were lowest in the Gaussian condition, in which learning was actually possible.</p><p>We adapted the experiment by introducing five Gaussian conditions with different underlying variances, which manipulate the difficulty of correctly guessing a number. Participants interacted with the distributions by guessing which number the machine would produce next (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3a</ref>). After submitting the number, we displayed the number the machine produced, as well as the difference between their guess and the machine's number. After each guess (after a minimum of three guesses), people could either continue guessing with the current distribution or stop and go on to a new distribution (with a new mean and variance), until the experiment automatically ended after a certain time (for more details, refer to the methods section). Importantly, players knew that they would not receive any performance-dependent bonus and did not need to interact with the game, so everything they engaged in during the time was purely for their entertainment. Thereby, we strongly focused on the enjoyment aspect of the game. We measured how many guesses participants played with each machine as an approximation of how much they enjoyed interacting with it.</p><p>We predicted that, in this controlled environment, participants would act according to the theory of learning progress. This would result in them spending most time with machines with intermediate variances, as they offer the most potential for learning. Machines with small variances would produce the same number repeatedly, while machines with big variances create numbers almost randomly. In both cases, participants would not make learning progress over a longer time which should prevent their enjoyment and consequently lead to participants changing to the next machine.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Simulation</head><p>To model this behavior, we used a Kalman filter, which is a Bayesian agent that integrates observations optimally to generate an estimate of the current mean. Initially, we assumed a prior variance of 10 and a prior mean of 50. With each sample, the Kalman filter updates the estimates of the mean and variance according to the Kalman Gain, which depends on the relationship between the estimated variance and the true underlying variance (for more details, see SI). We believe that participants try to track the mean of the distribution, as choosing the mean would give them the best chance to be close to the next generated number. Here, we therefore define learning progress as the update of the mean at each time step. As can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3b</ref>, the trajectory of learning progress differs based on the underlying variance. When simulating distributions with small variances (i.e. 0.1 or 1), the initial update at step 0 was large but is approaching 0 fast over the next few steps. When simulating distributions with high variances (i.e. 1000), there was almost no learning progress from the beginning onwards. When looking at intermediate variances (i.e. 10 or 100), the agent took an intermediate-sized step in the beginning but kept on making learning progress in the following steps. Which variances qualify as "small", "big" or "intermediate" is, of course, dependent on the assumed prior variance, which, in this case, was set to 10.</p><p>We assumed that people engage with a machine as long as their learning progress per step lies above a certain threshold. To simulate the amount of engagement -the number of guesses until they turn to the next machine -we stop the simulations when the update of the mean lies below this threshold, here set to 0.5 for simplicity (for other threshold values, see SI). We force the simulation to guess at least three times, similar to the experiment. We compared the different points of stopping based on the true and the prior variance. Each setup displayed an inverted U-shape when plotting the true variance on the x-axis and the number of guesses on the y-axis. Furthermore, the peak of the inverted U-shape was determined by the prior variancethe lower the prior, the lower the peak of the curve (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3c</ref>). This indicated that participants might like to interact with distributions with variances that are close to what they expect as prior variances.  Participants interacted with machines producing numbers from Gaussian distributions by adjusting a slider to guess the number the machine would produce next. After each guess, they could decide whether to stay with the current machine or move on to the next one. b: Simulated learning progress with a Kalman filter. The trajectory of the update of the mean depends on the true underlying variance of the Gaussian distribution. The smaller variances make large updates only during the first step, while the high variances make only small updates directly from the first step onwards. Only intermediate variances continue to make larger updates. c: Simulated engagement. The simulation samples from the current distribution until the update of the mean lies below a threshold -here set to 0.5 (for other values, see SI). The peak of the inverted-U shapes -the true variance the simulation is interacting with the longest -depends on the prior variance. d: Behavioral results. Data from 98 participants showed that they liked to interact most with machines with variance 1. e: Mixed-effects regression analysis. The significant negative squared effect of the variance accounts for the inverted U-shape seen in the human engagement behavior. f: Influence of the difficulty-expectation disparity on human behavior. The difference between the estimated variance -calculated based on the samples participants have seen in the current distribution -and the estimated expected variance -calculated based on the machines participants have seen so far -shows an inverted-U relationship to the number of guesses with a peak close to 0. This indicates that participants preferred to interact with variances that lie close to their expected variance. The inset plot displays a zoomed-in version of the data. Error bars (in d and e) indicate the standard error of the mean.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6/23</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>We used the data of 98 participants collected via Amazon Mechanical Turk. Participants played on average with 14 machines (mean 13.68, SD 8.55), made on average 77 guesses in total (mean 77.35, SD 27.65) and 8 guesses per machine (mean 8.42, SD 7.74).</p><p>First, we checked whether the manipulation of the variance indeed manipulated the difficulty of guessing correctly. We found that, with increasing variance, the average difference between the guesses and the numbers produced by the machine increased (β = 5.79, t = 33.03, p &lt; .001), while the number of correct guesses decreased (r = −0.94), as expected (for more details, see SI).</p><p>We examined whether participants' guess updates diminished over time, signifying convergence in their guesses. This would indicate progress in guessing the numbers generated by the machines. We performed a regression analysis, using the scaled update -the absolute difference between the current and last guess -and included a random intercept for each participant. We found that the number of the current trial had a significant negative effect on the size of the current update (β = −0.63, z = −5.80, p &lt; .001): players' updates got smaller over time for each machine, indicating that they converged on a number to guess.</p><p>We assessed whether players acted according to the learning progress hypothesis in this controlled environment by investigating the relationship between the variance and the engagement -the number of participants' guesses with each machine. According to our simulations and the original theory, players should engage most with environments with intermediate variance.</p><p>We first plotted the average number of interactions over variances and participants (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3d</ref>). We saw that people showed an inverted U-shape relationship and engaged most with machines of variance 1. To confirm this result, we performed a negative binomial mixed-effects regression analysis including the variance and the squared variance as components while adding a random intercept for each participant. We found that the linear component had a significant positive effect (β = 0.07, z = 2.99, p = .003), while the squared component had a significant negative effect (β = −0.03, z = −3.40, p &lt; .001), which indicated an inverse U-shape (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3e</ref>). Hence, participants engaged most with intermediate variances.</p><p>Additionally, we wanted to test whether participants' difficulty-expectation disparity -the mismatch between prior expectations of the current variance and the true variance -influenced their playing behavior, similar to what we had observed in the Super Mario Maker data set. We approximated players' prior difficulty by considering the machines participants had encountered thus far in the experiment. To calculate the current expectation, we took the average of the observed estimated variances up to this point, weighted by the number of guesses for that round. Additionally, we calculated the estimated variance of the current machine based on all the samples the machine produced before stopping. We then looked at whether the difference between the estimated variance and the estimated expected variance influenced participants' engagement (for details and different versions, see SI). Again, we found an inverted U-shape relationship between the difference and the number of guesses (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3f</ref>). A negative binomial mixed-effects analysis supported this finding. While controlling for the number of machines played so far and including a random intercept for each participant, we found a significant negative effect of the scaled difference squared (β = −0.06, z = −4.16, p &lt; .001), but no significant effect of the scaled linear component (β = 0.02, z = 1.33, p = .185), indicating that the peak of the inverted U-shape was not significantly different from 0. This indicates that participants engaged most with distributions with a variance close to their prior expected variance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2: An exploration game</head><p>People seem to take learning progress and the difficulty-expectation disparity into account when deciding how long to engage with each distribution in the guessing game. However, as we saw in the Super Mario Maker data set, players might also be motivated by simply having a preference for success. We believe that players prefer to interact with environments that offer higher reward values, even if these are not cumulative and players are not instructed or compensated to do so. Ideally, we wanted to test the influence of this additional component in a second experiment, in which we could discriminate between the influence of learning progress and the influence of uncompensated rewards on players' behavior. Moreover, we wanted to expand our initial observations on learning progress to another setting in which learning progress could be manipulated. Thus, we decided to use an additional paradigm for our second experiment -a grid exploration game. In this game -based on the grid search paradigm developed by Wu et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39</ref> -we could not only manipulate the difficulty of the environment but also its point values, independent of each other. Additionally, this setting was somewhat richer than the original guessing game, thereby further closing the gap between lab experiments and games.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Paradigm</head><p>In this game, participants interacted with multiple grids by iteratively opening tiles and observing their point values (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig.  4a</ref>). At each time step (after a minimum of five tiles), they could decide whether they wanted to open another tile or if they wanted to go to a new grid until the experiment automatically ended. They were only instructed to explore the grids, and no specific goal was given. As before, players knew that they would not get any performance-dependent bonus, and did not need  to interact with the task: they again were free to use the time as they liked. We approximated engagement by measuring how many tiles participants opened in each grid. We manipulated the structure of the grids across two dimensions. We manipulated the difficulty of predicting the value of a tile by changing the smoothness (the spatial correlation) of the underlying landscape of values, defined by a lengthscale parameter λ . The smaller the lengthscale parameter, the rougher the landscape -the value of a tile gives almost no information about the values of its neighbouring tiles. The bigger the lengthscale, the smoother the landscape -the value of a tile gives a lot of information about the values of its neighbouring tiles. The second dimension is the value of points -some grids constituted of higher point values, some of lower point values.</p><p>We assumed that participants would prefer to interact with intermediate difficult environments, which corresponded to intermediate lengthscales in this paradigm, as these lead to the biggest potential for learning progress. We, therefore, expected to see an inverted U-shape relationship between the lengthscale parameter λ and the engagement of participants. Additionally, we predicted that participants would engage more with grids that had a higher point value range. We assumed that participants enjoy the feeling of success, which we believe occurs when sampling high-value tiles. Thus, we expected to see a linear relationship between the maximum point values and participants' engagement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Simulation</head><p>We first tested the learning progress hypothesis by conducting several simulations with a Bayesian learning model using Gaussian Processes. The learning curves of the Gaussian Process model can be calculated, providing insight into the predictability of each function <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">40</ref> . Schulz et al. showed that these learning curves match human behavior. Additionally, manipulating the smoothness (defined by the lengthscale parameter λ ) influences people's perceived predictability of the functions <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41</ref> . For this simulation, we generated 1000 grids per lengthscale parameter. In each grid, we iteratively randomly sampled and opened tiles. After each tile, we let the model update its predictions of the values of all other tiles in the grid, based on the samples so far. We then compared this prediction to the ground truth of the grid to calculate the mean squared error. We took the mean over all grids for each lengthscale parameter and plotted the development of the error over time (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 4b</ref>) to assess the learning progress of the model for the different lengthscale values (λ ). We found that for small λ values (i.e. 0.25, 0.5, and 1), the model reduced the error very fast in the beginning, but then quickly plateaued. For large values (i.e. 8 and 16), the model also reduced the error fast but approached 0 very quickly. In both cases, the model did not show learning progress over a longer time. However, for intermediate values <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(2 and 4)</ref>, the model learned over a longer period, which supports our hypothesis.</p><p>We simulated how long the model would engage with each grid. We set a threshold to the learning progress -the lower limit of what the model would consider as worth for continued engagement. In the current simulation, we again set the threshold to 0.5 for simplicity. However, the qualitative results -an inverted U-shape relationship between the lengthscale and number of samples -stay the same when changing the threshold (for examples of different thresholds, see SI). We then measured how many tiles the model would open before the absolute difference of the error between two steps trailed below the threshold while forcing the simulation to also open at least five tiles of each grid. We saw that, indeed, there exists an inverted U-shape relationship as expected (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 4c</ref>).</p><p>For the magnitude of uncompensated points, we did not run any simulations, as we expected a simple linear relationship between engagement and the point values of a grid.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>To test whether people were influenced by the smoothness and the point values of the grids, we ran an experiment on Amazon Mechanical Turk with 44 participants. Participants interacted on average with 40 grids (mean 39.57, SD 37.16) and opened on average 36 tiles per grid (mean 36.09, SD 28.99). We assessed how much they engaged with each grid as a function of the lengthscale (λ ) (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 4d</ref>) and magnitude of point values (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 4e</ref>). Participants liked to interact most with a lengthscale value of 8 confirming our hypothesis about the smoothness of the environment influencing engagement. While the downward trend of the second half of the inverted U-shape is driven by only one data point (λ = 16), we believe that testing higher lengthscale values will not lead to any further insights, as the grids will become increasingly non-differentiable <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">42</ref> . Participants also liked to interact most with the highest point values, confirming our hypothesis about the magnitude. We saw that especially environments with high point values positively influenced the number of tiles participants opened, similar to what we observed in the Super Mario Maker data set -players exhibited a linear relationship in the easier environments.</p><p>Additionally, we ran a negative binomial mixed-effects regression analysis using the scaled value of the lengthscale and the scaled value of the magnitude, including a random intercept for each participant, and found that the lengthscale had a significant positive linear effect (β = 0.12, z = 4.90, p &lt; .001) and a significant negative squared effect (β = −0.06, z = −3.41, p &lt; .001). Together, they accounted for the inverse U-shape. The magnitude of point values had a significant positive effect on engagement (β = 0.08, z = 6.05, p &lt; .001), as was predicted (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 4f</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>We studied the theory of learning progress in inherently enjoyable environments, based on three large-scale game data sets and two controlled experiments. Across three video games (a puzzle, a racing, and a platformer game, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2</ref>), we found that player's ratings depended on the difficulty of the level, as predicted by a theory of learning progress. Thus intermediate difficulty led to the most learning progress, which in turn led to higher ratings (indicating increased fun), which we were able to test in naturally enjoyable and engaging game settings. In the Super Mario Maker data set, we observed two additional factors that also influenced ratings: i) the difficulty-expectation disparity between prior expectations of difficulty and our difficulty calculations based on the success ratio of the task and ii) the effect of success in easy levels. Through two precisely controlled experiments -a guessing game (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3</ref>) and a grid exploration game (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 4</ref>) -we confirmed that both of these additional components influenced player's engagement beyond the influence of learning progress.</p><p>As a first factor, we found an influence of a difficulty-expectations disparity: Players' engagement was maximized in environments with a difficulty that matched their prior expectations of difficulty -indicating that they like to reduce their prediction error as fast as they predicted. This is in contrast to previous theories of fun and enjoyment, which state that fun is maximal when players reduce their prediction error faster than expected <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">44</ref> -indicating that players should most enjoy acting in environments that are less difficult than expected.</p><p>As a second factor, we found an influence of success: Players' engagement was maximized in environments with higher underlying point values. This aligns with findings from earlier studies that showed that different kinds of game rewards can influence enjoyment <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">37</ref> . Previous work already suggested that players enjoy a feeling of performing well, which we believe occurred by finding high point values <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45</ref> .</p><p>These results emphasize the benefits of combining naturalistic large-scale data sets with controlled experiments. Through this usage of a diverse set of paradigms and measurements, we were not only able to confirm the learning progress theory, but also discover additional factors relevant for players' experience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations and future directions</head><p>We start this paper by arguing that we want to understand people's experience of "fun" or "enjoyment". However, the exact nature of these concepts has been debated <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29</ref> . For example, Blythe and Hassenzahl 29 define "fun" as a subset of enjoyment and contrast it with "pleasure". They argue that fun is more trivial and short-lived, while pleasure is concerned with relevance and identity. Other work in psychology use the term pleasure more generally for enjoyable experiences <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46</ref> , while other work describe similar concepts as "momentary subjective well-being" or "momentary happiness" <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">47</ref> . In their work on learning progress, Oudeyer et al. use the term "intrinsic reward" 5 as the dependent variable in their theory. This is linked to the literature on intrinsic motivation, which suggests that certain properties of environments, such as novelty or surprise, can be intrinsically rewarding for agents <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">48</ref> . In our work, we aim to describe and understand the positive affect associated with intrinsically motivating paradigms, such as games. To do so, we use the terms "enjoyment" or "intrinsic reward" as appropriate. Thus, while Schmidhuber uses the expression "fun", we do not claim this to be the only appropriate term to refer to the researched concept.</p><p>In Experiment 2, we showed that participants were motivated by the magnitude of point values. Whether these point values can be categorized as intrinsic rewards is debatable. On the one side, the concept of "more points are better" is learned by the participants in many natural environments, which speaks for the categorization as extrinsic reward. However, in many computer games the points do not have any direct consequences on the gameplay. In our experiment, we even went a step further and did not accumulate the points and additionally instructed players that they would not be compensated for them. This speaks in favor of a categorization as intrinsic reward. Because of similar difficulties in other environments, it has been argued that rewards might lie on a spectrum between extrinsic and intrinsic <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">49,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">50</ref> . In this framework, our instantiation of point values might lie between the two extremes of purely intrinsic and extrinsic rewards. Other researchers even argue whether categorizing rewards into the dimension of intrinsic-extrinsic is sensible at all and propose to instead look at the specific properties of the different rewards <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">51</ref> .</p><p>While our results suggest that people enjoy interacting with environments in which they can make the most learning progress, people can find enjoyment in situations where this is not the case. On the one hand, people sometimes enjoy tasks where no learning progress is possible, such as repeatedly solving a Rubik's Cube when already knowing how to do it, or interacting with nearly impossible tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">52</ref> . On the other hand, people might make progress in learning, but still not enjoy the activity, such as studying for a boring exam. Instead of trying to accommodate every situation in which learning progress could matter, the goal of the current work was to closely investigate the theory of learning progress in realistic settings to capture the main aspects of fun while identifying additional concepts influencing enjoyment.</p><p>Arguably, the main motivation for playing computer games is that they are fun and provide an enjoyable experience. While different levels of a game can be considered more or less enjoyable, they all represent potentially fun tasks. In our controlled experiments, we aimed to cover a broader range of experiences, including rather boring conditions. However, we ensured that participants interacted with the task only if they were motivated, by instructing them that compensation was entirely independent of their performance or level of engagement. We therefore assume that, despite the simplicity of our paradigms, participants' engagement is at least partly driven by intrinsic motivation. In the future, we plan to develop more complex paradigms that are inherently more enjoyable while still allowing for a high level of experimental control.</p><p>In our work, we approximated the positive affect of "enjoyment" using two measures: the amount of engagement with the experiment and players' ratings. We believe that using a diverse set of measurements is beneficial for a comprehensive understanding of human experiences. However, these two measures capture distinct theoretical constructs. While engagement reflects persistence and effort ("wanting"), level ratings represent a retrospective evaluation of the experience ("liking") <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">53</ref> . These constructs can lead to different predictions about human behavior. Though traditionally considered two sides of the same coin, the distinction between "liking" and "wanting" is now well established in neuroscience, referring to distinct psychological and neurological processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">54</ref> . In our work, we adopt a multimodal approach to studying the higher-level concept of enjoyment in paradigms aimed at intrinsic motivation. Both engagement and subjective ratings have been widely used in intrinsic motivation research (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30</ref> ) and, more specifically, in studies on learning progress <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">55</ref> . By integrating these two sources of evidence -both encompassed by the broader concept of "enjoyment" -we aim to deepen our understanding of this phenomenon. In the future, the influence of different intrinsically motivating components on distinct psychological constructs, such as "liking" vs. "wanting" should be further disentangled. This can be achieved by incorporating multiple measurements within the same paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">56</ref> , and by capturing enjoyment more explicitly -such as through direct self-reports or psychophysiological measures like facial expressions and heart rate variability <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">57,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">58</ref> .</p><p>We were also only able to examine learning progress through simulations since it cannot be directly assessed in our behavioral data. It has been shown that people can monitor their learning progress accurately <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22</ref> , but it is still an open question for which specific tasks this is possible. For instance, it might be the case that monitoring learning progress in tasks characterized by slow scales of learning such as in motor-skill learning poses a challenge for humans <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> , and different heuristics are available in different settings <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">59</ref> . However, we still believe that the higher ratings and increased engagement with intermediate difficult stimuli in our data stems from learning progress, as the qualitative results of the learning progress simulations point to similar preferences. Additionally, Ten et al. recently proposed a theoretical framework, which proposes that the emergence of an inverted-U relationship between knowledge and curiosity is generally due to an enhancement of learning progress <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">56</ref> . Furthermore, it has been shown that a preference for intermediately difficult stimuli disappears if the sense of learning progress is suppressed <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26</ref> . Thus, the preference for intermediately difficult environments might not stem from a conscious decision to maximize learning progress, but rather an intrinsic feeling of enjoyment as we have investigated here.</p><p>We simulated players as passively confronted with tasks of unknown difficulty. However, in video games, as well as in real life, people can often decide on the difficulty of the next task, or follow a predefined curriculum with increasing difficulty. While previous studies have demonstrated that learning progress plays a role in actively choosing difficulties <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">55</ref> , there exist situations in both video gaming and real life where people may not know how difficult a task is going to be or may only have vague prior intuitions. With many unexplored options available, instead of actively choosing the next task based on an estimate of difficulty, people often encounter new tasks about which they do not know anything: For example, when attempting to write a paper or trying out a new sport, one might not necessarily know how difficult it will be, yet can still experience enjoyment. However, people nonetheless need to assess whether and how long to engage in these tasks. Therefore, we think that our experiments capture important aspects of everyday activities, as participants also do not know the difficulty of a task beforehand, but still need to decide whether to continue engaging in it.</p><p>While it is important to identify the set of possible strategies used by humans in non-instrumental settings, future research should further explore when and where people rely on which factor influencing their enjoyment, and how different factors might interact <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">60</ref> . For example, work by Dubey and Griffiths 7 reconciled novelty-based and complexity-theories, by showing that their usefulness depends on the structure of the environment and that people use them accordingly. Although the rich environments here allowed us to uncover two factors influencing enjoyment beyond just learning progress, we can currently not examine the combined influence of the difficulty-expectation disparity and the feeling of success (induced by point values), as well as how much people might rely on one or the other. Thus, a more detailed analysis of how different factors interact will require the development of new games that provide access to individual skill levels and preferences, a thorough manipulation of prior expectations of difficulty, and a careful control of point values. Further research focusing on the interaction between these factors will be key to advancing our theory of human behavior in non-instrumental settings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>We investigated the theory of learning progress by looking at the relationship between difficulty and intrinsic reward in three richly structured, large-scale game data sets and two simple experiments, which focus on enjoyment, rather than learning. We found that -as predicted by the theory of learning progress -players preferred environments of intermediate difficulty. On top of that, we found in one of the game data sets, as well as in two highly-controlled experiments and detailed simulations, that a difficulty-expectation disparity, as well as a sense of success had additionally influenced enjoyment. These results enrich our understanding of the dynamics of fun in realistic environments and emphasize the importance of using both realistic, game-like environments and highly controlled experiments together with detailed simulations to advance theories of human learning and decision-making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and methods</head><p>The guessing game experiment was approved by the ethics committee of the medical faculty at the University of Tübingen (number 701/2020BO). The grid exploration game was approved by University College London Ethics Board. Both experiments were carried out in accordance with the relevant guidelines and regulations and informed consent was obtained from all subjects before participation. Both experiments were created with standard JavaScript. The simulations and data analyses were conducted in R and Python.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Game data sets</head><p>The Robozzle data set was created from the information on the official website of the game (http://robozzle.com/js/ index.aspx 61 ), which lists all generated levels. The data set includes all data from the "puzzle list" available in October 2020.</p><p>The Trackmania data set was created from information available on the webpage "Trackmania Exchange" (https: //tmnf.exchange/ 62 ). We included all generated race tracks available in November 2020.</p><p>The Super Mario Maker data set was provided on kaggle (https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/leomauro/ smmnet/data 63 ). Its data originates from SMM Bookmark, the official website of Super Mario Maker, which was discontinued in March 2021. The data from all three data sets is publicly available and does not include any identifiable information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Guessing Game</head><p>Players of the guessing game were told that they were scientists on an intergalactic mission, who stopped on an alien planet to get their spaceship fueled. They needed to pass ten minutes on an alien playground until the spaceship would be ready. On this playground, they found machines that produced numbers according to different Gaussian distributions. Each machine sampled from a Gaussian distribution with a fixed mean -uniformly sampled between 20 and 80 -and a fixed variance -uniformly sampled out of the following five values: 0.1, 1, 10, 100, 1000. Players always interacted with one machine at a time. They could guess the next number (between 0 and 100), the current machine would produce -if the machine would generate a number that lies below 1 or above 100 it would resample. After participants submitted their current guess through interacting with a slider, the machine displayed the number it produced, as well as the difference between this number and the participant's guess. After each guess, players could decide whether they wanted to make another guess or go on to the next machine, which would have a new fixed mean and variance (with the constraint of having to guess at least three times per machine before going on). The order of the machines participants encountered was randomized. Participants were not able to visit a machine again, once they advanced to the next one. Players were instructed that the compensation consists of 3$, with no option for additional compensation. The instructions also made clear that the study would end after 10 minutes independent of their engagementwith how many machines they played or how many guesses they made -or of their performance. The experiment automatically ended when the participant pressed a button once the time was up. Therefore, some participants did not encounter all 5 different variances, as they only visited a few machines.</p><p>We recruited 103 participants on Amazon's Mechanical Turk (30 females, mean age 33.26, SD 9.65). We excluded 4 participants, as they needed at least 10 retries on our comprehension check, consisting of four multiple-choice questions. Additionally, we removed the data on the last machine of every participant, as we could not assess how long they would have liked to interact with that machine. Therefore, we removed one additional participant, who played with only one machine. In the end, we used the data of 98 participants for our analyses. Participants played on average with 14 machines (mean 13.68, SD 8.55), made on average 77 guesses in total (mean 77.35, SD 27.65) and 8 guesses per machine (mean 8.42, SD 7.74).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Grid exploration game</head><p>Players of the grid exploration game were told that they would explore different grids with 30x30 tiles, with values from 5 to 75. They encountered one grid at a time, iteratively opened its tiles and observed their point values together with a corresponding color. At each time point, players could decide which new tile they want to open or to go on to the next grid (with the constraint of having to open at least 5 tiles per grid). When encountering a new grid, only one tile was revealed. They were not able to go to a previously encountered grid. Participants did not receive any specific goal, instead they were told to explore the grids. They were instructed that the experiment would automatically end after 10 minutes, no matter how many grids they interacted with or how many tiles they opened. Once participants left a grid after 10 minutes were over, the task ended. They also were instructed that they are compensated with 3$ independent of their performance or engagement in the task.</p><p>The grids were generated using a Gaussian process with a radial basis function kernel. We manipulated the smoothness of the grids, by uniformly sampling the length-scale parameter (λ ) of the kernel from the following values: 0.25, 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 8, 16. three games, we applied different methods for cleaning the respective data. In Robozzle, we excluded one level including null 4 values in the difficulty and rating, and all levels that had a "?" instead of a value as their difficulty (66 of 8241). Additionally, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> we excluded levels that had no ratings -neither likes nor dislikes (180 of 8241). Thereby, we reduced the data set from 8241 to 6 7994 levels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>7</head><p>In Trackmania, we included all 128662 levels, as every level had at least one award.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>8</head><p>In Super Mario Maker, several levels were included in the dataset multiple times, with the data extracted from the game 9 website at different time points, spanning several months. For our analysis, we only included the data of the newest time point 10 per level. We then included all 115032 levels in our analysis, even if they did not have any rating (here called star). We think it 11 is reasonable to include levels without any rating, as -in contrast to Robozzle -players cannot give negative ratings, and no 12 ratings might just be a sign of players not liking the level. All the levels were attempted by at least 10 players. We believe that  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Super Mario Maker -Categories</head><p>In the analysis of the Super Mario Maker data set we used the given categories to approximate participants' expectations. When plotting the relation between the players' ratings and the true difficulty for the individual categories, we found that the given 20 difficulty categories do often not correspond to the true difficulty, but span almost the whole range of difficulty values (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig.   21</ref> 6). This indicates that the label of the difficulty category might be misleading for many levels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>22</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Comparison</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>23</head><p>Due to the size of the three datasets, standard null-hypothesis testing methods yield trivially significant results for increasingly <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24</ref> higher-degree polynomials, despite only modest improvements in fit. Therefore, we used a scree plot to identify the "elbow"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>25</head><p>where the goodness of fit begins to level off with increasing model complexity. Specifically, we measured goodness of fit with 26 the mean squared error of the residuals (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Fig. 7</ref>), and analyzed how they improved for polynomial degrees 1 through 10 for each dataset. We observed that adding a quadratic term meaningfully improved model fit for all three datasets. However, in the polynomial did not. This aligns with our observation that ratings tend to have a negative relationship with difficulty in the simplest levels, while they follow an inverted-U relationship in levels of higher difficulty.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>31</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Super Mario Maker -Analysis of difference between calculated difficulty and expected difficulty 32</head><p>In our analysis of the difference between the categories and our calculated difficulty measure, we mapped the four category levels to the average calculated difficulty of the levels they include -very easy: 0.15, normal: 0.47, expert: 0.79, super expert:  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>40</head><p>Guessing game report the average difference between participant's guesses and the numbers produced by the machine, averaged per participant and variance in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>. Additionally, we report the number of correct guesses and ratio of correct guesses per variance across variance and found a (β = 5.79, t = 33.03, p &lt; .001). We also found a significant correlation between the variance and the number of correct guesses (r = −0.94, p = .016). For the main regression analysis of the guessing game, we used a negative binomial mixed effects model. We took the base-10</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>51</head><p>logarithm of the variance -as its values range from 0.1 to 1000 -, but did not scale it. This has the advantage that by including 52 the beta coefficients into a quadratic equation, the peak and thereby the preferred variance of players is directly interpretable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>53</head><p>Nevertheless, when scaling the variance before including it in the regression analysis, the squared variance still had a significant 54 negative effect. Additionally, we included random slopes for each participant to the analysis. We still see similar results as 55 before when not scaling the values. The model did not converge when scaling the values. The regression results of the different 56 analyses can be found in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>. and slopes. We saw that for 76 of the 98 analyzed players, the coefficient of the variance squared was negative, as predicted by 60 the theory. For 64 of these, the peak of the inverted U-shape was between the base-10 logarithm of 0.1 and 1000 indicating that 61 they actually exhibit an inverted U-shaped behavior within the tested variances.</p><p>their enjoyment, as they were instructed to, which meant that they were allowed to do whatever they wanted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>66</head><p>However, we still wanted to analyze whether the exclusion of participants creating a low amount of data changed our results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>67</head><p>Therefore, we tried out two additional methods of cleaning the data: excluding all participants who never made more than 3</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>68</head><p>guesses per machine and participants who did not play with more than two different variances. Both of these groups would not 69 display an inverted U-shape in their behavior. We saw that when excluding both of these groups -thereby reducing the data set 70 to 83 participants, we still saw a significantly negative squared effect of the variance, as expected (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>). first estimating the true underlying variance for each machine a participant encountered, based on all the generated numbers the 74 participant observed before continuing to the next machine. We then averaged for each machine the estimated true variances 75 from all the machines encountered before, weighted by number of guesses participants played with each. This was used as an 76 approximation of players prior expectation of the variance of the current machine. We then took the difference of the base-10 77 logarithm of the estimated true variance and the estimated expected variance. We included the scaled difference in a negative 78 binomial mixed-effects regression analysis, together with the scaled number of machines the participant has seen so far. With 79 this setup, we found an inverted U-shape relationship, as expected. We changed some details of the procedure -not scaling 80 the difference, not weighing the machines to create the expected variance, taking the base-10 logarithm before averaging to 81 calculate the expected variance -to see whether the results were robust. In all cases, we saw a significant negative effect of the 82 squared variance, as expected. As the influence of the linear variance component was never significant, the peak of the inverted 83 U-shape always was at a difference of 0 between the expected and the true difficulty. The details of the different regression 84 analyses can be found in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>85</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rating data 86</head><p>We approximated players' enjoyment by the number of guesses they played with different machines. As an additional measure,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>87</head><p>we asked players after each machine how much fun they were having on a scale from 1 -7. We did not include the results of 88 this questionnaire, as we believe that this is not the ideal way to assess enjoyment in an experiment in which players can decide 89 how long to engage with each task. As we only asked players after interacting with a machine, they might already have played 90 with it for many trials, and the enjoyment at the current moment might be different from the enjoyment at the beginning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>91</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Simulation and threshold 92</head><p>We simulated the guessing game by using a Kalman filter. We set the prior mean to 50 (the average of the possible value span), and the prior variance to one of the five considered variance values -0.1, 1, 10, 100, 1000. We then calculated the Kalman Gain, the updated mean, and the updated variance according to the following equations:  . Examples of generated grids. We generated grids with a radial basis function kernel with seven different λ values. These influence the roughness and smoothness of the grid. We also manipulate the magnitude of point values of the grids, indicated by the color of the tiles.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">K t =v t−1 v t−1 + v truê µ t =μ t−1 + K t • (x −μ t−1 )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>21/23</head><p>(λ) Smoothness <ref type="figure">Figure 10</ref>. Spatial correlation between the values of tiles, dependent on the distance, plotted for the seven different λ values. The higher the λ value, the stronger the correlation.  <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref>. Simulation of the grid exploration task. ae: Simulation results for different thresholds ranging from 0.1 to 1. The higher the threshold, the sooner the simulation stops -i.e. after fewer samples. The shapes of the different curves are qualitatively similar, regardless of the threshold used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Main regression analysis</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Rating behavior in game data sets. a: People's ratings of different levels of Robozzle. b: People's ratings of different levels of Trackmania. c: People's ratings of different levels of Super Mario Maker. The orange part indicates that players also liked simple levels, on top of learning progress. d: People's ratings of levels in relation to their expectations of difficulty and our difficulty calculation (success ratio)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>of Variance f: Influence of Expectations e: Regression Results</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Overview of guessing game experiment. a: Game design.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Overview grid exploration game. a: Game design: Participants explored tiles of a grid produced by an underlying Gaussian Process. We manipulated the smoothness and the point values of the grids. After each sample, participants could decide to open another tile or go on to the next grid. b: Simulated error over time with a Gaussian Process. The trajectory of the error -calculated as the mean squared error between the true values and the predicted values of the grid -is dependent on the smoothness of the grid, defined by the underlying lengthscale parameter (λ ). Smaller values plateau quickly, while larger values quickly reach an error of 0. Only intermediate values continue reducing their error over a longer time frame. c: Simulated engagement. The simulation samples new tiles until the error lies below a threshold -here set to 0.5 (for other values, see SI). We see an inverted U-shape relationship between the smoothness -defined by the lengthscale parameter (λ )and the number of samples. d: Behavioral results based on smoothness. We gathered data from 44 participants. They interacted the most with grids with a λ value of 8. e: Behavioral results based on the magnitude of point values. Values are summarized in bins of 5. Participants interacted the most with grids that had high point values. f: Mixed-effects regression analysis. The significant negative squared effect of smoothness accounts for the inverted U-shape seen in the behavioral plot. The linear effect of magnitude showed that participants engaged most in environments with higher point values. Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>13 this</head><label>13</label><figDesc>might have been a pre-selection by the creator of the data set. their marginal histograms (see Fig. 5). a: Robozzle -Raw data c: Super Mario Maker -Raw data b: Trackmania -Raw data</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Raw data of human rating behavior in game datasets, including marginal histograms a: Raw data of people's ratings of different levels of Robozzle. b: Raw data of people's ratings of different levels of Trackmania. c: Raw data of people's ratings of different levels of Super Mario Maker.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Human rating behavior in the Super Mario Maker game dataset, divided by given difficulty category. We used different y-axis for the four plots to improve visibility of the different trends. a: People's ratings of different true difficulty levels, labeled as "easy". b: People's ratings of different true difficulty levels, labeled as "normal". c: People's ratings of different true difficulty levels, labeled as "expert". d: People's ratings of different true difficulty levels, labeled as "super expert". Error bars indicate the standard error of the mean.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Goodness of fit as a function of polynomial degree for the linear regression models. Goodness of fit is measured by the mean squared error of the residuals from polynomial regression models with degrees ranging from 1 to 10. a: Goodness of fit for Robozzle. b: Goodness of fit for Trackmania. c: Goodness of fit for Super Mario Maker. the category the level is placed in. In our regression analysis, we included a linear and quadratic component of this difference. component, when scaling the difference (linear: β = 0.00, z = 6.72, p &lt; .001, quadratic: β = −0.01, z = −40.12, p &lt; .001), 39 as in the original analysis.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Simulation of the guessing game for different prior variances. ae: Simulation results for different thresholds ranging from 0.1 to 1. The higher the threshold, the sooner the simulation stops -i.e. after fewer samples. The shapes of the different curves are qualitatively similar, regardless of the threshold used. with different λ and point valuesFigure 9</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary statistics of the guessing performance.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Variance Average difference of guesses Total nr. of correct guesses Ratio of correct guesses</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.1</cell><cell>7.57</cell><cell>282</cell><cell>0.28</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>8.85</cell><cell>247</cell><cell>0.17</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>10</cell><cell>10.03</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>0.05</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>100</cell><cell>13.84</cell><cell>36</cell><cell>0.03</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1000</cell><cell>25.14</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>50</cell><cell>Main regression analysis</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Regression coefficients for the mixed effects analysis of the guessing game.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Main analysis</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>2.99</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.03</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>-3.40</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Using scaled variance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-0.02</cell><cell>0.99</cell></row><row><cell>Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.07</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-3.40</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Including random slopes</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-0.02</cell><cell>0.99</cell></row><row><cell>Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.07</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-3.40</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Regression coefficients for the mixed effects analysis of the guessing game, excluding participants who never played more than three guesses and who interacted with only two different variances.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>3.08</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.03</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>-3.26</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Analysis of expectations</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Regression coefficients for the mixed effects analysis of the guessing game includingexpectations =v t−1 • (1 − K t )K t is the Kalman Gain used to update the mean and variance estimates based on the observed sample x and the true variance</figDesc><table><row><cell>Main analysis</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>1.33</cell><cell>0.19</cell></row><row><cell>Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.06</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>-4.16</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Machines</cell><cell>-0.06</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-2.67</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Without scaling the difference</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell>Variance</cell><cell>-0.02</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>-1.73</cell><cell>0.08</cell></row><row><cell>Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.02</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>-4.16</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Machines</cell><cell>-0.06</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-2.67</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Without weighting the previous machines according to the</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>number of samples</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>1.35</cell><cell>0.18</cell></row><row><cell>Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.04</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>-3.29</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Machines</cell><cell>-0.06</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-2.56</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Taking the base-10 logarithm before taking the average to</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">calculate the expected variance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>1.20</cell><cell>0.23</cell></row><row><cell>Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.06</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>-4.29</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell>Machines</cell><cell>-0.06</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-2.76</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>v t</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Regression coefficients for the mixed effects analysis of the exploration game</figDesc><table><row><cell>Main analysis</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>4.90</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.06</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-3.41</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Magnitude</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>6.05</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Including random slopes (resulting in a singular fit)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.16</cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell>4.22</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.08</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-3.33</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Magnitude</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>3.71</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Including an interaction effect</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Estimate Std. Error z value Pr(&gt;|z|)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Variance</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>4.85</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Variance squared</cell><cell>-0.06</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-3.37</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Magnitude</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>5.00</cell><cell>0.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Variance*Magnitude</cell><cell>0.06</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>2.25</cell><cell>0.02</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Variance squared*Magnitude</cell><cell>-0.03</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>-1.61</cell><cell>0.11</cell></row><row><cell>a: Threshold = 0.1</cell><cell cols="2">b: Threshold = 0.25</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>c: Threshold = 0.5</cell></row><row><cell>d: Threshold = 0.75</cell><cell cols="2">e: Threshold = 1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Super Mario Maker dataset, adding a cubic term did further reduce the mean squared error noticeably, while a fourth-degree</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>CMW is supported by the German Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF): Tübingen AI Center, FKZ: 01IS18039A and funded by the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG, German Research Foundation) under Germany's Excellence Strategy-EXC2064/1-390727645. ES is supported by the Max Planck Society, the Volkswagen Foundation (VW98569) and a Jacobs Research Fellowhsip.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The tile values of each grid spanned a range of 40 values. For each grid, we uniformly sampled a value between 5 and 35, as the lowest value a tile would display, thereby setting the highest value between 45 and 75. The value of each tile was visualized by a shade of red. Low values had a lighter shade, while high values had a darker shade. Every time a participant clicked on the button "Next", they encountered a new grid with a new smoothness and new range of values. Each grid was randomly sampled at the time of advancing, therefore the order of grids was different between subjects. Therefore, some participants did not experience all length-scale values (dependent on the number of grids they visited).</p><p>We </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Code and data availability</head><p>Anonymized participant and player data, as well as the code used for the experiments, simulations, and analyses are available at https://github.com/franziskabraendle/fun_learning_progress.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author Contributions</head><p>FB, CMW, and ES conceived the study. FB implemented the experiments with contributions from CMW. FB and ES collected the data. FB performed the analyses and prepared the figures. FB, CMW and ES wrote the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supporting Information</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Game data sets</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data cleaning 2</head><p>We cleaned the game datasets before using them for our analyses. As we had access to very different formats of data in the</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data visualization 15</head><p>To give an insight into the distribution of difficulty and rating values, we plotted the data for all three datasets together with 0.92. We then took the difference between the calculated difficulty of each level and this prior expected difficulty according to Summary statistics <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">42</ref> We checked whether the manipulation of variances indeed had an influence on the difficulty of guessing the correct number. We all participants. For these analyses, we excluded the first guess made for each machine, as it is by definition always random.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Individual data</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Different versions of data cleaning</head><p>For the main guessing game analysis, we only excluded participants who needed at least ten trials for the comprehension check.</p><p>We decided to not exclude any additional participants, as we wanted to assess participants' behavior when acting according to</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing fun by creating data with easily reducible subjective complexity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schmidhuber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Intrinsically motivated learning in natural and artificial systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intrinsic motivation systems for autonomous mental development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Hafner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE transactions on evolutionary computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information-seeking, curiosity, and attention: computational and neural mechanisms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gottlieb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lopes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baranes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="593" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Formal theory of creativity, fun, and intrinsic motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schmidhuber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Auton. Mental Dev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="230" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intrinsic motivation, curiosity, and learning: Theory and applications in educational technologies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gottlieb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lopes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Prog. Brain Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The goldilocks effect: Human infants allocate attention to visual sequences that are neither too simple nor too complex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kidd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Piantadosi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Aslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reconciling novelty and complexity through a rational analysis of curiosity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dubey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="476" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wick in the candle of learning: Epistemic curiosity activates reward circuitry and enhances memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1111/j.1467-9280.2009.02402.x</idno>
		<idno type="PMID">19619181</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="963" to="973" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Boredom, information-seeking and exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Geana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Csikszentmihalyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Abuhamdeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nakamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Flow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="238" />
			<pubPlace>Netherlands, Dordrecht</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mind in society: Development of higher psychological processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Vygotsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
			<publisher>Harvard university press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a theory of intrinsically motivating instruction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Malone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="369" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intrinsic motivation systems for autonomous mental development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Hafner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1109/TEVC.2006.890271</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Evol. Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Curious exploration via structured world models yields zero-shot object manipulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sancaktar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Blaes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Martius</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24170" to="24183" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The eighty five percent rule for optimal learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Straccia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of human curiosity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Berlyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://bpspsychub.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/j.2044-8295.1954.tb01243.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://bpspsychub.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/j.2044-8295.1954.tb01243.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br. J. Psychol. Gen. Sect</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of curiosity: A review and reinterpretation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1037/0033-2909.116.1.75</idno>
		<idno>DOI: 10.1037/ 0033-2909.116.1.75</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Piaget</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Play</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Dreams, and Imitation in Childhood</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Routledge &amp; Paul</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1945" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Midbrain dopamine neurons signal preference for advance information about upcoming rewards</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bromberg-Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Hikosaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Orbitofrontal cortex uses distinct codes for different choice attributes in decisions motivated by curiosity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Blanchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hayden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bromberg-Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="602" to="614" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information-seeking in the brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Charpentier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Cogliati-Dezza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Drive for Knowledge: The Science of Human Information-Seeking</title>
		<editor>Dezza, I. C., Schulz, E. &amp; Wu, C. M.</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Humans monitor learning progress in curiosity-driven exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kaushik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gottlieb</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Curiosity and the dynamics of optimal exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Poli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>O'reilly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mars</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hunnius</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of task difficulty, novelty and the size of the search space on intrinsically motivated exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baranes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gottlieb</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning progress mediates the link between cognitive effort and task engagement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sayalı</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Heling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cools</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">236</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105418</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Difficulty-skill balance does not affect engagement and enjoyment: a pre-registered study using artificial intelligence-controlled difficulty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cutting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Deterding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Demediuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sephton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Royal Soc. Open Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Formal theory of creativity, fun, and intrinsic motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schmidhuber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Auton. Mental Dev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="230" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">fun, fun, fun&quot;: Types of fun, attitudes to fun, and their relation to personality and biographical factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mcmanus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Furnham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">01</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blythe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hassenzahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Semantics of Fun: Differentiating Enjoyable Eeperiences</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Netherlands, Dordrecht</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="100" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intrinsic Motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Deci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<publisher>Plenum Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using games to understand the mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PsyArXiv</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognitive control and optimal learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Son</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sethi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="759" to="774" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In search of the neural circuits of intrinsic motivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Curiosity-based learning in infants: A neurocomputational approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Twomey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Westermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dev. science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12629</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gobet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Retschitzki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>De Voogt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Moves in mind: The psychology of board games</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manifesto for a new (computational) cognitive revolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Greater rewards in videogames lead to more presence, enjoyment and effort</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalization guides human exploration in vast decision spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Speekenbrink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1038/s41562-018-0467-4</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="915" to="924" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Searching for rewards like a child means less generalization and more directed exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ruggeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1561" to="1572" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning curves for gaussian processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sollich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>14/23</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing the perceived predictability of functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Reshef</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Speekenbrink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In Cogsci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gaussian processes for machine learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rasmussen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<publisher>MIT press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Play in predictive minds: A cognitive theory of play</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kiverstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Roepstorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">462</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mastering uncertainty: A predictive processing account of enjoying uncertain success in video game play</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Deterding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kiverstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">924953</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relationship of task success to task liking and satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Locke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">379</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Measuring emotion: Behavior, feeling, and physiology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bradley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="242" to="276" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational and neural model of momentary subjective well-being</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rutledge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Skandali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12252" to="12257" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Curiosity-driven exploration: foundations in neuroscience and computational modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Modirshanechi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kondrakiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gerstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Haesler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A goal-centric outlook on learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Molinaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intrinsic motivation and reinforcement learning. Intrinsically motivated learning natural artificial systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="47" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A reward-learning framework of knowledge acquisition: An integrated account of curiosity, interest, and intrinsic-extrinsic rewards</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">175</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Motivated for near impossibility: How task type and reward modulate task enjoyment and the striatal activation for extremely difficult task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sakaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/10.1101/828756</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2022/10/01/828756.full.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotions as computations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Emanuel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Eldar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2022.104977</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2022.104977" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">144</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wanting and liking: Observations from the neuroscience and psychology laboratory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Berridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="398" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contributions of expected learning progress and perceptual novelty to curiosity-driven exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Poli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mars</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hunnius</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The curious u: Integrating theories linking knowledge and information-seeking behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-Y</forename><surname>Oudeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sakaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PsyArXiv</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inferring player experiences using facial expressions analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bakkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Pisan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Interactive Entertainment</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Interactive Entertainment</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated detection of engagement using video-based estimation of facial expressions and heart rate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Monkaresi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bosch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Calvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mello</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Affect. Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An inductive bias for slowly changing features in human reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hedrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hall-Mcmaster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Schuck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2024" to="2025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empowerment contributes to exploration behaviour in a creative video game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Brändle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stocks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1481" to="1489" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Trackmania Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://tmnf.exchange/" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2024" to="2025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Smmnet -super mario maker</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mauro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/leomauro/smmnet/data" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2024" to="2025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
