<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
							<email>david.v.smith@temple.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Wyngaarden</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cooper</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sharp</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Sazhin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ori</forename><surname>Zaff</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominic</forename><surname>Fareri</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Adelphi University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johanna</forename><surname>Jarcho</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>LocaKon: Philadelphia</addrLine>
									<region>Pennsylvania</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18112/openneuro.ds004920.v1.1.0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>FuncKonal magneKc resonance imaging</term>
					<term>fMRI</term>
					<term>substance use</term>
					<term>decision making</term>
					<term>brain</term>
					<term>reward sensiKvity</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Trait reward sensiKvity, risk for developing substance use, and mood disorders have each been linked with altered striatal responses to reward. Moreover, striatal response to reward is sensiKve to social context, such as the presence of a peer, and drugs are oPen sought out and consumed in social contexts or as a result of social experiences. Thus, mood disorder symptoms, striatal responses to social context and social reward may play a role in substance use. To invesKgate this possibility, this dataset was collected as part of a NIDA grant Ktled &quot;Aberrant Reward SensiKvity: Mechanisms Underlying Substance Use.&quot; The overarching goal was to characterize the associaKons between neural responses to social and nonsocial rewards, trait reward sensiKvity, substance use, and mood disorder symptoms. APer obtaining quesKonnaire data quanKfying reward sensiKvity, substance use, and other psychosocial characterisKcs, young adults (N=59; mean age: 20.89 years ± 1.75 years) completed four fMRI tasks tesKng different features of social and reward processing. These included: 1) a strategic reward-based decision-making task with UlKmatum and Dictator Game condiKons; 2) a task where parKcipants shared rewards or losses with peers, strangers, or non-human partners; 3) a task in which parKcipants received well-matched social and monetary rewards and punishment; and 4) a monetary incenKve delay (MID) task in which parKcipants tried to obtain or avoid rewards and losses of different magnitude. This dataset includes sociodemographic quesKonnaire data, anatomical, task-based fMRI, and corresponding behavioural task-based data. We outline several opportuniKes for extension and reuse, including exploraKon of individual differences, cross-task comparisons, and representaKonal similarity analyses. SPECIFICATIONS TABLE Subject Biological Sciences à Neuroscience: CogniKve Specific subject area Social and nonsocial reward systems Data format Raw; BIDS-compliant Type of data structural brain images (compressed NIfTI files [.nii.gz]) funcKonal brain images (compressed NIfTI files [.nii.gz]) experimental design informaKon (tab-separated values [.tsv]) experiment meta-data (Java Script objecKon notaKon [.json]) Data collec$on We collected neuroimaging data from 59 parKcipants using a 3T Siemens Prisma MRI scanner (Syngo MR E11) with a 20-channel head coil. FuncKonal images were acquired using a simultaneous mulKslice (mulK-band factor = 2) gradient echo-planar imaging (EPI) sequence (240 mm in FOV, TR = 1,750 ms, TE = 29 ms, voxel size of 3.0 x 3.0 x 3.0 mm 3 , flip angle = 74°, interleaved slice acquisiKon, with 52 axial slices). During imaging, parKcipants engaged in four tasks tapping into different aspects of social and nonsocial reward processing. We also collected quesKonnaire data using 20 different measures. All data conform to the Brain Imaging Data Structure (BIDS) standard.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">VALUE OF THE DATA</head><p>• These fMRI data are valuable to understand how the young adult brain responds to rewardbased decision-making and feedback in social and non-social contexts. • Each task includes well-matched contrasts to test neural response to different features of social or reward processing: 1) UlKmatum vs. Dictator Game: Strategic reward-based decision-making with and without threat of social retribuKon; 2) Shared Reward: Sharing monetary losses or gains with a friend, stranger, or non-human partner; 3) Social Doors: differences in response to social or monetary reward (liked by a peer/win money) and punishment (disliked by a peer/lose money); 4) Monetary IncenKve Delay Task: differences in response to high or low levels of gain or loss. • Specificity or generalizability of brain funcKon engaged during reward processing in social and nonsocial contexts can be tested in relaKon to numerous sociodemographic and clinically relevant individual differences measures. • Data can be analyzed using a whole brain, region of interest (ROI), or circuit level <ref type="bibr">(PPI)</ref> approach.</p><p>• Researchers interested in brain-based reward processing, and social cogniKon more specifically, may benefit from this dataset through its well-matched tasks and wide range of individual difference measures. • Expanding beyond univariate analyses, researchers could use mulKvariate methods, such as representaKonal similarity analysis (RSA), to test for specificity and generalizability of processing across reward decision-making contexts (with/without threat of retribuKon), partners (friend, stranger, non-human), and domains (social/monetary). Moreover, high quality anatomical images could be used to test for relaKons between brain funcKon and structure (e.g., VBM). SensiKvity to reward (e.g., striatal response to MID) or social reward (e.g., striatal response to social vs. non-social reward) could be used as an individual difference measure in each of the other tasks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">BACKGROUND</head><p>Prior studies have shown links between trait reward sensiKvity and risk for developing substance use and mood disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Building on these observaKons, neuroimaging studies have shown that substance use and mood disorders are associated with altered striatal responses to reward <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Yet, the striatal response to reward is also sensiKve to social context, such as the presence of a peer <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Furthermore, drugs are oPen sought out and consumed in social contexts or as a result of social experiences <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Thus, striatal responses to social context and social reward may play a role in substance use.</p><p>To invesKgate this possibility, this dataset was collected as part of a NIDA grant Ktled "Aberrant Reward SensiKvity: Mechanisms Underlying Substance Use." The overarching goal of this project was to characterize the associaKons between neural responses to social and non-social rewards, trait reward sensiKvity, substance use, and other psychosocial variables <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. To date, we have published/preprinted efforts that show links between substance use and trait reward sensiKvity in tasks focused on social reward <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, social context <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, and social decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. The current data arKcle adds to these papers/preprints by describing the full scope of the dataset and outlining possibiliKes for reuse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">DATA DESCRIPTION</head><p>This dataset is available as OpenNeuro Dataset 4920 <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, and it is composed of neuroimaging data from 59 parKcipants who completed four tasks involving social and nonsocial reward processing. The data are organized in accordance with the Brain Imaging Data Structure (BIDS) specificaKon <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> using HeuDiConv <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. Anatomical images (T1w) were defaced using PyDeface.</p><p>As part of the BIDS standard, all files are accompanied by .json sidecars that contain metadata regarding the file. This organizaKon is parKcularly important in the case of NIFTI data (.nii.gz files) and tabular data (e.g., .tsv files). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Files</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Ques(onnaires</head><p>We collected self-reported data on several different facets of behavior, health, and personality. These measures are stored in the phenotype directory in the BIDS dataset. The accompanying json sidecar file contains all of the necessary metadata to reconstruct the items in the scale and the original citaKon for the measure. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>File Name Goal of Measure</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Experimental Tasks</head><p>All tasks were completed by parKcipants while undergoing fMRI. Task order was counterbalanced across parKcipants.</p><p>Ul$matum Game and Dictator Game. To measure strategic behavior in social contexts, we used the Dictator Game (DG; <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>) and UlKmatum Game (UG; <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>). In both games (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>), a sum of money is divided between a proposer and a recipient. In the DG, the proposer allocates money to a passive recipient. To maximize earnings, proposers should choose to keep a greater allocaKon for themselves. In the UG, a recipient can reject the proposer's allocaKon and both players receive nothing. To maximize earnings, proposers should offer closer to an even split to avoid rejecKon by the recipient. ParKcipants made decisions in the Dictator Game as a Proposer (DG-P), UlKmatum Game as a Proposer (UG-P) and as an UlKmatum Game Recipient (UG-R). They were led to believe that each trial was played with a different parKcipant (i.e., one shot games), proposals they received were from past parKcipants, their own proposals would be used with future parKcipants, and a bonus payment would be made depending on the outcome of a randomly selected proposal. We presented 72 total trials, 24 in each of the three condiKons (DG-P, UG-P, UG-R), across two 7:30 minute runs (total Kme of ~15 minutes). Each trial consisted of an endowment phase (1 seconds), intersKmulus interval (ISI) of 1.5-4.5 seconds M = 2.42 seconds, decision phase (3 seconds), and an intertrial interval (ITI) of 1-8 seconds; M = 2.7 seconds. Each parKcipant was endowed with a sum of money between $15-$25. To indicate whether the parKcipant was playing as a DG-P, UG-P, or UG-R, they were presented with a target sKmulus of a triangle, square, or circle respecKvely. During the decision phase, proposers were presented with the opKon to offer combinaKons of 6, 19, 32, or 45 percent of the endowment. ParKcipants were able to select between two opKons, to offer More or Less, or Accept or Reject their offer. These opKons switched sides between trials. If a parKcipant missed a trial, the screen indicated they were too slow and logged a missed trial.   <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p><p>Shared Reward Task. In the card guessing game <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 2</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15]</ref>, parKcipants used their right hand's index finger or middle finger to guess whether the value of a playing card was 'lower' or 'higher' than 5, respecKvely. ParKcipants were told that they would be spliwng monetary gains of $10 or losses $5 evenly with one of three partners. The possible partners were: 1) a gender-matched close friend who parKcipants put research staff in contact with; 2) a gender-matched confederate, said to be a past parKcipant in the study, serving the role of a stranger; and 3) a non-human control in the form of a computer. Money shared with the partner on the selected trial was said to be sent to the friend or stranger via Amazon giP card, or returned to a pool of lab funds for the computer. The image of the partner for any given round appeared at the beginning of the trial phase and remained unKl the end of the outcome phase. ParKcipants cycled through each partner for blocks of 8 trials, with each block primarily geared towards wins or losses (6 trials in the condiKon of interest, and 2 neutral or opposing condiKons; cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>). Two runs were completed, each lasKng 6 minutes and 54 seconds.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Delgado et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Fareri et al., 2012)</ref> with social context manipulated through a computer, a gender-matched confederate (Jack/Jill), or a close friend condi(on. Par(cipants were told that wins ($10) or losses ($5) would be shared equally with their partner. A green up-arrow indicated a correct guess and a monetary gain of $10.00; a red down-arrow indicated an incorrect guess and a monetary loss of $5.00; a white arrow poin(ng side-to-side indicated a neutral outcome with no money won or lost. Players guessed whether the number on a card would be above or below 5, with choices between 1 and 9. A picture of the partner's face remained above the card from the onset of decision-making through the end of the outcome phase. We measured the responses associated with winning or losing money con(ngent on the social context of partner type. This figure was adapted from previous work with permission <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>Social Doors Task. The monetary and social reward task <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref> were presented in separate runs, order counterbalanced across parKcipants). This design eliminates task switching costs while sKll preserving our ability to directly contrast responses associated with social and nonsocial reward. In the monetary condiKon, parKcipants were shown two doors. ParKcipants were instructed to pick the door that contained a $0.50 prize (3 seconds; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>). On monetary reward trials, feedback (1 second) indicated that the parKcipant won $0.50. On monetary loss trials, feedback indicated that the parKcipant lost $0.25. In the social condiKon, parKcipants were shown the faces of two peers. ParKcipants were informed that each peer had indicated whether they liked or disliked the parKcipant based on a photo of them, and they were instructed to pick the peer that liked them. On social reward trials, feedback indicated that the peer liked them. On social loss trials, feedback indicated that the peer disliked them. Each run included 60 trials: 50% resulted in reward and 50% resulted in loss feedback. Although both tasks involve feedback about correct/incorrect guesses, the result of that feedback occurs in social or monetary domains. Trials were separated by a variable duraKon intertrial interval (1.1 -11.6 seconds; M = 3.5 seconds).  <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><p>Monetary Incen$ve Delay Task. The monetary incenKve delay (MID) task (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref> ; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>) is comprised of five condiKons in which parKcipants respond to visual cues indicaKng potenKal monetary outcomes: high gain (orange triangle), low gain (orange square), high loss (blue triangle), low loss (blue square), and neutral (no gain or loss; white circle). During the endowment phase parKcipants are shown the condiKon for the current trial via presentaKon of one of the unique cues. This is followed by a jimered inter-sKmulus interval, lasKng from 1 to 8 seconds. At the end of the interval, a small square appears indicaKng the onset of the decision phase, where parKcipants have 1 second to make a bumon press. If they respond within the decision phase, they win the monetary prize (gain trials) or avoid the monetary loss (loss trials). If they are too slow, they do not with the monetary prize (gain trials) and fail to avoid the monetary loss (loss trials). ReacKon Kme serves as a proxy for moKvaKonal impact of these disKnct incenKve condiKons. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">MRI Data Acquisi(on</head><p>FuncKonal images were acquired using a 3.0 Tesla Siemens PRISMA MRI scanner and a 20-channel head coil. Blood OxygenaKon Level-Dependent (BOLD) sensiKve funcKonal images were acquired using a simultaneous mulKslice (mulK-band factor = 2) gradient echo-planar imaging (EPI) sequence (240 mm in FOV, TR = 1,750 ms, TE = 29 ms, voxel size of 3.0 x 3.0 x 3.0 mm 3 , flip angle = 74°, interleaved slice acquisiKon, with 52 axial slices). We also collected single-band reference images with each funcKonal run of mulK-band data to improve moKon correcKon and registraKon. To facilitate anatomical localizaKon and co-registraKon of funcKonal data, a high-resoluKon structural scan was acquired (sagimal plane) with a T1-weighted magneKzaKon-prepared rapid acquisiKon gradient echo (MPRAGE) sequence (224 mm in FOV, TR = 2,400 ms, TE = 2.17 ms, voxel size of 1.0 x 1.0 x 1.0 mm 3 , flip angle 8°). In addiKon, we also collected a B0 fieldmap to unwarp and undistort funcKonal images (TR: 645 ms; TE1: 4.92 ms; TE2: 7.38 ms; matrix 74×74; voxel size: 2.97×2.97×2.80 mm; 58 slices, with 15% gap; flip angle: 60°).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">LIMITATIONS</head><p>Our dataset has some notable limitaKons. First, we collected 10 scans before the COVID-19 pandemic halted data collecKon for 15 months. Upon resuming the study, we dropped some components of the original study due to budgetary constraints. These addiKonal measures included diagnosKc interviews that assess history of substance use and mood disorders. Second, due to an experimenter error, we are missing Inclusion of Other in Self data for the stranger condiKon for several parKcipants (missing for 23/59 parKcipants who have brain data). This omission limits some analyses that seek to compare relaKve closeness between friends and strangers. Third, although our sample size is larger than many neuroimaging studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>, it may sKll be too small to detect some brain-behaviour associaKons <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1. Ul,matum and Dictator Games. We opera(onalized strategic behaviour as offering more in the Ul(matum Game and less in the Dictator Game, as this strategy would maximize earnings for the par(cipant. During the Endowment phase, par(cipants received $15-25. A square indicated that the par(cipant would be ac(ng as the Proposer in the Ul(matum Game or deciding how much money to split with a counterpart. A triangle indicated that the par(cipant would act as the Proposer in the Dictator Game. Finally, a circle indicates that the par(cipant would be the Recipient in the Ul(matum Game, which allowed them to decide whether they would accept or reject an offer given to them. During the Decision Phase, the par(cipant as a proposer decided to offer More or Less to their counterpart. As a recipient, whether to Accept or Reject the offer. This figure was adapted from previous work with permission [8].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Shared Reward Task. The task consisted of a card guessing game</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Social Doors Task. On each trial, par(cipants choose either between two doors (monetary condi(on) or the faces of two peers (social condi(on) in search of a reward. A_er a brief interval, they receive feedback: an upward arrow indica(ng a win (monetary condi(on=$0.50 gain; social condi(on=posi(ve peer feedback) or a downward arrow indica(ng a loss (monetary condi(on=$0.25 loss; social condi(on=nega(ve peer feedback). This figure was adapted from previous work with permission</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Monetary Incen,ve Delay Task. In the monetary incen(ve delay task, par(cipants have a limited (me to respond to visual cues indica(ng five different condi(ons: high gain, low gain, high loss, low loss, and neutral. Reac(on (mes reflect the mo(va(onal impacts of the condi(ons. This figure was adapted from previous work with permission<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>1. Ul,matum and Dictator Games.</head><label></label><figDesc>We opera(onalized strategic behaviour as offering more in the Ul(matum Game and less in the Dictator Game, as this strategy would maximize earnings for the par(cipant. During the Endowment phase, par(cipants received $15-25. A square indicated that the par(cipant would be ac(ng as the Proposer in the Ul(matum Game or deciding how much money to split with a counterpart. A triangle indicated that the par(cipant would act as the Proposer in the Dictator Game. Finally, a circle indicates that the par(cipant would be the Recipient in the Ul(matum Game, which allowed them to decide whether they would accept or reject an offer given to them. During the Decision Phase, the par(cipant as a proposer decided to offer More or Less to their counterpart. As a recipient, whether to Accept or Reject the offer. This figure was adapted from previous work with permission</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Review &amp; EdiKng, Supervision, Project AdministraKon, Funding acquisiKon.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</head><p>This work was supported in part by grants from the NaKonal InsKtute of Mental Health (R15-MH122927 to DSF), the Eunice Kennedy Shriver NaKonal InsKtute of Child Health and Human Development (R21-HD093912 to JMJ), the NaKonal InsKtute on Aging (RF1-AG067011 to DVS), and the NaKonal InsKtute on Drug Abuse (R03-DA046733 to DVS), and a fellowship from the Temple Public Policy Lab (to JMJ). We thank Caleb Haynes, Jeffrey Dennison, Athena Vafiadis, and Makayla Collins for assistance with data collecKon.</p><p>We note that code relaKng to the generaKon of the behavioral source data, curaKon of the BIDS dataset, and the presentaKon of the sKmuli are available on GitHub (hmps://github.com/DVS-Lab/ISTART-DataInBrief).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ETHICS STATEMENT</head><p>All parKcipants provided wrimen informed consent to engage in the study and share their de-idenKfied data publicly. The study was approved by the InsKtuKonal Review Board at Temple University (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA) under Protocol Number 24452, and it was conducted in accordance with the DeclaraKon of Helsinki. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CRediT AUTHOR STATEMENT</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DECLARATION OF COMPETING INTERESTS</head><p>The authors declare that they have no known compeKng financial interests or personal relaKonships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bipolar spectrum-substance use co-occurrence: Behavioral approach system (BAS) sensi?vity and impulsiveness as shared personality vulnerabili?es</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Alloy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Pers Soc Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="549" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward processing and mood-related symptoms: An RDoC and transla?onal neuroscience perspec?ve</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nusslock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Alloy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Affect Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">216</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social Rewards and Social Networks in the Human Brain. NeuroscienKst</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fareri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Delgado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="402" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time to connect: bringing social context into addic?on neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Heilig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="592" to="601" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Role of Social Reward and Cor?costriatal Connec?vity in Substance Use</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sazhin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Psychiatr Brain Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Wyngaarden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>2023: p. 2023.01.17.524305</idno>
		<title level="m">Reward sensi?vity and cor?costriatal func?on during social rewards. bioRxiv</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social Context and Reward Sensi?vity Enhance Cor?costriatal Func?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Zaff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>on during Experiences of Shared Rewards. bioRxiv, 2023: p. 2023.10.19.562908</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sazhin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Trait Reward Sensi?vity Modulates Connec?vity with the Temporoparietal Junc?on and Anterior Insula during Strategic Decision Making. bioRxiv</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2023" to="2033" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An fMRI dataset of social and nonsocial reward processing in young adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18112/openneuro.ds004920.v1.1.0</idno>
		<ptr target="hmps://doi.org/10.18112/openneuro.ds004920.v1.1.0" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The brain imaging data structure, a format for organizing and describing outputs of neuroimaging experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gorgolewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ScienKfic Data</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">160044</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HeuDiConv -flexible DICOM conversion into structured directory layouts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Halchenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Open Source SoPware</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>under revision</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dictator games: A meta study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="583" to="610" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">More than thirty years of ul?matum bargaining experiments: Mo?ves, varia?ons, and a survey of the recent literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Güth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kocher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; OrganizaKon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="409" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social network modula?on of reward-related signals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fareri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9045" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tracking the hemodynamic responses to reward and punishment in the striatum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Delgado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurophysiol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3072" to="3079" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Barch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Func?on in the human connectome: task-fMRI and individual differences in behavior. Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="89" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of the electrocor?cal response to monetary and social reward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Distefano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc Cogn Affect Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="247" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Knutson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">FMRI visualiza?on of brain ac?vity during a monetary incen?ve delay task</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scanning the horizon: towards transparent and reproducible neuroimaging research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Poldrack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reproducible brain-wide associa?on studies require thousands of individuals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Marek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">603</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7902</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="654" to="660" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
