<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malte</forename><surname>Lüken</surname></persName>
							<email>malte_lueken@arcor.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Netherlands eScience Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julia</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Haaf</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Potsdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Potsdam</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dora</forename><surname>Matzke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Lüken https://orcid.org</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>0000-0001-7095-203X Andrew Heathcote</addrLine>
									<country key="MT">Malte</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Netherlands eScience Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Science Park 402</addrLine>
									<postCode>1098 XH</postCode>
									<settlement>Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-024-02621-1</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:13+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A variety of different evidence-accumulation models (EAMs) account for common response time and accuracy patterns in two-alternative forced choice tasks by assuming that subjects collect and sum information from their environment until a response threshold is reached. Estimates of model parameters mapped to components of this decision process can be used to explain the causes of observed behavior. However, such explanations are only meaningful when parameters can be identified, that is, when their values can be uniquely estimated from data generated by the model. Prior studies suggest that parameter identifiability is poor when error rates are low but have not systematically compared this issue across different EAMs. We conducted a simulation study investigating the identifiability and estimation properties of model parameters at low error rates in the two most popular EAMs: The Diffusion Decision Model (DDM) and the Linear Ballistic Accumulator (LBA). We found poor identifiability at low error rates for both models but less so for the DDM, for a larger number of trials, and designs with a manipulation of response caution. Based on our results, we recommend tasks with error rates between 15% and 35% for small, and between 5% and 35% for large trial numbers. We explain the identifiability problem in terms of trade-offs caused by correlations between decision-threshold and accumulation-rate parameters and discuss why the models differ in terms of their estimation properties.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>leading to the conclusion that accumulation rates can be identified even when error rates are low, as long as enough errors occur in other conditions and other parameters are fixed across these conditions. Ratcliff, however, did not give recommendations on how many errors are necessary to identify parameters in a single condition. For the <ref type="bibr">LBA, Heathcote et al. (2019)</ref> used simulations to show better estimation performance when the data included 25% compared to 2.5% errors but again did not make any specific recommendations.</p><p>Although demonstrating the importance of errors, previous studies do not provide a clear picture of how error rates influence parameter identifiability in the DDM and LBA.</p><p>This study aims to fill this gap by systematically manipulating the prevalence of errors in simulated data and analyzing how correlations between parameter estimates affect parameter identifiability at different levels of error rates. Our analysis may provide caveats for the interpretation of past studies that had applied the DDM and LBA to datasets with extremely low error rates (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hartmann et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Mattes et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">O'Callaghan et al., 2017)</ref>, potentially questioning the reliability and validity of the reported parameter estimates and the inferences based on them. where the accuracy condition had 2.5% less and the speed condition 2.5% more errors than the target error rate. In Studies 1 and 2, we explored situations with 150 and 1200 trials per dataset; in Study 3, we used 200 and 1200 trials per dataset (the difference is due to the number of design cells over which trials were equally distributed). In the Supplementary Materials, we also report results for 450 and 750 trials for Studies 1 and 2, and 500 and 800 trials for Study 3. For each model, error rate, and trial number, 100 datasets were generated.</p><p>For the DDM, the diffusion coefficient was set to s = 1, as is conventional, and non-decision time variability was fixed to s t 0 = 0 as this parameter has no impact on error rates. For the LBA, we expressed decision thresholds as B = b − A and followed the s v false = 1 convention for scaling.</p><p>All other data-generating parameter values were sampled from empirically observed distributions of parameter estimates. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kuhne (2024)</ref> used a bottom-up model selection approach (as described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Donkin et al., 2011)</ref> to obtain separate maximum likelihood estimates for each participant <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Myung, 2003)</ref> for the DDM and LBA from 17 published experiments reporting RT and accuracy data in perceptual decision making, random dot motion, lexical decision, and various cognitive-conflict tasks. Their procedure started by fitting the most simple model (in terms of the number of parameters) to the data and then used the resulting parameter estimates as starting values to fit more complex models.</p><p>Then, the best fitting model was chosen using the AIC <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Akaike, 1974)</ref> and BIC <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Schwarz, 1978</ref>). If the AIC and BIC selected different models, the AIC-selected model was chosen.</p><p>In total, Kuhne estimated 580 parameter sets for the DDM and 765 for the LBA. The empirical distributions of parameter estimates were then transformed into a normal shape and fit with truncated multivariate normal distributions. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows the correlation matrices of the truncated multivariate normal distributions for the DDM and LBA, respectively. These are between-subject correlations reflecting individual differences among estimated parameters within each model. We used these truncated multivariate normal ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 11 distributions to sample the data-generating values for our simulations while taking the empirically observed between-subject correlation structure of the parameters into account.</p><p>As the error rate is determined by the data-generating parameters, we repeatedly generated datasets with different parameter samples until the following criteria were met:</p><p>1. For Study 1, the empirical error rate was within a margin of 1% around the target error rate (e.g., in the 5%-error scenario, datasets included between 4% and 6% errors). For Studies 2 and 3, the summed difference between empirical and target across conditions was within a margin of 2%.</p><p>2. To produce datasets with slower error than correct responses, the constraints s v &gt; s z <ref type="bibr">(DDM)</ref> and s vtrue &gt; s v false (LBA) had to hold.</p><p>3. The RT distributions (in seconds) fulfilled the following criteria (adapted from Evans, 2020): 0.4 ≤ Mean(RT) ≤ 2.5; 0.4 ≤ Median(RT) ≤ 2.5; 0.1 ≤ IQR(RT) ≤ 2 2 ;</p><p>1.5 ≤ Maximum(RT); 0.5 ≥ Minimum(RT).</p><p>These inclusion criteria ensured that the generated RT distributions were approximately in line with those observed in typical empirical studies. Datasets that failed to meet all three criteria were discarded, and replaced with a new one, with the maximum number of replacements set to 100, 000, after which no new dataset was returned.</p><p>For the 50%-error scenario in Study 1, no datasets generated by the DDM met all three criteria, most likely because parameters leading to such a high error rate could not be sampled from the empirical distribution. Specifically, it was impossible to sample drift rates sufficiently close to zero to obtain chance performance. In many applications, participants with near-chance performance are excluded because they are assumed to disregard the task instructions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Evans et al., 2017)</ref>. However, as it is theoretically interesting to explore the 50%-error scenario, so instead of sampling drift rates from the empirical distribution, we used a uniform distribution bounded by 0.005 and 0.05 to obtain sufficiently small drift rates to generate the targeted error rate of 50%.</p><p>In Studies 2 and 3, we modified the data generation procedure: We computed the 25 th and 75 th quantiles of the data-generating drift rates for the different error rates from Study 1 and matched them to the target error rates in Studies 2 and 3 (e.g., quantiles for drift rates in the 5% error condition in Study 1 would be matched to the 5% error conditions in Studies 2 and 3). New drift rates were sampled from a uniform distribution bounded by the two quantiles for the conditions in Studies 2 and 3. The other parameters were generated using the truncated multivariate normal distribution conditional on the new drift rates. In Study 3, parameters were first sampled for the accuracy condition (these were conditional only on the new drift rates). For the speed condition, we sampled a second decision threshold parameter conditional on the other newly generated model parameters (these were conditional on all parameters besides the threshold in the accuracy condition, including the new drift rates). This modification ensured ordinal consistency between the data-generating parameter values across conditions (e.g., lower drift rates in the difficult vs. easy condition).</p><p>Some of the DDM datasets, even though they met our inclusion criteria, were generated from parameters that were larger than typically observed in empirical studies.</p><p>To ensure that the data-generating values align well with the literature at large, we removed datasets generated with a &gt; 3 or v &gt; 5 (Study 1: 35.8%; Study 2: 26.7%; Study 3:</p><p>35.9%). These thresholds were based on visual inspection of empirically observed parameter distributions reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Tran et al. (2021)</ref>. Removing these datasets did not change the conclusions of our simulations. In the Supplementary Materials, we show results that include all datasets.</p><p>For data generation, we used the Dynamic Model of Choice software (DMC; version:</p><p>210114; <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Heathcote et al., 2019)</ref> which relies on the R packages rtdists <ref type="bibr">(version: 0.11-2;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Singmann et al., 2020)</ref>, which in turn uses parts of the fast-dm software <ref type="bibr">(Voss &amp; Voss, ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 13 2007)</ref>. The simulations and analyses were run using R (version: 3.6.3; R Core Team, 2020).  </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">a v s v z s z A t 0 B s vtrue v</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Parameter Estimation</head><p>Response boundaries in the DDM and accumulators in the LBA were mapped to correct vs. incorrect responses. In Study 2, separate DDM v and LBA v true and v false parameters were estimated for the three difficulty conditions; in Study 3, separate DDM a and LBA B parameters were estimated for the speed-vs-accuracy conditions.</p><p>For each dataset, the joint posterior distributions of the model parameters were estimated with Bayesian Differential-Evolution Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC)</p><p>sampling <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Turner et al., 2013)</ref>, as implemented in DMC. Specifically, parameters were estimated using the RUN.dmc function which repeatedly removes and adds samples to the MCMC chains until they converge to their stationary distribution (for details, see ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 14 <ref type="bibr">Heathcote et al., 2019, p. 969)</ref>. We ran 3k MCMC chains, where k is the number of free parameters in the model. Each chain was initialized with 120 samples and samples were added and removed in steps of 40 until (a) multivariateR andR for all parameters were below 1.1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Brooks &amp; Gelman, 1998)</ref>; and (b) effective sample size (computed using the effectiveSize function from the coda R package; <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Plummer et al., 2006)</ref> for every parameter was at least 1, 000. These criteria ensured that the MCMC chains were well-mixed and enough samples were available to robustly estimate summary statistics of the posterior distributions. We visually inspected random samples of chains to confirm convergence.</p><p>For the DDM, prior distributions were based on <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Tran et al. (2021)</ref>, who provided an overview of DDM parameter estimates based on a systematic literature review. For the LBA, priors were adapted from Evans (2020). As both sets of prior distributions were relatively informative (i.e., had a narrow spread), we increased their variances to reduce their influence on the posterior distributions (see Supplementary Materials for details).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assessing Parameter-Recovery Performance</head><p>We used the median of the marginal posterior distributions as point estimates for the parameters. We compared these point estimates to the true data-generating values using scatterplots, Pearson correlations, and the root mean squared deviation</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">RM SD = 1 n (x true − x est ) 2</formula><p>. RMSD can be compared across the various error-rate scenarios but not across parameters or models due to scale differences, whereas Pearson correlations can be compared across both. To assess the uncertainty of the results, we also calculated the 95% interval (i.e., 2.5 th and 97.5 th quantiles) of the absolute deviations between the true and estimated parameter values abs(x true − x est ). To investigate parameter trade-offs, we computed pairwise Pearson correlations between MCMC samples comprising the marginal posterior distributions. To account for conditional dependencies, we also calculated partial pairwise correlations between the marginals. Importantly, the correlations encapsulated in the posterior distributions reflect the mathematical structure of the model and are defined within participants, whereas the correlations between data-generating parameter values <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 1) reflect individual differences and are defined</ref> between participants. The two types of correlations therefore cannot be compared.</p><p>For Study 1, we focus on the core DDM and LBA parameters, and present results for the DDM s v and s z parameters and the LBA A parameter in the Supplementary Materials. For Studies 2 and 3, results related to DDM z and DDM and LBA t 0 are also relegated to the Supplementary Materials. <ref type="figure">Figure 2A</ref> and B show scatterplots of true vs. estimated DDM parameters across 100 synthetic datasets for different error rates. For 150 trials per dataset <ref type="figure">(Figure 2A</ref>), estimates of a and v increasingly overestimate the true values as error rates decrease. The overestimation is still present for 1200 trials ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2B</ref>) with 0% and 1% errors, but it is substantially smaller than for 150 trials. The overestimation is reflected in weaker correlations between true and estimated parameters as error rates decrease <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table 2)</ref>. These results are supported by <ref type="figure">Figure 2C</ref> and D, where RMSDs of a and v are generally higher for lower error rates. For t 0 and z, estimates align well with true parameter values even at low error rates, with RMSDs being relatively stable across the different error scenarios. <ref type="figure">Figure 3A</ref> and B show scatterplots of true vs. estimated LBA parameters across error rates. Estimates of B, s vtrue , v false , and v true are biased upwards for decreasing error rates for 150 trials. The bias largely disappears above 5% errors for 1200 trials. The bias is also evident in correlations between true and estimated parameters in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>, where correlations are weaker for lower error rates. Notably, correlations between true and estimated LBA parameters are lower overall than for the DDM, both with 150 and 1200 trials. <ref type="figure">Figure 3C</ref> and D show that RMSDs increase with decreasing error rates, except for</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Parameter-Recovery Performance</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1: Stimulus Manipulation</head><formula xml:id="formula_2">t 0 .</formula><p>ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 16 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 4A</ref> shows RMSDs for the DDM with a simulated difficulty (Study 2) and speed-vs-accuracy manipulation (Study 3) for different error rates and trial numbers. As in Study 1, RMSDs of a and v are higher for decreasing error rates and for 150 (Study 2) and 200 (Study 3) compared to 1200 trials. RMSDs are also higher for drift rates estimated for conditions with lower difficulty (as these have a lower error rate) and similar to RMSDs for drift rates in Study 1 with a comparable error rate of 5%. RMSDs for decision thresholds are similar in accuracy and speed conditions. Interestingly, RMSDs for decision thresholds and drift rates are overall lower for the speed-vs-accuracy manipulation than for the difficulty manipulation. They are also lower than RMSDs for decision thresholds in Study 1 with a comparable error rate of 5%. This is true even for a acc in the accuracy condition which was estimated with a lower error rate and smaller trial number than a in the difficulty manipulation. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 4B</ref> shows RMSDs for the LBA with a simulated difficulty and speed-vs-accuracy manipulation. Again, RMSDs are generally higher for decreasing error rates and for 150 compared to 1200 trials, as well as for parameters in conditions with lower error rates (e.g., v</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Studies 2 and 3: Difficulty and Speed-vs-Accuracy Manipulation</head><p>(easy) true or B acc ). In contrast to the DDM, only s vtrue appears to have lower RMSDs for the speed-vs-accuracy manipulation with 200 trials and 25% and 45%</p><p>errors. Other parameters show no systematic differences between the manipulations. In the Supplementary Materials, we also show parameter estimates from Studies 2 and 3. <ref type="figure">Figure 5A</ref> shows distributions of pairwise Pearson correlations between DDM parameters across the 100 synthetic datasets, each with 150 trials, for different error rates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pairwise Within-Subject Correlations</head><p>Correlations for 1200 trials, which closely mirror the results in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>, are reported in the Supplementary Materials. Correlations between a − v are very close to 1 except for the 50% scenario and decrease with increasing error rates. The near-perfect correlation between a − v at low error rates indicates a trade-off, where simultaneously increasing a ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 17 and v leads to (almost) identical predictions.</p><p>Trade-offs between other DDM parameters can be more easily observed when accounting for conditional dependencies, as shown with the partial correlations in <ref type="figure">Figure   5B</ref>. Between a − t 0 , partial correlations tend to become more negative with decreasing error rates, suggesting a trade-off where decreasing a and increasing t 0 leads to (almost) identical predictions. Partial correlations between a − v and also v − t 0 decrease from close to 1 in the 0% scenario to 0 in the 50% scenario, supporting our earlier conclusion based on</p><p>Pearson correlations and again suggesting trade-offs between these parameters. <ref type="figure">Figure 5C</ref> shows correlations between LBA parameters for different error rates.</p><p>Correlations are typically more extreme (i.e., closer to 1 or -1) than in the DDM. We observe correlations close to 1 with decreasing error rate between</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">B − s vtrue , B − v false , B − v true , v false − s vtrue , and v true − s vtrue . Correlations between v true − v false are close to 1</formula><p>regardless of error rate. Interestingly, correlations between B − t 0 seem to approach −1 as error rates increase. These results indicate strong and frequent parameter trade-offs, especially in the presence of near-chance or near-perfect performance.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 5D</ref>, pairwise partial correlations in the LBA follow a qualitatively different pattern than Pearson correlations. Correlations generally become less extreme when we account for conditional dependencies, and some even switch signs (e.g., B − s vtrue ).  <ref type="figure">Figure 2A</ref>-D and 3A-D as well as <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>, ratios are substantially better recovered than individual parameters at low error rates, except for the LBA with 150 trials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2</head><p>Parameter Recovery for the Diffusion Decision Model True parameter True parameter Errors (%)        between true values and posterior medians for 150 and 1200 trials, respectively, for different error rates. Error bars indicate the 2.5 th and 97.5 th quantiles of the absolute deviations. Note that the</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q qq q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q a t 0 v z v</formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">Estimate A q q q q q q q q q qq q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q qq q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q a t 0 v z v<label>a</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_6">Estimate B q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q a t 0 v z v<label>a</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">RMSD C q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q a t 0 v z v<label>a</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q</formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q</formula><formula xml:id="formula_10">q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q qqq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q</formula><formula xml:id="formula_11">q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q</formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q B sv true t 0 v false v true v</formula><formula xml:id="formula_13">q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q qq q q q q q q q q q qq q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qqq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q qq q q qq q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q</formula><p>x-axis in C and D is not linear and has a discrete scale. 97.5 th quantiles of the absolute deviations. Study 2 has separate drift rates for difficulty conditions (easy, medium, hard) and study 3 separate decision thresholds for speed (sp) and accuracy (acc) conditions. Studies 1 and 2 have datasets with 150 trials and Study 3 has datasets with 200 trials.</p><p>Note that the x-axis is not linear and has a discrete scale.    </p><formula xml:id="formula_14">a − t 0 a − v a − z v − t 0 v − z z − t 0 Correlation A q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q −0.5 0.0 0.5 a − t 0 a − v a − z v − t 0 v − z z − t 0</formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">1.0 B − sv true B − t 0 B − v false B − v true t 0 − sv true t 0 − v false t 0 − v true v false − sv true v true − sv true v true − v false Correlation C q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qqq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q qq q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q q −1.0 −0.5 0.0 0.5 1.0 B − sv true B − t 0 B − v false B − v true t 0 − sv true t 0 − v false t 0 − v true v false − sv true v true − sv true v true − v</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In three simulation studies, we investigated how error rates influence the identifiability of parameters in two prominent evidence-accumulation models, the Diffusion Decision Model (DDM) and the Linear Ballistic Accumulator (LBA). We also examined relationships between parameter estimates within each model, searching for parameter trade-offs that might contribute to estimation difficulties at low error rates.</p><p>We observed increasing bias as error rates decreased for v and a in the DDM and v true and B in the LBA. The biases were stronger for small than large trial numbers (150 vs. 1200). In Studies 2 and 3, we showed that adding a speed-vs-accuracy manipulation with selective influence on the parameters reduced the bias at low error rates for the DDM but not for the LBA. The difficulty manipulation did not reduce the bias in either model.</p><p>Overall, the bias at low error rates was less pronounced for the DDM than the LBA, We investigated parameter trade-offs further by looking at estimates of ratios of parameter pairs. For DDM v and a, parameter ratios were recovered substantially better for small trial numbers and excellently for large trial numbers across all error rates. For LBA v true and B, this was only evident for large trial numbers. For small trial numbers, v true /B was less well recovered than the individual parameters. For 150 trials and low error rates, the data might not provide enough information to estimate LBA parameters or their ratios with sufficient accuracy, irrespective of correlations between parameter posteriors.</p><p>Moreover, we found strong negative dependencies between DDM a and t 0 as well as LBA B and t 0 . However, the dependencies did not compromise parameter recovery across error ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 25 rates since t 0 only affects the leading edge of RT distributions and not accuracy.</p><p>As detailed in the Supplementary Materials, for simpler models with no between-trial parameter variability (e.g., DDM s v = s z = 0 and LBA A = 0), identifiability was generally better. In parameter regions producing faster error than correct responses, identifiability was comparable to or slightly worse than in slow-error regions. In Study 2, drift rates decreased with increasing difficulty, which is consistent with Ratcliff (2014), but were biased at low error rates (see also <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 4</ref>). Thus, our results show that ordinally consistent yet poorly identified estimates can be obtained at low error rates when drift rates are estimated separately for difficulty levels. In Study 3, separate decision threshold parameters for response caution levels were well identified at low error rates when drift rate estimates were shared across levels.</p><p>To strengthen our conclusion that parameter identifiability was compromised by within-subject parameter trade-offs and were not the result of between-subject correlations between the parameters in each model, we also looked at correlations between data-generating parameters in datasets that satisfied our inclusion criteria. As shown in the Supplementary Materials, these correlations are low and do not systematically vary with the error rate for most parameters. Exceptions are v true and v false in the LBA.</p><p>However, the correlations between these two parameters are low at low error rates and the opposite of what would be required to explain our results.</p><p>Lastly, we conducted a post-hoc analysis of how well group differences could be identified at low error rates (see Supplementary Materials). For Studies 2 and 3, we created a between-group manipulation by treating datasets with slow and fast errors as independent experimental groups. For each group, we calculated the mean of the posterior medians for each parameter of each model. Then, we compared the group difference between estimated means to the difference between true means. For both studies, the analysis showed a bias where the mean group difference in drift rates was largely overestimated at low error rates. Despite being a crude approach to recovering group ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 26 differences, it indicates that low error rates can interact with experimental manipulations biasing estimates of group differences in parameters.</p><p>Why are the DDM parameters poorly identified at extremely low error rates? To produce low error rates, the drift rate must be high relative to the distance from the starting point of evidence accumulation to the response threshold, so that the lower, incorrect, boundary is (almost) never hit. Similarly, in the LBA, the matching accumulator tends to (almost) always win if v true is high relative to B. In both cases, the parameter pairs can trade off to produce almost identical model predictions because their ratio influences the predictions instead of their individual values. The trade-offs lead to high correlations between the parameter estimates and poor parameter identifiability.</p><p>Why is the LBA more prone to these effects than the DDM? This is likely because the DDM assumes a simpler one-dimensional process driven by only the difference between the evidence for each response, whereas the LBA (and other racing accumulator models)</p><p>are also sensitive to the magnitudes of each type of evidence (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Miletić et al., 2021)</ref>.</p><p>When error rates are low, there is little information available to differentiate difference and magnitude effects, and so identifiability suffers.</p><p>Our results are in line with those of <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Ratcliff and Tuerlinckx (2002)</ref> who also observed a larger variation of estimates around true parameters for higher values of the DDM a and v, which produce lower error rates. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Lerche et al. (2017)</ref> found that more trials are required to reliably estimate a and v when fewer than 4% of the responses reached the upper or lower decision boundary, respectively. For the LBA, we confirm findings by <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Heathcote et al. (2019)</ref> that lower error rates impair the recovery of LBA parameters and provide a more comprehensive picture of the relationship between error rates and parameter identifiability. Our results can also explain the seemingly diverging results of Evans (2020), <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Heathcote et al. (2019)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Palestro et al. (2018)</ref>. Evans reported poor identifiability for high values of LBA v true and B and suspected a trade-off between these parameters, leading to the recommendation to use a constrained version of the LBA ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 27</p><p>where v true /B is estimated. However, high v true and B parameters produce data with low error rates, which we showed causes poor identifiability. In contrast, Palestro et al. generated data with ∼ 30% errors and reported good recovery, similar to Heathcote et al.</p><p>with 25% errors. Thus, instead of Evan's conclusion that the standard LBA is an inherently flawed model that should generally not be used, our results indicate that it has an identifiability issue at low error rates, as does the DDM but is applicable in situations where error rates are higher.</p><p>Based on our findings, we recommend future studies using the DDM and LBA to aim for choice tasks resulting in error rates between 15% and 35%. For small trial numbers (e.g., 150), error rates below 15% could compromise parameter identifiability for both models. For very small trial numbers (&lt; 150), although not explicitly investigated here, we expect identifiability at low error rates to be even worse. For large trial numbers, we recommend error rates of at least 5%, although for the DDM 2% may still be sufficient.</p><p>Generally, higher error rates are more important for the LBA than for the DDM. We do not advise going much beyond 35% error rates as near-chance-level performance compromises the interpretability of the parameters. If accuracy in a task is low, our results suggest that manipulating response caution improves the identifiability of the DDM parameters more than manipulating task difficulty. We note that avoiding accuracy ceiling effects is also important for traditional analyses of choice data; ceiling effects reduce the variability in the data, which in turn can bias correlations and decrease power.</p><p>Our parameter-recovery study relied exclusively on Differential-Evolution Markov chain Monte Carlo (DE-MCMC) sampling for parameter estimation. Other estimation methods, for instance, those based on quantiles <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Heathcote, 2004)</ref>, may recover parameters differently across error rates. However, because DE-MCMC showed robust estimation of highly correlated parameters <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Turner et al., 2013)</ref>, it likely performs better than methods that are not equipped to deal with sloppiness.</p><p>ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 28</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Future Directions</head><p>Future studies can build on ours in multiple ways. Our systematic methodology might be used to investigate other EAMs, such as the increasingly popular racing diffusion model <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Tillman et al., 2020)</ref>, which combines elements of the DDM and the LBA (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Castro et al., 2019</ref>, for a parameter recovery study focused on their specific design).</p><p>Similarly, it seems likely to be worthwhile to investigate the effect of errors in other models with potential identifiability issues (e.g., White et al., 2018).</p><p>Our study based estimation on single-subject data, although hierarchical estimation is common in the contemporary EAM literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Heathcote et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wiecki et al., 2013)</ref>. Future studies could examine if shrinkage effects associated with hierarchical estimation (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Boehm et al., 2018)</ref> can be used to improve parameter identifiability at low error rates.</p><p>Lastly, our results can be treated as an upper bound for identifiability under ideal conditions. It is important to assess whether our simulation results generalize to empirical data. This is challenging because the data-generating parameter values in empirical data are unknown. The comparison of empirically obtained and simulated pairwise correlations between marginal posteriors may provide a solution. If empirical correlations align with simulated correlations, identifiability patterns for empirical and simulated data will also likely align.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Declarations</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Funding</head><p>This work was supported by a Vidi grant <ref type="bibr">(VI.Vidi.191.091)</ref> and Veni grant (VI.Veni.201G.019) from the Dutch Research Council (NWO).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conflicts of Interest</head><p>The authors have no relevant financial or non-financial interests to disclose.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Graphical Illustration of the Diffusion Decision Model and the Linear Ballistic Accumulator</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The parameters from<ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kuhne (2024)</ref> were transformed to a normal shape prior to estimation of the correlation matrices. DDM = Diffusion Decision Model; LBA = Linear Ballistic Accumulator.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and B: Bivariate distributions of true values and posterior medians for the Diffusion Decision Model for different error rates (colors). Each point represents a dataset of 150 (A) or 1200 (B) trials; the dashed line represents perfect recovery. C and D: Root mean squared deviation (RMSD) between true values and posterior medians for 150 and 1200 trials, respectively, for different error rates. Error bars indicate the 2.5 th and 97.5 th quantiles of the absolute deviations. Note that the x-axis in C and D is not linear and has a discrete scale.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3 Parameter Recovery for the Linear Ballistic Accumulator</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and B: Bivariate distributions of true values and posterior medians for the Linear Ballistic Accumulator for different error rates (colors). Each point represents a dataset of 150 (A) or 1200 (B) trials; the dashed line represents perfect recovery. C and D: Root mean squared deviation (RMSD)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Parameter Recovery for the Diffusion Decision Model and the Linear Ballistic Accumulator With a Difficulty and Speed-accuracy Manipulation Root mean squared deviation (RMSD) between true values and posterior medians for the Diffusion Decision Model (A) and the Linear Ballistic Accumulator (B) for different error rates (xaxis), studies (color and point shape) and trial numbers (opacity). Error bars indicate the 2.5 th and</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 5 Pairwise Within-Subject Correlations Between Posterior Distributions for Each Model</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and C: Distribution of the Pearson correlation between the marginal posterior distributions across the 100 synthetic datasets, each with 150 trials, for the Diffusion Decision Model (DDM) and the Linear Ballistic Accumulator (LBA), respectively. B and D: Distribution of partial correlations for the DDM and the LBA, respectively. Boxplot hinges show the 25 th and 75 th quantiles; whiskers point to 1.5 times the interquartile range beyond the hinges; correlations beyond the whiskers are shown as outliers. ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 23</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>especially for small trial numbers. Pairwise Pearson and partial correlations between marginal posterior distributions revealed strong positive relationships between v and a in the DDM, and B and v true in the LBA at low error rates. These high correlations occur because, at low error rates, the models are almost exclusively constrained by RTs. Different pairs of v − a and B − v true can lead to similar RT distributions causing trade-offs and hence high parameter correlations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Correlation Matrices of the Multivariate Normal Distributions Used for Sampling the Data-generating Parameter Values DDM LBA</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The patterns for B − v true and v true − s vtrue remain largely unchanged, i.e., strong positive correlations for low error rates that decrease, and even reverse for v true − s vtrue , as error rates increase. The pattern for B − t 0 also remains similar in so far true /B because they showed similarly high Pearson and partial correlations indicating strong trade-offs independent of other model parameters. As shown in the most right panels in</figDesc><table><row><cell>ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 18</cell></row><row><cell>v</cell></row><row><cell>that correlations approach −1 as error rates increase, but as opposed to Pearson</cell></row><row><cell>correlations, the strength of partial correlations is only weakly influenced by error rates.</cell></row><row><cell>Lastly, we investigated whether there are combinations of parameters that can be</cell></row><row><cell>adequately recovered even if their constituents are poorly estimated due to strong</cell></row><row><cell>trade-offs (as has been done for the LBA by Evans, 2020, and for conflict diffusion models</cell></row><row><cell>by White et al., 2018). For the DDM, we examined the ratio of v/a and for the LBA</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Pearson Correlations Between True and Estimated ParametersNote. Correlations for DDM v are low at 50% errors due to low variance in the true parameters.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>DDM</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>LBA</cell></row><row><cell>Errors (%)</cell><cell>a</cell><cell>t 0</cell><cell>v</cell><cell>z</cell><cell>v/a</cell><cell>B</cell><cell>s vtrue</cell><cell>t 0</cell><cell cols="2">v false v true v true /B</cell></row><row><cell>150 trials</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0</cell><cell cols="5">0.47 0.83 0.29 0.96 0.93</cell><cell cols="4">0.41 0.13 0.64 0.08 0.19</cell><cell>0.34</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell cols="5">0.55 0.77 0.50 0.95 0.94</cell><cell cols="4">0.47 -0.07 0.72 0.22 0.01</cell><cell>0.58</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell cols="5">0.72 0.89 0.76 0.96 0.96</cell><cell cols="4">0.70 0.31 0.81 0.38 0.28</cell><cell>0.49</cell></row><row><cell>15</cell><cell cols="5">0.85 0.88 0.82 0.93 0.94</cell><cell cols="4">0.71 0.16 0.66 0.64 0.47</cell><cell>0.65</cell></row><row><cell>25</cell><cell cols="5">0.84 0.93 0.84 0.97 0.91</cell><cell cols="4">0.62 0.43 0.61 0.57 0.54</cell><cell>0.56</cell></row><row><cell>35</cell><cell cols="5">0.88 0.86 0.80 0.96 0.91</cell><cell cols="4">0.79 0.28 0.70 0.72 0.65</cell><cell>0.44</cell></row><row><cell>50</cell><cell cols="5">0.89 0.81 -0.09 0.95 0.33</cell><cell cols="4">0.64 0.62 0.66 0.74 0.72</cell><cell>0.62</cell></row><row><cell>1200 trials</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0</cell><cell cols="5">0.60 0.95 0.85 1.00 0.99</cell><cell cols="4">0.61 0.55 0.92 0.46 0.59</cell><cell>0.90</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell cols="5">0.81 0.96 0.81 0.99 0.99</cell><cell cols="4">0.72 0.51 0.90 0.56 0.61</cell><cell>0.88</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell cols="5">0.96 0.97 0.97 0.99 0.99</cell><cell cols="4">0.89 0.62 0.89 0.68 0.73</cell><cell>0.90</cell></row><row><cell>15</cell><cell cols="5">0.98 0.96 0.97 0.99 0.99</cell><cell cols="4">0.95 0.59 0.94 0.81 0.77</cell><cell>0.87</cell></row><row><cell>25</cell><cell cols="5">0.98 0.97 0.97 1.00 0.99</cell><cell cols="4">0.95 0.80 0.94 0.91 0.85</cell><cell>0.94</cell></row><row><cell>35</cell><cell cols="5">0.97 0.98 0.96 1.00 0.97</cell><cell cols="4">0.95 0.84 0.95 0.92 0.90</cell><cell>0.92</cell></row><row><cell>50</cell><cell cols="5">0.98 0.96 0.31 1.00 0.54</cell><cell cols="4">0.95 0.91 0.97 0.94 0.93</cell><cell>0.94</cell></row></table><note>DDM = Diffusion Decision Model; LBA = Linear Ballistic Accumulator.ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 24</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ethics Approval</head><p>Not applicable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consent to Participate</head><p>Not applicable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consent for Publication</head><p>Not applicable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Availability of Data and Materials</head><p>The datasets generated during and/or analysed during the current study are available in the Open Science Framework repository, https://osf.io/d389x/, and figshare repository, https://figshare.com/account/home#/projects/181213. None of the simulation studies were preregistered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Code Availability</head><p>The code used for the current study is available in the Open Science Framework repository, https://osf.io/d389x/.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new look at the statistical model identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Akaike</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="716" to="723" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating across-trial variability parameters of the Diffusion Decision Model: Expert advice and recommendations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Annis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-M</forename><surname>Krypotos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lerche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Palmeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Servant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Singmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Starns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Wiecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Matzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2018.09.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmp.2018.09.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">General methods for monitoring convergence of iterative simulations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Brooks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/10618600.1998.10474787</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/10618600.1998.10474787" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="455" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical mechanical approaches to models with many poorly known parameters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Sethna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1103/PhysRevE.68.021904</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.68.021904" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physical Review E</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The simplest complete model of choice response time: Linear ballistic accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2007.12.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2007.12.002" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive workload measurement and modeling under divided attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Castro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Strayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Matzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="826" to="839" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xhp0000638</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xhp0000638" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response times and decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781119170174.epcn509</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119170174.epcn509" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Stevens&apos; handbook of experimental psychology and cognitive neuroscience</title>
		<editor>E.-J. Wagenmakers</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-03" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>4th ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 31</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The overconstraint of response time models: Rethinking the scaling problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/PBR.16.6.1129</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/PBR.16.6.1129" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1129" to="1135" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Drawing conclusions from choice response time models: A tutorial using the linear ballistic accumulator</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2010.10.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmp.2010.10.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Same model, different conclusions: An identifiability issue in the linear ballistic accumulator model of decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/2xu7f</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/2xu7f" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Need for closure is associated with urgency in perceptual decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bushmakin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13421-017-0718-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-017-0718-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1193" to="1205" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evidence accumulation models: Current limitations and future directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/74df9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/74df9" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential sampling models in cognitive neuroscience: Advantages, applications, and extensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev-psych-122414-033645</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-psych-122414-033645" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="666" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Same same but different? Modeling N-1 switch cost and N-2 repetition cost with the diffusion model and the linear ballistic accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-M</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rey-Mermet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gade</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">198</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.actpsy.2019.05.010</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2019.05.010" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fitting Wald and ex-Wald distributions to response time data: An example using functions for the S-PLUS package</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03206550</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03206550" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods, Instruments, &amp; Computers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="678" to="694" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An introduction to good practices in cognitive modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>LBA 32</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND</title>
		<editor>B. U. Forstmann &amp; E.-J. Wagenmakers</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An introduction to model-based cognitive neuroscience</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4939-2236-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4939-2236-9" />
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="49" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic models of choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y.-S</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Strickland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gretton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Matzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="961" to="985" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-018-1067-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-018-1067-y" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Improving the validity, reliability, and usability of evidence accumulation models [Doctoral dissertation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kuhne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Newcastle</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Information theory of choice-reaction times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R J</forename><surname>Laming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://trove.nla.gov.au/work/10790467?q&amp;versionId=12596990" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How many trials are required for parameter estimation in diffusion modeling? A comparison of different optimization criteria</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lerche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nagler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="537" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-016-0740-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-016-0740-2" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parallel and serial task processing in the PRP paradigm: A drift-diffusion model approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mattes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tavera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ophey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Roheger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gaschler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Haider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s00426-020-01337-w</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-020-01337-w" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Facilitation in recognizing pairs of words: Evidence of a dependence between retrieval operations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Schvaneveldt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0031564</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0031564" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="234" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A new model of decision processing in instrumental learning tasks. eLife, 10, e63055</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Miletić</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Boag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Trutti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/elife.63055</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.63055" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thou shalt identify! The identifiability of two high-threshold models in confidence-rating recognition (and super-recognition) paradigms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2016.03.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmp.2016.03.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tutorial on maximum likelihood estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Myung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 33</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual hallucinations are characterized by impaired sensory evidence accumulation: Insights from hierarchical drift diffusion modeling in Parkinson&apos;s Disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>O'callaghan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tomassini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Walpola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Moustafa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.bpsc.2017.04.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpsc.2017.04.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry: Cognitive Neuroscience and Neuroimaging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="680" to="688" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Palestro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sederberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Osth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Van Zandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-72425-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-72425-6" />
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CODA: Convergence diagnosis and output analysis for</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Plummer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Best</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Cowles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Vines</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MCMC. R News</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.r-project.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring psychometric functions with the diffusion model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0034954</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0034954" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="870" to="888" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diffusion decision model: Theory and data for two-choice decision tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="873" to="922" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/neco.2008.12-06-420</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/neco.2008.12-06-420" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling response times for two-choice decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rouder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1467-9280.00067</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-9280.00067" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion decision model: Current issues and history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2016.01.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2016.01.007" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Estimating parameters of the diffusion model: Approaches to dealing with contaminant reaction times and parameter variability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tuerlinckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 34</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="481" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03196302</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03196302" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating the dimension of a model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="464" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Singmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gretton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/rtdists/rtdists/" />
		<title level="m">Response time distributions</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relative merit of empirical priors in non-identifiable and sloppy models: Applications to models of learning and decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Spektor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2047" to="2068" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-018-1446-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-018-1446-5" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models for choice-reaction time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF02289729</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02289729" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="260" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential sampling models without random between-trial variability: The racing diffusion model of speeded decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Van Zandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="911" to="936" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-020-01719-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-020-01719-6" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Systematic parameter reviews in cognitive modeling: Towards a robust and cumulative characterization of psychological processes in the diffusion decision model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N.-H</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Van Maanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Matzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.608287</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.608287" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approaches to analysis in model-based cognitive neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Love</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Palmeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Van Maanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2016.01.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmp.2016.01.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A method for efficiently sampling from distributions with correlated dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sederberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0032222</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0032222" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="368" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ERROR RATES AND PARAMETER IDENTIFIABILITY IN THE DDM AND LBA 35</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The interpretation of behavior-model correlations in unidentified cognitive models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Van Maanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Miletić</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-020-01783-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-020-01783-y" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L J</forename><surname>Van Der Maas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Molenaar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Maris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kievit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Borsboom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive psychology meets psychometric theory: On the relation between process models for decision making and latent variable models for individual differences</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0022749</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0022749" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="356" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parameter recovery, bias and standard errors in the linear ballistic accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Visser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Poessé</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Mathematical and Statistical</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
