<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Baccarat gamblers follow trends rather than adhere to the gambler&apos;s fallacy: Analyses of field data from a casino</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2025-01-03">January 3, 2025</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroyuki</forename><surname>Muto</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for the Future of Human Society</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Sustainable System Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Osaka Metropolitan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Sakai</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryusuke</forename><surname>Nakai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for the Future of Human Society</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshiya</forename><surname>Murai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Medicine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sakiko</forename><surname>Yoshikawa</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Art and Design</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University of the Arts</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nobuhito</forename><surname>Abe</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for the Future of Human Society</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Sustainable System Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Osaka Metropolitan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1-1 Gakuen-cho, Naka-ku</addrLine>
									<postCode>599-8531</postCode>
									<settlement>Sakai</settlement>
									<region>Osaka</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Baccarat gamblers follow trends rather than adhere to the gambler&apos;s fallacy: Analyses of field data from a casino</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2025-01-03">January 3, 2025</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:13+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This study investigated the cognitive biases underlying baccarat gambling behaviors through an analysis of 17,970,830 games played by 6,625 customers in a casino. Baccarat, a popular high-stakes game in East Asia, involves predicting the outcome of two hands, where the results are inherently unpredictable, similar to the structure of games such as roulette. In contrast to existing theories predicting the emergence of the gambler&apos;s fallacy-or negative recency-when the outcome generation mechanism is clearly random, most baccarat gamblers exhibit the opposite bias, demonstrating a tendency toward positive recency. Specifically, customers increasingly placed bets on future outcomes to match past consecutive outcomes as streaks grew longer. This trend-following behavior diminished when streaks were interrupted, ruling out explanations based on the &quot;hot outcome&quot; fallacy, which is typically associated with adaptive behaviors such as resource foraging. Moreover, betting amounts increased slightly but reliably when gamblers followed trends. These findings provide new insights into cognitive biases in gambling, challenge established theories of positive and negative recency, and underscore the importance of considering the unique structural characteristics of specific games when studying gambling behavior. This perspective may also contribute to a deeper understanding of pathological and problem gambling. Keywords baccarat; casino; gambling; cognitive biases; decision-making; field study Highlights • Baccarat gamblers follow trends, not the gambler&apos;s fallacy or negative recency. • Field data analysis showed that baccarat players predict outcomes based on trends. • Betting amounts slightly increase when baccarat gamblers follow trends. • Positive recency in baccarat challenges existing theories of the gambler&apos;s fallacy. • The findings contribute to the understanding of pathological and problem gambling.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>When a fair coin is tossed five times and results in consecutive heads, people tend to believe that the outcome of the next toss will be tails, even though the probability of the next outcome is entirely unrelated to the previous outcomes and remains at 50%; this is an example of the so-called "gambler's fallacy," which is the erroneous belief that a different outcome is more likely to occur than previous trials immediately following a sequence of consecutive identical outcomes <ref type="bibr">(Laplace, 1825</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Laplace, /2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1971</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">, 1974</ref>. In particular, previous studies have suggested that people are more prone to fall into the gambler's fallacy when the sequence generation mechanism is specified to be random (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Ayton &amp; Fischer, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Burns &amp; Corpus, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Caruso et al., 2010</ref>; for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Oskarsson et al., 2009)</ref>. However, gamblers playing baccarat, one of the most popular casino games, are suggested to exhibit a fallacy that is entirely opposite to the gambler's fallacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Huang, 2016)</ref>, despite the evident randomness of the generation mechanism. Here, we provide the first quantitative evidence for baccarat gamblers' tendency to bet with the trend rather than against it, using large-sized field data from a land-based casino.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">General features and rules of baccarat</head><p>Baccarat is the most popular game among high-stakes casino enthusiasts, particularly in East Asia, where it significantly contributes to total casino revenue in gambling enclaves such as the Macao Special Administrative Region (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Huang, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Loi &amp; Kim, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Philander et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Additionally, baccarat is the favored game for the majority of problem gamblers seeking help in Macao (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Huang, 2016)</ref>. Despite its prevalence and pathological significance, only a few studies have focused on gambling behavior during baccarat.</p><p>Baccarat is a card game in which gamblers place bets by predicting the outcome of two hands, referred to as the "player" and the "banker." Please note that in baccarat, the terms "player" and "banker" refer to fictional figures rather than representing actual players and bankers. Gamblers may also wager on a "tie" if they anticipate a draw. Multiple bets are permitted, but simultaneous betting on both the player and the banker is prohibited. The dealer draws up three cards for both the player and the banker, following specific drawing rules, and the hand with a sum of digits closer to 9 in one place is declared the winner. For standard eight-deck baccarats, the probability of the player winning is 44.6%, the probability of the banker winning is 45.9%, and the probability of a tie is 9.5%.</p><p>Generally, winning bets on the player, banker, and tie are paid at odds of 1 to 1, 1 to 1, and 1 to 8, respectively. However, winnings on banker bets are subject to deductions according to the rules established for each table. Under the commission rule, 5% of the winnings are deducted (resulting in a net payout of 1 to 0.95). Under the no commission rule, 50% of the winnings are deducted only when the banker wins on 6 (resulting in a net payout of 1 to 1 or 1 to 0.5).</p><p>The general procedure of baccarat is outlined as follows. At the commencement of each round, the dealer shuffles eight decks of 52 playing cards, which are not reshuffled or reused until the round concludes. The player subsequently provides an indicator card to cut the cards, and the dealer inserts the cards into the shoe to initiate the first game of the round. Each game commences with the dealer taking the lead in betting. Following the "no more bets" call, the dealer draws cards from the shoe according to the drawing rules. Once payouts have been disbursed, the subsequent game ensues. The round concludes upon the emergence of the indicator card, signaling the final game.</p><p>In the context of the present study, it is crucial to emphasize that the order of cards is randomly determined at the beginning of each round. In other words, the outcomes of the game are predetermined and unchanged. Therefore, from an objective standpoint, any appearance of trends in the sequence of outcomes is entirely coincidental, and there is no rational basis for making betting decisions based on such trends, although gamblers can determine where to place their bets by consulting a scoreboard that records past outcomes within the round, similar to other games such as roulette.</p><p>Strictly speaking, the outcomes of each game in baccarat do not follow an independent and identical distribution, primarily due to the finite number of cards in each round. However, this effect is quite small and negligible. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Thorp (1985)</ref>, the card-counting strategy is only effective for the last 20 cards at most in eight-deck baccarat, whereas each round concludes before the remaining number of cards becomes less than that, as determined by the indicator card. Consequently, baccarat can essentially be considered a pure chance game with no involvement of the skill of players <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Huang, 2016)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">Gambler's fallacy and relevant beliefs</head><p>The "gambler's fallacy" was originally described by <ref type="bibr">Laplace (1825</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Laplace ( /2019</ref> and has since been empirically studied in terms of cognitive bias in decision-making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1971</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">, 1974</ref>. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Oskarsson et al. (2009)</ref>, we define the gambler's fallacy as the "expectation that a streak of events will end." The gambler's fallacy is also referred to as negative recency. This expression is useful because it is more neutral, can be taken more literally, and contrasts well with the later-mentioned "positive recency." The gambler's fallacy or negative recency has been repeatedly observed not only in classical laboratory experiments (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Anderson, 1966;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Anderson &amp; Whalen, 1960;</ref><ref type="bibr">Jarvic, 1951;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Nicks, 1959)</ref> but also in a variety of real gambling situations, including lotteries <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Clotfelter &amp; Cook, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kong et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Suetens et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Terrell, 1994)</ref>, roulette <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Croson &amp; Sundali, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Sundali &amp; Croson, 2006)</ref>, and horse or dog racing <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Metzger, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr">Terrel &amp; Farmer, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Terrell, 1998)</ref>. Typically, this bias is explained by the representativeness heuristic or the law of small numbers (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Rabin, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1971</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">, 1974</ref>.</p><p>To refer to the opposite belief of the gambler's fallacy, we use the term positive recency, which can be defined as "expectation that a streak of events will continue" <ref type="bibr">(Oskarson et al., 2009, p. 263)</ref>. A similar erroneous belief known as the hot hand fallacy is widely recognized. However, its definition varies among researchers, and positive recency is not necessarily the same as the hot hand fallacy.</p><p>The term hot hand fallacy was originally used in the context of sports, particularly basketball. In a pioneering study on basketball, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gilovich et al. (1985)</ref> referred to the hot hand belief as "a belief that the performance of a player during a particular period is significantly better than expected on the basis of the player's overall record" <ref type="bibr">(pp. 295-296)</ref>. Their analysis of shooting and free-throw records from professional basketball players revealed no positive correlation between the outcomes of successive shots (however, recent research by <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Miller and Sanjurjo (2018)</ref> suggested that the apparent absence of positive recency might be attributed to statistical artifacts). Nonetheless, a controlled laboratory experiment demonstrated that both basketball players and observers mistakenly anticipated a positive correlation between the outcomes of successive shots. Consequently, Gilovich and colleagues concluded that the hot hand belief falls under the category of fallacies.</p><p>The hot hand fallacy and positive recency differ in at least two ways. First, while the hot hand fallacy pertains to beliefs concerning a particular person, such as a sports player, positive/negative recency concerns events encompassing both players' wins/losses and game outcomes. In roulette, for example, predicting black as the outcome after it has appeared five times in a row is an instance of positive recency for game outcomes. On the other hand, predicting that a player who has won five times in a row will win again, regardless of whether they bet on red or black, exemplifies the hot hand fallacy. Crucially, the hot hand fallacy can coexist with negative recency, underscoring its distinction from positive recency, which cannot coexist with negative recency. Based on this distinction, Croson and colleagues demonstrated that roulette players exhibit the gambler's fallacy (i.e., negative recency for game outcomes) and the hot hand fallacy simultaneously <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Croson &amp; Sundali, 2005)</ref>. They also reported that these two fallacies are positively correlated at the individual level <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Sundali &amp; Croson, 2006)</ref>. In baccarat, while the presence of the hot hand fallacy was partially supported by field data showing that baccarat gamblers in a casino tend to take riskier bets after consecutive wins <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abe et al., 2021)</ref>, positive/negative recency for game outcomes (i.e., player wins, banker wins, and ties) has yet to be studied quantitatively.</p><p>Second, while positive/negative recency assumes a sequence of consecutive outcomes, the hot hand fallacy does not inherently require such consecutiveness. For example, consider a basketball player with 20% shooting accuracy. In a game, this player successfully makes four consecutive shots but misses the fifth shot. Despite the streak ending, given the notably high success rate (80%) during this period, one might perceive the player to have a hot hand, attributing the missed shot to chance and anticipating success in the next shot. This reasoning is rational in the context of probability learning, where observers should guess the true probability of a Bernoulli (or categorical) distribution.</p><p>Likewise, if animals recognize a location with a high likelihood of finding food and perceive it as a "hot outcome," staying in that area for a while would be adaptive, even if food is occasionally not found (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Blanchard et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Wilke &amp; Barrett, 2009)</ref>. In a study focusing on a lottery, Suetens et al. (2016) calculated the "hotness" indicator for each number, based on its frequency of occurrence in the past 1 to 6 weeks, and they demonstrated both the gambler's fallacy (i.e., avoidance of numbers from the previous week) and the hot outcome fallacy 1 (i.e., a preference for numbers with higher hotness). Although different researchers use the same terms differently, we define the hot outcome fallacy as the belief that outcomes frequently occurring within a recent short period are likely to recur in the next period, distinguishing it from positive recency. Given the conceptual differences between these beliefs, it is possible to observe positive recency for outcomes without the presence of the hot outcome fallacy.</p><p>In short, the focus of the present study was on how baccarat players' betting choices are influenced by the sequence of game outcomes (player wins, banker wins, and ties) rather than by the sequence of gamblers' wins/losses (c.f., the hot hand fallacy). We also distinguish between positive/negative recency for outcomes (based on consecutiveness) and the hot outcome fallacy (based on frequency in recent games), which can be tested empirically.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3.">Determinants of positive or negative recency</head><p>Previous studies have attempted to identify the factors influencing whether people exhibit positive or negative recency. According to the most prominent account (for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Oskarsson et al., 2009)</ref>, people tend to show negative recency when they perceive the sequence generation mechanism as entirely random (e.g., roulette, lottery). Conversely, they exhibit positive recency when they perceive the sequence generation mechanism as reliant on skilled human performance (e.g., sports).</p><p>This account has been supported by findings from experimental studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Ayton &amp; Fisher, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Burns &amp; Corpus, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Caruso et al., 2010)</ref>. For example, <ref type="bibr">Ayton and Fisher (2004)</ref> conducted Experiment 1 involving a simulated roulette that generated entirely random sequences. They reported that people tend to anticipate a different outcome after a streak of identical outcomes (i.e., negative recency) while displaying high confidence in their predictions following a streak of successful outcomes (i.e., positive recency). In Experiment 2, they further revealed that individuals are inclined to attribute sequences with more streaks (i.e., low rates of alteration) to human performance (e.g., a basketball player's scoring), whereas they tend to attribute sequences with fewer streaks (i.e., high rates of alteration) to chance processes (e.g., coin toss, roulette). This account predicts that baccarat gamblers exhibit negative recency for outcomes because, akin to roulette, the sequence of outcomes in baccarat games is unequivocally governed by a random process.</p><p>Nevertheless, this account falls short in fully explaining gambling behaviors observed in real-world settings. For example, despite the typical manifestation of negative recency among lottery players <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Clotfelter &amp; Cook, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Suetens et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Terrell, 1994)</ref>, likely owing to its inherently random nature, a recent study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kong et al. (2020)</ref> revealed cases where lottery players exhibit positive recency for outcomes. Kong et al. described their findings as "surprising" and experimentally confirmed that while negative recency occurs when there is only one winning number, positive recency is observed when there are two or three winning numbers. The cognitive mechanism underlying this phenomenon remains unclear, but their findings suggest that gamblers' expectations for future outcomes can shift in the opposite direction, with only a slight modification in the structure of pure chance games.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4.">Present study</head><p>The main aim of the present study was to investigate whether baccarat gamblers exhibit positive or negative recency concerning outcomes (i.e., player wins, banker wins, and ties). As already mentioned, baccarat is a pure chance game, much like roulette, where players make bets based on predictions of outcomes generated through unequivocally random processes. Therefore, if perceived randomness is a crucial factor that elicits the gambler's fallacy or negative recency <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Oskarsson et al., 2009)</ref>, baccarat gamblers should tend to wager more frequently on different hands than previous consecutive outcomes, as roulette players do <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Croson &amp; Sundali, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Sundali &amp; Croson, 2006)</ref>.</p><p>Conversely, considering the potential impact of baccarat's unique game structure on betting decisions, as evidenced by recency shifts observed in lotteries due to slight variations in game structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kong et al., 2020)</ref>, baccarat gamblers might also exhibit positive recency, unlike roulette players.</p><p>To the best of our knowledge, no study has quantitatively examined baccarat gamblers' tendencies toward positive/negative recency for outcomes by directly analyzing their betting data. In a qualitative study, Huang (2016) scrutinized baccarat guidebooks written by five experienced gamblers, identifying potential erroneous perceptions prevalent among baccarat gamblers, some of which are unique to baccarat. Huang reported that all five authors mentioned baccarat gamblers' inclination toward a "following trend" strategy, which involves betting on the same outcome after a streak of consecutive identical outcomes based on the scoreboard. This strategy can be considered a manifestation of positive recency rather than negative recency. However, since Huang's research was qualitative, the prevalence of positive recency in baccarat remains anecdotal. The present study is the first to quantitatively analyze baccarat gamblers' adherence to the following trend strategy and their underlying beliefs about future outcomes via real casino data.</p><p>We hypothesized that if baccarat gamblers hold positive or negative recency, then they would likely place larger and more frequent bets on a hand identical to or different from the previous outcome, respectively, especially after a prolonged streak of consecutive outcomes. To foreshadow our results, Analysis 1 demonstrated that the predominant strategy among baccarat gamblers follows a trend that is consistent with positive recency. Analysis 2 indicated that the finding from Analysis 1 cannot be attributed to the hot outcome fallacy by showing no systematic relationship between the likelihood of betting with the trend and the streak length once a streak was interrupted, highlighting the importance of consecutiveness over frequency. Analyses 3-5 revealed that the betting amount slightly but reliably increased with streak length when betting with the trend, whereas it slightly but reliably decreased when betting against the trend, further confirming positive recency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Data acquisition</head><p>We analyzed data gathered from baccarat tables at a land-based casino located in the capital region of Korea from 20 April 2017 to 8 August 2019. These data were provided by SEGA SAMMY HOLDINGS, Inc., an affiliated company of the casino and a funding body for this study. In our prior work, we analyzed an earlier version of the data, covering the period from 20 April 2017 to 31 January 2018, for a different purpose <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abe et al., 2021)</ref>. The casino operates 24/7 and exclusively caters to foreign nationals. To enter the casino, customers need to agree to its terms and conditions and create a customer account with ID cards. Unique player identifiers, embedded within the ID card system, allow for demographic analysis encompassing age, gender, and ethnicity. The playing data are electronically recorded via card and chip recognition systems, which track all baccarat wagers made by customers throughout the day. SEGA SAMMY HOLDINGS, Inc. provided deidentified data while retaining customers' demographic information such as gender, ethnicity, and age in five-year intervals, except for a group aged 19-25 years. Prior stringent anonymization ensures that individuals cannot be identified by the researchers. Owing to the retrospective nature of this study, no written informed consent was obtained from the customers for the specific purpose of this study. However, the casino's policy explicitly permits the analysis of deidentified playing data collected from customers for academic research. This study was approved by the Ethical Committee of Kyoto University for Advanced Study of Mind (29-P-26).</p><p>The rules for the eight-deck baccarat applied in this casino are essentially the same as those described in the introduction. In each game, customers have the option to wager on the player win, banker win, or a tie, while simultaneously betting on both the player win and the banker win is prohibited. The probability of the player winning is 44.6% (with a payout of 1 to 1), the probability of the banker winning is 45.9% (with a payout of 1 to 0.95 under the commission rule but 1 to 1 or 1 to 0.5 under the no-commission rule), and the probability of a tie is 9.5% (with a payout of 1 to 8).</p><p>The house advantage for each outcome is 1.24% for the player win, 1.06% for the banker win under the commission rule, 1.45% for the banker win under the no-commission rule, and 9.52% for the tie.</p><p>In addition to the regular bets, customers at the casino can also bet on a player pair and/or banker pair as high-risk side bets, each with a probability of 7.47% and a payout of 11 to 1, independent of the regular bets 2 . However, these side bets fall outside the scope of interest for this study. For detailed baccarat rules at the casino, please refer to the Supplementary Methods in Abe et al. (2021).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Data details and preprocessing</head><p>The original dataset included records from 37,856,793 games played by 29,295 customers.</p><p>Following Abe et al. <ref type="formula">2021</ref>, we isolated data from 13,250 customers who met the following inclusion criteria: (1) aged between 19 and 80, (2) visited the baccarat table for at least three sales days, and (3) placed more than 70 bets within at least one sales day. Additionally, we randomly selected half of these customers for the present study. This data division enables future validation via an independent dataset. Hence, the present study analyzed data from 17,970,830 games played by 6,625 customers (5,692 men and 933 women). Most customers in the dataset were Japanese (46.1%) or Chinese (38.7%). Other customer nationalities included Korea (2.7%), Mongolia (2.6%), Taiwan (1.7%), the U.S.A. (1.5%), Vietnam (1.1%), Uzbekistan (1.0%), and others (32 countries). The distribution of ages is presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>In the present study, the main variables in the playing data were customer ID 3 , game ID, bet amount 4 (KRW) per hand, game outcomes (i.e., player win, banker win, or tie), and the table at which the customer played. Additionally, we computed (1) the streak length of consecutive outcomes per table (i.e., the number of times the same outcome occurred in succession before a particular game),   <ref type="table">Table ID</ref> 1-104</p><p>(2) a binary variable indicating whether the customer placed a bet on each hand (bet amount was nonzero) or not (bet amount was zero) for Analyses 1 and 2, and (3) the natural logarithm of nonzero bet amounts for Analyses 3-5. Descriptive statistics for these variables are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>. As the dataset contained as few as 623 invalid games, likely due to dealer errors or other issues, we excluded data from games following an invalid game.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Statistical analysis</head><p>We conducted five analyses to examine how consecutive outcomes influence the betting behaviors of baccarat gamblers, specifically focusing on the proportion of bets placed on a hand and the bet amount. To account for the hierarchical structure of the data (at the game and customer levels) and the nonnormality of the dependent variables, we utilized generalized linear mixed-effect models (GLMMs) with the lmerTest R package <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kuznetsova et al., 2017)</ref>. In all analyses, we separately analyzed the effects of individual outcomes (i.e., player wins, banker wins, and ties). Before each analysis, we excluded data from customers who did not place a wager after two or more consecutive outcomes, as estimating a slope in such cases was not feasible. All the analysis scripts used in this study are available at https://doi.org/10.17605/osf.io/9c2p3.</p><p>In Analyses 1 and 2, we examined the effect of streak length on the betting proportion via a binomial distribution model with a logit link function. The dependent variables were binary variables indicating whether a customer placed a bet on the same hand as consecutive outcomes in each game.</p><p>The independent variable was streak length, which was included as a fixed effect (as described later, the definition of streak length is different between Analyses 1 and 2). We also entered a random intercept and slope for customers. We formulize this model as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">logit( ) = 0 + 1 ( − 1) + 0 + 1 ( − 1),</formula><p>where is the probability that customer i bet on a relevant hand in game j and where is the streak length. We entered − 1 instead of so that the estimate of the intercept ( 0 ) can be interpreted as the logarithm of the odds when the streak length = 1. This subtraction does not affect the estimation of the effect of the streak length ( 1 ). The random intercept ( 0 ) and slope ( 1 ) were assumed to follow a multivariate normal distribution with a mean vector of 0 and a covariance matrix of .</p><p>In Analyses 3-5, we examined the effect of streak length on betting amounts via a log-normal distribution model with the identity link function. (This model essentially represents a linear mixedeffect model with a normal error distribution for the log-transformed dependent variable.) The dependent variable was the bet amount on relevant hands, which varied across Analyses 3-5, in each game. As with the previous model, we entered the streak length as a fixed effect and both a random intercept and slope for customers. This model can be mathematically expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">ln = 0 + 1 ( − 1) + 0 + 1 ( − 1) + ,</formula><p>where is the bet amount (KRW) placed on relevant hands by customer i in game j. The error term was assumed to follow a normal distribution with a mean of 0 and a standard deviation of σ. The other parameterizations were the same as those in the previous model.</p><p>We report both marginal and conditional coefficients of determinant (Rm 2 and Rc 2 , respectively) for each model. These coefficients represent the proportion of total variance explained by the fixed effects (Rm 2 ) or by both fixed and random effects (Rc 2 ). For analysis of the proportion of bets (Analyses 1</p><p>and 2), we set the theoretical variance (π 2 /3) for the binomial error distribution (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Nakagawa et al., 2017)</ref>. For analysis of the bet amount (Analyses 3-5), we computed coefficients of determination according to the definition for log-transformed bet amounts. To compute these coefficients, we utilized the r.squaredGLMM function included in the MuMIn R package <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bartoń, 2022)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Analysis 1: Proportion of bets following the trend</head><p>The first analysis aimed to provide empirical evidence for the pervasiveness of the following trend strategy in baccarat gamblers, as suggested by qualitative research <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Huang, 2016)</ref>. For this purpose, we examined the effect of the streak length of consecutive outcomes on the proportion of bets following the trend.</p><p>The proportions of bets on a player win following a streak of player wins are shown in the upper panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1A</ref>. On average, customers placed bets on the player with a probability of 46. For ties (the lower panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1A</ref>), on average, customers bet on the tie with a probability of  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2A</ref> shows customers' point estimates of odds ratios per streak length (i.e., exponentials of β1 + γ1i). The proportions of customers whose estimates were numerically larger than one (indicating no effect) were 91.5% for player wins, 91.8% for banker wins, and 97.4% for ties.</p><p>In summary, Analysis 1 consistently demonstrated that the majority of baccarat gamblers preferred betting in accordance with trends. This finding aligns with the notion that baccarat gamblers have positive recency rather than gambler's fallacy or negative recency.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Analysis 2: Proportion of bets after a streak is interrupted</head><p>The results of Analysis 1 were consistent not only with positive recency but also with the hot outcome fallacy. To disentangle them, in Analysis 2, we focused on betting behaviors after a streak of consecutive outcomes was interrupted. To clarify the logic, suppose that the player won five times in a row and then the banker won (streak length = 5). In this case, if a gambler believes in positive recency, then the proportion of bets on the player win should not be high because the streak has been interrupted. On the other hand, if a gambler holds the hot outcome fallacy, they should bet on the player winning because the recent outcomes are still consistent with a higher probability of the player wining than the banker winning (5:1). Hence, we examined whether baccarat gamblers are more likely to bet on hot outcomes than on others even after a streak of consecutive outcomes is interrupted in the previous game.</p><p>After a streak of player wins is interrupted (the upper panel in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1B</ref> After a streak of ties is interrupted (the lower panel in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1B)</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2B</ref> shows customers' point estimates of odds ratios per streak length (i.e., exponentials of β1 + γ1i). The proportions of customers whose estimates were numerically larger than one (indicating no effect) were 36.5% for player wins, 35.7% for banker wins, and 89.4% for ties.</p><p>In summary, the majority of customers tend to place bets on hands different from the recent outcomes following a streak of consecutive player or banker wins being interrupted. These results align with positive recency but contradict the hot outcome fallacy. In contrast, the proportion of bets on a tie increases with streak length even after a streak of ties has been interrupted, which is consistent with the hot outcome fallacy. Speculatively, this contrast may be attributed to the low probability of ties (9.5%); when events that are supposed to be unlikely occur frequently within a short period, individuals may be prone to falling into the hot outcome fallacy. Notably, this result does not necessarily indicate the absence of positive recency for ties, as the hot outcome fallacy can coexist with positive recency. Indeed, the effect of streak length after the streak was interrupted (β1 = 0.054) was only approximately 16% of the effect observed when the streak was not interrupted (β1 = 0.339),</p><p>as shown in Analysis 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Analysis 3: Bet amount when following the trend</head><p>Analyses 1 and 2 provided evidence for positive recency in baccarat gamblers by demonstrating that the proportion of bets on a specific hand increased with the length of a streak of consecutive corresponding outcomes. To provide additional evidence for positive recency, Analysis 3 examined the bet amounts wagered when gamblers followed the trend. If baccarat gamblers adhere to positive recency and mistakenly believe in the effectiveness of the following trend strategy, then they would place more bets following the trend after a longer streak of consecutive outcomes.</p><p>When betting on the player winning after a streak of consecutive player wins (the upper panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3A</ref>), the average customer slightly increased the bet amount with streak length, β1 = 0.032, 95% CI = [0.031, 0.034], t(4784.5) = 42.02, p &lt; .001 (for the intercept, β0 = 12.069, 95% CI = <ref type="bibr">[12.035, 12</ref>.104]). The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 = .001 and Rc 2 = .758, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by ̂= 174,433 × 1.033 −1 .</p><p>Similarly, when betting on the banker win after a streak of consecutive banker wins (the middle panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3A)</ref>, the average customer slightly increased the bet amount with a streak length, β1 When betting on a tie after a streak of consecutive ties (the lower panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3A)</ref>, again, the average customer slightly increased the betting amount with streak length, β1 = 0.020, 95% CI = [0.013, 0.028], t(1677.4) = 5.54, p &lt; .001 (for the intercept, β0 = 10.208, 95% CI = [10.179, 10.237]).</p><p>The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 &lt; .001 and Rc 2 = .752, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by ̂= 27,122 × 1.021 −1 . <ref type="figure">Figure 4A</ref> shows customers' point estimates of rates of changes in bet amounts per streak length (i.e., exponentials of β1 + γ1i). The proportions of customers whose estimates were numerically larger than one (indicating no effect) were 85.3% for player wins, 84.3% for banker wins, and 86.6% for ties.</p><p>In summary, irrespective of the outcome type, the majority of customers increased their bet amounts with streak length when they followed the trend, although the average rate of increase was small (i.e., 2-3%). In the following two sections, we substantiate this finding by analyzing the bet amounts when customers did not follow the trend.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Analysis 4: Bet amount when betting against the trend</head><p>For transparency, we analyzed the bet amounts when customers did not follow the trend (e.g., when betting on either the banker win or a tie after a streak of consecutive player wins). This situation represents the exact complementary event of the situation given in Analysis 3.</p><p>When betting on the banker win or a tie after a streak of consecutive player wins (the upper panel in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3B</ref>), the average customer decreased the bet amount with a streak length, β1 = −0.105, 95%  <ref type="bibr">β0 = 11.843,</ref><ref type="bibr">95% CI = [11.809,</ref><ref type="bibr">11.878]</ref>). The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 = .004 and Rc 2 = .643, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by ̂= 139,116 × 0.900 −1 .</p><p>Similarly, when betting on the player win or a tie after a streak of consecutive banker wins (the  <ref type="bibr">CI = [11.758,</ref><ref type="bibr">11.826]</ref>). The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 = .005</p><p>and Rc 2 = .633, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by ̂= 132,232 × 0.896 −1 .</p><p>When betting on the player or banker win after a streak of consecutive ties (the lower panel in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3B</ref>), the average customer did not significantly change the bet amount with streak length, β1 = 0.000, 95% CI = [−0.005, 0.004], t(2445.0) = −0.21, p = .833 (for the intercept, β0 = 12.096, 95% CI = [12.061, 12.131]). The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 &lt; .001</p><p>and Rc 2 = .763, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by ̂= 179,077 × 1.000 −1 . <ref type="figure">Figure 4B</ref> shows customers' point estimates of rates of changes in bet amounts per streak length (i.e., exponentials of β1 + γ1i). The proportions of customers whose estimates were numerically larger than one (indicating no effect) were 9.7% for a streak of player wins, 9.2% for a streak of banker wins, and 49.2% for a streak of ties.</p><p>In summary, when betting against the trend, the majority of customers decreased the bet amounts after a streak of consecutive player or banker wins. After a streak of consecutive ties, customers tended not to change the bet amount significantly. Since this analysis was conducted as the exact complement to Analysis 3, the interpretation of the results should be performed with caution. In this <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. Distributions of customers' point estimates (N = 6,625) regarding the effects of the streak length on bet amounts when customers (A) bet following the trend (Analysis 3), (B) bet on the player win, the banker win, or a tie against the trend (Analysis 4), and (C) bet on the player or banker win against the trend. Black circles represent geometric means across customers. Horizontal lines in each violin plot depict quantiles.</p><p>analysis, bets against the trend after the player or banker win included risky bets on ties. Thus, the observed decrements in bet amounts after a streak of consecutive player or banker wins could be merely explained by the fact that customers bet smaller amounts on a long shot hand (tie) than on the regular hands (player and banker wins). For this reason, we conducted the next analysis excluding bets on ties.</p><p>3.5. Analysis 5: Bet amount when betting against the trend (excluding bets on ties)</p><p>Analysis 5 examined the bet amount when customers placed bets on the banker or player win against the trend after a streak of consecutive player or banker wins, respectively. The only difference from Analysis 4 was that Analysis 5 excluded bets placed on ties.</p><p>When betting on the banker win after a streak of consecutive player wins (the upper panel in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure   3C</ref>), the average customer slightly decreased the bet amount with streak length, β1 = −0.009, 95% CI = [−0.010, −0.006], t(4368.1) = −7.250, p &lt; .001 (for the intercept, β0 = 12.104, 95% CI = [12.069,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>12</head><p>.139]). The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 &lt; .001 and Rc 2 = .761, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by ̂= 180,583 × 0.992 −1 .</p><p>When betting on the player win after a streak of consecutive banker wins (the lower panel in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure   3C</ref>), the average customer slightly decreased the bet amount with streak length, β1 = −0.007, 95% CI = [−0.009, −0.005], t(4707.9) = −6.08, p &lt; .001 (for the intercept, β0 = 12.073, 95% CI = [12.039,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>12</head><p>.108]). The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 &lt; .001 and Rc 2 = .758, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by ̂= 175,134 × 0.993 −1 . <ref type="figure">Figure 4C</ref> shows customers' point estimates of rates of changes in betting amounts per streak length (i.e., exponentials of β1 + γ1i). The proportions of customers whose estimates were numerically larger than one (indicating no effect) were 37.2% for a streak of player wins and 39.5% for a streak of banker wins.</p><p>In summary, when betting against the trend after a streak of consecutive player or banker wins, customers tended to decrease their wagers, although the average rate of decrease was small (i.e., 1%).</p><p>This contrasts with the situation in which customers followed the trend (Analysis 3) and further supports the prevalence of positive recency in baccarat gamblers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion</head><p>In the present study, we analyzed large-scale playing data from a land-based casino and demonstrated that most baccarat gamblers exhibit positive recency rather than negative recency or the gambler's fallacy. This was confirmed by our observation that customers in the casino tended to bet more frequently on the same hand as the previous outcomes (i.e., player win, banker win, or a tie)</p><p>after a longer streak of consecutive outcomes (Analysis 1; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1A</ref>). This pattern cannot be explained in terms of the hot outcome fallacy or frequency-based reasoning, such as probability learning, because the systematic pattern disappeared after the streak was interrupted (Analysis 2; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1B</ref>). Consistently, we also found slight but reliable effects of streak length on the bet amount, with customers placing more bets on the consecutive outcome but fewer bets on the nonconsecutive outcome (Analyses 3-5; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref>). All of these results indicate the prevalence of the trendfollowing strategy, which reflects baccarat gamblers' erroneous belief in the form of positive recency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Potential mechanisms of positive recency in baccarat</head><p>In a broad sense, the finding that baccarat gamblers predominantly exhibit positive recency can be regarded as a manifestation of illusory correlation <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Chapman, 1967)</ref>, a cognitive bias in which individuals erroneously perceive meaningful and predictable patterns in sequences that are, in fact, random. The important remaining questions concern the more detailed cognitive mechanisms underlying positive recency among baccarat gamblers. Notably, while the dominant theory suggests that perceiving a sequence generation mechanism as random typically leads to negative recency or the gambler's fallacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Oskarsson et al., 2009)</ref>-as observed in roulette <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Croson &amp; Sundali, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Sundali &amp; Croson, 2006)</ref> and lottery <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Clotfelter &amp; Cook, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kong et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Suetens et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Terrell, 1994</ref>)-baccarat gamblers demonstrate the opposite tendency, even in a situation where the sequence generation mechanism is clearly random. To account for this, it is essential to consider not only general cognitive biases but also contextual factors unique to baccarat. In this section, we review existing theories and explore four potential candidate mechanisms (which are not mutually exclusive)</p><p>that could explain the observed trend-following strategy.</p><p>First, the positive recency observed in baccarat gamblers may be explained by the law of small numbers, a cognitive bias in which individuals tend to believe that small samples should reflect the properties of larger populations. This bias has been used to explain both positive and negative recency (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Ayton &amp; Fischer, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Rabin, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1971</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">, 1974</ref>. For example, gamblers might interpret a short streak of consecutive outcomes-such as repeated wins by the player or banker-as a signal of a larger pattern, expecting that the streak will continue (positive recency).</p><p>Conversely, they might also expect a reversal after a short streak, assuming that the next outcome will balance the previous one (negative recency). However, while the law of small numbers could explain positive recency, it cannot explain why the trend-following behavior is specifically preferred in baccarat, as opposed to the contrarian behavior observed in games such as roulette and lotteries.</p><p>Second, we consider positive recency in terms of probability learning. In previous animal studies, behaviors consistent with positive recency or the hot outcomes belief have been considered adaptive in situations such as foraging for clumped resources (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Blanchard et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Wilke &amp; Barrett, 2009)</ref>. In these contexts, positive recency is advantageous because if food is found in one location, the likelihood of finding more food nearby increases. In general, positive recency is a rational belief when the probability of a favorable event is fixed or stable for a certain period, and one seeks to estimate this probability to decide whether to continue exploiting the resource. Consistent phenomena have been observed in lotteries <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Suetens et al., 2016)</ref>, where players are likely to bet on a "hot" number that appeared in previous weeks, even when the number has not appeared for two consecutive weeks. However, this explanation does not fully account for our findings. In baccarat, gamblers stop betting on a "hot" outcome as soon as a streak of player or banker wins is interrupted, even though the outcome would still be considered "hot" under the assumption of a fixed probability. Therefore, from the perspective of probability learning, we must consider the possibility that baccarat gamblers believe that the probability of outcomes is not stable but fluctuates (e.g., according to a hidden Markov process), interpreting the interruption of a streak as a cue for these probability fluctuations.</p><p>This hypothesis should be explored further in future studies using cognitive modeling approaches.</p><p>Third, we consider the effect of streak length on positive or negative recency. Research has suggested that shorter streaks tend to lead to negative recency, whereas longer streaks are more likely to induce positive recency (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kong et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Rabin &amp; Vayanos, 2010)</ref>. In this framework, gamblers may be more likely to expect a reversal of outcomes after short streaks but anticipate the continuation of long streaks. Indeed, <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kong et al. (2020)</ref> applied this framework to explain their "surprising" finding of positive recency in lottery games with two or three winning numbers. However, our data are inconsistent with this explanation. We observed that the probability of betting on the same outcome as the previous one increased monotonically with streak length, indicating that positive recency is dominant regardless of streak length. Therefore, positive recency in baccarat cannot be explained in the same way as a recent finding of positive recency in multiple-prize lotteries <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kong et al., 2020)</ref>, suggesting that distinct mechanisms may be at play.</p><p>Fourth, we consider the possibility that factors specific to baccarat, which may be the most compelling explanation for the observed positive recency, contribute to the effect. In baccarat, the scoreboard displays the outcomes (player win, banker win, or tie) of each game. The outcomes are typically recorded from left to right, but when consecutive outcomes are the same, they are displayed below the previous result rather than continuing to the right, thereby emphasizing the streak of identical results. This design draws attention to the continuity of outcomes, which may reinforce the belief in a pattern and encourage players to expect the streak to continue. In contrast, while roulette also often displays past outcomes, its design does not emphasize the continuity of outcomes in the same way. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Roney and Trick (2003)</ref> demonstrated that grouping based on consecutive outcomes of coin tosses strengthened negative recency compared with arbitrary grouping (although the direction was opposite to our findings). The possibility that baccarat scoreboards may promote positive recency by making consecutive outcomes more salient to players should be experimentally tested in future studies.</p><p>We demonstrated the prevalence of the trend-following strategy in baccarat, but the detailed mechanisms underlying this behavior remain untested, which is a limitation of the present study.</p><p>Notably, the mechanisms of gambling behaviors in real situations are complex and cannot be fully explained by a single factor or a few factors. For example, in addition to the mechanisms discussed here, factors such as the illusion of control <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Langer, 1975)</ref> and the illusion of validity <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1974)</ref> may play a role in maintaining or strengthening positive recency. Nonetheless, the finding that opposite behaviors can emerge in games with nearly identical structures (i.e., baccarat vs. roulette) highlights the importance of the need to closely examine how the specific structure of a gambling game influences betting behavior. This insight is theoretically important for a more comprehensive understanding of gambling behavior and its underlying mechanisms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Implications for problem gambling</head><p>The findings of the present study also have significant implications for understanding problem gambling, given the prevalence of cognitive distortions in pathological gamblers (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Fortune &amp; Goodie, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gaissmaier et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Myrseth et al., 2010)</ref>. Previous studies have shown that while negative recency is commonly observed in the general population and is not necessarily linked to pathological behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Matarazzo et al., 2019)</ref>, the hot outcome fallacy is more prominent in habitual gamblers at risk of problem gambling <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Wilke et al., 2014)</ref>. However, it remains unclear whether positive recency, as observed in baccarat, follows a similar pattern. In this section, we explore the implications of the belief in positive recency among baccarat gamblers in terms of problem gambling, considering its potential role in reinforcing maladaptive gambling behaviors.</p><p>Financial problems are among the primary concerns associated with problem gambling. Our results revealed that bet amounts tended to increase consistently with longer streaks when following trends, but the increment was quite small (2-3%), suggesting that trend-following itself poses trivial financial risk. For regular bets (i.e., betting on player wins or banker wins), trend-following is not inherently a risky betting strategy because it does not alter the expected value of the outcome, similar to countertrend betting in roulette <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Croson &amp; Sundali, 2005)</ref> and nonpari-mutuel lotteries <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Clotfelter &amp; Cook, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Terrell, 1994)</ref>. However, our findings also indicate that trend-following occurs even for tie bets. Since betting on the tie is a high-risk long shot with a house advantage of 9.52%, betting on ties after consecutive tie outcomes carries nonnegligible economic costs. Furthermore, even if trendfollowing itself involves minimal direct costs, it may indirectly contribute to problem gambling by encouraging continued betting in situations where gamblers might otherwise stop or by increasing the enjoyment of gambling, thereby fostering deeper engagement. These potential risks should be carefully considered when interventions for problems or pathological gambling are designed.</p><p>Is positive recency in baccarat gamblers related to other cognitive distortions in problem gambling?</p><p>While this question cannot be answered definitively at this point, existing evidence provides some indication of a potential link. For example, previous research on roulette gambling in casinos has demonstrated that negative recency is positively correlated with hot hand fallacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Sundali &amp; Croson, 2006</ref>). Furthermore, pathological gamblers tend to exhibit multiple cognitive distortions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Mathieu et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Xian et al., 2008)</ref>. These findings suggest an interrelationship between different cognitive biases in both healthy individuals and pathological gamblers. In the context of baccarat, Huang (2016) identified various cognitive biases, including trend-following, winner following, superstitions, and overconfidence, based on a qualitative analysis of baccarat guidebooks. In addition, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abe et al. (2021)</ref> demonstrated a tendency among casino gamblers to engage in risky betting after consecutive wins, which is consistent with hot hand fallacy. These biases may interact and mutually reinforce one another. Among them, the trend-following behavior observed in the present study could be a clear and easily measurable manifestation of these cognitive distortions in baccarat. If this behavior is indeed linked to other cognitive distortions or markers of pathological gambling, the degree to which individuals engage in trend-following could serve as a valuable indicator for identifying maladaptive gambling tendencies among baccarat players.</p><p>Understanding the cognitive foundations underlying pathological and problem gambling is crucial for developing more targeted interventions and effective prevention strategies. Given that gambling behaviors and cognitive distortions can manifest differently depending on the type of gambling <ref type="bibr">(Mathieu et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Phua et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr">Toneatto et al., 1997)</ref>, baccarat-which enjoys immense popularity in East Asia and has a high prevalence of problem gamblers <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Huang, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Loi &amp; Kim, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Philander et al., 2016)</ref>-represents an especially important focus for studying problem gambling. Examining cognitive distortions specific to baccarat, such as positive recency, is not only clinically valuable for understanding the development of problem gambling but also has broader societal and economic implications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Conclusion</head><p>This study demonstrates that baccarat gamblers tend to follow trends, as if they hold an erroneous belief in positive recency, rather than adhering to the gambler's fallacy or negative recency; this challenges existing theories regarding the determinants of positive and negative recency. Through a detailed analysis of large-scale field data from a casino, we consistently found that baccarat gamblers predict future outcomes to be positively correlated with past consecutive outcomes, even when the outcome sequence is, in fact, random and unpredictable. These results provide valuable insights into decision-making processes within the casino environment and offer a new perspective on how cognitive biases, such as positive recency in baccarat, influence gambling behavior. Future research should further explore the motivations behind trend-following behavior and its psychological underpinnings, as well as its broader implications for understanding gambling behavior in other contexts, including pathological and problem gambling.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ethical Statement</head><p>This study was approved by the Ethical Committee of Kyoto University for Advanced Study of Mind (29-P-26).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Funding Statement</head><p>This study was funded by SEGA SAMMY HOLDINGS, Inc., which had no control over the data analysis, interpretation, writing, or publication of this work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Accessibility</head><p>We cannot share the data publicly due to the contract with the funding body. Instead, the analysis scripts used in this study and fictitious data, which may help understand the analytic procedure, are available at https://doi.org/10.17605/osf.io/9c2p3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Declaration of Competing Interests</head><p>Hiroyuki Muto was employed with funding from SEGA SAMMY HOLDINGS, Inc. Ryusuke Nakai declares no conflicts of interest. Toshiya Murai, Sakiko Yoshikawa, and Nobuhito Abe are joint research partners of SEGA SAMMY HOLDINGS, Inc.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>6% after a single player win, β₀ = −0.135, 95% CI = [−0.149, −0.122]. The odds increased with streak length, β₁ = 0.325, 95% CI = [0.318, 0.332], z = 89.31, p &lt; .001. The marginal and conditional coefficientsof determination were Rm 2 = .314 and Rc 2 = .993, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by also observed for the proportions of bets on a banker win following a streak of banker wins (the middle panel ofFigure 1A). On average, customers bet on the banker with a probability of 47.8% after the banker won only once, β0 = −0.087, 95% CI = [−0.100, −0.073]. The odds increased with streak length, β1 = 0.318, 95% CI = [0.311, 0.325], z = 90.86, p &lt; .001. The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 = .304 and Rc 2 = .993, respectively.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Proportion of bets on the same hands as consecutive outcomes, (A) after a streak of the same outcomes (Analysis 1) and (B) after the streak is interrupted (Analysis 2). Each streak of outcomes is displayed in a distinct facet. Gray circles and black diamonds represent the proportions of bets for each customer (N = 6,625) and their medians across customers, respectively. Dashed lines and error bands depict predictive curves and their 99.9% confidence intervals, as estimated by generalized linear mixed-effect models.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Distributions of customers' point estimates (N = 6,625) regarding the effects of streak length on the proportion of bets on the same hands as consecutive outcomes, (A) following a streak of the same outcomes (Analysis 1) or (B) after the streak is interrupted (Analysis 2). Black circles represent geometric means across customers. Horizontal lines in each violin plot depict quantiles.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>), the proportion of bets on the player winning, on average, decreases with streak length, β1 = −0.026, 95% CI = [−0.030, −0.022], z = −13.42, p &lt; .001, starting at 46.9% when the streak length = 1, β0 = −0.123, 95% CI = [−0.135, −0.110]. The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 = .011 and Rc 2 = .917, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by a streak of banker wins is interrupted (the middle panel in Figure 1B), the proportion of bets on the banker winning, on average, decreases with streak length, β1 = −0.025, 95% CI = [−0.029, −0.021], z = −13.69, p &lt; .001, starting at 48.3% when the streak length = 1, β0 = −0.069, 95% CI = [−0.081, −0.056]. The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 = .011 and Rc 2 = .913, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Relationship between streak length and bet amounts. (A) Bet amount wagered following the trend (Analysis 3). (B) Bet amount wagered on the player win, the banker win, or a tie against the trend (Analyses 4). (C) Bet amount wagered on the player or banker win against the trend (Analysis 5). Each streak of outcomes is displayed in a distinct facet. Gray circles and black diamonds represent geometric means of bet amounts for each customer (N = 6,625) and their medians across customers, respectively. Dashed lines and error bands depict predictive curves and their 99.9% confidence intervals, as estimated by generalized linear mixed-effect models. middle panel ofFigure 3B), the average customer decreased the bet amount with streak length, β1 = −0.109, 95% CI = [−0.113, −0.106], t(5592.5) = −64.74, p &lt; .001 (for the intercept, β0 = 11.792, 95%</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Distribution of customers' ages in the data</figDesc><table><row><cell>Age</cell><cell>1925</cell><cell cols="2">26-30 31-35</cell><cell>36-40</cell><cell>41-45</cell><cell>46-50</cell><cell cols="6">51-55 56-60 61-65 66-70 71-75 76-80</cell></row><row><cell>Number</cell><cell>145</cell><cell>480</cell><cell>832</cell><cell>963</cell><cell>996</cell><cell>1,018</cell><cell>849</cell><cell>601</cell><cell>360</cell><cell>214</cell><cell>115</cell><cell>52</cell></row><row><cell>Percentage</cell><cell>2.2</cell><cell>7.3</cell><cell>12.6</cell><cell>14.5</cell><cell>15.0</cell><cell>15.4</cell><cell>12.8</cell><cell>9.1</cell><cell>5.4</cell><cell>3.2</cell><cell>1.7</cell><cell>0.8</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Descriptive statistics of focal variables included in the data</figDesc><table><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Description</cell></row><row><cell>Customer ID</cell><cell>1-6,625</cell></row><row><cell>Game ID</cell><cell>1-17,970,830</cell></row><row><cell>Bet amount on the player win</cell><cell>0-500,000,000 KRW (mean = 466,595, median = 0, SD = 4,572,910)</cell></row><row><cell>Bet or not</cell><cell>7,961,209 bets and 10,009,621 nonbets</cell></row><row><cell>Logarithm of nonzero values</cell><cell>6.91-20.03 (mean = 12.22, median = 12.21, SD = 1.69)</cell></row><row><cell>Bet amount on the banker win</cell><cell>0-500,000,000 KRW (mean = 506,075, median = 0, SD = 5,124,935)</cell></row><row><cell>Bet or not</cell><cell>8,322,899 bets and 9,647,931 nonbets</cell></row><row><cell>Logarithm of positive values</cell><cell>6.91-20.03 (mean = 12.26, median = 12.21, SD = 1.69)</cell></row><row><cell>Bet amount on the tie</cell><cell>0-500,000,000 KRW (mean = 18,149, median = 0, SD = 257,284)</cell></row><row><cell>Bet or not</cell><cell>3,451,126 bets and 14,519,704 nonbets</cell></row><row><cell>Logarithm of positive values</cell><cell>6.91-17.73 (mean = 10.33, median = 9.90, SD = 1.23)</cell></row><row><cell>Game outcome</cell><cell>8,015,853 player wins, 8,243,392 banker wins, 1,710,962 ties, 623 invalid games</cell></row><row><cell>Streak length</cell><cell>0-21</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>8.2% after a tie occurs only once, β0 = −2.422, 95% CI = [−2.470, −2.374]. The odds increased with streak length, β1 = 0.339, 95% CI = [0.312, 0.366], z = 24.93, p &lt; .001. The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 = .024 and Rc 2 = .992, respectively. The predictive curve is</figDesc><table><row><cell>represented by</cell><cell>1 −̂=</cell><cell>0.089 × 1.403 −1 .</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The marginal and conditional coefficients of determination were Rm 2 = .001 and Rc 2 = .988, respectively. The predictive curve is represented by</figDesc><table><row><cell>1 −̂=</cell><cell>0.096 × 1.055 −1 .</cell></row></table><note>, the proportion of bets on a tie, on average, increases with streak length, β1 = 0.054, 95% CI = [0.029, 0.078], z = 4.34, p &lt; .001, starting at 8.8% when the streak length = 1, β0 = −2.341, 95% CI = [−2.386, −2.296].</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1"><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Suetens et al. (2016)</ref> referred to this belief as the "hot hand fallacy." However, following the discussion in the previous paragraph and Croson and colleagues<ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Croson &amp; Sundali, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Sundali &amp; Croson, 2006)</ref>, it should be called the hot outcome fallacy.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">The casino currently offers the Lucky 6 option as a side bet, but the data analyzed in the present study was collected before the introduction of the Lucky 6.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">For anonymization, the customer IDs in the dataset were renumbered prior to our receipt. Hence, they did not match the customer IDs registered in the casino system.4  We calculated the bet amount without including complimentary chips wagered in 1.5% of the play data (also see the supplementary materials of<ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abe et al., 2021)</ref>. The inclusion of complimentary chips did not affect our results.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CRediT Authorship Contribution Statement</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of sequential winning vs. losing on subsequent gambling behavior: analysis of empirical data from casino baccarat players</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Abe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nakai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Yanagisawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Murai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yoshikawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Gambling Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="118" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14459795.2020.1817969</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14459795.2020.1817969" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Test of a prediction of stimulus sampling theory in probability learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0022984</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0022984" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="510" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Likelihood judgments and sequential effects in a twochoice probability learning situation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Whalen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0048007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0048007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="120" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The hot hand fallacy and the gambler&apos;s fallacy: Two faces of subjective randomness?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ayton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1369" to="1378" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03206327</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03206327" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">MuMIn: Multi-Model Inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bartoń</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://cran.r-project.org/package=MuMIn" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 1.47.1.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Randomness and inductions from streaks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Corpus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="184" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Gambler&apos;s fallacy&quot; versus &quot;hot hand</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03206480</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03206480" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The intentional mind and the hot hand: Perceiving intentions makes streaks seem likely to continue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Caruso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Waytz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Epley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="153" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2010.04.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2010.04.006" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Illusory correlation in observational report</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0022-5371(67)80066-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-5371(67)80066-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Verbal Learning and Verbal Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="155" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The &quot;gambler&apos;s fallacy&quot; in lottery play</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Clotfelter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.39.12.1521</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.39.12.1521" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1521" to="1525" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The gambler&apos;s fallacy and the hot hand: Empirical data from casinos</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Croson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sundali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11166-005-1153-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11166-005-1153-2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="209" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive distortions as a component and treatment focus of pathological gambling: A review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fortune</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Goodie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0026422</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0026422" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology of Addictive Behaviors</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="298" to="310" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Betting on illusory patterns: Probability matching in habitual gamblers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gaissmaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wilke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Scheibehenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mccanney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10899-015-9539-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10899-015-9539-9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Gambling Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="156" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The hot hand in basketball: On the misperception of random sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Vallone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0010-0285(85)90010-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0010-0285" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90010" to="90016" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Erroneous perceptions of Chinese baccarat players: Evidence from guidebooks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Gambling and Commercial Gaming Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.17536/jgcgr.2016.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.17536/jgcgr.2016.006" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probability learning and a negative recency effect in the serial anticipation of alternative symbols</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Jarvik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="1951" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0056878</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0056878" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgment error in lottery play: When the hot hand meets the gambler&apos;s fallacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Granic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lambert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Teo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="844" to="862" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.2018.3233</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2018.3233" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">lmerTest package: Tests in linear mixed effects models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kuznetsova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Brockhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H B</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18637/jss.v082.i13</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v082.i13" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The illusion of control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Langer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.32.2.311</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.32.2.311" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="328" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Philosophical essay on probabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Laplace</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B07NYP443X" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page">1825</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Macao&apos;s casino industry: Reinventing Las Vegas in Asia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K.-I</forename><surname>Loi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1938965509339148</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1938965509339148" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cornell Hospitality Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="268" to="283" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The gambler&apos;s fallacy in problem and non-problem gamblers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Matarazzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Carpentieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Greco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pizzini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Addictions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="754" to="769" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1556/2006.8.2019.66</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1556/2006.8.2019.66" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gambling motives: Do they explain cognitive distortions in male poker gamblers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mathieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Barrault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Brunault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Varescon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Gambling Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="145" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10899-017-9700-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10899-017-9700-8" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biases in Betting: An Application of Laboratory Findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Metzger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2466/pr0.1985.56.3.883</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2466/pr0.1985.56.3.883" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="883" to="888" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surprised by the hot hand fallacy? A truth in the law of small numbers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sanjurjo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3982/ECTA14943</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3982/ECTA14943" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2019" to="2047" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differences in cognitive distortions between pathological and non-pathological gamblers with preferences for chance or skill games</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Myrseth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Brunborg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eidem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10899-010-9180-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10899-010-9180-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Gambling Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="561" to="569" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The coefficient of determination R 2 and intra-class correlation coefficient from generalized linear mixed-effects models revisited and expanded</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nakagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C D</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schielzeth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rsif.2017.0213</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2017.0213" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of The Royal Society Interface</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">134</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017-02-13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prediction of sequential two-choice decisions from event runs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nicks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0045193</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0045193" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s next? Judging sequences of binary events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Oskarsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Van Boven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hastie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="262" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0014821</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0014821" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding discount program risk in hospitality: A Monte Carlo approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Philander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Raab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Berezan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Hospitality Marketing &amp; Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="218" to="237" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/19368623.2014.1002145</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/19368623.2014.1002145" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference by believers in the law of small numbers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/003355302760193896</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/003355302760193896" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="775" to="816" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The gambler&apos;s and hot-hand fallacies: Theory and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vayanos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-937X.2009.00582.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-937X.2009.00582.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of Economic Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="730" to="778" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grouping and gambling: A Gestalt approach to understanding the gambler&apos;s fallacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J R</forename><surname>Roney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Trick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Canadian Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0087414</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0087414" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting lotto numbers: A natural experiment on the gambler&apos;s fallacy and the hot-hand fallacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Suetens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Galbo-Jørgensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-R</forename><surname>Tyran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/jeea.12147</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/jeea.12147" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the European Economic Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="584" to="607" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biases in casino betting: The hot hand and the gambler&apos;s fallacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sundali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Croson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1930297500000309</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1930297500000309" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A test of the gambler&apos;s fallacy: Evidence from pari-mutuel games</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Terrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF01064047</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF01064047" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biases in assessments of probabilities: New evidence from greyhound races</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Terrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/a:1007771613236</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/a:1007771613236" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal betting and efficiency in parimutuel betting markets with information costs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Terrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Farmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/2235361</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/2235361" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">437</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">846</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The mathematics of gambling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Thorp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<pubPlace>Lyle Stuart</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hot-hand bias in rhesus monkeys</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Blanchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wilke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hayden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Animal Learning and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="280" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xan0000033</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xan0000033" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Belief in the law of small numbers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0031322</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0031322" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgment under uncertainty: Heuristics and biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.185.4157.1124</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.185.4157.1124" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">185</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1124" to="1131" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The hot hand phenomenon as a cognitive adaptation to clumped resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wilke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolution and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2008.11.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2008.11.004" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Illusionary pattern detection in habitual gamblers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wilke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Scheibehenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gaissmaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mccanney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolution and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2014.02.010</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2014.02.010" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Association of cognitive distortions with problem and pathological gambling in adult male twins</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Xian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Phillips</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Scherrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Volberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Eisen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.psychres.2007.08.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2007.08.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">160</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="300" to="307" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
