<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Implicit Bias Measurement with Finger Tracking: Going Beyond Reaction Time to Assess IAT Preferences</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
							<email>woodford@alumni.stanford.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Implicit Bias Measurement with Finger Tracking: Going Beyond Reaction Time to Assess IAT Preferences</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A dissertation chapter submitted in partial satisfaction of the requirements for the degree Doctor of Philosophy in Mathematics Education. The study was financially supported by the EDGE fellowship.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Research Question <ref type="bibr">Three......................................................................................................... 40 Visualizing Trajectory Data............................................................................................... 40</ref>    <ref type="bibr">............................................................................................................................... 49 Conclusion............................................................................................................................... 50</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Abstract</head><p>The Implicit Association Test is a widely used tool for measuring unconscious biases.</p><p>However, traditional Implicit Association Test designs do not provide detailed information about the cognitive processes involved in decision-making. In this study, I introduce a Finger Tracking paradigm, called a Finger Tracking Implicit Association Test, adapting the traditional block design of the Implicit Association Test to a screen-tracking tablet environment. The Finger</p><p>Tracking Implicit Association Test allowed us to collect in-flight data on the cognitive processes occurring during decision-making. Results suggest that the traditional D-score results used in Implicit Association Test literature can be enhanced by the inclusion of curvature, complexity, and temporal trajectory data collected through Finger Tracking adapted implicit association tests.</p><p>These in-flight metrics offer rich evidence of cognitive preference that is independent of D-score calculations, called d-scores when calculated for multiple metrics. Finally, a spatio-temporal analysis of trajectory data gives a nuanced look at the time scale bias present in flight during sorting stimuli. The approach gives a visually appealing way to assess bias independent of D-score methodology by assessing decision development. Findings suggest that a Finger</p><p>Tracking Implicit Association Test is a valuable addition to the implicit cognition toolkit, providing insight into the cognitive processes involved in decision-making and providing discriminant power above that of traditional reaction time-based tests like the Implicit Association Test.</p><p>Keywords: Implicit Association Test, Finger Tracking, cognitive bias measurement.</p><p>Implicit Bias Measurement with Finger Tracking:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Going Beyond Reaction Time to Assess IAT Preferences</head><p>As an illustration imagine an individual is presented with a series of prompts on a touchscreen device and is asked to make decisions by selecting an answer as they swipe their finger across the screen. The selection process is intended to be fast and almost effortless, as the stimuli are designed to be easily comprehended and quickly digested. By completing tasks in this fashion, data recorded indicates a variety of factors that are understood to be connected to our strength of associations with the prompts presented.</p><p>The evidence presented suggests there is potential for adding a new layer to implicit association test style task which provide thick trial-level data about cognitive processing. The approach allows for data-rich analysis based on real-time cognitive proxies. As a first step in a research program, this study adapts an implicit association test (IAT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Greenwald, McGhee &amp; Schwartz, 1998)</ref> to a Finger Tracking environment and dissects the processing clues left behind.</p><p>Unlike traditional reaction time approaches, Finger Tracking methods have the potential to bypass some of the limitations present with measuring time as a proxy for the strength of association. The IAT approach is one of the most widely used and well-known psychometric assessments to measure implicit cognitive processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(De Houwer, Teige-Mocigemba, Spruyt &amp; Moors, 2009)</ref>. A shortcoming inherent with Reaction Time paradigms is that the data only reflect the end result of a cognitive process leaving an inherent unreliability due to speed-accuracy interactions <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Draheim, Mashburn, Martin &amp; Engle, 2019)</ref>. This means that when using reaction time (RT) in present IAT research, investigators are collecting data on the outcome of potentially complex cognitive processes with no way to differentiate between them. The approach can lead to reporting results influenced by factors in-flight that remain opaque without additional streams of information.</p><p>IATs measure implicit social cognition through pure reaction times, but the test has faced criticism for their limited ability to capture the full range of cognitive processes involved in decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Blanton, Jaccard, Klick, Mellers, Mitchell &amp; Tetlock, 2009)</ref>. Finger tracking, on the other hand, offers a more nuanced understanding of cognitive processes by providing a trial-specific, granular glimpse into decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Spivey, Dale, Knoblich &amp; Grosjean, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>Studies using this method have found that finger movements are a reliable indicator of underlying cognitive processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Dotan, Pinheiro-Chagas, Al Roumi &amp; Dehaene, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Marghetis, Núñez &amp; Bergen, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Spivey, Grosjean, &amp; Knoblich, 2005)</ref>. Finger tracking gives researchers numerous continuous response variables, providing a more nuanced understanding of the internal workings of the mind compared to pure reaction time paradigms.</p><p>A related issue established in the medical research literature is that self-report measures and physiological measures do not always align <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Prince et al., 2020)</ref>. In a review and meta-analysis of self-report measures versus physiological markers of sedentary behavior, researchers demonstrated the ever-present discrepancies between directly measured physiological activity and self-report measures of activity. These findings highlight the limitations of relying on self-report measures for accuracy and the importance of collecting behavioral data alongside explicit answers when collecting self-report data.</p><p>The IAT has been demonstrated to be a useful tool for examining aggregate data to accurately measure regional and cultural attitudes through linking implicit social cognition results to historical data. In a recent study, researchers analyzed the large-scale data collected by Project Implicit and found that present-day racial bias measures as measured by the IAT are highly correlated with historical slave ownership populations <ref type="bibr">(Payne, Vuletich &amp; Brown-Iannuzzi, 2019)</ref>. As the historical census data varied with slave populations, the aggregated IAT racial preferences in present-day studies also increased, illustrating the lasting effects of regional norms on cognition. The finding should raise an eyebrow for educators as it glaringly illustrates the lasting impact of cultural legacy on regional attitudes and dispositions.</p><p>The presence of these often-limiting attitudes, which can be tied to regional culture and pose a challenge to promoting progressive educational practices among teachers and students within the microclimate of a classroom is surely embedded in regional social norms.</p><p>The concept of directly linking brain activity and behavioral metrics has been prevalent for some time, but new tools have opened up new lines of inquiry. A review of the literature on intra-individual variability (IIV) in relation to cognitive tasks found that the functional connection between behavioral measures and brain variability was an open question <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(MacDonald, Nyberg, and Bäckman, 2006)</ref>. Body tracking techniques like Finger Tracking offer low-cost methods for assessing these relationships. While advances in technology have enabled a greater understanding of this brain-behavior relationship using techniques such as mental chronometry, EEG, and fMRI. Numerous open questions remain regarding the link between cognition and behavioral correlates that provide ample opportunities for further exploration. The present investigation is a small but novel contribution to this ongoing line of research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trace Processes</head><p>According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Collier (2011)</ref>, the use of trace processes, such as Finger Tracking techniques, facilitates the identification of individual differences by analyzing continuous behavioral measures recorded during answer selection. The approach diverges from the common technique of assessing statistical power on IATs through pure reaction time to analyze variability which is often interpreted in opaque ways and has produced results that may not replicate <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Norman, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>The objective of this pilot study is to assess the viability and usefulness of employing the touchscreen environment for administering IAT tasks. It has been observed that when a clear, familiar, and contextually-relevant stimulus is presented, participants tend to exhibit an unambiguous response, characterized by consistent velocity and a straightforward path to the desired response <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Monaro, Gamberini &amp; Sartori, 2017)</ref>. Conversely, when a stimulus contrasting personal or socially acquired attitudes is introduced, it may lead to hesitation due to increased cognitive processes. In such cases, individuals may experience slowdowns or multiple changes in their intended response before making a decision, reflecting hesitation, ambiguity, and choice gravitation. The methods proposed in this adapted IAT paradigm hold the potential to contribute to a new level of sophistication in collecting implicit data utilizing recently available methods for wide-scale dissemination.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Questions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Question One</head><p>Implicit Association Test paradigms use a difference score (D-score) to measure preference based on reaction time, leading to ask if the Finger Tracking method allows reliable d-scores to be obtained through the use of analyzing classification indices?</p><p>Compared to the traditional method of recording simple reaction time, trajectory indices available through the use of Finger Tracking can expand what data the IAT procedure can produce. The multiple continuous outputs raise the possibility of using the typical D-score algorithm to derive a more robust difference score using full trial metrics provided by the Finger Tracking paradigm.</p><p>A similar approach using the mouse-tracking environment demonstrated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Yu, Wang, Wang &amp; Bastin (2012)</ref> was undertaken using updated methods that clarify and extend what can be gleaned with current Finger Tracking analysis methods. It has been noted that Finger Tracking opens new avenues for advancing social cognitive theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Stillman, Shen &amp; Ferguson, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>The investigation here seeks to do that in a simple step forward by applying the established D-score algorithm to various metrics produced in the Finger Tracking environment. The approach allows for a comparative analysis between d-scores derived from new sources.</p><p>Two steps are involved which are analogous to the widely used IAT D-score analysis. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Question Two</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Can trajectory indices or types analysis be utilized to analyze the effects between block conditions within the Finger Tracking Implicit Association Test paradigm to identify in-flight cognitive effects while categorizing stimuli?</head><p>Utilizing trajectory data can provide a more detailed understanding of the cognitive process beyond simple reaction time scores <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Stillman, Shen &amp; Ferguson, 2018)</ref>. If established methods can reveal significant differences in decision phases prior to final selection, then the processing stages during IAT procedures may be readily dissected to reveal in-flight measures of bias that can bolster the findings available with traditional implicit association test research.</p><p>Using trajectory indices allows for aggregate-level analysis of antecedent cognitive processes recorded prior to final categorical selection . Types analysis has also been suggested as an approach that has the power to reveal trial-level data that can be obscured by aggregate index analysis .</p><p>Two steps will be taken to look at static measures of increased cognitive complexity.</p><p>First, a test for bimodality is done to see which approach is appropriate since types is warranted when the data is bimodal and trajectory indices are more appropriate with unimodal data.</p><p>Evidence from trajectory indices evidences differential standardized effects between conditions;</p><p>while a trajectory types analysis can support claims of increased frequency of cognitive load during trials that involve increased decision making. Traditional IAT assessment depends on calculating a D-score, observing that a compatible block condition elicits behavior that may align with apriori chosen response types observed in previous movement tracking research offers the chance for valuable insights into alternative approaches to measuring differential strength of associations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Question Three</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Do IAT block effects show up by examining the spatio-temporal development of in-flight trajectory data?</head><p>Examining differences in-flight towards the target categories INSECT/FLOWER using methods outlined in <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck (2021)</ref>, trace process methodology allows unpacking average processing stages recorded with the FT-IAT sample. While the analysis is a first of its kind to my knowledge, these established techniques allow investigators to dig deeper into the surface-level differences measured with the traditional IAT paradigm.</p><p>The spatio-temporal analysis will consist of three parts accompanied by visualizations of facets of trajectory data. The velocity analysis is performed following <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Freeman (2014)</ref> to examine how velocity changes often bookend cognitive processes, slowing when deliberating and accelerating when a decision has been reached. The x-position relative to the horizontal axis analysis is thought to give insight into the current absolute preference throughout decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Koop &amp; Johnson, 2013)</ref>. The angle relative to the y-axis is a measure of implied direction and gives insights into the deliberative processes happening in flight <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Stillman, Shen &amp; Ferguson, 2018)</ref>. When participants consider alternative answers their finger will point toward to option under consideration. These three facets together can give a detailed understanding of the average decision-making process as reflected by finger tracking and offer quantifiable advantages above existing D-score methodology for assessing implicit bias.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Literature Review</head><p>The investigation is seeking to create a feasible solution that can facilitate the integration and analysis of IAT and mouse-tracking paradigms for a Finger Tracking environment. One advantage of this combination is eliminating the additional proxy introduced by the use of a mouse in traditional mouse tracking methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Dotan, Pinheiro-Chagas, Al Roumi, &amp; Dehaene, 2019)</ref>. Additionally, with the increasing prevalence of smartphones, the use of a mouse has declined presenting an opportunity for researchers to utilize Finger Tracking methods in large-scale studies. The use of Finger Tracking Implicit Association Tests (FT-IATs) offers more nuanced ways of measuring bias in tasks that typically employ IAT methods. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Greenwald and Banaji (1995)</ref> aimed to develop a measurement tool that could access individuals' unconscious processes, revealing information that they might be unwilling or unable to report due to social desirability bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Nisbett &amp; Wilson, 1977;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Nosek, Greenwald, &amp; Banaji, 2007)</ref>. In order to address this measurement issue, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Greenwald, McGhee, and Schwartz (1998)</ref> introduced the Implicit Association Test (IAT). The IAT indirectly assesses evaluative associations between a target concept and an attribute dimension <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fazio &amp; Olson, 2003)</ref>. By sorting stimuli from different pairings such as "bad/good" with "black/white," and measuring The question of whether the cognitive motor link is a continuous or discrete process has been a central focus of research utilizing finger and mouse tracking paradigms <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021)</ref>. Previous studies have produced mixed results on this issue, with earlier work assuming continuous processing updates are reflected in motor movements <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bogacz et al., 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Busemeyer et al., 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Lamberts, 2000)</ref> while others argue evidence for discrete stage-based processing can be interpreted from movement tracking data <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Van Der Wel, Eder, Mitchel, Walsh &amp; Rosenbaum, 2009)</ref>. However current understanding suggests that both continuous and discrete processing can be present, and the specific features that manifest may be influenced by the design of the paradigm, the nature of the question being studied, and individual participant's response style.</p><p>In this study the aim is to examine cognitive processing differences revealed during response selection and reflected in movement traces. Rather than seeking to distinguish between continuous and discrete trajectories here we assume both are present and instead examine average trajectories to look at differences in average response behavior. The use of the time normalization assumption is key to enabling this comparison of apples to apples with trajectories of various response times. However it is important to note that the significance of these differences may vary depending on the length of the reaction time. Trajectories with similar qualitative features may have opposing theoretical meanings when considering very short (&lt;1.5 seconds) versus long (2.5-5 seconds) reaction times <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021</ref>). These differences cannot be interpreted in the traditional IAT paradigms solely through analysis of reaction times, but can be probed in various ways in the context of Finger Tracking.</p><p>The IAT is a well known experimental procedure that employs the two-alternative forced choice paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Greenwald, McGhee &amp; Schwartz, 1998</ref> Body movement tracking paved the way for Finger Tracking research and has also been used in research to examine cognitive processes. <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Song and Nakayama (2009)</ref> demonstrated that recording body movements during reaching tasks allowed for the identification of hidden cognitive states not reflected in final reaction times or choice selections. This insight underscored and set the stage for using innovative methods like Finger Tracking to better understand the relationship between perception, cognition, and action.</p><p>Mouse tracking was subsequently used to build on body tracking research to investigate the time course of an auditory lexical decision task <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Krestar, Incera, and McLennan's, 2013)</ref>. The researchers found that real words presented in contrast to pseudowords, led to earlier time scale responses, which was thought to be evidence of stronger spatial attraction to incorrect responses in the nonword condition. Analysis of the results for these two conditions showed that familiar prompts elicited a trajectory closer to the ideal straight line path with earlier recognition for real words; a lexicality effect was observed, which could be detected as early as 100ms into individual trials. The study highlights that information is lost from both reaction time and implied endpoint analysis, as either method used alone fails to capture the processing information and may lead researchers to overlook effects occurring in-fight. <ref type="bibr">Dotan &amp; Dehaene (2016)</ref> used Finger Tracking to assess the number to position mappings for placing numbers on a number line and analyzed the trajectories to determine that there is a logarithmic effect when sorting large numbers in-flight that becomes linear during final spatial placement. The findings show that large and small digit numbers mapped to a number line are processed in the same way at the terminal stages, and FT data serves to disentangle the stages of that dynamic process which is otherwise invisible to pure RT analysis.</p><p>In a related study, Dotan, Pinheiro-Chagas, Roumi &amp; Dehaene <ref type="formula">2019</ref> Through categorizing types of movement such as acceleration/deceleration, change of direction, lingering in-flight, and deviation from idealized paths, we are able to adapt research findings developed with mouse tracking that categorize these process traces into metrics that can be readily understood using existing software packages in the R statistical computing environment.</p><p>Taken together previous research has shown the utility of Finger Tracking to augment cognitive research. Expanding on the methods previously established with mouse-tracking allows for various applications in assessing psychological constructs, as with the FT-IAT currently being introduced. Finger Tracking may allow for the traditional IAT methods to be readily adapted for future studies, the FT-IAT approach attempts to mirror the most current design after adapting minor facets to the new data collection method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Theoretical Framework</head><p>Cognitive processing, the mental processes involved in acquiring, storing, and using knowledge, has been extensively studied by various disciplines, each proposing their own theories to explain phenomena of interest. One approach to detecting cognitive complexity, or the level of mental effort required for a task, is through the use of reaction time as a proxy. It is believed that more salient ideas are more easily and quickly retrieved, leading to shorter reaction times <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Greenwald, McGhee &amp; Schwartz, 1998)</ref>. When presented with unfamiliar or deceptive cognitive links, a slight delay in reaction time is observed, known as mental chronometry. This method of measuring delay in reaction time to infer the complexity of cognitive processes has been valuable in the field of psychology. However the present research is exploring using in-flight process markers and rich spatial variables as additional tools for mental chronometry. It should be noted that the term "mental chronometry" may not be entirely accurate when the techniques are combined with trace process methods; the use of Finger Tracking allows for the detailed study of unfolding mental processes after the fact, the term "mental chronology" may be more appropriate to aptly describe the new paradigm as the term denotes the study of arranging mental events in chronological order rather than single time measurements.</p><p>Finger tracking allows researchers to track and analyze the changes in body movements that occur during the decision-making process. It is based on evidence that there is a relationship between mental processes and physical movements <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Dotan, Pinheiro-Chagas, Al Roumi &amp; Dehaene, 2019)</ref>. The technique can be used to identify patterns of cognitive activity based on the type and duration of movements made. Additionally Finger Tracking enables the possibility for repeated measurement over time, providing the opportunity to study individual response patterns.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Classification Indices</head><p>The development of Finger Tracking methods has been informed by previous research using mousetracking, which has recorded data on response time (RT) and various movement metrics. While finger movements are being recorded, several other markers can be calculated for later analysis using statistical software. There are three main categories of discrete metrics know as classification indices make up of three classes: curvature, spatio-temporal complexity, and temporal development. The classification indices can be used to answer questions about individual participant attitudes or group attitudes by performing hypothesis tests between conditions. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 0</ref> provides a summary of these classification indices and relevant citations. The focus here is put on whole trial indices rather than point estimates, reasoning that whole trial measures lend to a holistic interpretation of individual trials analagous to RT rather than a granular look within the trial afforded by point estimates. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 0</ref> gives a more detailed breakdown of classification indices with citations and the following sections give a breif overview.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Curvature Indices</head><p>Decision competition manifested by trajectory curvature can be assessed through various methods. One common approach involves drawing an idealized straight line between the starting and ending points of a trial, and then comparing the behavior of participants along various measures related to this line <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Freeman &amp; Ambady, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Spivey, Grosjean &amp; Knoblich 2005)</ref>.</p><p>The maximum absolute deviation (MAD) measure can be used to determine the timing and severity of the point at which deviation from the idealized route is greatest. It is important to note that there is a distinction between point estimates and metrics measuring the accumulation of evidence over an entire trial. Cumulative response competition is believed to be evidenced by the area under the curve (AUC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Freeman &amp; Ambady, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Spivey et al., 2005)</ref> along with RT and movment from the temporal metrics which also measure whole trial indices. Average Deviation (AD) is explored within the curvature indices because it reflects the mean of all deviations from the idealized path across the entire trajectory.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spatio-temporal Complexity Indices</head><p>Complexity values are used to assess the level of competition as respondent search for a response; they were originally derived through analyzing the number of changes in the x-position and later through calculating sample entropy. Among these measures, only sample entropy is relevant to the focus on overall trial indices but is omitted from the d-score calculations because of complications with interpretation. Sample entropy is a measure of the similarity between trajectories and evaluates the predictability of changes in direction <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Temporal Development Indices</head><p>The next class of metrics are the temporal development metrics, which are expected to have a strong correlation with reaction time. These values may also provide insight into intermediate processing moments, such as the amount of time spent lingering after decision selection, which is thought to reflect answer satisfaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Shadmehr &amp; Ahmed, 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Researchers can use the rich trajectory data obtained through these metrics to explore a range of questions relevant to their specific research goals, including measures such as total movement time, total pause time, and hesitation to launch. For the current purpose of extending IAT D-score analysis, RT and movement are metrics reflecting a single numerical value for the entire trial.  Note. See source literature for more information on the development and rationale for each metric mentioned.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trajectory Types Analysis</head><p>Cluster analysis has emerged as a prevalent statistical method for identifying distinct types within a set of objects <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Hastie, Tibshirani, &amp; Friedman, 2001</ref>). This approach involves categorizing objects, such as trajectories, into a predetermined number of clusters, with the goal of maximizing similarity within each cluster while minimizing similarity between clusters . The process involves determining pairwise distances, selecting an appropriate clustering algorithm, and determining the optimal number of clusters. However, it should be noted that cluster solutions may differ across datasets and experimental conditions, posing challenges for cross-study comparison and meta analysis.</p><p>To mitigate the clustering issue, one strategy involves defining prototypical trajectories and assigning each trajectory to the nearest prototype based on a specified distance metric . This strategy establishes a fixed partitioning of the object space, facilitating whole trial comparisons across the conditions being investigated <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Dale &amp; Duran, 2011)</ref>. After the pilot stage it is appropriate to make custom types from pilot work in order to make more refined predictions with established FT paradigms <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spatio-temporal In-flight Decision Analysis</head><p>The study of decision making during flight has been advanced by analyzing the spatio-temporal development of answer selection. Researchers <ref type="bibr">(Kieslich, Henninger, Wulff,</ref> Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2019; Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021) have examined the dimensions of x-position relative to the horizontal axis, angle relative to the vertical axis, and trajectory velocity to understand facets of how movement is related to decision evolution.</p><p>The analysis of x-position is believed to reflect current absolute preference in decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Koop &amp; Johnson, 2013)</ref>. Angle relative to y-axis analysis provides insights into the process of deliberation <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Stillman, Shen &amp; Ferguson, 2018)</ref>. Velocity measures are thought to evidence uncertainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Freeman, 2014)</ref>. By examining the average behavioral differences during answer selection at each time-normalized step, valuable evidence can be obtained about the time-accuracy interactions happening in-flight.</p><p>To ensure comparability between trajectories with different reaction times, the trajectories are time normalized using 101 timesteps, following the convention established by <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Spivey, Grosjean &amp; Knoblich (2005)</ref>. Various other resampling techniques can be used during analysis to achieve diverse reserach goals but the convention is sufficient for most general purposes <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021)</ref>. Time normalization allows for a comparative analysis of average trajectories between trace evidence with a range of reaction times.</p><p>The evolution of decision making in-flight has been examined previously through the analysis of spatio-temporal development during answer selection <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021)</ref>. When considering the dimensions of x-position, angle and velocity reearchers get a quantitative glimpse into the processing stages participants undertake as they sort FT-IAT stimuli. The analysis provides valuable insights into choice gravitation, deliberation, and certaintly respectively while the time normalization hypothesis allows for meaningful comparisons across different reaction times. The standard filtering procedures for the IAT involve examining response time as a means of excluding certain trials. The approach poses a challenge when analyzing trajectory data, as there is no equivalent filter established for a new paradigm. As an interim step until new filtering methods are adapted, all trials that fall within the standard IAT sorting algorithm for response time are retained for analysis across all dimensions. Trials with response times shorter than 500 milliseconds (2 trials in total) and longer than 8 seconds (4 trials in total) were excluded from the analysis. In order to facilitate analysis within the mousetrap environment, all trials were remapped to have symmetrical start and end points. To allow for comparison and visualization of the highly variable data inputs the absolute duration of the trials was time-normalized or spatially normalized as appropriate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Summary of Analysis Spproaches in Movement Tracking Paradigms</head><p>Three common analysis approaches are: (1) a types analysis for bimodal data, (2) an examination of trajectory indices in the absence of bimodality, or (3) a temporal evolution analysis looking at x-position, angle, or velocity curves; then one may compare conditions across a sample population to identify statistically significant differences within average trajectory development. If significant differences are found, specific time windows can be analyzed to determine if the differences persist across divisions of reaction times. This is a test of the robustness of the results.</p><p>Making comparisons using the five common trajectory types is typically elected apriori, so that future work can be easily compared with these findings. An alternative is to use custom types derived from the data, but this can be challenging to compare across studies and makes meta-analytic methods for aggregating findings nearly impossible. Additionally, custom sets of types must be developed in pilot work and hypothesized to hold in future work <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021)</ref>, which is beyond the scope of the current investigation.</p><p>The question of whether the cognitive motor link is a continuous or discrete process has been a central focus of research utilizing finger and mouse tracking paradigms <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021)</ref>. Previous studies have produced mixed results on this issue, with earlier work assuming continuous processing updates reflected in motor movements <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bogacz et al., 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Busemeyer et al., 2019</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Lamberts, 2000)</ref> while others argue evidence for discrete stage-based processing can be interpreted from movement tracking data <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Van Der Wel, Eder, Mitchel, Walsh &amp; Rosenbaum, 2009</ref>). However, current understanding suggests that both continuous and discrete processing can be present, and the specific features that manifest may be influenced by the design of the paradigm, the nature of the question being studied, and individual participant's response style.</p><p>The aim is to examine cognitive processing differences revealed during response selection and reflected in movement traces. Rather than seeking to distinguish between continuous and discrete trajectories, here we assume both are present and instead examine average trajectories to look at differences in average response behavior. The use of the time normalization assumption is key to enabling this comparison of apples to apples with trajectories of various response times. It is important to note that the significance of these differences may vary depending on the length of the reaction time. For example, trajectories with similar qualitative features may have opposing theoretical meanings when considering very short (&lt;1.5 seconds) versus long (2.5-5 seconds) reaction times <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021</ref>). These differences cannot be interpreted in the traditional IAT paradigms solely through analysis of reaction times, but can be probed in various ways in the context of Finger Tracking. The dataset includes 18 participants who completed all seven blocks of the standard IAT procedure. The analysis was restricted to the mixed condition critical and practice trials from blocks 3, 4, 6, and 7. Specifically, the critical blocks (40 trials) were recorded for comparison across blocks 4 and 7, while the practice blocks (20 trials) corresponded to blocks 3 and 6. As is typical in IAT research, both the practice and critical blocks were compared for differences across 120 trials for each participant included in all d-score calculations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study Summary</head><p>The participants were recruited from an undergraduate online seminar course at a university in Arizona. The course had a total of 63 students, all of whom were required to complete a university-sponsored survey as part of their course credit. The students had the option to take multiple surveys, and the data analyzed here was collected as one of them.</p><p>The research program has received IRB approval from Stanford University. Participants have been recruited from various remote sources as specified in the IRB approval, including class/academic settings, with the requirement that all participants be adults 18 or older. Informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to data collection, those did not give informed consent were thanked for their participation and brought to the end of the survey. The IRB has reviewed the research materials and approved the study involving human subjects. Using guidelines outlined by Wolff et al. <ref type="formula">2021</ref>, the present study adopts best practices in mouse-tracking research during design, including the use of a dynamic starting procedure. As described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Scherbaum &amp; Kieslich (2018)</ref>, this procedure requires participants to initiate each trial by placing their finger on the fixation square located at the bottom center of the screen.</p><p>During the trial, stimuli are presented at 25% of the vertical range of the screen. To make a selection, participants must continuously drag their finger upwards and towards the chosen option without the need for a click or tap <ref type="figure">(Figure 1</ref>). Once the selection is made, the next trial can be initiated by moving or lifting the finger and returning it to the fixation square.</p><p>The analysis is conducted using the R programming language and R studio (Studio Team, 2020). To facilitate visualization and sampling of time intervals the mousetrap package was utilized <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Kieslich &amp; Henninger, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, F., Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021)</ref>. As suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Scherbaum &amp; Kieslich (2018)</ref>, the dynamic starting procedure was employed in which participants were required to begin moving their finger up the tablet device prior to the initiation of each trial stimuli. Prior research indicated that this starting procedure resulted in the "leakage" of more cognitive markers during trials <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Scherbaum &amp; Kieslich, 2018)</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Illustration of the Finger Tracking Implicit Association Test paradigm</head><p>Note: Each trial is presented for both attributes with sides switched halfway through the procedure.. Trials are started when a finger is placed in the fixation square. Target stimuli are presented at 25% of the vertical screen space. Spatial movements are tracked at 60 Hz time intervals for the duration of each trial. Error messages are triggered for: incorrect categorizing, stopping, going backwards, moving too slow, or lifting a finger before a selection is made. Each error trial is repeated randomly until all trials from each block are complete.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Brief Summary of Interpreting Cognitive Proxies</head><p>This pilot study evaluates the use of will proceed with a types analysis. Otherwise I will use time-normalized trajectories, which are resampled to create 101 time divisions following convention from previous research regardless of the total reaction time recorded <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Spivey, Grosjean &amp; Knoblich, 2005)</ref>. The specific number of time divisions can be resampled for various research goals, but the convention seems to work for most purposes and was elected to be used here.</p><p>What is represented by these various methods of analysis are some reasonably easy to </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Findings</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Question One</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D-score Analysis</head><p>The D-score is calculated using an algorithm previously described in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Greenwald, McGhee &amp; Schwartz, 1998)</ref>, is a commonly used metric for evaluating the results of IAT tasks. While the interpretation of individual D-scores from a single IAT sitting may be controversial, the aggregated D-scores collected through Project Implicit have been shown to reflect social and cultural factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Payne, Vuletich, and Lundberg, 2017)</ref>. Elsewhere D-scores are typically reported as averages across a group of participants, rather than as individual scores.</p><p>In addition to the D-score, other indices may be analyzed in order to better understand the In this study, there is a strong and significant correlation between reaction time (RT) and movement (r=.96**), as would be expected based on the fact that these are temporal markers that are often highly correlated. Similarly, there is a strong and significant correlation between the d-scores for AUC and AD (r=.80**), both are whole trial curvature measures of deviation from an idealized path. However, there is a weaker but significant correlation between AD and both RT (r=-.51*) and movement (r=-.55*), this provides evidence of a systematic but weak</p><p>relationship, suggesting absolute deviation may be a unique construct also related to the whole trial time becaues of the longer time needed to trace a longer path. While the low correlation and lack of significance observed between AUC and the temporal indices (r=-0.34 for RT and r=-0.34 for movement) suggests that these measures are not measuring the same construct, previous research has shown that the AUC metric can be a useful independent whole-trial index for augmenting response time analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Monaro, Gamberini &amp; Sartori, 2017)</ref>. Observing that each d-score is agreeing in sign and relatively similar in magnitude is a strong indicator that they are measuring a similar phenomenon, and measuring it differently in each case. In the next section, we will evaluate the split-half reliability of these d-scores to determine the most reliable relative measures within this candidate set. Given the exploratory nature of pilot work, it is possible that the baseline numbers for RT may be improved upon over time. Although it seems more likely after preliminary investigation that the in-flight metrics might prove to be more useful and explain much of the instability present in pure reaction time paradigms. It is important to interpret these numbers relative to one another rather than making absolute judgments about the strength of magnitude at this early pilot stage. In general evidence of higher reliability suggests a more robust measure for calculating d-scores compared with RT.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Split-half Reliability Checking Internal Consistency</head><p>It is useful to first compare the response time and movement metrics when evaluating the reliability of the FT-IAT. The approach is relatively novel, as there has been limited research on adapting the IAT to a Finger Tracking environment. The exception is <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Yu et al. (2012)</ref>, which adapted the IAT to a mouse-tracking environment. The normal range for internal consistency on IAT tasks is typically between .7 and .9 <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Greenwald &amp; Nosek, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr">Schmudle &amp; Egloff, 2004)</ref>.</p><p>However, early versions of tasks such as the Go/No-go Association Task that rely on latency-based measures have shown weaker reliability with an average split-half correlation of 0.20 <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Nosek &amp; Banaji, 2001</ref>).</p><p>To assess the reliability of the FT-IAT, a split-half reliability analysis was performed by randomly sampling half of the trajectories recorded in compatible and incompatible blocks, and examining the correlations between each half. The adjusted values should be interpreted as the 2 internal consistency measure due to the repeated testing aspect of multiple split-half calculations.</p><p>The data is grouped first by user and then by compatibility condition. This process was repeated 30 times, and the average split-half correlation is reported among all the randomly split samples.  is taken naively that the current procedure is identical to the original IAT method, then the stronger internal consistency given by movement time suggests that a more relaible alternative to RT and is readily adapted without theoretical changes to the paradigm by using the movement metric for D-score in a FT environment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Question Two Trajectory Types Analysis</head><p>Before looking at trajectory indices, it is appropriate to determine the suitability of conducting a types analysis on the IAT category/attribute pairings using Finger Tracking trials.</p><p>It is generally considered that one or the other analysis is performed, unless there is ambiguity in the test for bimodality when conducting a types analysis. As a reminder, types are predetermined trajectory categorizations that are expected to aid in identifying the most common behaviors displayed by participants. To determine if a types analysis would be appropriate, we first visualized the behavior of the trajectories using a difference heatmap (see Appendix M). Considering the statistical tests available is a matter of research goals, as they can vary in their sensitivity and reliability. Bimodality tests, in particular, can be dependent on the specific data set being analyzed <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Pfister et al., 2013)</ref>. In order to confirm the results of a bimodality test it is advisable to perform a second bimodality test on the same data. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Pfister et al. (2013)</ref>, if the Bimodality Coefficient (BC) is above 0.555, there is evidence of bimodality, with larger values indicating stronger evidence. In this case, the BC values for RT, movement, AUC, and AD were 0.5961533, 0.3922954, 0.1414372, and 0.4369357 respectively. Based on these results, there is only marginal evidence for bimodality in the RT data. It is important to exercise caution when interpreting the results of a types analysis, as the findings may be inconclusive even if significance is detected due to the mixed results on the bimodality tests. It is still worthwhile for posterity to conduct a chi-squared test using trajectory types to determine if there are statistically significant differences in the distribution of response style frequencies within the data set.</p><p>According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Wulff et al. (2021)</ref>, the evaluation of differences in the distribution of types of trajectory paths can be carried out by first calculating the distribution of types and frequencies of each within the set <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">(Table 1)</ref>. A chi-square test is then conducted to determine if there is a statistically significant difference between the frequency of types. Finally, a post hoc analysis of the residuals is performed to identify where the significance is concentrated among the different trajectory types. This approach has been supported by the analysis and code provided by <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Wulff et al. (2021)</ref>.</p><p>A chi-squared test was conducted on the frequency distribution of trajectory types using the top-down a priori types provided within the mousetrap analysis package. The results of the test showed that there were statistically significant differences in the distribution of trajectory frequencies, with X-squared = 17.715, df = 4, and a p-value of 0.001403 (***). However, it should be noted that the previous bimodality results were inconsistent, so the interpretation of these results should be approached with caution. Upon examination of the residuals following <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Wulff et al. (2021)</ref>, it appears that curved, continuous change of mind, and discrete change of mind contributed significantly to the observed effects. Furthermore, the direction of these effects was reversed between straight/curved and cCoM/dCoM, which is consistent with expectations since the incompatible trials should exhibit more evidence of deliberation. The residuals and chi-squared results were omitted since the information didn't reveal anything beyond what the frequency table intuitively demonstrates.</p><p>The results of the study suggest that participants in the incompatible condition exhibited a higher tendency towards deliberation, as indicated by a higher frequency of cCoM/dCoM. This finding is consistent with the concept of cognitive bias as a competition for cognitive activation between familiar and less easily endorsed concepts. Specifically, the results suggest that participants answering in the compatible condition, which are assumed to consist of more easily activated category/attribute pairings, exhibited a higher prevalence of straight and curved trajectories. The low p-value of p&lt;0.001403 *** indicates that they are highly statistically significant and unlikely to be the result of chance alone. However, the inconclusive results of the bimodality tests across a range of variables suggest that further research is necessary to fully understand the usefulness of a priori types analysis in the FT-IAT paradigm.</p><p>When using types approaches, the ideal situation is a pilot phase used to train types for the specific paradigm. Following a custom types construction, subsequent applications of the types produced can serve as a hypothesis to test for future FT-IAT interations. There are advantages and drawbacks to this approach: namely that the types are an iterative process, and metanalysis across studies is difficult unless the apriori types are used across studies. Being a pilot study, the apriori types were utilized for the chi-squared analysis, although future applications of IAT norming tools could be compared to custom types constructed from this pilot for future iterations. A middle ground may be to perform both approaches in published research so that data sets can be compared in various ways at a later date. The next analysis focuses on evaluating behavior variability using trajectory indices. Note: This set includes five prototypes, representing straight, curved, continuous change of mind (cCoM), discrete change of mind (dCoM), and discrete double change of mind (dCoM2) trajectory types <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021</ref>).</p><p>Since the types bimodality analysis was inconclusive, assuming normality conditions are satisfied warrants a deeper look using additional trajectory analysis methods. Seeking to extend the insights available with RT, a key consideration to evaluate the usefulness of trajectory indices is to examine the stnadardized effect size between block conditions. One approach for examining this is to calculate the standardized effect size using Cohen's d. <ref type="table">Table 2 presents</ref>  Cohen's d is a measure of the effect size of a statistical test, which indicates the magnitude of the difference between two groups <ref type="bibr">(Cohen, 1988)</ref>. In this study, the results of   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trajectory Response Time distributions and Cohen's d Effect Sizes Between Block Conditions</head><p>A B</p><p>Note: Correlations and effect sizes from trajectory indices. Panel A is the is the distribution of response times divided by block conditions with the means labeled for conveience. Panel B is the Cohen's d (standardized difference between two means) effect size and 99% confidence interval graphed for each variable from the standard trajectory classification indices. The three classification divisions are (from top to bottom by the breaks) curvature, complexity, and temporal dimensions of the trajectories. MAD is maximum average deviation from the ideal path, MDabove is the maximum deviation above the ideal path. AD is average deviation. AUC is area under the curve. Flips refers to x-position changes of direction as do reversals. RT is response time, initiation time is the time spent on the fixation square, motor pauses are times when movement stopped, and movement is the entire time in-flight without pauses of initiation time included.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Question Three</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Visualizing Trajectory Data</head><p>The analysis of trajectory data can be enhanced by normalizing the trajectory paths and comparing the average position for each condition along each resampled step. Normalization procedures allow for the comparison of cognitive processing without the need for consistent response times across all examined finger trajectories. There are two types of normalization that can be utilized: time and spatial normalization.</p><p>The assumption behind normalization is that regardless of the speed of response, there are stages of processing evident in trajectory data that can be inferred by examining the trace processes recorded during individual trials.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IAT Trajectory Averages between Compatible/Incompatible Block Conditions</head><p>Note: The figure displays the results for compatible/incompatible block condition averages and individual trial data superimposed under the averages, the graph is colored across conditions with black corresponding to compatible blocks (Insect/Unpleasant -Flower/Pleasant) and yellow corresponds to incompatible blocks (Flower/Unpleasant -Insect Pleasant). The length normalized trajectories are presented across all trials and averaged by block condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spatio-temporal Analysis</head><p>The data presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref> reveal average trajectory patterns for velocity, x-position and angle relative to the y-axis while participants navigate towards a final answer selection.</p><p>These patterns were analyzed to identify a difference in attraction to competing categorizations.</p><p>Significance testing was conducted on the differences in average trajectories at each time step.  In the x-position relative to the horizontal axis analysis, significant effects between timesteps 36-100 post stimuli presentation are immediately apparent <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 4</ref> Panel B). The incompatible conditions display a stronger divergence towards the alternative answer evidenced by x-position significant effects for the duration of the trajectory averages. Alternatively, compatible blocks keep a rather straight trajectory until a deicison has been made. The traditional IAT reaction time paradigm involves averaging the response time data between blocks for individual participants, then reporting a difference score to summarize the entire data set with a single number. Here a similar approach was taken when testing across participants using a mixed models design that emulates the within participant aspect, and then tests the average trajectories with a unique intercept for each individual contribution. Contrary to D-score reporting with Finger Tracking data the graph serves to visually demonstrate regions of significant differences during categorical sorting. The significance stars represent a p&lt;0.01 probability that the difference between the compatible and incompatible block conditions is not due to random chance at the specified time step for all three dimensions of interest.</p><p>The angle relative to the y-axis, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref> panel B, reveals an important aspect of the evolution of decision-making processes. Specifically, significant differences start between timesteps 66-85 illustrate the average number of timesteps during which deliberation and a commitment to an answer is made. The processing analysis is buttressed by the velocity profiles which evidence a velocity increase slightly later than the angle averages and convege in agreement in that both graphs evidence earlier decisions for compatible blocks and later answer comitment for incompatible blocks. Individual timestep differences are not meaningful on their own but a series of significant differences between many timesteps across multiple metrics provides compelling evidence. The FT-IAT allows for a spatio-temporal analysis of differences in the average cognitive complexity involved during in-flight decision-making and extends previous IAT methods in exciting new ways. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trajectory Velocity, X-position and Angle Analysis Compared Between Block Conditions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A B C</head><p>Note: For each panel the light cloud of data represents each individual trial while the dark lines represent averages between block conditions. Panel A is the velocity profile for average responses. Panel B is position relative to the horizontal axis with average responses. Panel C is the angle relative to the vertical axis with average responses. All data is visualized and tested using time normalized trajectories with 101 steps across all trials. The significant difference stars across the top represent 99% confidence mixed models repeated tests between the trajectory averages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>The IAT has garnered significant attention and popularity as a tool for measuring implicit social cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(De Houwer, Teige-Mocigemba, Spruyt &amp; Moors, 2009)</ref>. However, there remains debate about its ability to accurately assess individuals rather than simply gauging group attitudes at the aggregate level <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Payne, Vuletich &amp; Lundberg, 2017)</ref>. Administering the IAT multiple times with similar contexts over a period of time holds promise for evaluating individual bias using latency-based methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Nosek, Greenwald &amp; Banaji, 2007)</ref>. Current forms of the IAT make it difficult to ascertain exactly what is being measured, even if most agree that the measurment is meaningful.</p><p>IAT literature has explored various aspects of RT-based IAT procedures. This paper proposes an advancement of the IAT paradigm that lends itself to a scalable touchscreen version of IAT administration. Given the widespread availability of smartphones and tablets it is attractive to go beyond the keyboard or tapping a screen and instead collect rich processing data relevant to IAT mechanism. The traditional IAT paradigm can be extended and the data that can be collected is significantly expanded through this emerging FT approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Stillman, Shen &amp; Ferguson, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>The IAT is a widely used procedure that relies on difference scores to measure the reaction time between compatible and incompatible conditions, with the goal of quantifying an individual's implicit cognition by comparison. However, the reliance on RT as a metric has limitations, as it only provides an endpoint-oriented approach to understanding cognitive processes and is ignorant of the speed-accuracy interactions happening during decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Draheim, Mashburn, Martin &amp; Engle, 2019)</ref>. RT measures only provide a snapshot of cognitive processes at a specific endpoint but do not offer a comprehensive understanding of the processes leading up to that point.</p><p>In Research Question One, three novel difference score metrics are proposed that utilize The importance of measuring the relationships between categories and their individual strengths cannot be overstated. As the Implicit Association Test gained popularity it was implemented in various professional settings, such as business training and legal proceedings.</p><p>However, this widespread adoption may have occurred before the IAT was adequately validated for mainstream use <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Blanton, et al., 2009)</ref>. There is now substantial evidence supporting the concept of "bias of the crowd," <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Payne, Vuletich &amp; Lundberg, 2017)</ref> which posits that IAT results can be seen as a measure of cultural and institutional perceptions that are contextually endorsed by individuals that have been socialized in expectation filled environments. The theory also gives weight to the need for contextually sensitive measures of bias that can track changes over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Jost, 2019)</ref>. Given the current social and political divisions being promoted through social and mainstream media, it is important to have methods for accurately measuring the implicit cognitive effects of these divisions.</p><p>As issues of educational equity gain greater attention and influence on funding decisions, it is crucial to understand the cognitive biases present within institutions and individuals who hold positions of power. The biases and effects connected to racial differences within law enforcement have been extensively documented using IAT literature as evidence (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Joy, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Knight, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Menifield, Shin &amp; Strother, 2019)</ref>. Regardless of how it is measured it is clear these biases can have detrimental effects on the lives of systemically oppressed demographic groups.</p><p>It is important to note that the existing Implicit Association Test is not a definitive method for determining secret cognitive states. However, there is substantial evidence indicating that reliable assessment of an individual's cognitive strength of association can have implications that should be better understood. The findings presented here suggest that IAT research can be further enhanced by analyzing in-flight processing. With the potential leading to a new era of bias research conducted in real-life situations and utilizing the convenience of repeated testing on touchscreen devices that are commonly carried by individuals. With a step forward by presenting the FT-IAT along with the additional methods suggested in paper three of this dissertation, there is substantial evidence to suggest meaningful individual measures of bias that can be tracked over time, discussed more openly, and used to track change efforts within social systems that may harbor bias or unintentionally propagate inequity through culture.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations</head><p>One of the most obvious limitations of this study is the sample size at N=18. While the large number of trials in each block condition alleviate much of the worries about power in the experiment. At this early pilot stage each finding should be considered relative to the internal findings within the study. Metanalytic techniques over a range of similar studies is the only way to make conclusive generalizations about the power to detect bias with Finger Tracking.</p><p>Another limitation is the nature of online data collection. If you assume the IAT is a contextually relevant tool for measuring bias, then the context where the test is taken becomes vitally important. The upside is that context specific data collection can be facilitated online and school settings are a perfect home for the methods introduced here and change efforts are plentiful in educational settings.</p><p>The Flower/Insect IAT is of little consequence to most people other than methodologists, the understated manner in which a methodology pilot is presented may not serve to properly underscore the implications of Finger Tracking on psychology research. A program that introduces these methods with constructs of greater consequence and is able to show convergent evidence of the utility of the evidence will be necessary to get these methods into the spotlight, a job for future researchers to take on.</p><p>Limiting analysis to whole trial indices left much of the data available from the FT-IAT untouched. Future research in the field of Finger Tracking may examine the relationships between time scale markers by analyzing across various both time and movement indicators. The analysis here was restricted to whole trial indices as a choice to follow the analogy of RT. By examining point estimates from Finger Tracking data,researchers may be able to determine the cognitive complexity for individuals on a trial-specific level. There remains much to be learned by analyzing evidence of cognitive events such as the precise behaviors and timing of decision making. This topic, while beyond the scope of this study, holds significant potential for discovery and warrants further investigation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Next Steps</head><p>Past research has identified the value of area under the curve to indicate response conflict <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Stillman, Shen &amp; Ferguson, 2018)</ref>; further research should explore the potential incorporation of classification indices into stable, individually relevant measures of implicit attitude endorsement that takes into account AUC, AD, RT, and movement. Additionally the point estimates may prove useful in similar calculations and statistical testing. It may also be beneficial to consider the impact of design and setting on the reliability of results as these are important factors in traditional IAT procedures and a topic of interest in Finger Tracking literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Jost, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Fazio, 2007</ref>). Ultimately, a robust d-score that incorporates multiple implicit measures is likely to exhibit the greatest stability across various implicit association tasks and be more individually relevant in terms of measuring individual strengths of association.</p><p>In order to optimize the reaction time algorithms for Finger Tracking, it is necessary to consider multiple trace-processes and their associated metrics. Future research could examine repeated testing for individuals to gain a deeper understanding of how intra-individual variability influences trajectory paths. A look at time locked stimuli with collaboration between various cognitive disciplines will be crucial in using these methds to differntiate individual behavior in a systematic way.</p><p>Finger tracking is just one aspect of behavior that can be examined during decision making, while the integration of other methods such as eye tracking, facial tracking, skin conductance, movement tracking, EEG, and fMRI could provide a more comprehensive understanding of behavior. Advances in technology combined with new theories, have the potential to revolutionize the field of behavioral neuroscience and enhance educational change efforts. However, it should be noted that these methods are still in the developmental stages and it will take sustained interest as well as funding to refine these new methods for practical and mainstream implementation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Finger tracking has potential to offer valuable insights into an individual's implicit cognitive makeup through the use of indirect or more direct tasks in a readily available smartphone or tablet environment. Depending on the nature of the questions and the frequency of administration, new measures can provide insight into near real-time changes in an individual's concept availability. The addition of these trajectory curves into psychology research can serve as a useful tool in continuing the search for a reliable measure of individual unconscious bias.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Table 1............................................................................................................................. 37Figure 2............................................................................................................................39</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>...........................................................................................................................41 Spatio-temporal Analysis...................................................................................................41</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>...........................................................................................................................44 General Discussion.......................................................................................................................44 Limitations............................................................................................................................... 48 Next Steps.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>References..................................................................................................................................... 51 Appendix.................................................................................................................................... 57 Appendix M............................................................................................................................57</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>First</head><label></label><figDesc>d-scores are derived from each of the whole trial classification indices and compared to response time in direction and magnitude. Next, a split-half correlation is performed to test the relative strength of each metric compared to response time D-scores. These are methodological approaches to extend the available utility of IAT procedures and leave the arguments about what the use of implicit measures means to theorists (Oswald, Mitchell, Blanton, Jaccard &amp; Tetlock, 2013).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>response latencies, researchers infer underlying strengths of association. The IAT's technique involves averaging and comparing response latency differences between pairings to create a D-score thought to assess the strength of the subject's comparative association of the target concepts with each attribute pairing. Since its online proliferation IATs have gained considerable attention and widespread use as a measurement tool for assessing implicit social cognition (De Houwer, Teige-Mocigemba, Spruyt &amp; Moors, 2009).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, looked at inflight changes during cascading cognitive primes presented as arrows on the screen. Through analyzing finger trajectories in-flight researchers were able to show strong correlations between processing stages reflected in finger movements, and the time-locked stimuli that prompted them. A key takeaway is that FT methods are viable, scalable, and more easily used than traditional cost prohibitive and machinery intensive methods such as Eye Tracking or EEG. Dotan, Pinheiro-Chagas, Roumi &amp; Dehaene (2019) noted that there are various possibilities for expanding on the uses of these methods, the present goal of this forthcoming study. Work done within a mouse-tracking paradigm paved the way for analysis of Finger Tracking data (e.g. Wulff, Haslbeck, Kieslich, Henninger &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2019).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Freeman</head><label></label><figDesc>Records the frequency at which a trajectory crosses the midline dividing the options.<ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Koop &amp; Johnson, 2013)</ref> Sample entropy Measure used with time series data to quantify the degree of self-similarity between trajectories.<ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dale et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Hehman et al. 2015)</ref> Temporal development indicesRTThe time recorded between trial onset and choice selection.<ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff et al. 2021)</ref> Initiation time Idle time prior to the first onset of movement.<ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dale et al., 2007;</ref>   Faulkenberry et al., 2015; with movement continuously ongoing, calculated by removing initiation and pause times from the total response time.<ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Cheng &amp; González-Vallejo, 2018)</ref> </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Finger Tracking as a research tool to supplement the data traditionally available using IAT methodology. Finger tracking provides additional measures of valence not available on traditional Implicit Association Tests, leaving room to expand on the limitations inherent in D-score analysis commonly used to evaluate IAT results. The IAT selected is a variant of a classic IAT norming device in which the category and attribute pairings are Flower/Insect and Like/Don't like, respectively. Evaluating the D-score is expanded on through applying various methods to examine the attitude valence clues associated with movement during the sorting process. Data analysis is covered in various ways including examining the internal consistency of the presented candidates for d-scores, examining differences between specific trial conditions on an aggregated basis, and examining the time scale evolution of those aggregated trajectories using velocity, angle, and x-position metrics. If there is evidence of heterogeneity in the data, I</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>understand ideas. Analysis by types is done by grouping responses into categorical divisions based on the shape of the trajectory. The shapes have been organized based on past trajectory research behavior and elected apriori. The D-score is a commonly calculated difference metric based on whole block response latencies. The classification indices represent continuous variables thought to be linked to behavior in ways that allow for statistical testing. When examining x-position, angle relative to y-axis, and velocity the interpretation is rather intuitive. A drift or sharp movement in the x-direction indicates a pull towards current answer preference.Changes of direction may indicate cognitive complexity or other deliberative processes, whereas consistent pull towards an answer can indicate salience during answer selection. The angle relative to y-axis analysis is similar but looks at the angle of trajectory, which can exist independently of position. Velocity decreases are used to sense hesitation while increases in velocity are thought to represent certainty. In other words, someone may pull towards an answer which can be indicated by x-position, periodically waver in angle of approach, indicating deliberative processes, and slow down or accelerate before or after these stages have been reached.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>results of IAT tasks. These indices include reaction time (RT), movement, area under the curve (AUC), and Average Deviation (AD), and they are meant to provide a comprehensive view of the participant's performance during the entire trial. Through the use of Finger Tracking (FT), it is possible to examine the relationships between these indices and the implicit measures obtained from IAT tasks. The method can provide insight into individual attitudes and biases, and can be used as a tool for measuring attitude valence.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Note: The asterisks (* and **) indicate the level of statistical significance, with * indicating p&lt;.05 and ** indicating p&lt;.01. The mean d-scores for each whole trial indices are D=-0.13 for RT, d=-0.20 for movement, d=-0.15 for AUC, d=-0.35 for AD. The measures of RT and AUC seem to be similar in magnitude, but the low correlation between the variables ( =-0.35) and the lack of 2 significance in the correlation suggest that this similarity in score is probably a coincidence and these constructs are likely distinct. Both movement and AD show significantly higher valence measures than RT or AUC, indicating that these non-standard measures of valence may have greater discriminative utility compared to traditional response time valence inferences.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Split-half reliability tests are commonly used to assess the internal validity of IAT tasks, they allow for the determination of whether similar results are obtained when half of the trials for each participant are sampled using various splitting algorithms. The approach used here involves examining the split-half reliability for each metric included in the d-score analysis, with the aim of identifying the most robust relative results within the relevant full-trial classification indices.While split-half reliability is typically only assessed using Reaction Time (the metric used to calculate traditional D-scores), the other classification indices are compared to Response Time reliability in a relative sense to gauge their comparative strength within this data set. The distinction between reaction/response times is simple, when recording reaction time it is the only time point available, with Finger Tracking the data tracks a response en route and the final time is less meaningful compared to other metrics.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>2</head><label></label><figDesc>It is worth examining the relationships in the split-half correlation by comparing the relative strength of the associations. While the RT reliability measure is low by IAT standards, an acceptable split-half reliability is generally considered to be between 0.7 and 0.9, the closely related movement metric falls marginally close to the acceptable range for traditional IAT-style tasks. This suggests that the movement metric may be a suitable alternative to RT for scoring iterations of FT-IAT tasks using the D-score algorithm. AD appears to have a stronger internal consistency than either RT or AUC, and may be the most promising option for incorporating spatial trajectory indices into novel d-score calculations for IAT-style tasks. It may be beneficial for future researchers to consider developing an algorithm that averages across multiple indexed dimensions in order to provide a more robust and individually relevant measure of wholistic d-score findings. Such an approach may serve to strengthen both interpretation and statistical significance when establishing personal attitude valence. In addition, there is no reason point estimates cannot be evaluated for d-scores and an internal consistency in the manners presented.Findings suggest that d-score approaches that utilize Finger Tracking may serve as stronger indicators of valence than traditional D-score analysis of reaction time. Additionally if it</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a summary of the analysis, displaying both reaction time distributions and Cohen's d analysis contrasting compatible and incompatible block conditions. The effect sizes are considered low by Finger Tracking standards, but effects on pilot work are not expected to provide all the answers, these effect sizes are best interpreted by comparing against each other in a relative sense as a baseline for future refinement.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Cohen's d calculations reveal that certain classification indices such as Average Deviation(AD)    and Movement, demonstrate strong implicit cognitive effects between the compatible/incompatible block conditions. AUC displays a moderate IAT effect while sample entropy, and RT show negligible effects. It is worth noting that these results should be interpreted with caution, as this is a pilot study with a small robust sample of trajectories and not a systematic random sampling; the focus should remain on the relative strength of effects between available indices rather than the exact effect size. The rest of the classification indices inFigure 2Panel B are point estimates or values with no significant observable effect.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>two shows that AD and Movement had stronger IAT effect sizes than the traditional Response Time (RT) measure used in IAT research. Given these findings, it is suggested that Absolute Deviation has the potential to supplement RT as a spatial implicit measure of d-score in IAT tasks that utilize spatial index values. Further research may be necessary to explore the feasibility of improving the strength of these effect sizes through future design iterations. For ease of interpretation, it would be attractive to combine the whole trial trajectory indices into a single cohesive and robust measure of personal cognitive bias on future FT-IAT tasks.At this point an unexpected and convergent finding is present in this particular dataset when compared to prior research on the behavior of Cohen's d effects. Specifically, the comparison of RT and movement shows a stronger effect for movement in investigation one and two between incompatible and compatible trials. Based on these results and the relatively high split-half correlation results, it appears that the movement variable may be a more useful metric for basing d-scores and more desirable than using traditional RT when implementing FT-IATs. It is likely that this particular paradigm, which includes a dynamic start, is more sensitive to movement than response time in assessing categorical valence.Similarly the relative relationship between curvature indices indicates that AD is a strong contender for spatially derived d-scores to quantify FT-IAT findings. Future work should continue to report D-scores for comparison across paradigms, but movement and AD d-scores are the best contenders for reliable assessment of FT based implicit attitudes with this data set.The exact interpretation of each of these metrics will depends on the goals of the theorists, but the methods presented here are reproducible on a variety of existing IAT tasks and readily translated to the FT paradigm.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3displays a comparison of block conditions for all IAT trial data collected. The length-normalized (x, y) trajectory paths are visualized to help aide in understanding the analysis of specific facets of the trjaectory pathways, namely, velocity, x-position, and angle relative to the y-axis. The overlaid averages suggest a difference effect across conditions. It is often easy to identify which conditions are driving the observed effects with Finger Tracking visualizations, an advantage over the often opaque D-score values reported on traditional IAT research.It is clear from the visuals presented inFigure 3that significant differences in participant behavioral responses are present between compatible and incompatible trials. In order to determine statistical significance and further examine the decision-making process with significance tests performed on the velocity, x-position and angle dimensions of the trajectories. While the visualizations are useful in identifying areas of interest, they do not directly provide a format for statistical analysis. Visualizing the trajectories is a valuable tool in communicating the results of Finger Tracking research.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The results of this analysis indicate the regions of interest that contribute to the processing differences observed in the average trajectories during categorization. Long strings of significance indicate regions of interest, while single points of significant difference mean little.The mixed model approach used for this analysis accounted for individual participant intercepts and the repeated testing inherent in the trajectory indices with significance testing conducted at the p=0.01 significance level. Finger tracking allows for a deeper examination of the real-time processing data in the IAT paradigm, beyond the established D-score analysis, which supplies a single number meant to compare compatible and incompatible trial response times. The traditional approach allows for the identification of differential effects between block conditions to derive a difference score.The approach is reimagined with the rich data available with Finger Tracking, mixed models testing displayed inFigure 4showns that there are significant differences in velocity,x-position and angle relative to the y-axis. This method helps to identify where the FT-IAT effects are present across relevant regions of time-normalized trajectory paths. The range of significance stars observed across block differences suggests group differences exist in behavior independent of difference scores. The regions of significant differences can be interpreted as evidence of an increase in cognitive complexity between block conditions, or as evidence of implicit bias between available target category attribute pairings.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Figure 4 ,</head><label>4</label><figDesc>panel A illustrates evidence to support a rapid detection of block condition effects at the beginning of trials. The significant differences present in the velocity curve prior to stimulus presentation at timesteps 3-14 indicates a behavioral preference to move more quickly in incompatible conditions evidencing a block compatibility bias is present before the target word is available for cognitive processing. The target word is presented at 25% of the screen space so differential effects before target word presentation are attributable to the early recognition of block conditions based on the displayed selection corners (seeFigure 1). The late velocity differences between timesteps 71-86 proceed generally after the deliberation evidence present in the angle relative to y-axis analysis inFigure 4panel C. Once deliberation is completed there is a surge towards the selected answer side which happens more quickly for compatible than incompatible block conditions, providing a quantitative spatial measure of bias indepdent of D-score methodology.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head>Finger</head><label></label><figDesc>Tracking classification indices and the same difference score algorithm used in the IAT.These new difference scores can be easily calculated using the FT-IAT, and offer a new cognitively linked behavioral measure of implicit cognition. The approach provides insights into cognitive familiarity between category/attribute pairings similar to the original IAT. In-flight processing analogies to D-score gives convergent evidence of IAT effects that can be analyzed for trends in larger scale research programs. RT-based difference scores like those used in the IAT have been central to many mental chronometry approaches like the Stroop test and the go/no-go task. However this proposed metrics offer a scalable and low-cost alternative for assessing implicit cognition with rich processing data recorded from the start of a trial until a final selection is made Three new approaches to d-score analysis, namely absolute deviation, movement, and area under the curve, have been proposed within the framework of the FT-IAT. These measures provide whole trial evaluations of deviation from an idealized path. While the utility of these d-scores in the assessment of cognitive bias has yet to be fully explored, each may offer unique insights into the strength of associations endorsed by individuals and provide a more more robust measure of bias when considered in conjunction. Further research is necessary to determine the specific meaning of these metrics in the context of individual cognition. However, it is clear that new approaches to understanding implicit bias warrant consideration in future research.Considering current evidence, Average Deviation<ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Koop &amp; Johnson, 2013</ref>) may be the most promising spatial variable for calculating individual d-scores from trajectory indices, as it demonstrates higher internal reliability and agrees with D-score direction and magnitude as an indication of bias on this data set. Additionally, the movement metric, which is closely related to response time D-score, has demonstrated high internal consistency through split-half corelations evidencing that movement may be a promising replacement for response time in future FT-IAT investigations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 0 .</head><label>0</label><figDesc>Trajectory indices definitions and source literature</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The current practices in use for analyzing Finger Tracking data have been outlined elsewhere by the creators of mousetrap, a proprietary package in the R programming language developed for mousetracking experiments<ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Wulff, Kieslich, Henninger, Haslbeck &amp; Schulte-Mecklenbeck, 2021)</ref>. The mousetrap environment makes available a culmination of many years of mousetracking methodology and is well suited to do finger tracking analysis. One common approach is to first assess the homogeneity of the data set. To determine if there is heterogeneous behavior, researchers often examine bimodality in trajectory indices and use difference heatmap plots to identify differences between experimental conditions. Bimodality tests are not the most robust statistical tests they can help identify which analysis approach to</figDesc><table /><note>take. If there is evidence of sample heterogeneity a trajectory types analysis can be conducted to see if the frequency of types varies significantly between conditions.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>ParticipantsA total of 73 responses were collected from a pilot survey by completing a Qualtrics questionnaire. After eliminating incomplete submissions and false start entries, a total of 22 participants completed useable data for the entire survey. Of these 22 participants, 14 completed , only two were left-handed reasoning that the balanced block design would mitigate any handedness effects. The focus of this investigation is on the results of the FT-IAT, as it had the highest sample size due to its block design.</figDesc><table /><note>a Big Five Personality Survey, 18 completed a Finger Tracking Implicit Association Test, and 15 completed a section on entomophobia. Out of the total pool of participants, only 8 completed usable data for analysis in all sections. Out of the 22 participants who completed the survey</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>All materials are on record with the Stanford IRB and the research is being conducted by two doctoral students in the Stanford Graduate School of Education.All participants completed the full set of IAT prompts in a single session, administered remotely via the online platform Qualtrics. The study utilized a touchscreen device and included three Finger Tracking tasks, two Likert-type surveys that paralleled the Finger Tracking procedures, and a brief demographic questionnaire, a common practice in research. The survey took approximately 30 minutes for each participant to complete. The survey items were administered using Qualtrics survey software, and the Finger Tracking tasks were coded by</figDesc><table><row><cell>Procedure</cell></row></table><note>Ethan Roy and integrated into the Qualtrics environment using Pavlovia (Sauter, Draschkow &amp; Mack, 2020).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Based on these results, we found no evidence of bimodality and therefore conclude that a types analysis is not likely to be appropriate for our data.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Since visual inspection gave cause for a test of bimodality, a check was performed on the</cell></row><row><cell>distribution of classification indices for evidence of bimodality. One commonly used method for</cell></row><row><cell>detecting bimodality is Hartigans' dip statistic, where a low value D between [0, 1) indicates</cell></row><row><cell>unimodality and significance is reported as a p-value. Applying Hartigans' dip statistic to test for</cell></row><row><cell>bimodality obtained the following results: for RT, D = 0.0084447, p-value = 0.4108; for</cell></row><row><cell>movement, D = 0.0048857, p-value = 0.9923; for AUC, D = 0.0045218, p-value = 0.9947; for</cell></row><row><cell>AD, D = 0.0047145, p-value = 0.9934.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Frequency Table of Types Analysis Between IAT Block Types</figDesc><table><row><cell>straight</cell><cell>curved</cell><cell>cCoM</cell><cell>dCoM</cell><cell></cell><cell>dCoM2</cell></row><row><cell>compatible</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>910</cell><cell>131</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>incompatible</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>844</cell><cell>173</cell><cell>52</cell><cell>2</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix M</head><p>Heatmap for visual examination of bimodality in trajectory indices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Difference Heat Maps Comparing IAT Conditions Across All Trials</head><p>Note: Areas in yellow are incompatible trials and blue are compatible. The white areas in the difference heatmap indicate no difference or no trajectories present.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strong claims and weak evidence: Reassessing the predictive validity of the IAT</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Blanton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jaccard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Klick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mellers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of applied Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">567</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The physics of optimal decision making: a formal analysis of models of performance in two-alternative forced-choice tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Moehlis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">700</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lies, damned lies, and survey self-reports? Identity as a cause of measurement bias</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Brenner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Delamater</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social psychology quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive and neural bases of multi-attribute, multi-alternative, value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unpacking decision difficulty: Testing action dynamics in intertemporal, gamble, and consumer choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>González-Vallejo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">190</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding process tracing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Collier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PS: Political Science &amp; Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="823" to="830" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Track it to crack it: dissecting processing stages with Finger Tracking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dotan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pinheiro-Chagas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Al Roumi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dehaene</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1058" to="1070" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The elements of statistical learning. Springer series in statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hastie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Tibshirani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The cognitive dynamics of negated sentence verification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Duran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="983" to="996" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Graded motor responses in the time course of categorizing atypical exemplars</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kehoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Spivey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implicit measures: A normative analysis and review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>De Houwer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Teige-Mocigemba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Spruyt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moors</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">347</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reaction time in differential and developmental research: A review and commentary on the problems and alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Draheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mashburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Engle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">145</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">508</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Towards a reconsideration of the use of agree-disagree questions in measuring subjective evaluations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dykema</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schaeffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Garbarski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Assad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Blixt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Research in Social and Administrative Pharmacy</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tracking the continuous dynamics of numerical processing: A brief review and editorial</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Faulkenberry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Witte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Numerical Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Implicit measures in social cognition research: Their meaning and use. Annual review of psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Fazio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Olson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="327" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Abrupt category shifts during real-time person perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="92" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MouseTracker: Software for studying real-time mental processing using a computer mouse-tracking method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ambady</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Behavior research methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="226" to="241" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A very brief measure of the Big-Five personality domains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gosling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Rentfrow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Swann</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="504" to="528" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implicit social cognition: attitudes, self-esteem, and stereotypes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Banaji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring individual differences in implicit cognition: the implicit association test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mcghee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1464</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Health of the Implicit Association Test at age 3</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nosek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advanced mouse-tracking analytic techniques for enhancing psychological science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hehman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Stolier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Group Processes &amp; Intergroup Relations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="384" to="401" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive tutoring induces widespread neuroplasticity and remediates brain function in children with mathematical learning disabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Iuculano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rosenberg-Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tenison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fuchs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Supekar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Menon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The IAT is dead, long live the IAT: Context-sensitive measures of implicit attitudes are indispensable to social and political psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Jost</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Race matters in jury selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Joy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nw. UL Rev. Online</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">180</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mousetrap: An integrated, open-source mouse-tracking package</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kieslich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Henninger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior research methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1652" to="1667" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kieslich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Henninger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Wulff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Haslbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schulte-Mecklenbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mouse-tracking: A practical guide to implementation and analysis 1</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A handbook of process tracing methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="130" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive conflict in social dilemmas: An analysis of response dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kieslich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hilbig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="510" to="522" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Justice is not blind: The role of race in law enforcement decisions and practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Michigan</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The response dynamics of preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Koop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using mouse tracking to examine the time course of an auditory lexical decision task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Krestar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Incera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mclennan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ohio Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">29</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information-accumulation theory of speeded categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lamberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">227</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A technique for the measurement of attitudes. Archives of psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Likert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1932" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Doing arithmetic by hand: Hand movements during exact arithmetic reveal systematic, dynamic spatial processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Marghetis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Núñez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Bergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1579" to="1596" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intra-individual variability in behavior: links to brain structure, neurotransmission and neuronal activity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Nyberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bäckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in neurosciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="480" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do white law enforcement officers target minority suspects?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Menifield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Strother</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Public Administration Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="68" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The detection of faked identity using unexpected questions and mouse dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Monaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gamberini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sartori</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">177851</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Telling more than we can know: Verbal reports on mental processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nisbett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">231</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Likert scales, levels of measurement and the &quot;laws&quot; of statistics. Advances in health sciences education</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="632" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The go/no-go association task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nosek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Banaji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="666" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Implicit Association Test at age 7: A methodological and conceptual review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nosek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenwald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Banaji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Automatic processes in social thinking and behavior</title>
		<editor>J. A. Bargh</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="292" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The bias of crowds: How implicit bias bridges personal and systemic prejudice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Vuletich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lundberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="248" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Good things peak in pairs: a note on the bimodality coefficient</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pfister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Janczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">700</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of self-reported and device measured sedentary behaviour in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Prince</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cardilli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Douillette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing questions with agree/disagree response options to questions with construct-specific response options</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Saris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Revilla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Krosnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Shaeffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18148/srm/2010.v4i1.2682</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Survey Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stuck at the starting line: How the starting procedure influences mouse-tracking data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Scherbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kieslich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2097" to="2110" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Vigor: Neuroeconomics of movement control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shadmehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does the Implicit Association Test for assessing anxiety measure trait and state variance?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schmukle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Egloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="483" to="494" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hidden cognitive states revealed in choice reaching tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Nakayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="360" to="366" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do curved reaching movements emerge from competing perceptions? A reply to van der</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Spivey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Knoblich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grosjean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<editor>Wel et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="254" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Continuous attraction toward phonological competitors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Spivey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grosjean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Knoblich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10393" to="10398" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How mouse-tracking can advance social cognitive theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="543" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">RStudio: Integrated Development for</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Rstudio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pbc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Boston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Url</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.rstudio.com/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Van Der Wel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Eder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Mitchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trajectories emerging from discrete versus continuous processing models in phonological competitor tasks: a commentary on Spivey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Knoblich</forename><surname>Grosjean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Wulff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Haslbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kieslich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Henninger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schulte-Mecklenbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mouse-tracking: Detecting types in movement trajectories</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A Handbook of process tracing methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="145" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Movement tracking of cognitive processes: A tutorial using mousetrap</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Wulff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kieslich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Henninger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M B</forename><surname>Haslbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schulte-Mecklenbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/v685r</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/v685r" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond reaction times: Incorporating mouse-tracking measures into the implicit association test to examine its underlying process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bastin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="289" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
