<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Likelihood Difference Heuristic and Binary Test Selection Given Situation-Specific Utilities</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2021-10-14">October 14, 2021</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson $</surname></persName>
							<email>jonathan.d.nelson@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Surrey</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Guildford</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Rosenauer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincenzo</forename><surname>Crupi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Turin</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig Maximilians University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katya</forename><surname>Tentori</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Trento</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Björn</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="institution">Health and Medical University Potsdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Surrey</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>GU2 7XH</postCode>
									<settlement>Guildford</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Likelihood Difference Heuristic and Binary Test Selection Given Situation-Specific Utilities</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2021-10-14">October 14, 2021</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">Preprint submitted to Decision</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:20+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>likelihood difference heuristic</term>
					<term>medical decision making</term>
					<term>information search</term>
					<term>diagnosis</term>
					<term>payoffs</term>
					<term>utilities</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Consider the task of selecting a medical test to determine whether a patient has a particular disease. Normatively, this requires taking into account (i) the prior probability of the disease, (ii) the likelihoodfor each available test-of obtaining a positive result if the medical condition is present or absent, respectively, and (iii) the utilities for both correct and incorrect treatment decisions based upon each possible test result. But these quantities may not be precisely known. Are there strategies that could help identify the test with the highest utility given incomplete information? Here we consider the Likelihood Difference Heuristic (LDH), a simple heuristic that selects the test with the highest difference between the likelihood of obtaining a true positive and a false positive test result, ignoring all other information. We prove that the LDH is optimal when the probability of the disease equals the therapeutic threshold, the probability for which treating the patient and not treating the patient have the same expected utility. By contrast, prominent models of the value of information from the literature, such as information gain, probability gain, and Bayesian diagnosticity, are not optimal under these circumstances. Further results show how, depending on the relationship of the therapeutic threshold and prior probability of the disease, it is possible to determine which likelihoods are more important for assessing tests&apos; expected utilities. Finally, to illustrate the potential relevance for real-life contexts, we show how the LDH might be applied to choosing tests for screening of latent tuberculosis infection.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">The Likelihood Difference Heuristic and Binary Test Selection Given Situation-Specific</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Utilities</head><p>In medical diagnosis, as in many other domains, it is rarely possible to obtain all potentially-relevant information before deciding what course of action to take. Nonetheless, a limited number of carefully chosen tests can greatly facilitate diagnosis and treatment. But how should these tests be selected? When the relevant probabilities and utilities (i.e., benefits and harms of diagnostic decisions associated with tests' outcomes) are fully known, the utility-maximizing test can be determined using Bayesian decision theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(Savage, 1954)</ref>. Outcome-based (or situation-specific) utility functions measure the extent to which an agent values the outcomes of actions, for instance the benefits and harms associated with correct and incorrect treatment decisions. In practice, such utility functions can be derived from objective measures (e.g., monetary costs), subjective measures (e.g., side effects experienced by a patient, or treatment benefits and harms as judged by doctors; <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Christensen-Szalanski &amp; Bushyhead, 1981)</ref>, or a mix of both (e.g., quality-adjusted life years; <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">Weinstein, Torrance, &amp; McGuire, 2009)</ref>. In this article, when we speak of utilities, unless denoted otherwise we mean such outcome-based, non-informational, utilities.</p><p>Accordingly, the expected utility gain of a test refers to the average improvement in non-informational outcome-based utility. The best test is defined as the test that among available tests maximizes expected utility gain, given the applicable utility function.</p><p>While mathematically straightforward, this kind of analysis faces two challenges in real diagnostic situations. First, from a descriptive point of view, people may have difficulty weighting all probabilities and utilities and acting accordingly. This raises the question of how people intuitively evaluate tests, and to what extent their test selection strategies are sensitive to normative principles. Second, a precise quantification of appropriate utility functions is often challenging. Difficulties include measurement issues and comparability of subjective valuations, incommensurability of different metrics, and diverging views on treatment benefits and harms among multiple stakeholders (e.g., patients, health care providers, policy makers). Thus, attempts to derive appropriate utilities for evaluating medical tests are both important and notoriously difficult.</p><p>One proposal to circumvent these difficulties is to evaluate medical tests using epistemic (or pure information) utility functions <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Benish, 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Benish, , 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Good &amp; Card, 1971)</ref>. Such utility functions are also sometimes called Optimal Experimental Design (OED, <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Nelson, 2005)</ref> or Optimal Data Selection <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Oaksford &amp; Chater, 1994)</ref> models of the value of information. Epistemic utility functions consider the probabilities of diseases and test outcomes, but disregard any further utilities associated with subsequent treatment decisions. Within this perspective, test selection should be determined solely by tests' ability to reduce epistemic uncertainty about the true state of nature, such as whether a patient has a particular medical condition or not. Information gain <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Lindley, 1956)</ref>, which is based on the expected reduction in <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Shannon (1948)</ref> entropy, Bayesian diagnosticity <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Good, 1950;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Good &amp; Card, 1971)</ref>, and probability gain <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Baron, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Baron, Beattie &amp; Hershey, 1988)</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Slowiaczek, Klayman, Sherman &amp; Skov, 1992)</ref>, a simple strategy that is applicable to the selection of binary tests (e.g., medical tests that can have only positive or negative outcomes) in a binary hypothesis space (e.g., disease vs. no disease, where the possible actions are to treat or not to treat the disease). The LDH requires only two pieces of information for each test, namely the likelihood that the test is positive when the disease is present (the true positive rate) and the likelihood that the test is positive when the disease is absent (the false positive rate). Both quantities are typically available for routine medical tests. The LDH then deterministically selects the test with the highest likelihood difference, ignoring any further available information, a feature shared with other heuristics from the judgment and decision making literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Gigerenzer &amp; Gaissmaier, 2011)</ref>. Because of its simplicity, the LDH can be used even when the prior probability of the disease or the outcome-based utilities are completely unknown. Of course, the fact that the LDH can be used does not demonstrate that the LDH-or any heuristic-would be sensible to use in any particular test-selection situation. Theoretical analyses <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Nelson, 2005)</ref> show that the LDH invariably selects tests in accordance with impact, an epistemic utility function that quantifies belief change as the average absolute difference from prior to posterior probabilities. However, the LDH has not yet been studied with respect to outcome-based utility functions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">Human Inquiry and Test Selection</head><p>Carefully deciding which information to acquire is a central ability in many domains. Early research on how humans intuitively select queries was inspired by <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Popper's (1959)</ref> philosophy of science and the idea that one should seek out potentially disconfirming evidence <ref type="bibr">(Wason, 1960</ref><ref type="bibr">(Wason, , 1968</ref>. More recent approaches conceptualize human query selection as probabilistic inductive inference, where the goal is not to obtain potentially disconfirming information for a single hypothesis, but rather to acquire information in order to discriminate among multiple hypotheses <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Coenen et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Crupi et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr"></ref> Gureckis <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Meder et al., 2021)</ref>. This approach, sometimes referred to as the Optimal Experimental Design (OED) framework, has theoretical roots in <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Chamberlin's (1890)</ref> Method of Multiple Working Hypotheses, with instantiations in information theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">(Shannon, 1948;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Lindley, 1956)</ref>, Bayesian philosophy of science <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Good, 1950)</ref>, and automatic Bayesian experiment design <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Myung &amp; Pitt, 2009</ref>).</p><p>In the cognitive and decision sciences, OED models are widely used as normative benchmarks against which human information acquisition can be considered. Domains studied include hypothesis testing <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Austerweil &amp; Griffiths, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Crupi et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Oaksford &amp; Chater, 1994)</ref>; eye movements for perception <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Najemnik &amp; Geisler, 2005)</ref>, concept formation <ref type="bibr">(Nelson &amp; Cottrell, 2007)</ref>, and reading <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Legge et al., 1997)</ref>; categorization <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Markant &amp; Gureckis, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Nelson et al., 2010)</ref>; causal induction <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Bramley et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">Steyvers et al., 2003)</ref>; the neural value of obtained or expected information <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Filimon et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Nakamura, 2006)</ref>; eyewitness identification <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(Wells &amp; Lindsay, 1980)</ref>; medical diagnosis <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Baron, Beattie &amp; Hershey, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Benish, 1999)</ref>; and children's behavior on 20 questions games <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Meder et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Nelson et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Ruggeri et al., 2015)</ref>. Most of this work <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Coenen et al., 2019)</ref> suggests that at least to a first approximation, the OED framework provides a good basis for understanding human behavior. It is important to remember, however, that in all of the above tasks, the goals are purely epistemic, and the OED models employed disregard any benefits and costs associated with subsequent decisions based upon the obtained information. was used to convey the relevant probabilities. In a subsequent search phase, participants had to choose between two queries before making a categorization decision. Varying monetary rewards were associated with different kinds of correct classification decisions; for instance, a correct Category A classification may have been worth 10 times as much as a correct Category B classification. The test that maximized classification accuracy was in these cases different from the test that maximized average payoffs. Participants' test-selection strategies were influenced by the applicable payoffs during the learning phase.</p><p>However, if the payoffs were changed for the test phase, participants were not able to take this into account. Moreover, if probability information was conveyed using words and numbers, rather than experientially, neither utility gain nor probability gain could explain test-selection behavior. <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Markant and Gureckis (2012)</ref> also studied search under situation-specific reward conditions, where participants had to identify different shapes on a game board by sampling targets on a grid. Their task involved both test costs (i.e., sampling itself was costly) and costs for specific kinds of errors. The task was designed in such a way that there was a conflict between obtaining information to minimize overall costs and selecting queries in accordance with information gain. In two experiments, searchers' behavior was better accounted for by information gain than utility gain, lending support to the hypothesis that people often focus on reducing epistemic uncertainty even if situation-specific utilities apply. Thus, the psychological literature to date, sparse though it is, suggests that people have at best very limited ability to use task-specific payoff structures into account when choosing which tests to conduct.</p><p>The LDH, known also as the feature-difference heuristic, has to our knowledge not yet been studied, either theoretically or empirically, in medical test selection or other domains with outcome-based utilities.</p><p>However, behaviors consistent with the LDH have been reported in various experimental tasks with purely epistemic goals. One such task is the Planet Vuma scenario, in which participants have to rate the usefulness of a set of binary-outcome features in order to categorize fictitious aliens into one of two species <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Nelson, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Skov &amp; Sherman, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Slowiaczek, Klayman, Sherman &amp; Skov, 1992)</ref>. Another task involves more naturalistic crime scenarios, in which participants select one of two queries they find most useful for an investigation <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Liefgreen, Pilditch &amp; Lagnado, 2020)</ref>.</p><p>The use of likelihood subtraction has also been documented in the literature on belief revision.</p><p>In particular, it is a non-normative strategy that can lead to base-rate neglect (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Gigerenzer &amp; Hoffrage, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">McDowell, Galesic, &amp; Gigerenzer, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Domurat, Kowalczuk, Idzikowska, Borzymowska, &amp; Nowak-Przygodzka, 2015)</ref>. Both laypeople and physicians have been reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hoffrage &amp; Gigerenzer, 1998)</ref> to estimate the positive predictive value of diagnostic problems by computing the difference between the sensitivity of a test, P (e|h), and the false-positive rate of the test, P (e|¬h). The likelihood subtraction algorithm is also a prominent model in covariation assessment (often referred to as ∆P model), both in the Bayesian confirmation framework, where it represents a specific measure of evidential support <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Nozick, 1981)</ref>, and in the causal induction literature, where it corresponds to the probabilistic contrast model <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Cheng &amp; Novick, 1990</ref>).</p><p>To summarize, use of likelihood differences have been observed in empirical research on test selection, belief updating, covariation assessment, and causal induction. This suggests that the likelihood difference is a signal that people could use in a wide range of circumstances. In this article we explore the circumstances, in situations with outcome-based payoff utilities, under which it could be sensible (or not) to use the LDH when choosing among binary tests to conduct.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">Goals and Scope</head><p>We provide a formal analysis of the LDH as a strategy for selecting tests in situations where outcomebased utilities apply (e.g., medical diagnosis). We focus on the simplest-possible test selection scenario, which is characterized by the option to conduct one binary test (i.e. a test that will have a negative or positive result), after which it is necessary to decide which course of action to take (i.e., to treat a patient or not). We use a simple medical diagnosis scenario to explain our mathematical results. However, our results apply without loss of generality to all situations with binary tests, hypotheses, and decisions. An analogous situation would be deciding what piece of information is most important for deciding whether an accused person is guilty or not guilty, in criminal law.</p><p>Our analyses are based on mathematically well-defined probabilities and utilities. What utilities are appropriate for a given situation or for a particular person (e.g., a patient or a doctor) is an important question, but is not part of our analyses. Similarly, we will not take into account the costs of the tests per se, but only the outcome-based utilities resulting from correct or incorrect treatment decisions. Nor will we consider the implications of planning a sequence of tests, although the best first test in a sequence can be different from the best single test if just one test can be conducted <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Geman &amp; Jedynak, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Hyafil &amp; Rivest, 1976;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Meder et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Meier &amp; Blair, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Nelson et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>The rest of this paper is structured as follows.</p><p>• In Section 2 we introduce relevant definitions and illustrate how to compute a test's expected utility, given the applicable probabilities and utility function.</p><p>• In Section 3 we then show that an outcome-based utility function influences tests' relative utility only via a single number, the therapeutic threshold. Introduced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Pauker &amp; Kassirer (1975)</ref>, the therapeutic threshold is the probability of disease above which the best (utility-maximizing) course of action is to treat a patient, and below which the best course of action is not to treat.</p><p>• In Section 4 we analyze the LDH mathematically. We prove that, whenever there is maximal need for information, the LDH is guaranteed to select the test with the highest expected utility. The condition of maximal need for information applies when the probability of the disease equals the therapeutic threshold, such that a utility-maximizing decision maker would be indifferent among the available actions (i.e., to treat or not to treat). Further analyses apply to situations where the prior probability of disease and the therapeutic threshold are not equal. We show analytically that depending on whether the probability of disease is above or below the threshold, the utility of a test is either a function of the likelihood of obtaining a positive test result given the presence of the disease (the test's sensitivity) or of the likelihood of obtaining a negative test result given the absence of the disease (the test's specificity).</p><p>• In Section 5 we show via counterexamples and simulations that prominent OED models are suboptimal under conditions of maximal need for information. We also show that the LDH is reasonable to use somewhat beyond these conditions, given that its performance degrades only gradually as we move away from the situation where the prior probability of disease exactly matches the therapeutic threshold. Interestingly, the situations in which the LDH performs well highly overlap with situations in which the choice of test to conduct especially matters.</p><p>• In Section 6 we consider the LDH in the context of latent tuberculosis diagnosis. This allows us to show the potential relevance of the LDH to a real-life screening setting, as well as to discuss some limitations of our analyses.</p><p>• In Section 7 we conclude by highlighting key issues for future research on human information acquisition and test selection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Determining the Expected Utility Gain of a Test</head><p>We next define our terminology and describe how to calculate the expected utility gain of a test, that is, how much utility can be gained on average from carrying out the test, compared to making a treatment decision without conducting the test. This calculation is based on the prior probability of the disease and the test characteristics (i.e., likelihood of obtaining a positive test result, given that the disease is present or absent, respectively), as well as the applicable outcome-based utilities. We show that the utilities associated with different kinds of correct and incorrect decisions influence a test's expected utility gain only via a single number, the therapeutic threshold <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Pauker &amp; Kassirer, 1975)</ref>, the probability of disease above which it would be best to treat the patient, and below which it would be best to not treat the patient, if no further information could be acquired before deciding whether or not to treat. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> gives an overview of the terms and definitions that we use throughout this paper. We use the nomenclature of Bayesian decision theory, but related terms and concepts are used in other fields, in particular in the medical and Signal Detection Theory literature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Terminology</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Probability model</head><p>Let H = {h, ¬h} be a binary random variable (hypothesis space) associated with a particular disease, where h denotes the hypothesis that a person has the disease and ¬h denotes the hypothesis that she does not have the disease. The probability P (h) is the prior probability of the disease, with P (¬h) = 1 − P (h).</p><p>We assume that 0 &lt; P (h) &lt; 1, meaning that it is a priori uncertain whether the person has the disease or not. Another term from the medical literature is the pre-test probability, denoting the probability of disease before a test is conducted. A frequentist estimate for the prior probability of a disease, absent any individuating information for a particular patient, is the proportion of people in a given reference class that have the disease, often referred to as the disease's base rate or prevalence.</p><p>We use E = {e, ¬e} to denote a diagnostic test, another binary random variable. We only consider tests for which the outcome is probabilistic, i.e., 0 &lt; P (e) &lt; 1 and 0 &lt; P (¬e) &lt; 1, which means that there is some chance of a positive result and some chance of a negative result. In our scenario, e corresponds to a positive test result, and ¬e corresponds to a negative test result. The test results are labeled such that P (h|e) ≥ P (h) and P (h|¬e) ≤ P (h). In other words, a positive test result increases (or does not change) the probability of the disease while a negative test result decreases (or does not change) the probability of the disease. Thus we do allow for nondeterministic yet uninformative tests, for which no test result changes the probability of the disease. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Therapeutic threshold tx</head><p>Probability above which treating the patient has higher expected utility than not treating, given the applicable utility function Threshold probability, decision threshold</p><p>The conditional probabilities of test results e and ¬e under true states h and ¬h are the likelihoods.</p><p>The two likelihoods involving positive test results are P (e|h), the conditional probability of a positive test result given that the disease is present, and P (e|¬h), the conditional probability of a positive test result given that the disease is absent. Frequentist estimates of these probabilities are the proportion of people with a positive test result who indeed have the disease (true positive rate) and the proportion of people who have a positive test result but do not have the disease (false positive rate). In the medical literature, the true positive rate is often called the sensitivity of test E, sens(E).</p><p>The likelihoods involving negative test results are P (¬e|h), the conditional probability of a negative test result given that the disease is present, and P (¬e|¬h), the conditional probability of a negative test result given that the disease is absent. Frequentist estimates of these probabilities are the proportion of people with a negative test result who do have the disease (false negative rate), and the proportion of people without the disease who correctly obtain a negative test result (true negative rate), respectively.</p><p>In the medical literature, the true negative rate is often called the specificity of test E, spec(E).</p><p>If we administer a test E, we get a positive test result e with probability P (e) = P (h)P (e|h) + P (¬h)P (e|¬h), and a negative test result ¬e with probability P (¬e) = P (h)P (¬e|h) + P (¬h)P (¬e|¬h).</p><p>The posterior probability of disease given a positive test result, P (h|e), and the posterior probability of absence of disease given a negative test result, P (¬h|¬e), can be calculated using <ref type="bibr">Bayes's (1763</ref><ref type="bibr">Bayes's ( /1958</ref> theorem, i.e. P (h|e) = P (e|h)P (h)/P (e) and P (h|¬e) = P (¬e|h)P (h)/P (¬e). In frequentist terms, P (h|e) is the proportion of people with positive results that actually have the disease, and P (¬h|¬e) is the proportion of people with negative test results who do not have the disease. In the medical literature, P (h|e) is often called the positive predictive value, and P (¬h|¬e) the negative predictive value, of the test.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Utilities</head><p>In many real-world medical situations, in addition to administering a test and then updating the probability of the patient having the disease or not (i.e., computing the posterior probabilities of interest), a decision of whether or not to treat the patient has to be made. Such a decision should not depend on the probabilities alone, but also on the benefits and costs of the possible decisions, the outcome-based utilities. If we combine the two possible decisions, "treat" and "do not treat", with the two possible states, "disease present" and "disease absent", we have four different cases ( <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2)</ref>. The utility of a true positive outcome, u tp , is the utility of treating a patient who has the disease. The utility of a false positive outcome, u f p , refers to the consequences of treating a patient who does not have a disease. The utility of a false negative outcome, u f n , refers to the consequences of not treating a patient who has the disease. Finally, the utility of a true negative outcome, u tn , refers to the consequences of not treating a patient who does not have the disease.</p><p>In actual medical decision making, the numeric utilities should be based on things like the discomfort and harms caused by a disease, its individual and social consequences, costs of treatments, and distress associated with possible side effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Djulbegovic et al., 2015)</ref>. Thus, utilities can be positive or negative.</p><p>For instance, Christensen-Szalanski and Bushyhead (1981) asked physicians to estimate the utilities of </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Disease present Disease absent</head><p>Treat</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">u tp = 40 u f p = −26 Don't treat u f n = −22 u tn = 41</formula><p>each possible decision-outcome combination for the case of pneumonia, using a rating scale ranging from -50 (worst thing I could do) to +50 (best thing I could do). <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> gives the mean estimates.</p><p>These estimates illustrate specific relations among utility functions in medical contexts. Typically, if a patient does have the disease, treating the patient has a higher utility than not treating the patient (u tp &gt; u f n , e.g., 40 &gt; −22 in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>). Similarly, if a patient does not have the disease, not treating the patient typically has higher utility than treating the patient (u tn &gt; u f p , e.g., 41 &gt; −26 in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>).</p><p>Iff (if and only if) both these conditions (u tp &gt; u f n and u tn &gt; u f p ) hold, we will call a utility function</p><p>proper. If these conditions do not both hold, we will call a utility function improper. We will denote the utility function with a payoff matrix of the form u = utp u fp u fn utn , where the positioning of the utilities corresponds to the combination between the decision taken (treat or not treat) and the true state (disease or no disease) in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>. These ideas are graphically illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Utility Functions and the Therapeutic Threshold</head><p>The way in which utilities should affect behavior from a normative perspective has been studied in Bayesian decision theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(Savage, 1954)</ref>, medical decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Pauker &amp; Kassirer, 1975</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Djulbegovic et al., 2015)</ref> and Signal Detection Theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Green &amp; Swets, 1966;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Stanislaw &amp; Todorov, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Swets, 1992)</ref>. The best decision is typically defined as the decision that has the highest expected utility,</p><p>given the applicable utility function and the probability model (including the prior probabilities and any evidence that has been obtained). The expected utility of treating a patient is given by P (h)u tp + P (¬h)u fp , while the expected utility of not treating a patient is given by P (¬h)u tn + P (h)u f n . Note that they are both functions of P (h), which is the probability of the disease given everything known to date, including any prior test results. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1</ref> illustrates how various sets of underlying utility values lead to lines with the expected utility of treating or not treating, as a function of P (h).</p><p>The therapeutic threshold <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Pauker &amp; Kassirer, 1975</ref>), which we denote with t x , will be an important concept in subsequent analyses. It is the probability of disease for which treating the patient has the same expected utility as not treating the patient. If no further information could be obtained before deciding whether or not to treat the patient, the patient should be treated just in case the probability of disease is greater than t x . If the utility function is proper, then the therapeutic threshold t x can be identified by solving</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P (h)u tp + P (¬h)u f p = P (¬h)u tn + P (h)u f n<label>(1)</label></formula><p>for P (h), and setting the threshold t x to this value, namely to</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">t x = u tn − u fp (u tn − u fp ) + (u tp − u fn )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>But what if it is not known whether a given set of utility values constitutes a proper utility function?</p><p>To check whether a utility function is proper, the utility values can be plugged into the right side of </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Equation 2. If (u tn − u fp )/[(u tn − u fp ) + (u tp − u fn )] ≥ 1,</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5.">Expected Utility Gain of Tests</head><p>If the probabilities and utilities are given, then it is possible to calculate the expected utility gain of a test E, denoted eu(E). This is the expected utility associated with making the utility-maximizing decision after the test result is known, minus the prior utility that could be achieved on the basis of the prior probabilities and applicable utilities alone <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Meder &amp; Nelson, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Schlaifer &amp; Raiffa, 1961)</ref>.</p><p>Calculating eu(E) requires consideration of the utilities associated with the two possible test results. The utility of an individual test result, u(e) or u(¬e), is defined as the difference between the utility given the test result and the utility without the test result, assuming that the utility-maximizing decision (to treat or not to treat the patient) is taken in each case:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">u u tp u fp u fn u tn (e) =max[P (h|e)utp + P (¬h|e)u fp , P (¬h|e)utn + P (h|e)u fn ] − max[P (h)utp + P (¬h)u fp , P (¬h)utn + P (h)u fn ]<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The utility of a negative test result ¬e can be defined in the same way by replacing e with ¬e in Equation 3.</p><p>Accordingly, we can define the expected utility gain of Test E as the sum of the utilities of the possible test results e and ¬e, weighted by the probability of each respective test result:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">eu u tp u fp u fn u tn (E) = P (e)u u tp u fp u fn u tn (e) + P (¬e)u u tp u fp u fn u tn (¬e)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Note that not every diagnostic test increases expected utility. Intuitively, a test that does not change the probability of disease irrespective of its result (i.e., P (h|e) = P (h|¬e) = P (h)), has no informational value and zero utility gain. However, even if a test does provide information about the probability of disease (i.e., P (h|e) = P (h) and P (h|¬e) = P (h)), it does not necessarily have positive expected utility gain. If Test E has positive expected utility gain, i.e., if eu(E) &gt; 0, we will call it a useful test. </p><formula xml:id="formula_6">u tp =+ 40, u fp =− 26, u fn =− 22, u tn =+ 41, t x =0.52 u tp =+ 3, u fp =0, u fn =0, u tn =+ 1, t x =0</formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">u tp =− 1, u fp =+ 4, u fn =− 6, u tn =+ 3, t x =− 0.25 u tp =+ 3, u fp =+ 2, u fn =+ 3, u tn =+ 6, t x =1</formula><p>0.0 0.5 1.0 0.0 0.5 1.0  utility functions because the slope of the expected utility of the "treat patient" line is greater than the slope of the "do not treat" line, and those lines intersect where 0 &lt; P (h) &lt; 1 on the x axis. The bottom row illustrates two arbitrary improper utility functions, for which the best decision (up to a possible tie) does not depend on the probability of the disease. In the bottom-left panel treating the patient has higher utility than not treating, irrespective of the probability that the patient has the disease. The "treat" expected utility line has a higher slope than the "do not treat" line, illustrating that this is a necessary, but not sufficient, condition for having a proper utility function. The bottom-right panel illustrates another improper utility function, according to which it is always better to not treat the patient (up to a tie if P (h) = 1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Utilities Influence Tests' Relative Value Only via the Therapeutic Threshold</head><p>We next give three results that provide the foundation for our subsequent derivations.</p><p>Result 1. Let H = {h, ¬h} be a binary hypothesis space associated with a disease and let E = {e, ¬e} be a diagnostic test for H. Let u = utp u fp u fn utn be a utility function for H. Then the expected utility of E with respect to the utility function u, eu(E), is equal to the expected utility of E with respect to the utility function u * = utp−u fn 0 0 utn−u fp , which we denote by eu * (E); i.e., eu(E) = eu * (E).</p><p>The proof is given in Appendix A. The result above essentially says that the expected utility of a test E depends only on the differences between the utilities for correct and incorrect classifications and is independent of the particular points of reference relative to which these payoffs and costs are calculated.</p><p>Suppose we want to measure payoffs and costs in expected years of lifetime given that someone has received a specific test result. Then we could choose the amount of time someone is expected to live if they do not receive treatment for the disease as a reference point. Equally, we could choose the amount of time they are expected to live given that they do receive treatment for the disease, which they might or might not have, as our reference point. These modifications could change the utility of a positive or negative test result, u(e) and u(¬e), but would not change the expected utility of a test, eu(E).</p><p>Thus, to make things easier, we can always translate any set of utilities such that u fp = u fn = 0, as follows: For any utility function u = utilities do not need to be measured on a ratio scale for our subsequent results to hold. Furthermore, subsequent results will make clear that so long as utilities were measured at least on an interval scale, the expected utility gain of tests-up to a constant positive multiple-exists on a ratio scale, with a true zero point.</p><p>We next analyze the expected utility gain of tests. Consider a diagnostic test E, i.e., a test for which a positive result increases the probability of disease and a negative result decreases the probability of disease. What are possible values for eu(E)?</p><p>First, we know from <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Good (1967)</ref> that no test has negative expected utility, assuming (as we do here) that tests have no intrinsic cost. But under which circumstances is the expected utility of a diagnostic test strictly positive?</p><p>Result 2. Let H = {h, ¬h} be the hypothesis space associated with a disease and let u be a proper utility function with corresponding therapeutic threshold t x . Let E be a diagnostic test for H. Then the test has positive expected utility, i.e., eu(E) &gt; 0, if and only if both P (h|¬e) &lt; t x and P (h|e) &gt; t x .</p><p>The proof is given in Appendix A. This result may be intuitive, yet it has important implications.</p><p>It follows from Result 2 that the expected utility of a test E can be zero in exactly one of two possible ways. One way is if the probability of disease is less than the treatment threshold irrespective of the test result, i.e., P (h|¬e) ≤ t x and P (h|e) ≤ t x . The other way is if the probability of disease is greater than the treatment threshold irrespective of the test result, i.e., P (h|¬e) ≥ t x and P (h|e) ≥ t x . This means that, while a test is informative if either test result changes the probability of a person having the disease, i.e., if P (h|¬e) &lt; P (h) &lt; P (h|e), the test is useful only if its outcome is able to change the utility-maximizing course of action. More precisely, a test is useful if a positive test outcome results in the utility-maximizing decision changing from not treating to treating the patient, or if a negative test result results in the utility-maximizing decision changing from treating to not treating the patient.</p><p>Further note that for P (h) = t x , any informative test also has positive expected utility, since a change in beliefs necessarily results in P (h|¬e) &lt; t x and P (h|e) &gt; t x . Finally, the expected utility gain of a test E is always either zero or of the form eu(E) = P (e)P (h|e)utp + P (¬e)P (¬h|¬e)utn − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn]</p><p>given that we can set u fp = u fn = 0.</p><p>The relevant factors for computing the utility of any individual state-action combination (e.g., "the utility of treating the patient is 0.6") include the prior probability of disease, the likelihoods of obtaining a positive test given that the disease is present or absent, and the four specific utilities for correct and incorrect decisions with the resulting therapeutic threshold <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table 2</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1</ref>). Must each of the four individual utilities also be considered for determining tests' relative expected utility, i.e., the ratio of one test's utility to another test's utility, eu(E) eu(F ) ? In fact, for assessing the relative utility of tests, we do not need to know all four items from the utility function: all that matters is the therapeutic threshold t x that results from those four utility values. To show that this is the case, we need both Result 1, above, and Result 3, which is presented below.</p><p>Consider a situation in which the probabilities are known, but in which there are two possible sets of utilities, u and u * , where u * is formed by multiplying all the utilities in u by a positive constant. These two utility functions entail the same therapeutic threshold t x , and therefore the utility-maximizing decision under the two utility functions is identical. However, is it possible that one test has higher expected utility under u and the other test has higher expected utility under u The proof is given in Appendix A. Although this result may be intuitive, when combined with Result 1, its implications are far-reaching.</p><p>First, we can change the unit of measurement of the utility function, and the expected utility of the test will change accordingly. For example, if the expected utility of a test E is 0.10 expected life years, then the expected utility of test E is also 5.2 expected life weeks, assuming 52 weeks in a year.</p><p>Second, we can combine Result 1 with Result 3. Suppose we have a proper utility function u.</p><p>According to Result 1, we can replace u with a utility function u * with the same therapeutic threshold t x and u * f p = u * f n = 0, such that eu(E) = eu * (E) by setting u * tp = u tp − u f n and u * tn = u tn − u f p . For</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">α = u * tn +u * tp = u tn −u f p +u tp −u f n , we can rewrite u * as α• (1−tx) 0 0</formula><p>tx . If we denote the expected utility of E relative to (1−tx) 0 0 tx by eu tx (E), then, according to result Result 3, eu(E) = eu * (E) = α • eu tx (E).</p><p>For the present analyses, the relative expected utility of tests is especially important because we are concerned with identifying which test out of two (or more) has the highest expected utility gain. Suppose we have another test F with eu(F ) &gt; 0. Then the ratio eu <ref type="bibr">(E)</ref> eu(F ) for the two tests E and F relative to u is equal to <ref type="bibr">F )</ref> and is thus independent of α. Now suppose we have another payoff matrix u = u tp u fp u fn u tn with the same therapeutic threshold t x as u. Then we can replace u with a payoff matrix α • (1−tx) 0 0 tx , with α = u tn − u f p + u tp − u f n , α = 0 and again, the ratio eu <ref type="bibr">(E)</ref> eu(F ) for the two tests E and F relative to u is equal to <ref type="bibr">(F )</ref> . Thus, it doesn't matter whether the relative utility of tests E and F is calculated using u or u . As long as the two utility functions entail the same threshold t x , the ratio eu <ref type="bibr">(E)</ref> eu(F ) will be the same. The key insight from these analyses is that if a particular test selection strategy is optimal in a situation with normalized utilities of the form (1−tx) 0 0 tx , which entails a therapeutic threshold of t x , then such a test selection strategy is also optimal in any other situation whose utilities are associated with the same therapeutic threshold t x . As a consequence, it is possible to use such normalized utility functions without loss of generality in both analytical and simulation-based investigations. An important psychological implication is that if a physician has an idea of the appropriate therapeutic threshold, e.g. that it would make sense to treat a particular disease if the probability of that disease is at least 0.1, then the precise numerical ingredients of the utility function do not need to be known in order to assess the relative expected utility of the possible tests. 1</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">α•eut x (E) α•eut x (F ) = eut x (E) eut x (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_11">α •eut x (E) α •eut x (F ) = eut x (E) eut x</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Analytic Results on the Likelihood Difference Heuristic</head><p>The previous sections have provided a formal analysis of how to determine the expected utility of a test, and the relation between tests' utility and the therapeutic threshold implied by the utilities. In this section we are concerned with test selection: Given two (or more) available tests for diagnosing a patient, how should one determine which test to conduct? Our focus here is on a very simple strategy that does not rely on calculating each test's expected utility gain.</p><p>The likelihood difference of test E is the difference between the likelihood of obtaining a positive test result given the disease is present (the true positive rate), and the likelihood of obtaining a positive test result given the disease is absent (the false positive rate), formally λ(E) = P (e|h) − P (e|¬h). We call the strategy of conducting the test with the highest likelihood difference the Likelihood Difference Heuristic (LDH). Suppose there are two tests, E, such that P (e|h) = 1 and P (e|¬h) = 0.2, and F , such that P (f |h) = 0.9 and P (f |¬h) = 0.05. Test E has λ(E) = 0.80, whereas Test F has λ(F ) = 0.85, so the LDH would select test F to conduct. (If two or more tests tie for highest likelihood difference, the LDH selects among them randomly.)</p><p>1 Consider some arbitrary statistical environment, for instance where P (h) = 0.3, and P (e|h) and P (e|¬h) are generated from a uniform distribution between 0 and 1. Suppose the applicable utility function is u = u tp u fp u fn u tn = 0 −9 −1 0 , which corresponds to a therapeutic threshold of tx = 0.1. Further assume that a particular test-selection strategy identifies the objectively more useful test out of a pair of random tests in 70% of cases. Given these results we know that the performance of the heuristic would be the same in an environment where u = 0.9 0 0 0.1 , or any other proper set of utilities for which tx = 0.1, and no matter if the utilities measure extended life expectancy, dollars saved, or any other units.</p><p>The LDH, like information gain and other OED models, ignores outcome utilities, and does not in general choose the highest expected utility gain test <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Meder &amp; Nelson, 2012)</ref>. However, whereas most pure-information utilities take the prior probability of disease into account, the LDH also ignores the prior probability. In situations with outcome-based utilities, would it ever be sensible to use such a simplistic strategy to select tests? In the following, we prove that given maximal need for information, i.e. if the prior probability of the disease p(h) equals the therapeutic threshold t x , the LDH is guaranteed to identify the higher-expected-utility-gain test:</p><p>Result 4. Let H = {h, ¬h} be a hypothesis space associated with a disease and let u be a proper utility function for H with corresponding therapeutic threshold t x . If P (h) = t x , then there exists a positive β, such that for any diagnostic test E, we have eu(E) = βλ(E).</p><p>The proof is given in Appendix A. This result shows not only that the LDH will select the highest expected utility gain test, but that a test's expected utility gain is a constant multiple of its likelihood difference.</p><p>What should that constant multiple, β, be? If standardized utilities of the form (1−tx) 0 0 tx are used, then, according to the proof of Result 4,</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">β = P (h)(1 − P (h)) = t x (1 − t x )</formula><p>. Thus, for any diagnostic test E and given that the decision maker is subject to maximal need of information and therefore decision indifference, the expected utility gain is highest if P (h) = t x = 0.5. However, from</p><p>Results 1 and 3 it follows that the ratio of two tests' expected utility depends only on the therapeutic threshold t x entailed by the applicable utility function, and is otherwise independent of the particlar values in utp u fp u fn utn . Accordingly, in a situation of maximal need for information, the LDH invariably chooses a (not necessarily unique) utility-maximizing test.</p><p>What if a decision maker is not at the point of decision indifference, e.g. if P (h) = t x ? In this case, the LDH is not in general optimal:</p><p>Result 5. Let H = {h, ¬h} be a hypothesis space associated with a disease and let u be a proper set of utility values for H with corresponding therapeutic threshold t x . Then if P (h) = t x , there exist tests E and F such that λ(E) &gt; λ(F ) while eu(E) &lt; eu(F ).</p><p>The proof in Appendix A gives a procedure that is applicable in any situation where P (h) = t x , for finding a pair of binary tests E and F such that one test has higher expected utility, but the other test has a higher likelihood difference. Importantly, while this result demonstrates that the LDH is not exactly optimal if P (h) = t x , we do not know whether the LDH's performance degrades gracefully as we move away from its optimality condition. Nor do we know whether other pure information strategies (such as information gain or probability gain) would also be optimal if P (h) = t x . We also do not knowm whether other purely informational OED strategies would perform better or worse than the LDH under particular combinations of P (h) and t x values. We address these issues in a simulation experiment in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">What Likelihoods Matter Where: Sensitivity and Specificity</head><p>Result 4 implies that if an agent is at a point of decision indifference because P (h) = t x , and two tests have the same likelihood difference, then those tests also have the same expected utility. Are there some test characteristics that reveal which of two tests with the same likelihood difference has the highest expected utility if P (h) = t x ?</p><p>It turns out that there are. Specifically, the relevant test characteristics are the likelihood that the test is positive, given that the patient has the disease, P (e|h), and the likelihood that the test is negative, given that the disease is absent P (¬e|¬h). In the medical literature, P (e|h) is referred to as the sensitivity of a test, and P (¬e|¬h) is referred to as the specificity of a test. Which of these two likelihoods is more important for a test's expected utility gain depends on the relation between the prior probability of disease P (h) and the therapeutic threshold t x : If the prior probability of disease is below the threshold (i.e., P (h) &lt; t x ), the relevant likelihood is P (¬e|¬h), the test's specificity. Conversely, if the prior probability of disease is above the threshold (i.e., P (h) &gt; t x ), the relevant likelihood is P (e|h), the test's sensitivity.</p><p>Before we prove this, we will show that there is an interesting relationship that establishes which test likelihood is most important for the posterior probability of disease given a positive test result, P (h|e), and the posterior probability of the disease being absent given a negative test result, P (¬h|¬e). (In medicine, P (h|e) is referred to the as positive predictive value of a test, and P (¬h|¬e) is referred to as the negative predictive value of a test.)</p><p>Result 6. Let H = (h, ¬h) be a hypothesis space associated with a disease and let E and F be two diagnostic tests for H with equal likelihood difference, λ(E) = λ(F ). Then the following holds:</p><p>(i) If P (¬e|¬h) &gt; P (¬f |¬h), then P (h|e) &gt; P (h|f ). Thus, if E has higher specificity than F , then the posterior probability of disease is higher given a positive result from E than given a positive result from F . (ii) If P (e|h) &gt; P (f |h), then P (¬h|¬e) &gt; P (¬h|¬f ). Thus, if E has higher sensitivity than F , then the posterior probability of disease is lower given a negative result from E than given a negative result from F .</p><p>The proof is given in Appendix A. We now give a more general result on the relationship among the sensitivity P (e|h), the specificity P (¬e|¬h), the prior probability P (h), and the therapeutic threshold</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">t x .</formula><p>Result 7. Let H = (h, ¬h) be the hypothesis space associated with a disease and let u be a proper utility function for H. Let E = (e, ¬e) and F = (f, ¬f ) be two diagnostic tests for H, with λ(E) = λ(F ). Then the following holds:</p><p>(i) If P (h) &lt; t x , and P (¬e|¬h) ≥ P (¬f |¬h), we have eu(E) ≥ eu(F ).</p><p>(ii) If P (h) &gt; t x , and P (e|h) ≥ P (f |h), we have eu(E) ≥ eu(F ).</p><p>The proof is given in Appendix A. One interesting insight from the proof is that we can calculate the expected utility of a test E as a function of the specificity of E if P (h) &lt; t x , or as a function of the sensitivity of E if P (h) &gt; t x . More precisely, we can show that:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">(i) If P (h) &lt; t</formula><p>x , then the expected utility of a test is either zero or of the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">eu(E) = utpP (h)λ(E) + [spec(E) − 1][utnP (¬h) − utpP (h)] (6) (ii) If P (h) &gt; t</formula><p>x , then the expected utility of a test is either zero or of the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">eu(E) = utnP (¬h)λ(E) + [sens(E) − 1][utpP (h) − utnP (¬h)]<label>(7)</label></formula><p>This means that for p(h) &lt; t x , eu(E) will be smaller than u tp P (h)λ(E), as [u tn P (¬h) − u tp P (h)] is positive in that case. Similarly, for p(h) &gt; t x we can see that eu(E) will be smaller than u tn P (¬h)λ(E) as whereas Test E has zero expected utility gain, Test F has positive expected utility gain.</p><p>What is happening in this scenario? Because the prior probability of disease is greater than the therapeutic threshold, if no test could be conducted, the best decision would be to treat the patient. In this type of situation, a test has positive utility if the posterior probability of disease given a negative test outcome would be less than the therapeutic threshold. In this case, the posterior probability of disease given a negative outcome to test E is about 0.154, so the best decision would still be to not treat the patient. In the case of Test F , however, the probability of disease given a negative test result is about 0.138, which is below the therapeutic threshold. Since a negative test result changes the best course of action to take (i.e., utility-maximizing treatment decision), test F has positive expected utility gain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">The Bigger Picture: Simulation Results and Test Selection Based on OED Models</head><p>If the therapeutic threshold t x equals the prior probability of disease P (h), then the LDH invariably identifies the test with highest expected utility gain. Do better-known OED models, which select tests based on epistemic utility functions, also do so? What if the precise values of P (h) and t x are not known?</p><p>If the prior probability of disease is only approximately equal to the treatment criterion, P (h) ≈ t x , is it still a good bet to use the LDH? How does the LDH compare with prominent OED models if the prior probability of disease and the therapeutic threshold are not even approximately equal, P (h) = t x ? Here we address these questions via simulations and a numeric example.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Other OED Models are Suboptimal Where the LDH is Optimal</head><p>The LDH invariably identifies the best test if P (h) = t x . But if P (h) = t x , and 0 &lt; t x &lt; 1, then any informative test is useful. Do other models of the value of information also identify the most useful test in this case? Here we consider some OED models that are prominent in the medical decision making and psychological literature. (For equations and example calculations with these OED models, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Nelson, 2005</ref>.) The models we consider are:</p><p>• expected information gain, based on expected reduction in <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Shannon (1948)</ref> entropy <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Lindley, 1956;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Benish, 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Benish, , 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Oaksford &amp; Chater, 1994)</ref>;</p><p>• probability gain, which quantifies improvement in classification accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Baron, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Nelson, 2005)</ref>; and</p><p>• Bayesian diagnosticity and log diagnosticity, which are based on likelihood ratios or log likelihood ratios <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Good, 1950;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Good &amp; Card, 1971)</ref>.</p><p>Do these OED test-selection methods, like the LDH, also correctly identify the best test when P (h) = t x ? Consider a case where P (h) = t x = 0.25, P (e|h) = 0.81, P (e|¬h) = 0.27, P (f |h) = 0.43, and if P (h) = t x , can be counted on to identify the highest utility gain test to conduct.</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">P (f |¬h) = 0.</formula><p>Information gain and KL divergence, which have been suggested in the medical literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Benish, 1999</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Benish, , 2003</ref>, pick the lower-expected-utility-gain test. KL divergence and information gain are identical for purposes of evaluating tests' expected usefulness <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Oaksford &amp; Chater, 1994)</ref>. Probability gain, which accounts well for human test selection in probabilistic classification tasks when probabilities are learned experientially <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Nelson et al., 2010)</ref>, also picks the lower-expected-utility-gain test in this example.</p><p>It is worth noting that information gain and probability gain are both special cases of the Sharma-Mittal family of generalized information gain measures <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Crupi et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Sharma &amp; Mittal, 1975)</ref>, and other information-theoretic models could also be used. The likelihood ratio-based methods, Bayesian diagnosticity and log diagnosticity, are not part of the Sharma-Mittal family of information-theoretic models. These models actually deem the lower-expected-utility-gain test to be infinitely useful. The fact that the likelihood ratio-based methods fail here may be surprising to readers familiar with Signal Detection Theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Green &amp; Swets, 1966;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Stanislaw &amp; Todorov, 1999)</ref>, where it is a convention to state decision thresholds in terms of likelihood ratios. These likelihood ratios take prior probabilities and payoff utilities into account, in effect quantifying how much evidence would be needed to change the best decision. However, this example shows that it does not follow that likelihood ratio-based testselection methods are optimal. Nor is this example unique, or dependent on having a likelihood value that is either 0 or 1. For instance, suppose we were to change P (f |¬h) from 0 to 0.001, while keeping the therapeutic threshold, prior probabilities and other likelihoods unchanged. Probability gain and information gain would not change appreciably in this case. The likelihood ratio-based methods, though no longer deeming Test E to have infinite expected utility, would still deem Test E to be more useful than Test F . Further discussion of limitations of the likelihood ratio-based OED models, for instance how in some circumstances they are insensitive to prior probabilities, can be found in <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Nelson (2005)</ref>. Minka <ref type="formula">2001</ref>gives a broader discussion of limitations of likelihood-based methods in statistics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Where does choice of test matter?</head><p>Our analytic results on the LDH, and the example above, show that the LDH, but not prominent OED models from the literature, is optimal if the prior probability of disease exactly equals the therapeutic threshold. But even if one has a good estimate of those quantities, they seldom are exactly known. What happens if the prior probability of disease is close to, but not exactly, the therapeutic threshold? What if the prior probability P (h) and the therapeutic threshold t x are very different from each other?</p><p>Before simulating the performance of various strategies, we first explore the implications of various P (h) and t x values. This is important because it may be the case that for some combinations of P (h) and t x , few tests actually have positive expected utility gain, and that for other combinations of P (h) and t x , randomly drawn tests may differ substantially in their expected utility gain. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2</ref> shows the results of these simulations. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2a</ref> gives the empirical frequency that a randomly generated test has positive (greater than 10 −10 ) expected utility gain, as a function of P (h) and t x , each incremented from 0.01, 0.02, ... 0.99. Every test was generated by independently sampling two numbers from a uniform distribution on the interval [0,1], assigning the larger probability to the true positive rate P (e|h) and the smaller probability to the false positive rate P (e|¬h). Results show that the combination of P (h) and t x strongly influences the tendency of a random test to have positive expected utility gain <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Figure 2a</ref>). For instance, if P (h) is very low and t x is very high, it is extremely rare for a random test to have positive expected utility gain. This makes sense: if the prior probability of disease is low, and a high threshold t x applies, then only a test with very high positive predictive value p(h|e) can potentially change the best decision from don't treat to treat. Conversely, if P (h) is very high and t x is very low, then only a test with very high negative predictive value P (¬h|¬e) can have positive utility gain. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2b</ref> shows that this general pattern is preserved if we consider the mean expected utility gain of randomly-generated tests. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2c</ref> shows that a similar pattern applies if we consider the mean expected utility gain difference of randomly generated pairs of tests.</p><p>The upshot of all this is that, from the perspective of making the right test-selection decision, or of capturing as much expected utility gain as possible, not all combinations of P (h) and t x values are equally important. Rather, situations in which P (h) and t x have similar values, especially if these values are not too extreme, are by far the most important. In the next section we address how the LDH and other strategies perform as a function of P (h) and t x .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Simulations of the LDH, Information Gain and Probability Gain</head><p>We now know that prominent OED models in medical decision making and psychological literature, unlike the LDH, are not in general optimal when P (h) = t x . We further know that for purposes of making a right choice where it matters, situations where P (h) ≈ t x , especially if the values are not too extreme, are especially important. How do the LDH and other pure-information-based OED models perform for various P (h) and t x values?</p><p>To address this question we simulated the performance of the LDH, information gain, and probability gain, as shown in  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 3</ref> we plot the probability that using a particular strategy leads to choosing the higher-expected-utility-gain test out of a pair of tests. To be conservative, in the case where the difference in the normalized utility values is less than 10 −10 , we counted either test choice as a success. From left to right, results are plotted for the LDH, information gain, and probability gain. The LDH (top left) is optimal if P (h) = t x , consistent with our analytical results, with its performance decreasing quickly but smoothly as we move away from P (h) = t x . The LDH's performance is quite a bit better than chance throughout the range of P (h) and t x values considered. Information gain (top middle) is not optimal anywhere among the range of P (h) and t x values considered. However, information gain appears fairly robust across all combinations of P (h) and t x values, and performs better than the LDH for many combinations of P (h) and t x . Probability gain is optimal if t x = 0.5, which is the case where the utility-maximizing decision corresponds to the most probable state, namely to treat the patient iff P (h) &gt; 0.5. However, unlike the LDH and information gain, if P (h) and t x are both either very low or very high, probability gain performs very poorly, approaching chance performance.</p><p>In the bottom row of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 3</ref> we plot the mean loss in expected utility resulting from using the LDH, information gain, and probability gain, to select among pairs of tests. In some respects these results parallel the results for probability of selecting the best test. However, some key differences should be pointed out. One key difference is that if P (h) ≈ 0 and t x ≈ 1, there is next to no cost of whichever test selection strategy is used, because (as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2</ref>) almost no possible decision has positive expected utility gain. The other key difference is in the comparatively broad and smooth-boundaried regions bordering the boundary cases in which the LDH and probability gain are demonstrably optimal.</p><p>If P (h) ≈ t x , even if P (h) and t x are not exactly equal, using the LDH is a solid bet. A similar statement can be made for probability gain: if t x ≈ 0.5, using probability gain is a solid bet. To summarize, not all combinations of P (h) and t x are equally important from the perspective of maximizing outcome-based utilities; rather, cases where P (h) ≈ t x , and the values are not too extreme, are especially important. Interestingly, these conditions highly overlap with where the LDH is either exactly (P (h) = t x ) or approximately (P (h) ≈ t x ) optimal. If the optimality conditions of the LDH or probability gain are approximately met, then there is effectively no loss in utility from using the appropriate pure information strategy, rather than explicitly calculating the actual expected utility gain of each test. Information gain, though not optimal for any combination of P (h) and t x , gives robust performance throughout, and is in fact better than the LDH for many combinations of P (h) and t x .</p><p>Probability gain is optimal if t x = 0.5, and robust in cases where t x ≈ 0.5. However, it is not as though any pure information strategy would be sensible to use. In particular, if P (h) and t x are both fairly low, or if P (h) and t x are both fairly high, then using probability gain could be quite costly in terms of expected utility gain. <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Newell and Card (1985)</ref> noted that "Nothing drives basic science better than a good applied problem".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">A Real-World Example: Latent Tuberculosis Testing</head><p>Are there real-world situations in which the LDH could be applied? Indeed, there are many situations in medicine <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Alberg et al., 2004)</ref> and other domains in which it is necessary to choose among binary (or cases, and might benefit from preventive treatments <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Esmail, Barry, Young &amp; Wilkinson, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>LTBI screening represents an interesting case study for several reasons. To begin with, there is no "gold standard" test for LTBI. The existing tests can be grouped into two classes, the tuberculin skin test (TST) and the interferon gamma release assays (IGRA), each of which has advantages and limitations.</p><p>For simplicity, we will refer to the TST and to the IGRA as if each were a single test, rather than classes of tests. In particular, TST has been widely used for a century, with well-studied clinical applications and cut-off points for therapeutic indications for different ages and risk groups. However, its measurement is subject to interobserver variability, a positive test result does not distinguish between recent and earlier infections (which have a lower risk of progression to disease), and repetitions of the test might generate a booster phenomenon. IGRA tests are not subject to reader bias and do not tend to boost responses when repeated. However, accuracy can be decreased by problems in collecting or transporting blood specimens. Additionally, there is limited data on the use in some groups, such as young children and immunocompromised persons. Some studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Al-Orainey, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mazurek et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Smith et al., 2011</ref>) have suggested a slightly higher sensitivity for the TST and a higher specificity for the IGRA.</p><p>What likelihood values apply for the IGRA and TST tests? Based on our reading of the literature, reasonable estimates for each test's sensitivity and specificity, value are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>. The point for the present paper is not whether these numbers are exactly right. Indeed, every study has a different estimate, also depending on which specific IGRA or TST test is considered. Rather, our motivation here is to use plausible numbers from a real-world example to try to connect to our theoretical analyses. Recall that a test's sensitivity is P (e|h), and that 1 − specificity = 1 − P (¬e|¬h) = P (e|¬h). If we use these values to compute the likelihood difference λ for each test, we get λ(T ST ) = .78 and λ(IGRA) = .83 <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">(Table 3</ref>). According to these numbers, then, the likelihood difference is greater for the IGRA test.</p><p>Thus, if a doctor would use the LDH, they would choose the IGRA rather than the TST test. Map showing where the TST (blue) or IGRA test (red) has higher expected utility gain; with black denoting areas where neither test has expected utility gain. The tests tied exactly in 3 of the 99 2 = 9801 points plotted. All of these points were on the boundary between the regions where the TST and IGRA tests have higher utility. For purposes of plotting the figure, these three points were arbitrarily assigned to the TST test.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Figure 4a</ref> we plot the usefulness of the TST test as a function of the prior probability of disease P (h) and the therapeutic threshold t x , with both P (h) and t x ranging from 0.01, 0.02, ... 0.99. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Figure 4b</ref> shows the same analysis for the IGRA test. The color of each point denotes the expected utility gain of a test for a particular combination of p(h) and t x . As the legends to the right of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Figure 4a</ref> and 4b note, black denotes zero utility; dark purple denotes low utility; red denotes greater utility; orange and yellow denote highest utility. Broadly speaking, we see that both tests tend to have higher utility where P (h) and t x are similar in value to each other, and moderate (neither close to 1 nor close to 0). There is also a broad range of circumstances, for example if the prior probability of disease is high and the therapeutic threshold is low (or vice versa), in which both of the tests have zero utility. Given these two analyses, we can determine the circumstances under which each test has higher expected utility gain. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Figure 4c</ref> plots this, with red denoting where the IGRA test has higher utility and blue denoting where the TST test has higher utility. Black denotes where the tests are both useless, because no test result could change which course of action (treat or don't treat) has higher expected utility gain. This type of analysis, paralleling results from the simulations in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 3</ref>, shows that even approximate knowledge of the therapeutic threshold and prior probability of disease could be enough to enable selection of the higher-utility test.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">What Prior Probabilities and Therapeutic Threshold Values are Plausible?</head><p>What is the true probability of having LTBI? One reason for our interest in LTBI screening is the enormous variation of LTBI prevalence across countries and, within the same country, across specific sub-populations. For example, it has been reported that around one third of the world's population is affected by LTBI <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lamberti et al., 2014)</ref>, including more than 40% in Uganda or 50% in the Ivory Coast, but less than 5% in the United States and most European countries <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Bentley et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mazurek et al., 2010)</ref>. However, even in countries in which the general prevalence of LTBI is low, people working in hospitals, homeless shelters, correctional facilities, or residential facilities for patients with HIV infection are considered at higher risk <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Nienhaus et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b86">Zhang et al., 2013)</ref>. For example, the prevalence of LTBI within German healthcare workers has been reported to be around 9.9% <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Schablon, Harling, Diel, &amp; Nienhaus, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>What therapeutic threshold is appropriate for treating LTBI? We informally asked a small sample of experienced physicians from the Negrar Center for Tropical Diseases (Verona, Italy) to provide an estimate of the therapeutic threshold for LTBI. When asked for the probability of LTBI above which it would make sense to treat a young adult in good health, they gave an estimate of about t x = 10%.</p><p>Interestingly, this therapeutic threshold is essentially identical to the estimated LTBI prevalence of 9.9%</p><p>within German healthcare workers. Thus, if a screening LTBI test was to be performed on people from a similar reference class (e.g., healthcare professionals living somewhere else in Europe), IGRA should be preferred over TST as it is likely to provide a higher expected gain in utility, given that P (h) ≈ t x .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.">Limitations and Implications of the LTBI Analysis</head><p>A number of simplifications are required for the above (or any) analysis, some of which might limit its usefulness; we therefore consider some limitations here. To start with, probabilities we have estimated from some articles in the literature, and the therapeutic threshold t x estimate obtained from a small sample of physicians, should not be taken as authoritative. However, our formal analyses do not change according to where the payoffs come from, and they can easily be applied not only to the patient's utilities but also to public health or environmental objectives, and ideally to a combination of them. We also did not consider intrinsic test costs. TST is inexpensive, although it does require trained health care professionals and two visits (the first for administration, the second for interpretation). By contrast, IGRA tests can be done on a single visit, but require laboratory facilities. Such costs could be included in the analyses, and could change the results in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Figure 4</ref> as to the utility of each test, or the circumstances (combinations of P (h) and t x ) under which each test is more useful. Other simplifications are that people vary in their tendency for LTBI to progress to full TB or in what developing TB implies for them. A more sophisticated model would also include the risk of progressing to TB if not treated (which is higher for individuals with significant comorbidities) as well as the personal or social consequences of developing TB (which are more serious for individuals who are in contact with children or immunocompromised people). Information gain or other general-purpose OED models can be used in situations with multiple possible states of the world, e.g. if there were three or more possibilities in terms of the likelihood of LTBI to develop into active TB. However, the LDH, or other procedures that are based on binary tests and states of the world, would no longer be applicable.</p><p>Arguing in favor of the applicability of the LDH, although quantities in nature are often continuously variable, states of nature and test results are often treated as binary. Moreover, the LDH (in contrast to an equation that takes all payoffs into account) is easy to use and easy to explain, and thus could be a helpful tool in training practitioners about test selection. Another motivation for using the LDH could be its robustness: it makes sense to use the LDH if P (h) ≈ t x , even if neither P (h) nor t x are known exactly. Our LTBI analysis suggests that there may be relevant situations in which the LDH identifies the higher utility gain test.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">General Discussion</head><p>Actively acquiring information through test selection is important for reducing uncertainty and identifying the best course of action to take. However, tests are often time-consuming and costly, both in is entailed by the outcome-based utilities, known exactly. Our results show that if the prior probability of disease P (h) is even approximately equal to the therapeutic threshold t x , it is either optimal or close to optimal to use the LDH to select tests. Importantly, these circumstances overlap highly with the situations in which one's test-selection strategy has the biggest impact in terms of expected utility gain ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 2</ref>). Not just any pure information OED model should be used, however <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Figure 3</ref>). The LDH and information gain have reasonable performance across a wide range of P (h) and t x values. By contrast, for some cases-in particular where P (h) and t x are both low or high-probability gain approximates chance performance.</p><p>We have analyzed the situation of selecting a single test before making a treatment decision. However, in many situations, more than one test can be conducted. This is a critical issue, because it is not in general the case that the best standalone test is the best first test to conduct in a sequence of tests <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Geman &amp; Jedynak, 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">, 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Hyafil &amp; Rivest, 1976;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Meder et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Nelson et al., 2018)</ref>. Planning an optimal sequential question strategy requires knowledge of how the test results relate to each other, which cannot in general be derived from the individual test likelihoods. For instance, in the LTBI example it is unclear what the probability of disease given any particular set of results for the two tests is. People <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Jarecki, Meder &amp; Nelson, 2017)</ref>, popular machine learning methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Domingos &amp; Pazzani, 1997)</ref>, and medical decision making models <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Hamm, Beasley, &amp; Johnson, 2014)</ref> tend to presume a priori that tests are class-conditionally independent (i.e., test outcomes are conditionally independent given the true category). This assumption, even if seldom strictly correct, can lead to high classification performance under a wide range of circumstances <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Domingos &amp; Pazzani, 1997)</ref>; however, its implications for test selection need to be studied.</p><p>In addition, a number of empirical questions follow from the theoretical analyses of this paper. One is the relationship between direct estimates of t x (e.g., by doctors or other health care professionals) and</p><p>corresponding t x values computed from elicited situation-specific utilities. The possible match between these values would provide an important justification for the use of t x in clinical practice to compute the value of tests, even in case the underlying utilities are unknown. Moreover, while use of likelihood differences has been studied empirically in domains such as causal reasoning <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Cheng &amp; Novick, 1990)</ref> and belief updating <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Gigerenzer &amp; Hoffrage, 1995)</ref>, people's use of the LDH has not yet been tested in an explicitly medical diagnostic context or in related situations with external payoffs. Another question is how people select tests, as a function of how probability values and outcome utilities are communicated.</p><p>The implications of outcome utilities for human test selection have been studied in only a very small number of articles (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Meder &amp; Nelson, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>These studies suggest that it is difficult to make asymmetric payoffs intuitive in human test selection.</p><p>It is possible that people follow different strategies according to whether the relevant probability values are learned through experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Nelson et al., 2010)</ref> or presented using the standard probability format with explicit priors and likelihoods (in which case, the LDH is easy to apply) or via other numeric or graphical methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">(Wu et al., 2017)</ref>. One objective for future work should be to identify how to make utilities, probability values, and test characteristics intuitive, such that people take them into account appropriately when searching for information.</p><p>cross-sectional study. PLOS ONE, 8 (6 ), e66412.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Proofs</head><p>Proof of Result 1. Let H = {h, ¬h} be a binary hypothesis space associated with a disease and let E = {e, ¬e} be a diagnostic test for H. Let u = utp u fp u fn utn be a utility function for H. Then the expected utility of E with respect to the utility function u, which we denote by eu(E), is equal to the expected utility of E with respect to the utility function u * = utp−u fn 0 0 utn−u fp , which we denote by eu * (E); i.e., eu(E) = eu * (E).</p><p>Proof. Let us denote the utilities of e and ¬e with respect to u by u(e) and u(¬e) and the utilities of e and ¬e with respect to u * by u * (e) and u * (¬e). We first calculate the utility of a positive test result for the payoff function u * : </p><formula xml:id="formula_18">u</formula><p>In the same way we calculate the utility of a negative test result and get:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">u * (¬e) =u(¬e) + (P (h) − P (h|¬e))(u fn − u fp )<label>(9)</label></formula><p>To calculate the expected utility eu * (E) of test E, we weigh the utilities of the test results with the probabilities P (e) and P (¬e) of the test results and use the above relationship between the utilities with respect to the two payoff functions: </p><formula xml:id="formula_21">eu * (E) =P (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_22">(¬e ∧ h)](u fn − u fp ) =eu(E) + (P (h) − P (h))(u fn − u fp ) =eu(E)<label>(10)</label></formula><p>Proof of Result 2. Let H = {h, ¬h} be the hypothesis space associated with a disease and let u be a proper utility function with corresponding therapeutic threshold t x . Let E be a diagnostic test for H.</p><p>Then the test is useful, i.e., eu(E) &gt; 0, iff both P (h|¬e) &lt; t x and P (h|e) &gt; t x .</p><p>Proof. Without loss of generality (see Result 1) we can assume that u fn = u fp = 0.</p><p>We will first show that if eu(E) &gt; 0, it follows that P (h|¬e) &lt; t x and P (h|e) &gt; t x . If under both test results the same option as before is at least as useful as the other, then eu(E) = 0. This can easily be seen by calculating eu(E) and choosing the same alternative (to treat or not to treat) both before the test result is known and afterwards, independent of the particular test result. If eu(E) &gt; 0, then the decisions under the two test results have to be different, which is only the case if a negative test result leads to an updated probability of the person having the disease strictly below the therapeutic threshold, i.e., P (h|¬e) &lt; t x , and a positive test result leads to an updated probability of the person having the disease strictly above the therapeutic threshold, i.e., P (h|e) &gt; t x .</p><p>To show that from P (h|¬e) &lt; t x and P (h|e) &gt; t x it follows that eu(E) &gt; 0, consider the following:</p><p>For P (h) ≤ t x , the expected utility is given by eu(E) = P (e)P (h|e)utp + P (¬e)P (¬h|¬e)utn − P (¬h)utn &gt; P (e)P (¬h|e)utn + P (¬e)P (¬h|¬e)utn − P (¬h)utn = 0 (11)</p><p>The expected utility is thus strictly larger than 0. For P (h) ≥ t x , the expected utility can be calculated as eu(E) = P (e)P (h|e)utp + P (¬e)P (¬h|¬e)utn − P (h)utp &gt; P (e)P (h|e)utp + P (¬e)P (h|¬e)utp − P (h)utp = 0 (12)</p><p>Again, eu(E) is strictly larger than 0. </p><formula xml:id="formula_23">= α • u u tp u fp u fn u tn (e)<label>(13)</label></formula><p>and equally,</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">u α•u tp α•u fp α•u fn α•u tn (¬e) = α • u u tp u fp u fn u tn (¬e)<label>(14)</label></formula><p>thus</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">eu α•u tp α•u fp α•u fn α•u tn (E) =P (e)u α•u tp α•u fp α•u fn α•u tn (e) + P (¬e)u α•u tp α•u fp α•u fn α•u tn (¬e) = α • P (e)u u tp u fp u fn u tn (e) + α • P (¬e)u u tp u fp u fn u tn (¬e) = α • eu u tp u fp u fn u tn (E)<label>(15)</label></formula><p>Proof of Result 4. Let H = {h, ¬h} be a hypothesis space associated with a disease and let u be a proper utility function for H with corresponding therapeutic threshold t x . If P (h) = t x , then there exists a positive β, such that for any diagnostic test E for H, we have eu(E) = βλ(E).</p><p>Proof. Without loss of generality we can assume that u f n = u f p = 0 by Result 1. Since P (h) = t x by assumption, we have P (h)u tp = P (¬h)u tn , i.e. the utilities associated with choosing h and choosing ¬h are equal. We posit β = P (h)u tp = P (¬h)u tn . Note that β is strictly positive since P (h) &gt; 0 and Regarding negative test result ¬e we have P (¬h|¬e) ≥ P (¬h), and thus P (h|¬e) ≤ P (h), by which Putting all the foregoing together, we compute:</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">u tp &gt; u f n = 0. Also, β</formula><p>eu(E) =u(e)P (e) + u(¬e)P (¬e) Proof. Without loss of generality we can assume that u f n = u f p = 0 by Result 1. We will show a general method to generate a pair of binary tests E and F such that λ(E) &gt; λ(F ) while eu(E) &lt; eu(F ). More precisely, we will define an informative but useless test E, i.e. a test with P (h|¬e) &lt; P (h) &lt; P (h|e) and</p><p>eu(E) = 0, and a useful test F such that λ(E) exceeds λ(F ) by some tiny amount &gt; 0. We will prove this separately for the two subcases of P (h) = t x , namely P (h) &lt; t x and P (h) &gt; t x .</p><p>Case 1: P (h) &lt; t x . Let us posit:</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">P (e|h) = 1 (21) P (e|¬h) = P (h)u tp P (¬h)u tn (22) P (f |h) = 1 − P (h)u tp P (¬h)u tn + (23) P (f |¬h) = 0<label>(24)</label></formula><p>Note that P (h)utp P (¬h)utn &lt; 1, because by assumption P (h) &lt; t x and hence P (h)u tp &lt; P (¬h)u tn . To ensure that P (f |h) &gt; 0, must be chosen so that &lt; 1 − P (h)utp P (¬h)utn . As 1 − P (h)utp P (¬h)utn is strictly positive, one can always find a positive but tiny enough value of to satisfy this condition. Clearly, the likelihood difference heuristic favors test E over F , because</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">λ(E) − λ(F ) = 1 − P (h)u tp P (¬h)u tn − [1 − ( P (h)u tp P (¬h)u tn + )] = &gt; 0 (25)</formula><p>However, as we will now show, expected utility computations imply the opposite ranking, i.e. eu(E) &lt; eu(F ). More precisely, eu(E) = 0, while eu(F ) is strictly positive. Let us first show that eu(E) = 0.</p><p>Given that P (h) &lt; t x , we have P (h)u tp &lt; P (¬h)u tn , hence max[P (h)u tp , P (¬h)u tn ] = P (¬h)u tn .</p><p>Moreover, given that P (¬h|¬e) &gt; P (¬h) and thus P (h|¬e) &lt; P (h), we have: As for the positive test result e, note that by Bayes's theorem and our probability assignments:</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">P (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_31">P (h|e) = P (e|h)P (h) P (e|h)P (h) + P (e|¬h)P (¬h) = 1 • P (h) 1 • P (h) + P (h)u tp P (¬h)u tn P (¬h) = P (h) P (h)(1 + u tp u tn ) = utn utp + utn (28)</formula><p>which simply equals t x (because u f p = u f n = 0). So P (h|e) = t x , and thus P (h|e)u tp = P (¬h|e)u tn , which in turn implies: Regarding test F , we have once again P (¬h|¬f )u tn &gt; P (¬h)u tn &gt; P (h)u tp &gt; P (h|¬f )u tp , and thus:</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">u(¬f ) =max[P (h|¬f )utp, P (¬h|¬f )utn] − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn] =P (¬h|¬f )utn − P (¬h)utn (31)</formula><p>But, on the other hand, because P (f |¬h) = 0:</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">P (h|f ) = P (f |h)P (h) P (f |h)P (h)+P (f |¬h)P (¬h) =1 &gt; u tn u tp +u tn = tx (32)</formula><p>so P (h|f ) &gt; t x , and thus P (h|f )u tp &gt; P (¬h|f )u tn , by which in turn:</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">u(f ) = max[P (h|f )utp, P (¬h|f )utn] − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn] = P (h|f )utp − P (¬h)utn<label>(33)</label></formula><p>and: Case 2: P (h) &gt; t x . In this case, let us thus posit:</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">P (</formula><formula xml:id="formula_36">P (e|h) = 1 − P (¬h)u tn P (h)u tp<label>(35)</label></formula><p>P (e|¬h) = 0 (36)</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">P (f |h) = 1 (37) P (f |¬h) = P (¬h)u tn P (h)u tp +<label>(38)</label></formula><p>Note that P (¬h)utn P (h)utp &lt; 1, because by assumption P (h) &gt; t x , so P (h)u tp &gt; P (¬h)u tn . To ensure that P (f |¬h) &lt; 1, must be chosen so that &lt; 1 − P (¬h)utn P (h)utp . As 1 − P (¬h)utn P (h)utp is strictly positive, one can always find a positive but tiny enough value of to satisfy this condition. Clearly, the likelihood difference heuristic favors test E over F , because</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">λ(E) − λ(F ) = 1 − P (¬h)u tn P (h)u tp − [1 − ( P (¬h)u tn P (h)u tp + )] = &gt; 0<label>(39)</label></formula><p>However, as we will now show, expected utility computations imply the opposite ranking, i.e. eu(E) &lt; eu(F ). More precisely, eu(E) = 0, while eu(F ) is strictly positive. Let us first show that eu(E) = 0. Given that P (h) &gt; t x , we have P (h)u tp &gt; P (¬h)u tn , so max[P (h)u tp , P (¬h)u tn ] = P (h)u tp . Moreover, given that P (h|e) &gt; P (h) and thus P (¬h|e) &lt; P (¬h), we also have: P (h|e)u tp &gt; P (h)u tp &gt; P (¬h)u tn &gt; P (¬h|e)u tn which implies:</p><p>u(e) =max[P (h|e)utp, P (¬h|e)utn] − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn] =P (h|e)utp − P (h)utp (40)</p><p>As for the negative test result ¬e, note that by Bayes's theorem and our probability assignments: P (¬h|¬e) = P (¬e|¬h)P (¬h) P (¬e|¬h)P (¬h) + P (¬e|h)P (h) = P (¬h)</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">P (¬h) + P (¬h)u tn P (h)u tp P (h) = P (¬h) P (¬h)(1 + u tn u tp ) = utp utp + utn (41)</formula><p>which simply equals t x (because u f n = u f p = 0). So P (¬h|¬e) = t x , and thus P (¬h|¬e)u tn = P (h|¬e)u tp . This in turn implies: Putting all the foregoing together yields:</p><p>eu(E) =u(e)P (e) + u(¬e)P (¬e) =(P (h|e)utp − P (h)utp)P (e) + (P (h|¬e)utp − P (h)utp)P (¬e) =(P (h|e)P (e) − P (h)P (e) + P (h|¬e)P (¬e) − P (h)P (¬e))utp</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">=(P (h) − P (h))utp = 0<label>(43)</label></formula><p>Regarding test F , we still have P (h|f )u tp &gt; P (h)u tp &gt; P (¬h)u tn &gt; P (¬h|f )u tn and therefore: Proof of Result 6. Let H = (h, ¬h) be a hypothesis space associated with a disease and let E and F be two diagnostic tests for H with equal likelihood difference, λ(E) = λ(F ). Then the following holds:</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">u(f ) =</formula><p>(i) If P (¬e|¬h) &gt; P (¬f |¬h), then P (h|e) &gt; P (h|f ); i.e., if E has higher specificity than F , then E has a higher positive predictive value than F .</p><p>(ii) If P (e|h) &gt; P (f |h), then P (¬h|¬e) &gt; P (¬h|¬f ); i.e., if E has higher sensitivity than F , then E has a higher negative predictive value than F .</p><p>Proof. (i) Specificity clause: To prove the first part of this result, we will calculate the posterior P (h|e) as a function of λ, the specificity P (¬e|¬h) and the base rate P (h). We set α = 1 − P (¬e|¬h) = P (e|¬h). Then the sensitivity of E is given by P (e|h) = λ + α. Given this, the posterior probability P (h|e) can be calculated as P (h|e) = P (e|h)P (h) P (e) = P (e|h)P (h) P (e|h)P (h) + P Suppose we have two tests E and F with α 1 = 1 − P (¬e|¬h) and α 2 = 1 − P (¬f |¬h). If P (¬e|¬h) &gt; P (¬f |¬h), that is, if E has higher specificity than F , then α 1 &lt; α 2 . For α 1 &lt; α 2 we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_42">α 1 λ − α 1 λP (h) &lt;α 2 λ − α 2 λP (h) α 1 λ + α 2 λP (h) &lt;α 2 λ + α 1 λP (h) λ 2 P (h) + α 1 λ + α 2 λP (h) + α 1 α 2 &lt;λ 2 P (h) + α 2 λ + α 1 λP (h) + α 1 α 2</formula><p>(λP (h) + α 1 )(λ + α 2 ) &lt;(λP (h) + α 2 )(λ + α 1 ) λ + α 1 λP (h) + α 1 &gt; λ + α 2 λP (h) + α 2 λP (h) + α 1 P (h) λP (h) + α 1 &gt; λP (h) + α 2 P (h) λP (h) + α 2 P (h|e) &gt;P (h|f )</p><p>Thus, for two tests E and F with spec(E) &gt; spec(F ), we have P (h|e) &gt; P (h|f ). (ii) Sensitivity clause: Analogous to the first part of this result, we calculate the posterior P (h|¬e) as a function of λ, the sensitivity P (e|h) and the base rate P (h). We set β = 1 − P (e|h) = P (¬e|h). Then the specificity of E is given by P (¬e|¬h) = λ + β. Calculating the posterior P (h|¬e) yields Suppose we have two tests E and F with β 1 = 1 − P (e|h) and β 2 = 1 − P (f |h). If P (e|h) &gt; P (f |h), that is, if E has higher sensitivity than F , then β &lt; β 2 . For β 1 &lt; β 2 we have β 1 λ(1 − P (h)) &lt;β 2 λ(1 − P (h)) β 1 β 2 + β 1 λ(1 − P (h)) &lt;β 1 β 2 + β 2 λ(1 − P (h))</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">β 1 [β 2 + λ(1 − P (h))] &lt;β 2 [β 1 + λ(1 − P (h))] β 1 β 1 + λ(1 − P (h)) &lt; β 2 β 2 + λ(1 − P (h)) β 1 P (h) β 1 + λ(1 − P (h)) &lt; β 2 P (h) β 2 + λ(1 − P (h)) P (h|¬e) &lt;P (h|¬f )<label>(50)</label></formula><p>Thus, for two tests E and F with sens(E) &gt; sens(F ), we have P (h|¬e) &lt; P (h|¬f ).</p><p>Proof of Result 7. Let H = (h, ¬h) be the hypothesis space associated with a disease and let u be a proper utility function for H. Let E = (e, ¬e) and F = (f, ¬f ) be two diagnostic tests for H, with λ(E) = λ(F ). Then the following holds:</p><p>(i) If P (h) &lt; t x , and P (¬e|¬h) ≥ P (¬f |¬h), we have eu(E) ≥ eu(F ).</p><p>(ii) If P (h) &gt; t x , and P (e|h) ≥ P (f |h), we have eu(E) ≥ eu(F ).</p><p>Proof. Without loss of generality, we can assume that u f p = u f n = 0. We will prove this theorem separately for pairs of useless tests, pairs of useful tests and pairs where one test is useful and one is not.</p><p>Case 1: Suppose we have two useless tests E = (e, ¬e) and F = (f, ¬f ). Then both tests have an expected utility of zero, so it doesn't matter which of the two tests we choose and therefore both (i) and (ii) hold for these two tests.</p><p>Case 2: To prove that the theorem is true for pairs of useful tests, we will show that the expected utility of a test can be calculated from λ(E) and a positive multiple of the test's specificity for P (h) &lt; t x and from λ(E) and a positive multiple of the test's sensitivity for P (h) &gt; t x . Suppose we have a useful diagnostic test E = {e, ¬e}.</p><p>(i) P (h) &lt; t x : For a base rate P (h) below the therapeutic threshold t x , before knowing the test result acting on the hypothesis ¬h that the disease is absent maximizes expected utility. Since test E is useful, we have P (h|e) &gt; t x &gt; P (h|¬e) and the expected utility of E is thus given by eu(E) = utpP (h|e)P (e) + utnP (¬h|¬e)P (¬e) − utnP (¬h)</p><p>By elementary probability calculations we can rewrite eu(E) as </p><p>Note that u tn P (¬h) − u tp P (h) is positive, as P (h) &lt; t x . Thus, the larger the specificity of E, the larger the expected utility.</p><p>(ii) P (h) &gt; t x : For a base rate P (h) above the therapeutic threshold t x , before knowing the test result acting on the hypothesis h that the disease is present maximizes expected utility. Since test E is useful, we have P (h|e) &gt; t x &gt; P (h|¬e) and the expected utility of E is given by eu(E) = utpP (h|e)P (e) + utnP (¬h|¬e)P (¬e) − utpP (h)</p><p>Analogous to case (i), we can rewrite eu(E) as </p><p>Note that u tp P (h) − u tn P (¬h) is positive, as P (h) &gt; t x . Thus, the larger the sensitivity of E, the larger the expected utility.</p><p>Case 3: To show that the theorem is also true for pairs where one test is useful and the other is not, we will prove that it is not possible to find a pair of tests E and F with λ(E) = λ(F ) such that test E is the one with higher specificity or sensitivity respectively, but test E is useless while test F is not.</p><p>(i) P (h) &lt; t x : Suppose we have a pair of diagnostic tests E and F with λ(E) = λ(F ), eu(E) = 0, and eu(F ) &gt; 0, but spec(E) &gt; spec(F ), so that choosing the test with higher specificity would lead to choosing the useless test E instead of the useful test F . According to Result 6 we know that, if E has higher specificity than F , then P (h|e) &gt; P (h|f ). According to Result 2, test F is useful iff P (h|¬f ) &lt; t x &lt; P (h|f ). Since P (h|e) &gt; P (h|f ), P (h|e) has to lie above t x too and since E is a diagnostic test, we know that P (h|¬e) ≤ P (h) ≤ P (h|e). Therefore P (h|¬e) &lt; P (h) &lt; t x &lt; P (h|e)</p><p>and thus E is useful which contradicts the assumption that E is useless. Thus, such a pair of tests does not exist and for every pair E and F with λ(E) = λ(F ), eu(E) = 0, and eu(F ) &gt; 0, we know that spec(E) ≤ spec(F ) and choosing the test with higher specificity entails choosing the test with higher expected utility.</p><p>(ii) P (h) &gt; t x : Suppose we have a pair of diagnostic tests E and F with λ(E) = λ(F ), eu(E) = 0, and eu(F ) &gt; 0, but sens(E) &gt; sens(F ), so that choosing the test with higher sensitivity would lead to choosing the useless test E instead of the useful test F . According to Result 6 we know that, if E has higher sensitivity than F , then P (h|¬e) &lt; P (h|¬f ). According to Result 2, test F is useful iff P (h|¬f ) &lt; t x &lt; P (h|f ). Since P (h|¬e) &lt; P (h|¬f ),P (h|¬e) has to lie below t x too and since E is a diagnostic test, we know that P (h|¬e) ≤ P (h) ≤ P (h|e). Therefore P (h|¬e) &lt; t x &lt; P (h) &lt; P (h|e)</p><p>and thus E is useful which contradicts the assumption that E is useless. Thus, such a pair of tests does not exist and for every pair E and F with λ(E) = λ(F ), eu(E) = 0, and eu(F ) &gt; 0, we know that sens(E) ≤ sens(F ) and choosing the test with higher sensitivity entails choosing the test with higher expected utility.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>as in the bottom left panel of Figure 1, the utility function is improper and it is always (up to a possible tie) better to not treat, no matter what the probability of disease is. If (u tn − u fp )/[(u tn − u fp ) + (u tp − u fn )] ≤ 0, as in the bottom right panel of Figure 1, then the utility function is improper and it is always better to treat. Although improper utility functions may seem trivial mathematically, they could be relevant in real diagnostic contexts. Importantly, if the utility function is improper, not only no single test, but no possible combination of tests, could have positive expected utility gain.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Examples of utility functions. The top row illustrates two proper utility functions. The left panel is based on the pneumonia-related utilities reported in Christensen-<ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Szalanski &amp; Bushyhead (1981)</ref>, which entail a therapeutic threshold of tx = .52. The right panel is based on arbitrary values entailing a therapeutic threshold of tx = .25. These are proper</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>utp u fp u fn utn , we can define a new utility functionu * = u * tp 0 0 u * tn by setting u * tp = u tp − u fn and u * tn = u tn − u fp .While this can change the utility of an individual test result, the expected utility of the test as a whole stays the same. With respect to levels of measurement as traditionally defined, what this means is that utilities need only be measured on an interval scale;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>* ? No: If the individual utility values are multiplied by a constant, the resulting expected utility gain of the test is multiplied by that same constant: Result 3. Let H = {h, ¬h} be a binary hypothesis space associated with a disease and let E = {e, ¬e} be a diagnostic test for H. Let u = utp u fp u fn utn and u = αutp αu fp αu fn αutn , where α &gt; 0, be two utility functions for H. Then the expected utility of test E under u is α times the expected utility of E under u; i.e., eu (E) = α eu(E).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>[</head><label></label><figDesc>u tp P (h)−u tn P (¬h)] is positive in that case. Recall that for P (h) = t x , we have eu(E) = u tn P (¬h)λ(E) =u tp P (h)λ(E).Is this result also true if the tests have different likelihood differences? It is not, as the following counterexample shows. Suppose the prior probability of disease P (h) = 0.50 is larger than the therapeutic threshold t x = 0.15. Suppose further that we have two tests E and F , with P (e|h) = 0.90, P (e|¬h) = 0.45, P (f |h) = 0.84, and P (f |¬h) = 0. Because positive test results increase the probability of disease for both tests, both tests are informative. Test E has higher sensitivity (0.90) than Test F (0.84). But</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Characteristics of randomly generated tests. a) Proportion of randomly generated tests that have positive expected utility gain as a function of the probability of disease P (h) (x axis) and therapeutic threshold tx (y axis). b)Average utility gained from randomly-generated tests. c) Average difference in expected utility gain in pairs of randomly generated tests.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2aand b are based on 10,000 random tests for each combination of P (h) and t x ;Figure 2cis based on 10,000 pairs of random tests for each combination of P (h) and t x . To avoid floating-point errors, only tests with expected utility gain greater than 10 −10 normalized utility units of the form (1−tx) 0 0 tx were deemed to have positive expected utility gain.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3. Similar to Figure 2, we considered every combination of P (h) and t x , each ranging from 0.01, 0.02, ... 0.99. The values plotted are the means from simulations of 10,000 random pairs of tests at each point. In the top row of</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Simulation of various pure information test-selection strategies' performance. a) Probability that the best test is selected from a pair of tests if the LDH, information gain, or probability gain model are used. b) The expected utility gain loss that would be incurred by using the LDH, information gain, or probability gain model, respectively, to select among pairs of tests.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>binarized) tests. Here we consider the case of latent tuberculosis screening tests. According to the World Health Organization, active tuberculosis (TB) is one of the top 10 causes of death worldwide (WHO, 2019, 2020). TB is estimated to have killed 1.5 million people in 2018 and 1.4 million people in 2019 (WHO, 2019, 2020). An important strategy to prevent spread of the disease is to identify individuals with latent tuberculosis infection (LTBI), i.e., individuals who have been infected with Mycobacterium tuberculosis but do not present any radiographic or bacteriologic evidence or symptoms of TB. These individuals are expected to develop active TB at a later stage of their life in approximately 10-12% of</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Difference in expected utility gain of IGRA and TST tests, as a function of P (h) (x axis) and tx (y axis), each ranging from 0.01, 0.02, ... 0.99. a) Expected utility gain of the TST test. b) Expected utility gain of the IGRA test. c)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>* (e) =max[P (h|e)(utp − u fn ), P (¬h|e)(utn − u fp )] − max[P (h)(utp − u fn ), P (¬h)(utn − u fp )] =max[P (h|e)utp + P (¬h|e)u fp , P (¬h|e)utn + P (h|e)u fn ]− max[P (h)utp + P (¬h)u fp , P (¬h)utn + P (h)u fn ] − P (¬h|e)u fp − P (h|e)u fn + P (¬h)u fp + P (h)u fn =u(e) + (P (¬h) − P (¬h|e))u fp + (P (h) − P (h|e))u fn =u(e) + (P (h) − P (h|e))(u fn − u fp )</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>e)u * (e) + P (¬e)u * (¬e) =P (e)[u(e) + (P (h) − P (h|e))(u fn − u fp )] + P (¬e)[u(¬e) + (P (h) − P (h|¬e))(u fn − u fp )] =eu(E) + P (e)(P (h) − P (h|e))(u fn − u fp ) + P (¬e)(P (h) − P (h|¬e))(u fn − u fp ) =eu(E) + [P (e)P (h) − P (e ∧ h) + P (¬e)P (h) − P (¬e ∧ h)](u fn − u fp ) =eu(E) + [(P (e) + P (¬e))P (h) − P (e ∧ h) − P</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Proof of Result 3. Let H = {h, ¬h} be a binary hypothesis space associated with a disease and let E = {e, ¬e} be a diagnostic test for H. Let u = utp u fp u fn utn and u = αutp αu fp αu fn αutn , where α &gt; 0, be two utility functions for H. Then the expected utility of test E under u is α times the expected utility of E under u; i.e., eu (E) = α eu(E). Proof. Since u α•u tp α•u fp α•u fn α•u tn (e) = max[P (h|e)αutp + P (¬h|e)αu fp , P (¬h|e)αutn + P (h|e)αu fn ] − max[P (h)αutp + P (¬h)αu fp , P (¬h)αutn + P (h)αu fn ] = max[α(P (h|e)utp + P (¬h|e)u fp ), α(P (¬h|e)utn + P (h|e)u fn )] − max[α(P (h)utp + P (¬h)u fp ), α(P (¬h)utn + P (h)u fn )] = α • max[P (h|e)utp + P (¬h|e)u fp , P (¬h|e)utn + P (h|e)u fn ] − α • max[P (h)utp + P (¬h)u fp , P (¬h)utn + P (h)u fn )]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>is independent from test E as it is only affected by the prior probability and the utilities. Let us first look at the utilities of test results e and ¬e. The test results are labeled such that P (h|e) ≥ P (h) and thus P (¬h|e) ≤ P (¬h), by which P (h|e)utp ≥ P (h)utp = P (¬h)utn ≥ P (¬h|e)utn(16)This, in turn, implies u(e) = max[P (h|e)utp, P (¬h|e)utn] − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn] = P (h|e)utp − β (17)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>P</head><label></label><figDesc>(¬h|¬e)utn ≥ P (¬h)utn = P (h)utp ≥ P (h|¬e)utp (18) which in turn implies u(¬e) = max[P (¬h|¬e)utn, P (h|¬e)utp] − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn] = P (¬h|¬e)utn − β (19)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>=</head><label></label><figDesc>[P (h|e)utp − β]P (e) + [P (¬h|¬e)utn − β]P (¬e) =P (h|e)P (e)utp + P (¬h|¬e)P (¬e)utn − β[P (e) + P (¬e)]=P (e|h)P (h)utp + P (¬e|¬h)P (¬h)utn − β =βP (e|h) + βP (¬e|¬h) − β =βP (e|h) + β − βP (e|¬h) − β =βλ(E)Proof of Result 5. Let H = {h, ¬h} be a hypothesis space associated with a disease and let u be a proper set of utility values for H with corresponding therapeutic threshold t x . Then if P (h) = t x , there exist tests E and F such that λ(E) &gt; λ(F ) while eu(E) &lt; eu(F ).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>u(e) =max[P (h|e)utp, P (¬h|e)utn] − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn] =P (¬h|e)utn − P (¬h)utn (29)Putting all the foregoing together:eu(E) =u(e)P (e) + u(¬e)P (¬e) =[P (¬h|e)utn − P (¬h)utn]P (e) + [P (¬h|¬e)utn − P (¬h)utn]P (¬e) =[P (¬h|e)P (e) − P (¬h)P (e) + P (¬h|¬e)P (¬e) − P (¬h)P (¬e)]utn =[P (¬h) − P (¬h)]utn = 0 (30)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>h|f )utpP (f ) + P (¬h|¬f )utnP (¬f ) − P (¬h)utn &gt;P (¬h|f )utnP (f ) + P (¬h|¬f )utnP (¬f ) − P (¬h)utn P (h|f )utpP (f ) + P (¬h|¬f )utnP (¬f ) − P (¬h)utn &gt;0 P (h|f )utpP (f ) + P (¬h|¬f )utnP (¬f ) − P (¬h)utn(P (f ) + P (¬f )) &gt;0 u(f )P (f ) + u(¬f )P (¬f ) &gt;0 eu(F ) &gt;0 (34)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>u(¬e) =max[P (h|¬e)utp, P (¬h|¬e)utn] − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn] = P (h|¬e)utp − P (h)utp (42)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>max[P (h|f )utp, P (¬h|f )utn] − max[P (h)utp, P (¬h)utn] = P (h|f )utp − P (h)utp (44)But on the other hand, because P (¬f |h) = 0:P (h|¬f ) = P (¬f |h)P (h) P (¬e|h)P (h)+P (¬f |¬h)P (¬h) = 0 &lt; u tn u tp +u tn = tx(45)So P (h|¬f ) &lt; t x , and thus P (h|¬f )u tp &lt; P (¬h|¬f )u tn , thereforeP (h|f )utpP (f ) + P (¬h|¬f )utnP (¬f ) − P (h)utp &gt;P (h|f )utpP (f ) + P (h|¬f )utpP (¬f ) − P (h)utp P (h|f )utpP (f ) + P (¬h|¬f )utnP (¬f ) − P (h)utp &gt;0 P (h|f )utpP (f ) + P (¬h|¬f )utnP (¬f ) − P (h)utp(P (f ) + P (¬f )) &gt;0 u(f )P (f ) + u(¬f )P (¬f ) &gt;0 eu(F ) &gt;0 (46)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(e|¬h)P (¬h)= (λ + α)P (h) (λ + α)P (h) + α(1 − P (h)) = λP (h) + αP (h) λP (h) + αP (h) + α − αP (h)) = λP (h) + αP (h) λP (h) + α(47)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>)P (h) + P (¬e|¬h)P (¬h)= βP (h) βP (h) + (β + λ)(1 − P (h)) = βP (h) βP (h) + β + λ − βP (h) − λP (h) = βP (h) β + λ(1 − P (h))(49)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_25"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>eu(E) = utpP (e|h)P (h) + utnP (¬e|¬h)P (¬h) − utn[P (e|¬h) + P (¬e|¬h)]P (¬h)= utpP (e|h)P (h) − utn[P (e|¬h)P (¬h) = utpP (h)[1 − P (¬e|h)] − utnP (¬h)[1 − P (¬e|¬h)] = utpP (h) − utpP (h)P (¬e|h) − utnP (¬h) + utnP (¬h)P (¬e|¬h)(52)We can rewrite P (¬e|h) as 1 − P (e|h) = P (¬e|¬h) + P (e|¬h) − P (e|h) = spec(E) − λ(E) (53)This yields:eu(E) = utpP (h) − utpP (h)[spec(E) − λ(E)] − utnP (¬h) + utnP (¬h)spec(E) = utpP (h)λ(E) + spec(E)[utnP (¬h) − utpP (h)] + utpP (h) − utnP (¬h) = utpP (h)λ(E) + [spec(E) − 1][utnP (¬h) − utpP (h)]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_26"><head>=</head><label></label><figDesc>utpP (e|h)P (h) + utnP (¬e|¬h)P (¬h) − utp[P (e|h) + P (¬e|h)]P (h) = utnP (¬e|¬h)P (¬h) − utpP (¬e|h)P (h) = utnP (¬h)[1 − P (e|¬h)] − utpP (h)[1 − P (e|h)] = utnP (¬h) − utnP (¬h)P (e|¬h) − utpP (h) + utpP (h)P (e|h) = utnP (¬h) − utnP (¬h)[sens(E) − λ(E)] − utpP (h) + utpP (h)sens(E) = utnP (¬h)λ(E) + sens(E)[utpP (h) − utnP (¬h)] + utnP (¬h) − utpP (h) = utnP (¬h)λ(E) + [sens(E) − 1][utpP (h) − utnP (¬h)]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>are examples of epistemic utility functions. Under what conditions-if any-can pure-information test-selection strategies identify the highestutility test? We analyze the Likelihood Difference Heuristic (LDH;</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Terminology, Definitions, and Related Terms from the Medical Decision Making and Signal Detection Literature.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Term</cell><cell cols="2">Definition Explanation</cell><cell></cell><cell>Related Terms</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Prior probability P (h)</cell><cell cols="2">A priori probability of the disease being</cell><cell>Base rate, prevalence of disease, pre-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>present (with P (¬h) = 1 − P (h))</cell><cell></cell><cell>test probability</cell></row><row><cell>Diagnostic test</cell><cell>E</cell><cell cols="2">A test labeled such that a positive outcome e</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">is positively associated (if at all) with disease,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>i.e., P (h|e) ≥ P (h) and P (h|¬e) ≤ P (h)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Likelihoods</cell><cell>P (e|h)</cell><cell>Likelihood of positive test given disease</cell><cell></cell><cell>True positive rate, sensitivity sens(E)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>P (e|¬h)</cell><cell>Likelihood of positive test given no disease</cell><cell></cell><cell>False positive rate, 1 − spec(E)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>P (¬e|h)</cell><cell>Likelihood of negative test given disease</cell><cell></cell><cell>False negative rate, 1 − sens(E)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>P (¬e|¬h)</cell><cell cols="2">Likelihood of negative test given no disease</cell><cell>True negative rate, specificity spec(E)</cell></row><row><cell>Posterior</cell><cell>P (h|e)</cell><cell cols="2">Posterior probability of disease given positive</cell><cell>Positive predictive value</cell></row><row><cell>probabilities</cell><cell></cell><cell>test</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>P (¬h|e)</cell><cell cols="2">Posterior probability of no disease given pos-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>itive test</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>P (h|¬e)</cell><cell cols="2">Posterior probability of disease given negative</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>test</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>P (¬h|¬e)</cell><cell cols="2">Posterior probability of no disease given neg-</cell><cell>Negative predictive value</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ative test</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Likelihood</cell><cell>λ(E)</cell><cell cols="2">Difference in outcome likelihoods of a diag-</cell><cell>Difference between the test's true posi-</cell></row><row><cell>difference</cell><cell></cell><cell>nostic test E, P (e|h) − P (e|¬h)</cell><cell></cell><cell>tive rate and false positive rate</cell></row><row><cell>Utilities</cell><cell>utp</cell><cell cols="2">Utility of treating a person with a true posi-</cell><cell>Utility for a "hit"</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>tive test</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ufp</cell><cell cols="2">Utility of treating a person with a false posi-</cell><cell>Utility for a "false alarm"</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>tive test</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ufn</cell><cell cols="2">Utility of not treating a person with a false</cell><cell>Utility for a "miss"</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>positive test</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>utn</cell><cell cols="2">Utility of not treating a person with a true</cell><cell>Utility for a "correct rejection"</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>negative test</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Utility of test</cell><cell>u(e)</cell><cell>Utility gained from a positive test result</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>result</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>u(¬e)</cell><cell>Utility gained from a negative test result</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Expected utility</cell><cell>eu(E)</cell><cell>Average utility gained from test E.</cell><cell>If</cell></row><row><cell>of test</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">eu(E) &gt; 0 then E is a useful test. The best</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">test is the test that has highest expected util-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ity gain among available tests.</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Outcome-based utilities assigned by a sample of physicians for treating pneumonia<ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Christensen-Szalanski &amp; Bushyhead, 1981)</ref>. The numbers represent the assigned mean value for each combination of pneumonia diagnosis and true state of nature, on a scale from -50 ("worst thing I could do") to +50 ("best thing I could do"). These utilities give a therapeutic threshold tx = (41 − (−26))/[(41 − (−26)) + (40 − (−22))] ≈ .52.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Approximate Likelihoods of LTBI Screening TestsTestSensitivity Specificity P (e|h) P (e|¬h) LikDiff λ</figDesc><table><row><cell>TST</cell><cell>88%</cell><cell>90%</cell><cell>.88</cell><cell>.10</cell><cell>.78</cell></row><row><cell>IGRA</cell><cell>85%</cell><cell>98%</cell><cell>.85</cell><cell>.02</cell><cell>.83</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Gerd Gigerenzer, Rob Hamm, Laura Martignon and Shenghua Luan for very helpful ideas and comments. This research was supported by grants NE 1713/2 to JDN, ME 3717/2 to BM, and CR 409/1-2 to VC and KT from the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG) as part of the priority program "New Frameworks of Rationality" (SPP 1516), and by a MIUR grant FIRB D11J12000470001 to VC.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diagnosis of latent tuberculosis: Can we do better?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Al-Orainey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Thoracic Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The use of &quot;overall accuracy&quot; to evaluate the validity of screening or diagnostic tests</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Alberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Brock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Diener-West</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of General Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="460" to="465" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Seeking confirmation is rational for deterministic hypotheses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Austerweil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="526" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rationality and intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, England</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Beattie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hershey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Heuristics and biases in diagnostic reasoning: II</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Congruence, information, and certainty. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="88" to="110" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heuristics and biases in diagnostic reasoning: I. Priors, error costs, and test accuracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hershey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="279" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An essay towards solving a problem in the doctrine of chance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="296" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="1763" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Biometrika</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relative entropy as a measure of diagnostic information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Benish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medical Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="202" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mutual information as an index of diagnostic test performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Benish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Methods of Information in Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="264" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implications of the impact of prevalence on test thresholds and outcomes: lessons from tuberculosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Bentley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Catanzaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ganiats</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BMC Research Notes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conservative forgetful scholars: How people learn causal structure through sequences of interventions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bramley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Speekenbrink</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="708" to="731" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The method of multiple working hypotheses. textitScience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Chamberlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1890" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="96" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A probabilistic contrast model of causal induction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Novick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="567" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Physcians&apos; use of probabilistic information in a real clinical setting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J J</forename><surname>Christensen-Szalanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bushyhead</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="928" to="935" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asking the right questions about human inquiry: Nine open challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Coenen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gureckis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin and Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1548" to="1587" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized information theory meets human cognition: Introducing a unified framework to model uncertainty and information search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Crupi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cevolani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tentori</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1410" to="1456" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pseudodiagnosticity revisited</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Crupi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tentori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lombardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="971" to="985" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When is rational to order a diagnostic test, or prescribe treatment: the threshold model as an explanation of practice variation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Djulbegovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Van Den Ende</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hamm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mayrhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Hozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Pauker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Clinical Investigation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">485493</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>for the International Threshold Working Group (ITWG)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the optimality of the simple Bayesian classifier under zero-one loss</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pazzani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="130" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Domurat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Kowalczuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Idzikowska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Borzymowska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nowak-Przygodzka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian probability estimates are not necessary to make choices satisfying Bayes&apos; rule in elementary situations</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1194</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ongoing challenge of latent tuberculosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Esmail</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Barry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wilkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Esmail</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Barry 3rd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wilkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1645" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The ongoing challenge of latent tuberculosis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ventral striatum dissociates information expectation, reward anticipation, and reward receipt</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Filimon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sejnowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Sereno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cottrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the USA</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15200" to="15208" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An active testing model for tracking roads in satellite images</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Geman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Jedynak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-based classification trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Geman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Jedynak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Information Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1075" to="1082" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heuristic decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gaissmaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="482" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to improve Bayesian reasoning without instruction: Frequency formats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Hoffrage</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="684" to="704" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Probability and the weight of evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Good</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1950" />
			<publisher>Griffin</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the principle of total evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Good</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="321" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diagnostic process with special reference to errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Good</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Card</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Methods of Information in Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Signal detection theory and psychophysics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Swets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-directed learning: A cognitive and computational perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gureckis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Markant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="464" to="481" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A balance beam aid for instruction in clinical diagnostic reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hamm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Beasley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medical Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="854" to="862" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using natural frequencies to improve diagnostic inferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Hoffrage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academic Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="538" to="540" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constructing optimal binary decision trees is NP complete</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hyafil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rivest</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Processing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Naive and robust: Class-conditional independence in human classification learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Jarecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prevalence of latent tuberculosis infection and associated risk factors among 3,374 healthcare students in Italy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lamberti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Muoio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G L</forename><surname>Monaco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Uccello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sannolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mazzarella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garzillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Arnese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>La Cerra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Coppola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Occupational Medicine and Toxicology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mr. Chips: an ideal-observer model of reading</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Legge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Klitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tjan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="524" to="553" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategies for selecting and evaluating information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Liefgreen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pilditch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">101332</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On a measure of the information provided by an experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lindley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Annals of Mathematical Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="986" to="1005" />
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a unified theory of decision criterion learning in perceptual categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maddox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="567" to="595" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Base-rate and payoff effects in multidimensional perceptual categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maddox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bohil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1459" to="1482" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theoretical framework for understanding the effects of simultaneous base-rate and payoff manipulations on decision criterion learning in perceptual categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maddox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bohil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="320" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does the utility of information influence sampling behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Markant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gureckis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 34th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<editor>N. Miyake, D. Peebles, &amp; R. P. Cooper</editor>
		<meeting>the 34th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society<address><addrLine>Austin, TX</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cognitive Science Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="719" to="724" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is it better to select or to receive? Learning via active and passive hypothesis testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Markant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gureckis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">143</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="94" to="122" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Updated guidelines for using interferon gamma release assays to detect Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection -United States</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Mazurek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jereb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vernon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Lobue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Castro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MMWR Recommendations and Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">125</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>RR-5</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural frequencies do foster public understanding of medical tests: Comment on Pighin</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mcdowell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Galesic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Savadori</forename><surname>Gonzalez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Girotto</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medical Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="390" to="399" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What makes a good query? Prospects for a comprehensive theory of human information acquisition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Crupi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/9rpbw</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/9rpbw" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information search with situation-specific reward functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="148" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stepwise versus globally optimal search in children and adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ruggeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">103965</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Waiting and weighting: Information sampling is a balance between efficiency and error-reduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Meier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">126</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="325" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the pathologies of orthodox statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Minka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/publication/pathologies-orthodox-statistics/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-10-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal experimental design for model discrimination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Myung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">499518</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal eye movement strategies in visual search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Najemnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Geisler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">434</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="391" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural representation of information measure in the primate premotor cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Nakamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="478" to="485" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding useful questions: on Bayesian diagnosticity, probability, impact, and information gain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="979" to="999" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Children&apos;s sequential information search is sensitive to environmental probabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Divjak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gudmundsdottir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Martignon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="74" to="80" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experience matters: information acquisition optimizes probability gain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R M</forename><surname>Mckenzie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cottrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sejnowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="960" to="969" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Towards a theory of heuristic and optimal planning for sequential information search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/bxdf4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/bxdf4" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The prospects for psychological science in human-computer interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Card</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="242" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tuberculosis in healthcare workers a narrative review from a German perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nienhaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schablon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Preisser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ringshausen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Diel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Occupational Medicine and Toxicology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Philosophical Explanations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nozick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A rational analysis of the selection task as optimal data selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Oaksford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="608" to="631" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Therapeutic decision making: a cost-benefit analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Pauker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kassirer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New England Journal of Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">293</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="234" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The threshold approach to clinical decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Pauker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kassirer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New England Journal of Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">302</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1109" to="1117" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Logic of Scientific Discovery</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Popper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Basic books</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Children adapt their questions to achieve efficient search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ruggeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lombrozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">143</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The foundations of statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk of latent TB infection in individuals employed in the healthcare sector in Germany: a multicentre prevalence study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schablon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Harling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Diel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nienhaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BMC Infectious Diseases</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Applied statistical decision theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Schlaifer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Raiffa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New nonadditive measures of entropy for discrete probability distributions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mittal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Sciences (Delhi)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A mathematical theory of communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Shannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bell System Technical Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379423" to="623656" />
			<date type="published" when="1948" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information-gathering processes: Diagnosticity, hypothesisconfirmatory strategies, and perceived hypothesis confirmation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Skov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information selection and use in hypothesis testing: What is a good question, and what is a good answer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Slowiaczek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Klayman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Skov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="392" to="405" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interferon-gamma release assays for diagnosis of latent tuberculosis infection: evidence in immune-mediated inflammatory disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cattamanchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Steingart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Denkinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Dheda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Winthrop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Rheumatology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="377" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Calculation of signal detection theory measures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stanislaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods, Instruments and Computers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The science of choosing the right decision threshold in high-stakes diagnostics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Swets</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="522" to="532" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inferring causal networks from observations and interventions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Blum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="489" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical decision theory and trade-offs in the control of motor response</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Spatial Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">255</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">275</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical decision theory and rapid, goaldirected movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Optical Society of America</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">14191433</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">QALYs: The Basics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Weinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Torrance</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mcguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Value in Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On estimating the diagnosticity of eyewitness nonidentifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="776" to="784" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/329368/9789241565714-eng.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Health Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-02-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Global Tuberculosis Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Global Tuberculosis Report 2020</title>
		<ptr target="https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/336069/9789240013131-eng.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Health Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-08-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asking better questions: How presentation formats influence information search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Filimon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1274" to="1297" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Prevalence and risk factors for latent tuberculosis infection among health care workers in China: a</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
