<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Registered Report on Gender Bias in Interpersonal Dishonesty: Are Females and Males Cheated Differently?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jareef</forename><surname>Martuza</surname></persName>
							<email>jareef.martuza@nhh.no</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Strategy and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Norwegian School of Economics</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Bergen</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Dalgleish, T</roleName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Feldmanhall</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Navrady, L., Tedeschi, E</roleName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mobbs</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Tanner, C</roleName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<postCode>19485506241285079</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Behavioral and Social Sciences and Education, &amp; National Academies of Sciences, Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Committee on Measuring Sex, Gender Identity, and Sexual Orientation, Committee on National Statistics</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">European Economic Association</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>11(3), 525-547</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<address>
									<addrLine>10(5), 632-642</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="laboratory">American Economic Review</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>103(1), 532-548</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Registered Report on Gender Bias in Interpersonal Dishonesty: Are Females and Males Cheated Differently?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1177/19485506241285079</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Gender bias</term>
					<term>dishonesty</term>
					<term>moral typecasting and Medicine. (2022). Measuring Sex, Gender Identity, and Sexual Orientation (N. Bates, M. Chin, &amp; T. Becker, Eds.</term>
					<term>p. 26424). National Academies Press</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The study complies with all relevant ethical regulations regarding human research participants, including the guidelines from the Helsinki Declaration. As Norwegian laws and regulations do not require review by an institutional review board for anonymous, non-medical, lowrisk research with human participants, we did not submit the project to such a review. Informed consent was collected from all participants. No personally identifiable information was collected. The approved protocol after Stage 1 acceptance in principle was registered on the OSF here: https://osf.io/n5j43. All codes, data, and study materials from the experiment are available on the Open Science Framework (OSF) repository here: https://osf.io/425jd/?view_only=909603420693437f8dbaca3a6659f191. The data collection of the research was made possible with funding from the Distribusjonsøkonomiske forskningsprosjekter (Distribution economics research project) at NHH. For this, I sincerely thank Professors Sven A. Haugland, Aksel I. Rokkan, Vidar Schei, and Helge Thorbjørnsen. I am especially grateful to the Action Editor Alexa Tullet and two anonymous reviewers for helpful feedback throughout the peer review process. This research also benefitted from comments and suggestions by Esra Aslan, Hege Landsvik, and Denise Utochkin during the initial stages.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, dishonest behavior refers to lying to benefit the self at the cost of another entity, also known as "cheating" <ref type="bibr">(Jiang, 2013)</ref>. It has been well-documented in psychology and behavioral economics that both material self-interest and moral standards influence individual dishonesty <ref type="bibr">(Gibson et al., 2013)</ref>. Indeed, people do not cheat to the maximum when incentivized, basically leaving money on the table even when their decisions are completely anonymous <ref type="bibr">(Gerlach et al., 2019)</ref>. This suggests that individuals may have an internal "moral cost" of lying <ref type="bibr">(Kajackaite &amp; Gneezy, 2017)</ref>, which restrains dishonest pursuits of self-interest, even when there are zero risks of detection, punishment, or reputational consequences <ref type="bibr">(Gneezy et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Thielmann &amp; Hilbig, 2019)</ref>. This internal force can be viewed as the "moral cost" of dishonesty that promotes honest behavior even when there are no repercussions for dishonest behavior. Recent research hints that this moral cost of dishonesty is not fixed, but may vary depending on "at whose cost" the gains of dishonesty are attained. For example, when tempted with identical risk-free gains through dishonest behavior, individuals are less likely to cheat another person than an organization <ref type="bibr">(Soraperra et al., 2019</ref>), a small organization than a large organization <ref type="bibr">(Martuza et al., 2023)</ref>, and a harmless corporation than a harmful corporation <ref type="bibr">(Rotman et al., 2018)</ref>. These findings suggest that the mere characteristics of the target can play an important role when individuals face trade-offs between economic incentives and moral standards. At the intersection of gender and dishonesty research, although a meta-analysis on rates of dishonesty across experimental paradigms suggests that males are more dishonest than females on average <ref type="bibr">(Gerlach et al., 2019)</ref>, it remains unclear how the sex of the target can influence dishonesty against them.</p><p>In the social context, whether one's interaction partner is male or female is one of the first things an individual notices. Sex is an ever-present category people are socialized to notice from a young age <ref type="bibr">(Eagly, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Perales et al., 2023)</ref>. So, whether there is a gender bias in interpersonal dishonesty is important to examine because gender prescriptions and proscriptions apply not only to how men and women behave themselves but also to how people behave toward men and women <ref type="bibr">(Kosakowska-Berezecka et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kray et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Prentice &amp; Carranza, 2002)</ref>. Indeed, gender bias is quite pervasive in society <ref type="bibr">(Georgeac et al., 2019)</ref>, from affecting how people form impressions <ref type="bibr">(Oh et al., 2020)</ref> to how they judge music <ref type="bibr">(Boghrati &amp; Berger, 2023)</ref>. So much so, recent research shows that the target's gender can even shift the altruistic preferences of decision-makers even when all other external influences are held constant <ref type="bibr">(FeldmanHall et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Graso et al., 2023)</ref>.</p><p>In this registered report, the primary hypothesis predicted a gender 1 bias in interpersonal dishonesty: Decision-makers will be more dishonest against male targets than female targets (Hypothesis 1). This was informed by the moral typecasting theory <ref type="bibr">(Gray &amp; Wegner, 2009)</ref>, gender stereotypes <ref type="bibr">(Bem, 1974)</ref>, and gender bias in moral typecasting in itself <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Reynolds et al., 2020</ref>).</p><p>1 Gendered perceptions are often conflated with that based on biological sex <ref type="bibr">(Cameron &amp; Stinson, 2019</ref>). In the current research, we examine the role of the target's sex (how males and females are cheated differently) and NOT gender (how men and women are cheated differently). Sex is a biological descriptor based on reproductive, hormonal, anatomical, and genetic characteristics; and gender is a social construct encompassing gender identity, roles, expressions, behaviors, and attributes associated with certain sex traits (Committee on Measuring Sex, Gender Identity, and Sexual Orientation et al., 2022).</p><p>However, it is worth noting that part of previous research on informing our theoretical framework is based on gender research that implied biological male vs. female comparisons. So, when referencing those works, our paper stays consistent in how the original authors framed their comparisons (men vs. women). Moreover, biases toward males and females have been conceptualized as gender bias and not sex bias (e.g., gender bias in moral typecasting <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Reynolds et al., 2020)</ref>).</p><p>People's tendency to perceive men as moral agents who are less deserving of protection from harm, and women as moral patients who require protection <ref type="bibr">(Graso et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Reynolds et al., 2020)</ref> forms the basis of the prediction that people will cheat males more than females. The secondary hypothesis predicted that the sex of the decision-maker will moderate the aforementioned effect: Male decisionmakers will be more dishonest against male (vs. female) targets than female decision-makers will against other male (vs. female) targets (Hypothesis 2). This prediction was drawn from empirical evidence showing males are particularly more prone to condone the mistreatment of other males <ref type="bibr">(Arnestad et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Owuamalam &amp; Matos, 2022)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dishonesty against males and females</head><p>According to the moral typecasting theory <ref type="bibr">(Gray &amp; Wegner, 2009)</ref>, observers categorize others in social interactions as moral agents or patients. Those categorized as agents are considered more as capable performers and less as recipients of actions; whereas those classified as patients are considered more as recipients and less as performers of actions. This categorization of a moral dyad is mutually exclusive, such that in a given interaction, agentic characteristics of an interaction partner can make it easier to see them as a moral agent and less as a moral patient, and vice versa <ref type="bibr">(Gray &amp; Wegner, 2009)</ref>. In case of targets of moral harm-such as being cheated in an interpersonal interaction-decision-makers may typecast the target as an agentic moral perpetrator or a vulnerable moral victim depending on the characteristics of the target. Because of mutual exclusivity in a moral dyad, agentic perpetrators are perceived to be less capable of feeling pain whereas vulnerable victims are perceived to be more sensitive to feeling pain <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Reynolds et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Shepherd et al., 2019)</ref>. This greater vulnerability perception of a target can evoke greater moral concerns <ref type="bibr">(Dijker, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Gray &amp; Wegner, 2009)</ref>. Indeed, differences in vulnerability perceptions have been shown to explain why big businesses are more likely to be cheated than small businesses <ref type="bibr">(Martuza et al., 2023)</ref>. Similarly, differences in vulnerability perceptions of males and females suggest the possibility of a gendered bias in interpersonal dishonesty as well. Across history and cultures, gender stereotypes depict men as dominant, independent, and aggressive, whereas women as tender, vulnerable, and pain-sensitive <ref type="bibr">(Bem, 1974)</ref>. In the moral domain, people are systematically more accepting of harm befalling males than females <ref type="bibr">(Graso et al., 2023)</ref>, and are less outraged by the same transgression against males than females <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Reynolds et al., 2020)</ref>. Accordingly, many societies have instilled a heuristic that females should be protected from harm <ref type="bibr">(Graso et al., 2023)</ref>. A meta-analysis shows that females are more likely to receive help than their male counterparts <ref type="bibr">(Eagly &amp; Crowley, 1986)</ref>. Even in simple allocation choices, the gender of the recipient seems to play a role, with female players being allocated more money than male players in the Dictator game <ref type="bibr">(Saad &amp; Gill, 2001</ref>). Contrarily, men are thought to experience less pain <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Reynolds et al., 2020)</ref>, sacrificed more in trolley dilemmas <ref type="bibr">(FeldmanHall et al., 2016)</ref>, and are blamed more for their academic underperformance (Cappelen et al., 2019).</p><p>These findings suggest that people deem it more acceptable for males than females to incur the costs of negative treatment, which may spill over to dishonesty against them as well. Because if the average individual is more accepting of (Graso et al., 2023) and less outraged by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Reynolds et al., 2020</ref>) the same harm when it befalls males than females, the potential of cheating males may evoke a lesser feeling of wrongness. Much of people's moral decisions are based on what intuitively feels more or less right and wrong <ref type="bibr">(Greene &amp; Haidt, 2002)</ref>, and cheating females may feel more intuitively wrong than males. In our context, moral typecasting theory would predict that individuals may be more likely to cheat those they perceive as moral agents (i.e., males) and less likely to cheat those they perceive as moral patients (i.e., females). Then, when faced with the decision to cheat another male or female person, differences in the cognitive ease of seeing males and females as vulnerable victims might lead to systematic differences in cheating preferences against male and female targets.</p><p>Formally, we hypothesized: H1. Decision-makers will be more dishonest against male targets than female targets.</p><p>Counter to the primary hypothesis H1, there are reasons to expect females to be cheated more than males. Throughout history, it has been females who have been biased against more-such as being denied the right to vote, own property, and receive higher education. Bias against females persists across societies and domains, disadvantaging women in hiring processes <ref type="bibr">(Moss-Racusin et al., 2012)</ref>, job promotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Régner et al., 2019)</ref>, and media coverage <ref type="bibr">(Shor et al., 2019)</ref>. In a related domain, underperforming women are more likely to be given upwardly distorted feedback, and these white lies deprive women of the same quality of feedback as men (Jampol &amp; Zayas, 2021).</p><p>Moreover, research also suggests that negotiators believe women to be easier to mislead than men, leading to them being more likely to use deception toward women in negotiations <ref type="bibr">(Kray et al., 2014)</ref>. However, differences in cheating preferences across the target's sex in the negotiation context may be due to differences in perceived risks, such as expected retaliation from targets of cheating, which may be higher for male and female targets. However, our proposed experiment allows participants to cheat another male, female, or unmentioned-sex participant without any detection, punishment, or reputational consequences. So, we can delineate if people would be differently likely to cheat males or females when the target's sex is the only difference.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The role of the decision-maker's sex</head><p>The secondary hypothesis predicted an interaction effect: the sex of the decision-maker will moderate the effect of the target's sex on cheating such that male decision-makers will be more dishonest against other males (vs. females) than female decision-makers will other males (vs. females). This hypothesized moderation effect was informed by multiple streams of empirical evidence. Research suggests males (vs. females) are more biased in downplaying the harm inflicted on other males (Arnestad et al., 2020; Owuamalam &amp; Matos, 2022), suggesting an asymmetry of the effect across the sex of decision-makers. For example, although female participants judged maleaggressor-female-victim and female-aggressor-male-victim sexual harassment cases as equally bad, whereas male participants judged the male-aggressor-female-victim more negatively than femaleaggressor-male-victim, suggesting the trivialization of harm inflicted on male victims may be driven by male judgers (Arnestad et al., 2020). Moreover, when cued to the masculinity of homosexual male victims of a hate crime, heterosexual males downplayed their compassion for the victims <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Owuamalam &amp; Matos, 2022</ref>), suggesting the masculinity signals can typecast the target as less vulnerable, and thereby reduce moral concerns (Dijker, 2010). Furthermore, males (vs. females) scoring higher than women in benevolent sexism <ref type="bibr">(Glick &amp; Fiske, 1996)</ref> suggests that males may also be more likely to typecast females as victims who need to be protected <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Reynolds et al., 2020)</ref>, and thereby males (vs. females) may find it especially less acceptable to cheat females. Formally, we hypothesized:</p><p>H2. Male decision-makers will be more dishonest against male (vs. female) targets than female decision-makers will other male (vs. female) targets.</p><p>Nonetheless, research also suggests that females may be more favorable to other females than males may be to other males <ref type="bibr">(Rudman &amp; Goodwin, 2004</ref>), suggesting gendered in-group favoritism among females only. This in-group favoritism view would predict that females may also be especially less likely to cheat other females over males. So, it may be so that the decision-maker and target's sex interaction effect is not driven by male decision-makers (as opposed to originally hypothesized), but by female decision-makers instead.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>A large-scale, incentivized, and nine-country experiment examined two questions: (1) Are individuals more likely to cheat males or females? and (2) Are the effects symmetrical across the decision-maker's own sex and attitudes? To measure behavioral dishonesty, participants were tempted to cheat another same-sex or opposite-sex participant, with no risk of detection, punishment, or reputational consequences, in a modified "mind game" (Agneman &amp; Chevrot-Bianco, 2023;</p><p>Fischbacher &amp; Föllmi-Heusi, 2013; Jiang, 2013) task.</p><p>In a between-subjects design, an equal number of male and female participants were randomly assigned to one of three conditions depending on the disclosed sex of the paired participant serving as a target: male, female, or unmentioned. All participants were recruited through Prolific, a crowdsourcing survey platform that provides non-identifiable data and meets the high standards of GDPR. Bonus pay-outs were in addition to base payments for participation. The approved protocol after Stage 1 acceptance in principle was registered on the OSF here. All codes, data, and study materials from the experiment are available on the Open Science Framework (OSF) repository here.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants and power</head><p>A total of 3,380 complete responses were received from nine countries 2 : Australia, Canada, Germany, Italy, Poland, Portugal, South Africa, the UK, and the USA. Participants were recruited using 1:1 sex-balanced recruitment for English-speaking participants with at least a 95% approval rate for at least 50 submissions, with a quota of 375 complete responses per country. As pre-registered, 212 responses were removed from participants failing an attention check where they were asked to select "A lot" to the question "How much do you like painting?" to show that they were paying attention to instructions.</p><p>Deviating from one pre-registered exclusion criterion, responses deemed "fraudulent" by Qualtrics' metrics could not be removed as the feature was mistakenly not enabled in the Qualtrics file. Nonetheless, because Prolific screens participants when joining the platform and issues a unique participant ID and study completion code to each participant, the chances of duplicate responses are minimal. Finally, 2 responses, from participants who indicated their biological sex being neither male nor female, were removed. This resulted in a dataset with valid responses from 3,166 participants (1573 male and 1578 female; Mean age = 33.09, SD = 11.45). See <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> for achieved cell sizes.</p><p>Sensitivity power analyses using G*POWER <ref type="bibr">(Faul et al., 2007)</ref> showed that the minimal  income, and education, and were told they would be paired with another participant for the task.</p><p>Depending on the condition, participants were told, "You have been paired with another male/ female/ Prolific participant. Your decisions in the task can affect both your own and the male/ female/ Prolific participant's earnings." Participants did not engage in any direct communication or interaction with their pair, but their potential dishonesty could inflict monetary impacts on their pair (e.g., Dimant, 2023). Once the data collection phase was completed, programming in R was used for random assignment of decision-makers to targets based on their sex and experimental conditions, and then lottery payments were carried out accordingly. Please see Section "5. Participant pairing" in the Online Supplement for details regarding participant pairing.</p><p>Dishonesty task. For the measure of interpersonal dishonest behavior, participants completed a 10-round die-rolling task where they could earn up to £60 (in addition to their base payment)depending on their self-reported die scores and luck in the lottery. Participants were also instructed that if their additional earnings are less than £60, the remaining amount will be given to the participant (male, female, or no-sex) they have been paired with. To elicit incentive-aligned choices, participants were told that 40 participants in total will be randomly chosen by lottery, and be paid their additional payoffs within a week of completion of the study.</p><p>On the task page, participants were asked to roll a six-sided die privately (to exclude any detection risk) exactly 10 times and report the scores of the 10 die rolls. They could use a physical die, or simply search "Roll a die" on their browser to roll a virtual die. Then, participants were asked to self-report the 10 scores into a form field with 10 input boxes accepting numbers from 1 to 6. They also confirmed the total sum of reported die scores on a constant-sum double slider question that clearly showed how the decision-making participant's self-reporting can directly affect their own and their paired participant's potential additional earnings, while explicitly showing the male, female, or unmentioned sex signal of the paired participant.</p><p>Of course, participants could over-report the scores of their die rolls, and selfishly increase their earnings at the cost of their interaction partner without any detection, punishment, or reputational concerns. This creates a clear tradeoff between the moral motivation to report truthfully and the financial motivation to over-report scores and increase personal gain. Importantly, the question is, how much participants would over-report, and the amount may be systematically different when paired with male versus female targets. Furthermore, having ten rounds of die-rolls increases sensitivity as individuals not only have a binary decision to report truthfully or dishonestly each round but can also vary levels of dishonesty, over a wider range across the 10 rounds.</p><p>Individual-level measures. After the dishonesty task, participants were asked to what extent they agreed with statements about the morality of their actions ("I believe my actions in the previous task are acceptable."), inference about the paired participant ("I believe the paired X would view my actions as fair."), and beliefs about cheating different sexes in general ("It is equally unacceptable to cheat men or women for money.", "It is more acceptable to cheat men than women for money.", and "It is more acceptable to cheat women than men for money.") presented on slider scales from 0 (Completely disagree) to 10 (Completely agree).</p><p>Participants also responded to three questions on sex, gender, and sexual orientation taken At the end of the survey, participants indicated their agreement to three exploratory measures ("My paired X would have cheated if they were in my shoes", "If I were to cheat my paired participant, I would not feel guilty", and "My paired X would have expected me to cheat them") presented on slider scales from 0 (Completely disagree) to 10 (Completely agree).</p><p>In the aforementioned measurement items, "X" was replaced by a piped-in feature to show "participant", "male participant", or "female participant", depending on the experimental condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Pre-registered analyses. The main outcome variable is the sum of the 10 reported die scores.</p><p>If everyone reports all of their rolls truthfully, the average reported die score should be 3.5 and the mean of the sum of the 10 reported die scores 35 as per statistical expectation. Then, should the mean reported sum of die scores be above 35, we can infer that some participants may have over-reported their die-rolls to cheat their paired participant. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> illustrate mean participant earnings (indicator for dishonesty levels) across targets and decision-makers.  Following the pre-registration, a series of linear mixed-effects models were conducted, with the sum of die scores as outcome, random effects intercept for each country, and fixed effects predictors for experimental conditions. The model-building was incremental: starting with only random effects (Model 1), then adding fixed effects for the target's sex (Model 2), the decisionmaker's sex (Model 3), and finally, the decision-maker X target's sex interaction effect (Model 4). Our primary hypothesis H1 was that male targets would be cheated more than female targets.</p><p>Model 2 shows that male targets were not cheated significantly more than female targets, b = .47, p = .064, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-.03, .97</ref>], suggesting the primary hypothesis H1 is not supported. Rather, neutral targets were cheated significantly more than female targets, b = .51, p = .045, 95% CI [.01, 1.01].</p><p>3 Significant positive (negative) estimates suggest a positive (negative) effect on participant earnings, our indicator dishonesty levels. The reference level for target's sex as the predictor is female, while the reference level for decision-maker's sex as the predictor is male.</p><p>Post hoc tests showed that compared to mean participant earnings when the target was female (M=36.49, SD=5.81), mean earnings was significantly higher when target was neutral (M = 36.91, SD=6.02), t (3163) = 2.01, p = .045, d = .087, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[.002, .173]</ref>, and not significantly different when target was male (M = 36.87, SD = 5.70), t (3163) = 1.85, p = .064, d = .081, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-.002, .166]</ref>. Comparing mean participant earnings against the statistical expectation of £35, estimated dishonesty against female targets was 22% less than against neutral targets 4 .</p><p>Following our preregistration, we conducted a test of equivalence to examine if total earnings were not significantly different at the d = .2 effect size level. The results showed a non-significant TOST upper, t (2108) = -1.08, p = .861, and a significant TOST lower, t (2108) = -2.68, p = .004. As the upper TOST is non-significant at an alpha of .05, we cannot conclusively conclude null effects for Hypothesis 1, a significant TOST lower suggests that males were not cheated less than females.</p><p>Our secondary hypothesis H2 was that male decision-makers would cheat male targets more than they would cheat female targets. Model 4 shows a significant decision-maker [Female] X target</p><p>[Male] interaction effect, b = 1.47, p = .004, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[.47, 2.46]</ref>. However, contrary to H2, the effect was driven by female decision-makers, and not male decision-makers.</p><p>Post hoc tests showed that for female decision-makers, compared to mean participant earnings when the target was female (M=36.03, SD=5.68), mean earnings was significantly higher when target was male (M=37.22, SD=5.55), t (3160) = 3.34, p = . t (3160) = 0.99, p = 320, d = .061, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-.059, .181]</ref>. Following our preregistration, a test of equivalence showed a non-significant TOST upper, t (1032) = -1.30, p = .097, and non-significant TOST lower, t (1032) = -0.21, p = .582. The upper TOST being non-significant at an alpha of 0.05 suggests that the evidence from the experiment does not conclusively support or reject H2.</p><p>Although Hypotheses 1 and 2 are neither supported nor conclusively rejected, this experiment provides some evidence of gender bias in dishonesty, albeit not in the nature originally predicted.</p><p>Rather than male targets being cheated more than female targets, female targets were cheated less than neutral targets. Further, rather than male decision-makers cheating female targets less than male targets, female decision-makers cheated female targets less than they did male targets. 6</p><p>Exploratory analyses. First, a paired samples t-test showed that participants expressed higher agreement with the statement "It is more acceptable to cheat men than women for money" (M = 0.85, SD = 2.03) than the statement "It is more acceptable to cheat women than men for money" (M = 0.52, SD 1.41), t (3165) = 12.66, p &lt; . <ref type="bibr">001,</ref><ref type="bibr">d = .225,</ref><ref type="bibr">95% CI [.190,</ref><ref type="bibr">.260]</ref>. Although the mean agreements are quite low on the 0-10 scale, even in the presence of social desirability and the option to choose "Completely disagree" to both statements, both male and female decision-makers express greater agreement to cheat men than women versus women than men ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>). <ref type="bibr">6</ref> As an additional finding, unlike the results in the meta-analysis by Gerlach and colleagues (2019), male participants also did not cheat significantly more than female participants on average (see Model 3 in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>). Follow-up linear mixed-effects regressions showed that female (vs. male) decision-makers were significantly more likely to report greater acceptability of cheating men more than women (standardized beta = .20, 95% CI [.10, .30]), which was also robust across experimental conditions (see <ref type="table">Table S4</ref> in the Online Supplement for full model statistics). This provides additional support for pro-women bias among female (vs. male) decision-makers to be driving gender bias in interpersonal dishonesty.</p><p>Analyses of the other three exploratory measures revealed a greater lack of guilt at the prospect of cheating males, higher expectations of being cheated by male targets, and stronger beliefs that male targets expect to be cheated. The target and decision-maker sex interactions were not significant (see <ref type="table">Tables S5 and S6</ref>; Online Supplement).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Although individuals cheated female targets significantly less (about 22%) than unmentionedsex targets, male targets were not cheated significantly more than female targets overall, providing no statistically significant support for H1. Contrary to robust findings of gender bias in moral typecasting <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Reynolds et al., 2020)</ref>, moral judgments of harm inflicted <ref type="bibr">(Graso et al., 2023)</ref>, and altruistic preferences (FeldmanHall et al., 2016), we did not find gender-biased behavioral dishonesty across targets on average. This adds to the nascent literature on how the characteristics of the target affect dishonest behavior against them <ref type="bibr">(Rotman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Soraperra et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Yam &amp; Reynolds, 2016)</ref> by showing how an oft-salient signal as sex may not robustly affect interpersonal dishonesty.</p><p>Rather, our results show that gender bias in interpersonal dishonesty across male and female targets is moderated by the decision-maker's sex. Although the significant interaction between the target and decision-maker we found was of a different nature than predicted, it was robustly significant across different inclusion/exclusion of data points (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table S3</ref>; Online Supplement).</p><p>Whereas male decision-makers cheated male and female targets similarly (no support for H2), female decision-makers cheated female (vs. male) targets 53.6% less, echoing classical findings on how females are more favorable to other females than males to other males <ref type="bibr">(Rudman &amp; Goodwin, 2004)</ref>.</p><p>Exploratory self-reported belief measures also support this notion of female ingroup favoritism to underlie gender bias in interpersonal dishonesty (see <ref type="table">Table S4</ref>; Online Supplement). One could speculate that this pattern of results suggests females may be more dishonest toward other males than females for personal monetary gain as an act of retaliation against existing economic gender disparities (e.g., gender pay gap) in society.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations and Future Research</head><p>First, the selection of nine countries was based on the availability of participants on the recruitment platform. So, future research aiming for cross-cultural comparisons may benefit from developing theoretical selection criteria when choosing countries. Second, the current study was a "conservative test" of the hypotheses as participants made decisions toward each other without directly interacting. So, adding interpersonal communication to the honesty task (e.g., Tønnesen et al.,</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>detectable effect size in pairwise t-test with 90% and two-tailed p &lt; .05 ranged from d = .203 to d = .197. 2 The selection of countries was based on those having at least 1,500 active English-speaking participants on Prolific at the time of originally submitting the Stage 1 proposal.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Mean total earnings across decision-maker sex and experimental conditions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Comparative acceptability of cheating male versus female targets.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Final cell sizes.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Target sex</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Male</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Neutral</cell></row></table><note>Participant Pairing. After responding to the attention check, participants indicated their age,</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Means and standard deviations (in parentheses) of participant earnings (in £) across cells.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Target sex</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Male</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Neutral</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Results from linear mixed-effects models on participant earnings from 10 rounds of self-reported die rolls. The table presents the estimated coefficients of predictors (target and decision-maker sex), 95% confidence intervals in parentheses, and p-values for the predictors across models (1-4) 3 .</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Model 1</cell><cell></cell><cell>Model 2</cell><cell></cell><cell>Model 3</cell><cell></cell><cell>Model 4</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Predictors</cell><cell>Estimates (95% CI)</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>Estimates (95% CI)</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>Estimates (95% CI)</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>Estimates (95% CI)</cell><cell>p</cell></row><row><cell>(Intercept)</cell><cell>36.72</cell><cell>&lt;0.001</cell><cell>36.40</cell><cell>&lt;0.001</cell><cell>36.80</cell><cell>&lt;0.001</cell><cell>36.77</cell><cell>&lt;0.001</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(36.52 -36.93)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(36.04 -36.75)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(36.51 -37.09)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(36.27 -37.27)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Target [Male]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell>0.064</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.28</cell><cell>0.449</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(-0.03 -0.97)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(-0.99 -0.44)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Target</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.51</cell><cell>0.045</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.35</cell><cell>0.321</cell></row><row><cell>[Neutral]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.01 -1.01)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(-0.35 -1.06)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Decision-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.15</cell><cell>0.465</cell><cell>-0.74</cell><cell>0.040</cell></row><row><cell>maker</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(-0.56 -0.26)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(-1.44 --0.03)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>[Female]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Decision-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1.47</cell><cell>0.004</cell></row><row><cell>maker</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.47 -2.46)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>[Female] X</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Target [Male]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Decision-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.30</cell><cell>0.561</cell></row><row><cell>maker</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(-0.70 -1.29)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>[Female] X</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Target</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>[Neutral]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Random Effects</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>σ 2</cell><cell>34.24</cell><cell></cell><cell>34.21</cell><cell></cell><cell>34.24</cell><cell></cell><cell>34.13</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>τ00</cell><cell>0.00 Country</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.00 Country</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.00 Country</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.00 Country</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>N</cell><cell>10 Country</cell><cell></cell><cell>10 Country</cell><cell></cell><cell>10 Country</cell><cell></cell><cell>10 Country</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Observations</cell><cell>3166</cell><cell></cell><cell>3166</cell><cell></cell><cell>3166</cell><cell></cell><cell>3166</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Marginal R 2 /</cell><cell>0.000 / NA</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.002 / NA</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.000 / NA</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.005 / NA</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Conditional R 2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>https://doi.org/10.1257/aer.103.1.532 Glick, P., &amp; Fiske, S. T. (1996). The Ambivalent Sexism Inventory: Differentiating hostile and benevolent sexism. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 70(3), 491-512.   https://doi.org/10.1037491-512.   https://doi.org/10. /0022-3514.70.3.491   Gneezy, U. (2005. Deception: The Role of Consequences. American Economic Review, 95(1), 384-394. https://doi.org/10.1257/0002828053828662 Graso, M., Reynolds, T., &amp; Aquino, K. (2023) Oh, D., Dotsch, R., Porter, J., &amp; Todorov, A. (2020). Gender biases in impressions from faces:</p><p>Empirical studies and computational models. Journal of Experimental Psychology: General,</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xge0000638</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0000638" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="342" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heterosexual men in Trump&apos;s America downplay compassion more for masculine (than for feminine) gay victims of hate crime: Why?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Owuamalam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Matos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/ejsp.2787</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/ejsp.2787" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="280" to="304" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Like Father, Like Son: Empirical Insights into the Intergenerational Continuity of Masculinity Ideology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Perales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kuskoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Flood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sex Roles</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="412" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11199-023-01364-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11199-023-01364-y" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What Women and Men Should Be, Shouldn&apos;t be, are Allowed to be, and don&apos;t Have to Be: The Contents of Prescriptive Gender Stereotypes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Prentice</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Carranza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1471-6402.t01-1-00066</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1471-6402.t01-1-00066" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology of Women Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Committees with implicit biases promote fewer women when they do not believe gender bias exists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Régner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Thinus-Blanc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Netter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schmader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Huguet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-019-0686-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0686-3" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1171" to="1179" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Man up and take it: Gender bias in moral typecasting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sjåstad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Okimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baumeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Aquino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.obhdp.2020.05.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.obhdp.2020.05.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">161</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="141" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
