<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Three-Dimensional Signal Detection Model for Eyewitness Identification</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yueran</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<email>yuerany@unr.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nevada</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Reno</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Interdisciplinary Social Psychology Ph.D. Program</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nevada</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Reno</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janice</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Burke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Interdisciplinary Social Psychology Ph.D. Program</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nevada</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Reno</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Justice</forename><surname>Healy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Interdisciplinary Social Psychology Ph.D. Program</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nevada</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Reno</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Lancaster</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Smalarz</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nevada</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1664 N. Virginia St</addrLine>
									<postCode>89557</postCode>
									<settlement>Reno, Reno</settlement>
									<region>NV</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Three-Dimensional Signal Detection Model for Eyewitness Identification</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:40+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>eyewitness identification</term>
					<term>eyewitness memory</term>
					<term>witness decision making</term>
					<term>signal detection theory</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>How do witnesses make identification decisions when viewing a lineup? Understanding the witness decision-making process is essential for researchers to develop methods that can reduce mistaken identifications and improve lineup practices. Yet, the inclusion of fillers has posed a pivotal challenge to this task because the traditional signal detection theory is only applicable to binary decisions and cannot easily incorporate filler memory signals. This paper proposes a three-dimensional signal detection theory (3D-SDT) model to decipher the witness decisionmaking process. The 3D-SDT model clarifies the importance of considering the joint distributions of suspect and filler memory signals. The model also visualizes the joint memory distributions in a three-dimensional decision space, which allows for the incorporation of all eyewitness responses, including suspect identifications, filler identifications, and rejections. The paper starts with a set of simple assumptions to develop the 3D-SDT model, including equal variance, no criterion shift, and uncorrelated memory signals. The paper then develops the model under alternative assumptions that can accommodate more sophisticated considerations. Finally, the paper discusses potential applications of the 3D-SDT model for eyewitness research. With a mathematical modeling and visualization approach, the 3D-SDT model provides a transformative theoretical framework for understanding eyewitness identification decisions and analyzing how various factors affect these decisions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>involve more than two types of recognition items (i.e., guilty suspects, innocent suspects, and fillers). Reducing the memory signals of these items into a two-dimensional space may eliminate important information and fail to provide proper understanding of eyewitness identification decisions.</p><p>This paper proposes a three-dimensional signal detection theory (3D-SDT) model to understand eyewitness identification decisions. Importantly, the 3D-SDT model clarifies that researchers will be better able to understand identification decisions on the basis of joint distributions of suspect and filler memory signals. In addition to mathematically deriving the joint distributions, the model visualizes the distributions in a three-dimensional decision space.</p><p>Such a visualization allows the model to map witness decision rules onto the decision space and incorporate all three eyewitness responses (i.e., suspect identifications, filler identifications, and rejections). With a mathematical modeling and visualization approach, the 3D-SDT model provides a useful theoretical framework for understanding eyewitness identification decisions and analyzing how various factors affect these decisions.</p><p>The paper is organized as follows. The first section briefly reviews signal detection theory and its application to eyewitness decisions. The second section proposes the 3D-SDT model and discusses possible model variants. The last section discusses how the 3D-SDT model can be applied to analyze eyewitness data and understand effects of various lineup factors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Signal Detection Theory and Application to Eyewitness Decisions</head><p>Signal detection theory (SDT) provides a useful theoretical framework for understanding and analyzing diagnostic systems' decision process <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Green &amp; Swets, 1966)</ref>, including human recognition memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Yonelinas &amp; Parks, 2007)</ref>. In a recognition task, a person views either an old or a new item and decides if they have seen the item before, similar to a showup in which a witness views either a guilty or an innocent suspect without any fillers. SDT assumes that a person's memory signals of old and new items would form two distributions, typically assumed to be normal. The old-item distribution has a higher mean than the new-item distribution, meaning that people have stronger memory for old items than new items on average. When deciding whether an item is old or new, the person compares the item's memory signal with a decision criterion. If the memory signal exceeds the criterion, the item is identified as "old"; if not, the item is identified as "new" (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). According to SDT, a person's recognition decisions result from the combination of two parameters: discriminability (denoted as d'), which quantifies the mean distance between the old and new memory distributions; and decision criterion (denoted as γ), which quantifies the False positives (false alarms)</p><p>True positives (hits) criterion a person adopts to make a recognition decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Macmillan &amp; Creelman, 2005)</ref>. Many researchers have used the letter c to denote the decision criterion. This paper uses γ to denote the decision criterion to avoid a confusion between the decision criterion and a cost function, which is commonly used in evaluating lineup performance and denoted as c (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Yang et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Because discriminability reflects the properties of the old and new memory distributions and is not influenced by changes in decision criterion, researchers often use it as a primary measure for quantifying performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Swets, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Swets et al., 2000)</ref>.</p><p>As one of the most successful applications of mathematical modeling to psychology, SDT turns out to be both a rigorous model and a useful tool to understand and analyze recognition decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Luce, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Swets, 1996)</ref>. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, a person's true positive rate (or hit rate), which is the probability the person correctly recognizes old items as "old," corresponds to the area under the old-item distribution beyond the decision criterion. The person's false positive rate (or false alarm rate), which is the probability the person mistakenly recognizes new items as "old," corresponds to the area under the new-item distribution beyond the decision criterion. According to SDT, these two response rates change when a person changes the decision criterion. If the person holds a liberal criterion, both true and false positive rates will be high; if the person holds a conservative criterion, both true and false positive rates will be low. In other words, a trade-off between true and false positive rates occurs when a person changes their decision criterion. Researchers often visualize such trade-offs using receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves, which plot true positive rates against false positive rates at all levels of decision criteria <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Green &amp; Swets, 1966;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Macmillan &amp; Creelman, 2005)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SDT Application to Eyewitness Decisions</head><p>Because of its success in modeling recognition memory, researchers have applied the SDT framework to eyewitness identifications, which also involve recognition memory (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gronlund et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Wixted &amp; Mickes, 2014)</ref>. When viewing a lineup, witnesses rely on their memory to decide if any of the lineup members matches their memory of the culprit. Given suspects' guilt status, witness decisions conform to a 3 × 2 contingency table (also called a confusion matrix) that contains six possible identification outcomes (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>). In <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>, the letters G and I denote suspects' guilt status as either guilty or innocent (i.e., lineup status being culprit present or absent). The abbreviations IDS, IDF, and REJ denote witnesses' three possible responses-identify the suspect, identify a filler, and reject the lineup.</p><p>Because identification outcomes are contingent upon suspects' guilt status, they are denoted as conditional events, Response|Truth (read as response given truth). For example, IDS|G denotes identifying the suspect given that the suspect is guilty (i.e., in a culprit-present lineup), and REJ|I denotes rejecting the lineup given that the suspect is innocent (i.e., in a culprit-absent lineup).</p><p>The function ( * | * ) denotes the probabilities of these eyewitness identification outcomes.</p><p>Note that eyewitness identification outcomes do not conform to the 2 × 2 binary recognition tasks handled by the classic SDT model. This incompatibility is caused by the multiple recognition items involved in a lineup-witnesses view not only one suspect, but also fillers. To incorporate filler identifications, researchers have developed several modified SDT models, such as the WITNESS model <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark, 2003)</ref>, the compound signal detection model <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Duncan, 2006)</ref>, the Ensemble model <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Wixted et al., 2018)</ref>, and the multi-d' signal detection theory model <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lee &amp; Penrod, 2019</ref>). Below we briefly review each model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The WITNESS Model</head><p>The WITNESS model <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark, 2003)</ref> was developed as a computer simulation framework that can implement any model of eyewitness identification. The WITNESS model first simulates suspect and filler memory signals and then decides the identification responses according to two different decision rules: absolute and relative judgements <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Wells, 1984)</ref>. The model incorporates these two kinds of judgments in the form of a weighted sum of memory signals (or match values) that represent how well lineup members match to the memory of the perpetrator <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark, 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Absolute judgments are based on the memory signal of the best-matching lineup member (i.e., the BEST decision rule), whereas relative judgments are based on the difference in memory signals between the best and next-best lineup members (i.e., the DIFF decision rule).</p><p>The WITNESS model predicts that an identification of the best-matching lineup member will be made if the memory signal of the best match (absolute judgment) and the difference between the best and next-best match (relative judgment) are greater than a decision criterion. A rejection will be made if all matches are less than a rejection criterion. In addition, the model incorporates the "do not know" response by distinguishing the decision criterion and the rejection criterion. The WITNESS provides an important framework for mathematically modeling and simulating witness responses under different considerations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Compound Signal Detection Model</head><p>The compound signal detection (SDT-CD; <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Duncan, 2006</ref>) model conceptualizes a lineup task as a compound decision-making process that involves two components: a detection task and an identification task. For the detection task, witnesses determine whether the culprit is present or not. Once the culprit is detected to be present, witnesses then engage in the identification task and pick out the culprit among fillers. The compound decision task illustrates scenarios in which detection and identification components of the model rely on the same source of information <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Duncan, 2006</ref>).</p><p>For the detection task, the SDT-CD model discusses two different decision rules: the independent observation rule and the integration rule. The independent observation rule states that witnesses will make a positive detection if at least one lineup member's memory signal exceeds the response criterion; and the integration rule states that witnesses will make a positive detection if the sum of all lineup members' memory signals exceeds the response criterion. For the identification task, the decision rule is to choose the lineup member with the strongest memory signal. With the components involved in a compound decision task, the SDT-CD model seeks to better understand eyewitness identification decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Ensemble Model</head><p>The Ensemble model <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Wixted et al., 2018)</ref> proposes that witnesses make decisions on the basis of the difference between an individual lineup member's memory signal and the average memory signal of all lineup members. In other words, witnesses' decision variable is a lineup member's difference score from the average memory signal. Like the BEST decision rule in the WITNESS model, the Ensemble model relies on the MAX decision rule, whereby the lineup member that creates the strongest memory signal is identified if their difference score exceeds a decision criterion. In addition, the Ensemble model emphasizes the importance of considering correlated memory signals because faces in a lineup inevitably share features <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Wixted &amp; Mickes, 2014)</ref>. The model predicts that discriminability enhances when the correlation among lineup members' memory signals increases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Multi-d' Signal Detection Theory Model</head><p>The multi-d' signal detection theory (multi-d' SDT; <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Penrod, 2019)</ref> incorporates the role of fillers and proposes different measures of discriminability. Particularly, the model considers all three memory distributions in a lineup-a guilty suspect distribution, an innocent suspect distribution, and filler distributions. Resulting from these distributions, the model calculates multiple discriminability measures, including the discriminability of guilty from innocent suspects, guilty suspects from fillers, innocent suspects from fillers, and fillers in culprit-present lineups from fillers in culprit-absent lineups. The model shows that the discriminability of guilty from innocent suspects can be decomposed into other discriminability measures involving fillers, highlighting the importance of fillers in a lineup task.</p><p>The above eyewitness models have provided important insight and built a strong theoretical foundation for understanding eyewitness identification decisions. Particularly, the idea that using discriminability as a primary measure for quantifying lineup performance has been highly applauded and widely adopted by scholars and practitioners <ref type="bibr">(NRC, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Nevertheless, the most remarkable aspect of SDT-the mathematical modeling component-is not yet fully captured by these models. Thus, whereas previous eyewitness models have made significant theoretical contributions by applying SDT to eyewitness decisions, they have not supplemented these contributions with a rigorously defined mathematical model for understanding eyewitness decisions. Particularly, although these models verbally emphasize the importance of filler memory signals, they fall short of mathematically modeling memory distributions that can properly incorporate filler memory signals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data-Model Discrepancy in Previous SDT Application</head><p>The lack of a rigorously defined mathematical model could be problematic for the application of SDT to eyewitness research. Specifically, the omission of a mathematical model leads to discrepancies between previous models' verbal descriptions and visual presentations.</p><p>The visual presentation of a model reflects its underlying mathematical structure and should therefore be derived from a mathematical model <ref type="bibr">(Friendly et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Palais, 1999)</ref>. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, previous eyewitness SDT models generally project separate filler memory distributions onto the same two-dimensional (2D) decision space used in the classic SDT binary task, which includes a guilty suspect memory distribution (i.e., the old-item distribution) and an innocent memory distribution (i.e., the new-item distribution). Even though the 2D model is highly useful for understanding binary SDT tasks, it leads to an imprecise presentation of lineup memory distributions and thus may cause confusion when modeling lineup tasks that involve more than two types of recognition items-guilty suspects, innocent suspects, and fillers.</p><p>First, simply projecting a filler memory distribution on top of guilty and innocent memory distributions may give the wrong impression that witnesses form three memory distributions-one for guilty suspects, one for innocent suspects, and one for fillers. Yet, the nature of lineup tasks determines that only two distributions are involved-one for culpritpresent lineups and one for culprit-absent lineups, corresponding to the two possible states of ground truth (see the 3D-SDT model section for more detail). The 2D presentation of three memory distributions thus does not capture the correct number of eyewitness memory distributions involved in a lineup task, let alone provide a precise presentation of the distributions.   In addition, the decision criterion as presented in the 2D space deviates from the verbal decision rules proposed by previous eyewitness SDT models, leading to predictions inconsistent with actual lineup decisions. For example, the decision rule depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> suggests that a lineup member would be identified once their memory signal exceeds the decision criterion.</p><p>Accordingly, it is reasonable to infer that witnesses would identify multiple lineup members as long as these lineup members' memory signals all exceed the decision criterion. Such a situation does not happen in real lineups. The decision rules verbally described in previous eyewitness SDT models are more sophisticated and prevent these outrageous predictions; but their visual presentations clearly do not match.</p><p>Presenting three memory distributions in the 2D space further confuses how researchers should use the model to understand and estimate lineup data. In a binary SDT task, the areas under the two distributional curves, separated by the decision criterion, correspond to the probabilities of the four decision outcomes. This is because the model provides a precise mathematical account for describing binary decisions (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1)</ref>. understand eyewitness decisions, particularly with the presence of fillers.</p><p>Beyond mathematically modeling the joint memory distributions, another significant contribution of the 3D-SDT model is the visual presentation of the mathematical model. The 3D-SDT model visually presents the witness decision-making process in a three-dimensional decision space. The visual format of the model is profoundly important because visualizations allow for a deeper comprehension of complex concepts in a more structured way <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Keller &amp; Tergan, 2005)</ref>. Particularly, the visualization not only shows how the joint distributions incorporate both suspect and filler memory signals, but also shows how witness decision rules partition the joint distributions into segments that correspond to different eyewitness identification outcomes. In this paper, we primarily present the visual format of the model due to its ease of understanding and include most of the model's mathematical derivations in the appendices.</p><p>Before introducing the 3D-SDT model, we introduce some mathematical symbols to define the key concepts and assumptions involved in the model. We first focus on a set of simple assumptions for ease of understanding. In later sections, we show how the 3D-SDT model can modify its assumptions to accommodate more sophisticated considerations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Notations</head><p>(1) denotes the memory signal of a suspect in the lineup for the i th witness (ss stands for suspect signal). If the suspect is guilty, we denote the memory signal as | (suspect signal given guilt). If the suspect is innocent, we denote the memory signal as | (suspect signal given innocence). We denote means of innocent and guilty suspect memory signals as and , and variances as and , respectively.</p><p>(2) denotes the memory signal of the j th filler in the lineup for the i th witness (fs stands for filler signal). We denote the mean of filler memory signals as and the variance as . Among all the fillers, we use to denote the filler with the strongest memory signal in the lineup, that is, = max .</p><p>(3) denotes the decision criterion witnesses use to make an identification decision. As will be described in model assumptions, witnesses will identify a lineup member if it has the strongest memory signal among all lineup members and exceeds , and will reject a lineup if the strongest memory signal does not exceed .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Assumptions</head><p>(1) The memory signals of guilty suspects, innocent suspects, and fillers are random draws from independent normal distributions with the same variance (for simplicity, the variances are assumed to be 1). That is, the model assumes random sampling, independence, normal distribution, and equal variance for lineup member memory signals.</p><p>(2) The innocent suspect distribution has the same mean as the filler distribution (i.e., a fair lineup). For the sake of simplicity, we set up their means as zero, = = 0. The guilty suspect distribution has a higher mean compared to the other two distributions, &gt; = = 0. In other words, witnesses' memory signals of a guilty suspect would be stronger than memory signals of an innocent suspect and fillers on average. As mentioned above, discriminability is the standardized mean difference between the guilty and innocent distributions and is denoted as .</p><p>Given that the distribution variances are assumed to be 1 and the mean of the innocent suspect distribution is assumed to be 0, we will have = .</p><p>Using mathematical symbols, assumptions 1 and 2 can be expressed as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">| . . . ( , 1) | . . . (0, 1) . . . (0, 1)</formula><p>In the above expressions, i.i.d. stands for "independent and identically distributed."</p><p>(3) Witnesses use the MAX decision rule to make identification decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Wixted et al., 2018)</ref>. Specifically, witnesses determine which lineup member provides the strongest memory signal and then compare the strength of that signal to their decision criterion.</p><p>When the strongest signal exceeds the decision criterion, witnesses affirmatively identify the lineup member (suspect or filler) associated with that signal. When the strongest signal does not exceed the decision criterion, witnesses reject the lineup.</p><p>The decision tree in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref> depicts the process of how witnesses will produce different responses according to the MAX decision rule. The decision tree does not specify whether the suspect memory signal comes from a guilty or an innocent suspect because the same process applies to both culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups. Nevertheless, the decision tree does differentiate between suspect and filler memory signals. On one hand, witnesses do not distinguish between suspects and fillers during their decision process because they do not know lineup members' identities. On the other hand, police investigators do know lineup members' identities and thus would treat suspect identifications and filler identifications differently <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Smith et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Yang &amp; Smith, 2022)</ref>. To incorporate both views, the decision tree differentiates between suspect identifications and filler identifications in the witness decision-making process. Reject lineup &lt; lineup, and denotes the filler with the strongest memory signal ("max filler"). γ denotes witnesses' decision criterion.</p><p>(4) In eyewitness research, witnesses' confidence ratings are often used as a proxy for decision criteria <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Wixted &amp; Mickes, 2014)</ref>. The assumption is twofold. First, the proxy assumes all witnesses use the same decision criteria (i.e., no criterion variability; <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Smith et al., 2017)</ref>. For example, when witnesses report "high" confidence for identifications, they all use the same criterion = 2. Second, this proxy assumes the same confidence rating reflects the same decision criterion across culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups (i.e., no criterion shift). For example, a "high" confidence rating corresponds to the same criterion = 2 across both culpritpresent and culprit-absent lineups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Max Filler Memory Signal Distribution</head><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>, the MAX decision rule implies that a witness's decision process involves the memory signal of a filler with the strongest memory signal ("max filler").</p><p>Therefore, multiple filler signals in a lineup can be reduced to one-the max filler signal.</p><p>Understanding the distribution of max filler signals is important for understanding the role of fillers in the decision process. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> visualizes the probability density distributions of max filler signals in different-sized lineups (lineup size 2-6 and 12; or equivalently, filler size 1-5 and 11). Note that max filler signals do not follow a normal distribution, though individual fillers do follow a normal distribution as assumed in the model (see Appendix A for the derivations of the max filler probability density function).</p><p>Several properties of the max filler distributions are worth noting. First, the distributions are not symmetric (except for the one filler distribution, which follows a normal distribution).</p><p>The distributions have slightly longer tails to the right. This asymmetry is more apparent in the contour plots shown in the next section. Second, the distribution mean increases, and the distribution variance decreases as the number of fillers increases. The close forms of the distribution mean and variance are not easy to derive <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(David &amp; Nagaraja, 2003)</ref>. Therefore, we display their numeric approximations in Appendix A (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table A1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4</head><p>Probability can be reduced to one-the max filler signal. Therefore, such a joint distribution needs at least to incorporate both suspect signals and max filler signals. We first focus on culprit-present lineups and discuss the joint distribution of guilty suspect and max filler signals. We then turn to culpritabsent lineups and discuss the joint distribution of innocent suspect and max filler signals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 5</head><p>Joint Distribution of Guilty Suspect and Max Filler Memory Signals</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Joint Distribution for Culprit-Present Lineups</head><p>In culprit-present lineups, a witness's signal detection task can be described by a joint distribution of guilty suspect and max filler memory signals. Because of the independence</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">(b) (a) (c) (d)</formula><p>assumption, this joint distribution is just the product of the two marginal distributions. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> depicts such a joint distribution in a three-dimensional space. In this example, we set up the mean of the guilty suspect memory distribution to be 2 (i.e., = 2) and consider a six-person lineup (i.e., with one suspect and five fillers). In the three-dimensional coordinates, the x-axis presents guilty suspect memory strengths. The y-axis presents max filler memory strengths. The z-axis presents the probability density of the joint distribution.</p><p>All four panels in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> show different rotations of the same joint distribution. In To facilitate readers' understanding, we map the three-dimensional joint distribution onto a contour plot (see Figures 5b-5d and 6). In the contour plot, the x-and y-axes are the same as those in the three-dimensional coordinates, with the x-axis presenting guilty suspect memory strengths and the y-axis presenting max filler memory strengths. The contours capture the information on the z-axis in the three-dimensional coordinates by connecting the (x, y) points that have the same probability density (i.e., the same height). Therefore, the contour plot retains the same information from the three-dimensional space.</p><p>The joint distribution in the contour plot also provides useful information on the marginal distributions. For example, the x-axis direction reflects the marginal distribution of guilty suspect memory signals. Readers can observe that the mean of the marginal distribution is 2 and the distribution is symmetric around its mean. Similarly, the y-axis direction reflects the marginal distribution of max filler memory signals. As discussed above, this marginal distribution is not symmetric. The mean of the max filler distribution is bigger than the mean of a single filler distribution, and the variance is smaller. Specifically, the mean of the max filler distribution is 1.16 and the variance is 0.45 (also see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table A1</ref> in Appendix A). Most importantly, the MAX decision rule can be mapped onto witnesses' decision space.</p><p>In the original three-dimensional decision space, the MAX decision rule exists as three twodimensional vertical planes, all perpendicular to the xy plane. In the contour plot, these planes project to the x-y plane as lines, shown as the three red lines in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6</ref>. Specifically, the vertical and horizontal red lines present witnesses' decision criterion, which is set up arbitrarily as = 1</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Reject ( | ) Identify filler ( | ) Identify suspect ( | )</formula><p>in this example. The oblique red line presents the situation when suspect memory signal and max filler signal are the same (i.e., line of equality, = ).</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6</ref>, the MAX decision rule partitions the decision space into three regions. Witnesses will identify the suspect if the suspect memory signal exceeds both the max filler memory signal and the decision criterion (the region to the right of the equality line = and the vertical criterion line = 1). Witnesses will identify the max filler if the max filler memory signal exceeds both the suspect memory signal and the decision criterion (the upper left region to the left of the equality line = and beyond the horizontal criterion line = 1). Witnesses will reject the lineup if neither the suspect nor max filler memory signals exceed the decision criterion (the lower left region). These three regions thus partition the joint distribution into three segments. The volume of each segment corresponds to the probability of each of the three eyewitness outcomes in culprit-present lineups (i.e., the first row in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Joint Distribution for Culprit-Absent Lineups</head><p>In culprit-absent lineups, a witness's signal detection task can be described by a joint distribution of innocent suspect and max filler memory signals. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7</ref> displays this joint distribution in a contour plot. Note that for this joint distribution, the mean of the innocent suspect marginal distribution is zero. Same as the joint distribution of guilty suspect and max filler memory signals, this joint distribution is also partitioned into the three segments by the MAX decision rule, shown as the three red lines in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7</ref>. The volume of each segment corresponds to the probability of each of the three eyewitness outcomes in culprit-absent lineups (i.e., the second row in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>). Interested readers can look at Appendix B for how to derive the probabilities of the three eyewitness outcomes in culprit-absent and culprit-present lineups from the above model. These derivations are important for the inverse operation-calculating the discriminability and decision criterion from probabilities of eyewitness outcomes (i.e., eyewitness response rates), which will be discussed below.</p><p>Overlay Joint Distributions for Culprit-Present and Culprit-Absent Lineups the discriminability parameter, , which is the mean distance between the marginal distributions of guilty and innocent suspect memory signals. In other words, it is the mean distance between the two joint distributions in the x-axis direction. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reject</head><p>Identify filler Identify suspect</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Equation 1.1. Decision criterion γ = Φ Pr( | ) = Φ Pr ( | ) Equation 1.2. Discriminability = Φ Pr( | ) − Φ Pr( | ) Pr( | ) Pr( | )</formula><p>In the equations, m denotes the line size (i.e., number of lineup members), and ( − 1) denotes the filler size (i.e., number of fillers). Φ( * ) denotes the cumulative density function (cdf) of a standard normal distribution, and Φ ( * ) denotes its inverse function (i.e., calculating quantiles of a standard normal distribution). The derivations of these two equations are included in Appendix C.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Alternative Model Assumptions</head><p>The assumptions in the above model are highly useful in model development; yet they may be too simplistic to capture the complexities in eyewitness data. Below we discuss alternative model assumptions that can accommodate more sophisticated considerations. We refer to the model discussed above with the simplistic assumptions as the original model and the model below with more sophisticated assumptions as the advanced model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Unequal Variances and Criterion Shift</head><p>The original model assumes all memory signal distributions have the same variance.</p><p>Research from recognition memory, though, suggests that the guilty suspect memory distribution may be more variable than the innocent suspect and filler memory distributions because of encoding variability <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Wixted, 2007)</ref>. As a result, it may not be appropriate to assume an equal variance across all distributions.</p><p>The original model also assumes a same decision criterion for both culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups. However, because lineup tasks are between-subjects rather than withinsubjects, witnesses may not use the same decision criterion across culprit-present and culpritabsent lineups <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Smith et al., 2018)</ref>. Put differently, a criterion shift may happen between culpritpresent lineups and culprit-absent lineups even when police are using the same lineup procedure.</p><p>The Ensemble model, for example, implies that witnesses would use a more conservative decision criterion in culprit-present lineups than in culprit-absent lineups <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Wixted et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Thus, it may not be appropriate to assume the same decision criterion across culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups.</p><p>We can modify the model assumptions to capture these nuances. For example, we can assume a different variance for guilty suspect memory distribution from the variances of the innocent suspect and filler memory distributions. We can also assume witnesses use different decision criteria between culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups. Specifically, we denote witnesses' decision criterion in culprit-absent lineups as γ and the decision criterion in culprit-present lineups as ( + Δ ). Therefore, Δ represents the amount of the criterion shift from culprit-absent lineups to culprit-present lineups.</p><p>Note that the original model, which assumes equal variance and no criterion shift, is a special case of this more generic model when = 1 and Δ = 0.</p><p>One can calculate the decision criterion γ and the unstandardized discriminability for the unequal-variance criterion-shift model using the equations below. The derivations of the equations are included in Appendix D. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Correlated Memory Signals</head><p>The original model assumes independence among memory signals. This assumption, though, may not hold because lineup members often share some common features <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Shen et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Wixted et al., 2018)</ref>. Specifically, the correlations among lineup members' memory signals would increase as they become more similar to each other. In other words, whereas one witness may have comparably strong memory signals for all lineup members, another witness may have weak memory signals for all lineup members. In terms of model assumptions, memory signals would not follow independent normal distributions any further. Instead, we could assume that memory signals follow a multivariate normal distribution, which allows for non-zero correlations among memory signals from the same witness. For memory signals in culprit-absent lineups,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">⎣ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎡ ⋮ ⎦ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎤ . . . ⎝ ⎜ ⎛ = ⎣ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎡ 0 0 0 ⋮ 0 ⎦ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎤ , Σ = ⎣ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎡ 1 … 1 … ⋮ ⋮ 1 … ⋮ ⋱ ⋮ … 1⎦ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎤ ⎠ ⎟ ⎞</formula><p>For memory signals in culprit-present lineups,</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">⎣ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎡ ⋮ ⎦ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎤ . . . ⎝ ⎜ ⎛ = ⎣ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎡ 0 0 ⋮ 0 ⎦ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎤ , Σ = ⎣ ⎢ ⎢ ⎢ ⎡ … 1 … ⋮ ⋮ 1 … ⋮ ⋱ ⋮ … 1 ⎦ ⎥ ⎥ ⎥ ⎤ ⎠ ⎟ ⎞</formula><p>In the above assumptions, ρ denotes the correlations among lineup members' memory signals. denotes the unstandardized mean difference between guilty suspect and innocent suspect memory distributions. denotes the variance of the guilty suspect memory distribution. Appendix E for the derivations of the joint pdfs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Other Decision Rules</head><p>The original model assumes the MAX decision rule. Alternatively, previous eyewitness SDT models have proposed other decision rules. For example, the WITNESS model discusses the DIFF decision rule, in which a lineup member will be identified if it has the strongest memory signal and if the difference between its memory signal and the next-best memory signal exceeds a decision criterion <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark, 2003)</ref>.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref>, the DIFF decision rule can be partially mapped on the threedimensional decision space to explain suspect identifications. When the suspect memory signal exceeds the max filler memory signals, witnesses will identify the suspect if the difference between suspect and max filler memory signals surpasses the decision criterion (i.e., to the right of the red solid line − = ), and will reject the lineup if not (i.e., in-between the line of equality = and − = ). When the suspect memory signal does not exceed the max filler memory signal (to the left of the line of equality), witness could either identify the max filler or reject the lineup, depending on the difference between the max filler and the nextbest lineup member, who may or may not be the suspect. Because filler identifications and rejections involve the next-best filler, they cannot be fully visualized on the decision space. To fully present the DIFF decision rule, the decision space needs to be expanded to include the nextbest filler memory signals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 10</head><p>Map the DIFF Decision Rule</p><p>Note. The red lines present part of the DIFF decision rule.</p><p>The compound signal detection model discusses the integration decision rule, in which a lineup member will be identified when it has the strongest memory signal and when the sum of all lineup members exceeds a decision criterion <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Duncan, 2006)</ref>. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 11</ref>, the integration decision rule can be mapped on the three-dimensional decision space. Witnesses will reject the lineup when the sum of the suspect and max filler memory signals does not exceed the difference between the decision criterion and the sum of other fillers (to the left of the red solid line + = − ; C stands for the sum of other filler memory signals). Otherwise, witnesses will identify the lineup member with the strongest memory signal. Here the sum of other filler memory signals is approximated as a constant. To present the integration rule more precisely, the decision space needs to be expanded to incorporate the sum of other filler memory signals to account for its stochasticity. The Ensemble model treats the difference between a lineup member's memory signal and the average memory signal of all lineup members as the decision variable and applies the MAX decision rule to the difference scores <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Wixted et al., 2018)</ref>. As shown in Appendix F, these assumptions can be approximated as applying the MAX decision rule to the original memory signals with a criterion shift between culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 12</ref> presents such assumptions onto the decision space of the original memory signals. Specifically, applying the MAX decision rule to the difference scores implies a more conservative decision criterion for culprit-present lineups than culprit-absent lineups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reject Identify filler + Reject</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Identify suspect</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reject</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Identify filler</head><p>Identify suspect </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Applications and Implications</head><p>Theory development is essential for uncovering the structures and mechanisms of realworld phenomena <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Hintzman, 1991)</ref>. Among others, mathematical modeling stands as a profound form of theory development <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Luce, 1995</ref>). Yet, as noted by the National Research Council (2014), "this strong scientific foundation remains insufficient for understanding the strengths and limitations of eyewitness identification procedures in the field" (p. 113). With a mathematical modeling and visualization approach, the 3D-SDT model provides a transformative theoretical framework for understanding and analyzing eyewitness identification decisions, thereby building a stronger theoretical foundation for eyewitness research. Below we discuss a few potential applications of the 3D-SDT model for eyewitness research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reject</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Identify filler Identify suspect</head><p>Estimate Discriminability from Lineup Data</p><p>One beauty of SDT is that it explains a diagnostic system's decision process with only two simple parameters-discriminability and decision criterion. When applying SDT to recognition memory, researchers typically place a premium on discriminability because it reflects the mean difference between the old and new memory signals and is not influenced by changes in decision criterion <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Banks, 1970)</ref>.</p><p>In the same vein, researchers have advocated using discriminability as a primary measure to quantify eyewitness performance (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Wixted &amp; Mickes, 2012)</ref>. But how should one estimate discriminability from eyewitness data? For binary tasks such as memory recognition, discriminability can be directly estimated from true and false positive rates <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Macmillan &amp; Creelman, 2005)</ref>. The 3D-SDT model, however, reveals that the same approach does not work for eyewitness data (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 8</ref>). Unlike binary SDT tasks, one cannot accurately estimate discriminability for eyewitness SDT tasks from guilty and innocent suspect identification rates. This is because fillers draw responses away from suspect identifications (i.e., filler siphoning, <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Wells et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Smith et al., 2017)</ref>. Such filler siphoning is visualized in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 8</ref> with the area in between the dashed red line and the line of equality. The filler siphoning area makes it impossible to estimate discriminability directly from guilty and innocent suspect identification rates. Instead, one needs to estimate discriminability and decision criterion using rejection rates, as shown in Equations 1.1 and 1.2.</p><p>We conducted a simulation study to compare the accuracy in estimating the parameters when using equations derived from the 3D-SDT model (referred to as "the 3D model") versus when using equations derived from the traditional 2D-SDT model (referred to as "the 2D model"). We first simulated witness responses according to the assumptions that the suspect and filler memory signals follow independent normal distributions with variances of 1 and witnesses use the MAX decision rule to make identification decisions. We conducted 10,000 simulations for each combination of different values of discriminability and response criterion under different lineup sizes (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 2</ref>). Each simulation contained a total of 2,000 witness responses, 1,000 for culprit-present lineups and 1,000 for culprit-absent lineups. For each simulated dataset (n = 2,000), we then estimated discriminability and response criterion using the equations derived from the 3D model and the 2D model, respectively. Thus, a total of 10,000 estimates were generated for each parameter from the simulations. The R script for the simulation is available at osf.io/n2zbc/?view_only=d09783b0154647b287d842e40731119a. The summary statistics of the estimated parameters are displayed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>Two main observations emerge from the simulation results. First, the means of the discriminability (d') and response criterion (γ) estimated from the 3D model are consistently closer to the population parameters compared to the values estimated from the 2D model, regardless of lineup size. In other words, the 3D estimates provide less biased estimates of the population parameters than the 2D estimates. When such a convergence occurs-the mean of estimated parameters is close to the parameters used for the simulations-it suggests that the model is likely functioning as expected, accurately representing the problem, and producing consistent, reliable results <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Law &amp; Kelton, 2000)</ref>. Therefore, the convergence of the 3D estimates to the population parameters used for the simulations suggests that the 3D model accurately represents the lineup identification task. Note. The table displays the means and standard deviations (in parentheses) of discriminability and response criterion estimated from the simulated data. A total of 10,000 simulations were conducted for each combination of discriminability and response criterion under each lineup size. Each simulation contained 2,000 witness responses, 1,000 for culprit-present lineups and 1,000 for culpritabsent lineups.</p><p>Another observation from the simulation is that the means of the discriminability and response criterion estimated from the 2D model increasingly deviate from the population parameters as lineup size increases. This again raises concern that the 2D model does not adequately fit a lineup task in which fillers are included. Considering that the means of the parameters estimated from the 3D model are much closer to the population parameters than those estimated from the 2D model, and that the estimated parameter from the 2D model increasingly deviate from the population parameters as lineup size increases, it is likely that the 3D model better encompasses the eyewitness lineup decision-making task than the 2D model.</p><p>The above simulation study assumes independence among memory signals of lineup members. Future research could further examine the model's ability to estimate parameters when more sophisticated assumptions are involved. For example, the 2D model may be limited in its ability to handle more sophisticated assumptions such as a criterion shift or correlated memory signals, whereas the 3D model provides a more potent tool to handle these situations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Distinguish between Lineup Fairness and Filler Similarity</head><p>Eyewitness researchers often use "lineup fairness" and "filler similarity" interchangeably (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Colloff et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Lee et al., 2022)</ref>. But are these two concepts actually equivalent?</p><p>Clarifying these concepts is important for understanding and improving the choice of lineup fillers, which can significantly impact eyewitness performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fitzgerald et al., 2013)</ref>. The 3D-SDT model helps to elucidate the distinction between "lineup fairness" and "filler similarity."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lineup Fairness</head><p>Lineup fillers serve the purpose of protecting innocent suspects from mistaken identifications <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Wells, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Wells et al., 1979)</ref>. Accordingly, a "fair" (or "unbiased") lineup is defined to be a lineup in which the suspect does not stand out <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Brigham et al., 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr">Well et al., 2020)</ref>. Translating into SDT language, a "fair" lineup implies that the suspect and a filler should elicit similar memory distributions when viewed by individuals who have had no prior exposure to any of the lineup members. Such occurs when witnesses view culprit-absent lineups <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Quigley-McBride &amp; Wells, 2021)</ref> or mock witnesses view either culprit-present or culprit-absent lineups (i.e., the mock witness paradigm; <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Doob &amp; Kirshenbaum, 1973)</ref>. In such cases, the suspect would have an equal chance as any of the fillers of being identified by mock witnesses (see Appendix B</p><p>for the derivation). Clearly, this definition of "lineup fairness" differs from "filler similarity."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Filler Similarity</head><p>When two faces exhibit greater similarity, they share more features in common, resulting in an increased correlation between their memory signals <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Colloff et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Luus &amp; Wells, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Shen et al., 2023)</ref>. Although there can be variations in similarity values among different pairs of lineup members, this discussion assumes a simplified situation in which all possible pairs of lineup members have the same level of similarity (i.e., a consistent correlation among all possible pairs). For mock witnesses (or witnesses viewing culprit-absent lineups), the similarity among lineup members should not influence lineup fairness if all lineup members elicit similar memory distributions. This is because lineup fairness is concerned with the marginal distributions of lineup members' memory distributions, particularly their means, rather than the correlations among memory signals.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 13</ref> top panels, both low similarity and high similarity lineups could be fair as long as all lineup members elicit similar marginal distributions. There would be equal likelihood for the suspect to be identified as there would be for any of the fillers to be identified.</p><p>However, a lineup becomes unfair if the marginal distribution of the suspect is not the same as those of fillers. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 13</ref> bottom panels, if the suspect elicits stronger memory signals on average than do fillers (i.e., &gt; ), the suspect will have a higher likelihood of being identified than fillers. Such a situation could happen for both low similarity and high similarity lineups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 13</head><p>Lineup Fairness and Filler Similarity</p><p>Note. The red lines present the decision criterion, which is assumed to be consistent across all conditions. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Differences between 3D-SDT Model and General Recognition Theory</head><p>At face value, the proposed 3D-SDT model resembles an extension of signal detection theory-general recognition theory (GRT; also known as multidimensional signal detection theory; <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ashby &amp; Gott, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Ashby &amp; Perrin, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Ashby &amp; Townsend, 1986)</ref>, especially given that both the 3D-SDT and GRT models adopt key assumptions of the classic binary SDT and involve multi-dimensional decision spaces.</p><p>However, despite their superficial resemblance, the 3D-SDT model differs significantly from GRT. Like the classic binary SDT, GRT models focus on a simple recognition task in which only one item is shown; however, participants make decisions based on the multiple perceptual dimensions of the same item (e.g., judging gender and age of the same face). In other words, participants still make binary decisions; they just make such decisions multiple times,</p><p>with different perceptual signals, from the same recognition item. Thus, GRT recognition tasks still conform to the binary 2 × 2 contingency table (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Silbert et al., 2009)</ref>.</p><p>In comparison, the 3D-SDT model focuses on a lineup task in which participants handle only one perceptual dimension-witnesses' memory signals of the faces. However, the perceptual signals come from multiple recognition items as a lineup presents not only a suspect but also a few fillers. In other words, participants make one single lineup decision in which multiple recognition items are displayed simultaneously. Thus, such lineup decisions are not binary decisions and do not conform to the 2 × 2 contingency table. Unlike the binary SDT and GRT models which consider only one recognition item, the 3D-SDT model incorporates multiple recognition items into its decision space, thereby accommodating lineup decisions that align with the 3 × 2 contingency table (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional Topics and Future Research</head><p>Due to the scope of the paper, we limit our discussions on how to apply the 3D-SDT model to analyze effects of various lineup factors on eyewitness decisions. Nevertheless, the potential applications are broad. For example, the above discussion distinguishes between lineup fairness and filler similarity. Yet, a remaining question is how filler similarity influences eyewitness responses within fair lineups (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Colloff et al., 2021)</ref>. Using the 3D-SDT model, researchers can examine how witness memory distributions change as a function of filler similarity. For example, when lineup members become more similar to each other, not only will the correlation increase, but their marginal means will tend to converge; in other words, the mean of the joint memory distribution will move toward the line of equality ( = ). By examining how filler similarity influences witness memory distributions, the 3D-SDT model could shed light on how filler similarity affects witness responses.</p><p>Another important question in eyewitness research is how lineup size influences eyewitness responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Juncu &amp; Fitzgerald, 2021</ref>). To answer this question, researchers can examine how lineup size influences the max filler distribution in the 3D-SDT model. As discussed in the section "max filler memory signal distribution," when lineup sizes increase, the mean of the max filler distribution increases and the variance decreases as a result. The changes in the max filler distribution will in turn influence the joint memory distributions. Therefore, the 3D-SDT model could provide a theoretical account for analyzing the effect of lineup size on witness responses.</p><p>Furthermore, the 3D-SDT model raises several methodology considerations when researchers use the model to analyze lineup data. For example, the model assumes that innocent suspect memory signals and filler memory signals are from the same normal distribution (i.e., a fair lineup). Thus, researchers need to consider if the culprit-absent lineups satisfy this assumption when estimating discriminability from lineup data. The model also assumes equal variance across guilty suspect, innocent suspect, and filler memory distributions, which may not hold due to encoding variability <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Wixted, 2007)</ref>. Another model assumption concerns a criterion shift between culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups. Due to the between-subjects nature of lineup experiments, it may not be the case that witnesses use the same criterion across culpritpresent and culprit-absent lineups <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Smith et al., 2017)</ref>. Thus, future research should inspect whether the commonly used eyewitness experimental paradigms violate these model assumptions and design studies that can better satisfy the model assumptions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>This paper proposes a 3D-SDT model to better understand how witnesses use their memory to make identification decisions. The model addresses a major challenge in eyewitness research: the presence of lineup fillers, which creates a decision task that deviates from the binary decisions typically addressed by SDT <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Lampinen, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Wells et al., 2015)</ref>. The 3D-SDT model thus helps to scientifically understand eyewitness identification decisions, with implications for lineup construction and application to eyewitness data. Namely, the model can be used to predict eyewitness responses rates, differentiate lineup fairness and filler similarity, and so on. The model additionally has promise to advance knowledge across different fields, such as the basic memory and perception research when multiple signal detection items are involved. The 3D-SDT model therefore provides a transformative theoretical framework for understanding and analyzing eyewitness identification decisions, strengthening the theoretical foundation for eyewitness research. From the above model, one can derive the probabilities of the three eyewitness outcomes in culprit-absent lineups. One can derive these probabilities using two different approaches. The first approach uses integral calculus to integrate the probability density function (pdf) of the joint distribution of innocent suspect and max filler memory signals over each of the three regions divided by the MAX decision rule.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Pr( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) d ( ) d = ( ) d ( − 1)[Φ( )] ( ) d = Φ( ) • Φ( ) = Φ( ) Pr( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) d ( ) d = ( ) Φ( ) d = ( ) Φ( ) d = Φ( ) dΦ( ) = 1 [1 − Φ( ) ] Pr( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) Φ( ) d = ( − 1)[Φ( )] ( )Φ( ) d = ( − 1)[Φ( )] dΦ( ) = − 1 [1 − Φ( ) ]</formula><p>In the equations, m denotes the line size, and ( − 1) denotes the filler size. Φ( * )</p><p>denotes the cdf of a standard normal distribution, and Φ ( * ) denotes its inverse function (i.e., calculating quantiles of a standard normal distribution).</p><p>The second approach derives the probabilities directly from the conceptual definitions. is reflected in the model assumptions that both innocent suspect and filler memory signals are independent random draws from the same standard normal distribution. In other words, an innocent suspect has equal chance to be identified as any of the fillers. Accordingly,</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">Pr( | ) = 1 [Pr( | ) + Pr( | )] = 1 [1 − Φ( ) ] Pr( | ) = − 1 [Pr( | ) + Pr( | )] = − 1 [1 − Φ( ) ]</formula><p>Which lead to the same results as the calculus derivations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Culprit-Present Lineups</head><p>In culprit-present lineups, a witness's signal detection task can be described by a joint distribution of guilty suspect and max filler memory signals. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6</ref> in the manuscript displays this joint distribution in a contour plot. This joint distribution is also partitioned into the three segments by the MAX decision rule, shown as the three red lines in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6</ref>  Pr</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) d ( ) d = ( − ) d ( − 1)[Φ( )] ( ) d = Φ( − ) • Φ( ) Reject ( | ) Identify filler ( | ) Identify suspect ( | ) Pr( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) d ( ) d = ( ) Φ( ) d = ( − ) Φ( ) d = Φ( ) dΦ( − ) = Φ( ) dΦ( − ) Pr( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) ( − ) d d = ( ) Φ( − )d = Φ( − ) d[Φ( )] = Φ( − ) dΦ( )</formula><p>From the above equations, the ratio between guilty suspect identification and filler identification rates is not equal to , which is the ratio between innocent suspect identification and filler identification rates in culprit-absent lineups. It indicates that the guilty suspect does not have equal chance being identified as a filler. Yet, the mathematical constraint that all probabilities sum up to 1 still holds.</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">Pr( | ) + Pr( | ) = Φ( ) dΦ( − ) + Φ( − ) dΦ( ) = [Φ( − ) • Φ( ) ] = 1 − Φ( − ) • Φ( ) = 1 − Pr ( | )</formula><p>Appendix C: Derive γ and from Probabilities of Eyewitness Outcomes</p><p>From the above derivations of probabilities of eyewitness outcomes, one can derive witnesses' decision criterion γ from the rejection rate in culprit-absent lineups.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">Pr( | ) = Φ( ) ⇒ = Φ Pr( | ) = Φ Pr ( | )</formula><p>One can then derive the discriminability from rejection rates in both culprit-absent and culprit-present lineups.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">Pr( | ) = Φ( − ) • Φ( ) ⇒ Φ( − ) = Pr( | ) Φ( ) = Pr( | ) Pr( | ) ⇒ = − Φ Pr( | ) Pr( | ) = Φ Pr( | ) − Φ Pr( | ) Pr( | ) Pr( | )</formula><p>Therefore, one can estimate witnesses' decision criterion γ and the discriminability from the probabilities of eyewitness outcomes using the two equations below.</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">Equation 1.1. Decision criterion γ = Φ Pr( | ) = Φ Pr ( | ) Equation 1.2. Discriminability = Φ Pr( | ) − Φ Pr( | ) Pr( | ) Pr( | )</formula><p>Again, m denotes the line size, and ( − 1) denotes the filler size. Φ( * ) denotes the cdf of a standard normal distribution, and Φ ( * ) denotes its inverse function.</p><p>We modify some of the assumptions used in the original model to accommodate more sophisticated considerations. For the memory distributions, we can assume the variance of guilty suspect memory distribution may not be the same as those of the innocent suspect and filler memory distributions. We can also assume that witnesses may shift their decision criterion across culpritpresent and culprit-absent lineups. Specifically, if witnesses use the decision criterion γ in culprit-absent lineups, we assume they would use the decision criterion ( + Δ ) in culpritpresent lineups. Δ denotes the amount of criterion shift from culprit-absent lineups to culpritpresent lineups. Note that the original model, which assumes equal variance and no criterion shift, is a special case of this more generic model when = 1 and Δ = 0.</p><p>Because the joint distribution of innocent suspect and filler memory signals is not influenced by these modified assumptions, the probabilities of eyewitness outcomes in culpritabsent lineups stay the same as the ones in the original equal-variance consistent-criterion model.</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Pr( | ) = Φ( ) Pr( | ) = 1 [1 − Φ( ) ] Pr( | ) = − 1 [1 − Φ( ) ] 3D-SDT MODEL 62</formula><p>The joint distribution of guilty suspect and filler memory signals, however, is influenced by these modified assumptions. As a result, the probabilities of eyewitness outcomes in culpritabsent lineups change. But the derivations stay pretty much the same.</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">Pr( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) d ( ) d = 1 − d ( − 1)[Φ( )] ( ) d = Φ + Δ − • Φ( + Δ ) Pr( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) d ( ) d = ( ) Φ( ) d = 1 − Φ( ) d = Φ( ) dΦ − = Φ( ) dΦ − Pr( | ) = ( ) ( ) d d = ( ) 1 − d d = ( ) Φ − d = Φ − d[Φ( )] = Φ − dΦ( )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Derive γ and from Probabilities of Eyewitness Outcomes</head><p>From the above derivations of probabilities of eyewitness outcomes, we can derive witnesses' decision criterion γ in culprit-absent lineups, which is the same as the one in the original equal-variance consistent-criterion model.</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">Pr( | ) = Φ( ) ⇒ = Φ Pr( | ) = Φ Pr ( | )</formula><p>We can then derive the discriminability when assuming an unequal variance for the guilty suspect memory distribution and a criterion shift Δ between the culprit-absent and culprit-present lineups.</p><p>Pr</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">( | ) = Φ + Δ − • Φ( + Δ ) ⇒ Φ + Δ − = Pr( | ) Φ( + Δ ) ⇒ = ( + Δ ) − Φ Pr( | ) Φ( + Δ )</formula><p>Therefore, one can estimate witnesses' decision criterion γ and the (unstandardized) discriminability from the probabilities of eyewitness outcomes using the two equations below. Again, m denotes the line size, and ( − 1) denotes the filler size. Φ( * ) denotes the cdf of a standard normal distribution, and Φ ( * ) denotes its inverse function. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure A1</ref> visualizes the joint distributions under these modified assumptions. Note that the criterion shift component is similar to the Ensemble model depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 12</ref> in the manuscript. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conditional Distribution of Filler Signals</head><p>We first derive the pdf for the conditional distribution of all filler signals given the suspect signal. From the property of a multivariate normal distribution, the conditional distribution is also a multivariate normal distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Casella &amp; Berger, 2002)</ref>. The Ensemble model treats the difference between a lineup member's memory signal and the average memory signal of all lineup members as the decision variable and applies the MAX decision rule to the difference scores <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Wixted et al., 2018)</ref>. In fact, these assumptions can be approximated as applying the MAX decision rule to the original memory signals with a criterion shift between culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>| ~</head><p>Applying the MAX decision rule to the difference between the suspect's memory signal and the average memory signal, one would have, When witnesses view culprit-absent lineups, that is, when the suspect memory signal is from the innocent suspect, the above conditions can be transformed to,</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">| &gt; + &gt; +</formula><p>When witnesses view culprit-present lineups, that is, when the suspect memory signal is from the guilty suspect, the above conditions can be transformed to,</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">| &gt; + &gt; +</formula><p>Because &gt; , the above decision rule is equivalent to applying the MAX decision rule to the original memory signals, but with different decision criteria for culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups. Particularly, the above decision rule implies a more conservative decision criterion for culprit-present lineups than culprit-absent lineups.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 A</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Signal Detection Model for Item Recognition Note. The dashed curve depicts the distribution of new items' memory signals, and the solid curve depicts the distribution of old items' memory signals. The vertical dashed line depicts the decision criterion .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>A</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 Decision</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Tree for Eyewitness MAX Decision RuleNote.denotes the memory signal of a suspect in the lineup for the i th witness. could come from either a guilty suspect distribution (i.e., a culprit-present lineup) or an innocent suspect distribution (i.e., a culprit-absent lineup). denotes the memory signal of the j th filler in the</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>particular, panel (c) rotates to show the marginal distribution of guilty suspect memory signals, which is a normal distribution ( | ~ (2, 1)), and panel (d) rotates to show the marginal distribution of max filler memory signals, which is the same as the distribution of the max filler among five fillers in Figure 4. Interested readers can go to osf.io/n2zbc/?view_only=d09783b0154647b287d842e40731119a for a rotatable animation of the joint distribution.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 6 Contour</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Plot for the Joint Distribution of Guilty Suspect and Max Filler Memory Signals Note. The blue contours present the joint distribution of guilty suspect and max filler memory signals for culprit-present lineups. The red lines present the MAX decision rule.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7 Contour</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Plot for the Joint Distribution of Innocent Suspect and Max Filler Memory Signals Note. The green contours present the joint distribution of innocent suspect and max filler memory signals for culprit-absent lineups. The red lines present the MAX decision rule.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc>presents two joint distributions for culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups in the same plot. The three red lines show the MAX decision rule and assume witnesses would hold the same response criterion = 1 in both culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups. Same as Figures 6 and 7, the MAX decision rule partitions each distribution into three segments, corresponding to the three eyewitness outcomes under each lineup status. Figure 8 also visualizes</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 8 Joint</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Distributions for Culprit-Present Lineups and Culprit-Absent Lineups Note. The blue contours present the joint distribution of guilty suspect and max filler memory signals for culprit-present lineups. The green contours present the joint distribution of innocent suspect and max filler memory signals for culprit-absent lineups. The red lines present the MAX decision rule. The discriminability presents the distance between the marginal means of the two joint distributions in the x-axis direction. With the above model, one can estimate witnesses' decision criterion γ and the discriminability from the probabilities of eyewitness outcomes (i.e., eyewitness response rates) if the model assumptions hold.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>unstandardized mean difference between guilty suspect and innocent suspect memory distributions, and presents the variance of the guilty suspect memory distribution.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>max filler distribution will change if one assumes non-zero correlations among the memory signals (see<ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Arellano-Valle &amp; Genton, 2008)</ref>.Figure 9displays the contour plots of the joint distributions of suspect and filler memory signals when assuming correlated memory signals (specifically, = 0.5, = 2, and = 1). Interested readers can refer to</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Map the Integration Decision RuleNote. The red lines present the integration decision rule. C stands for the sum of all filler memory signals except the max filler.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 12</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Map the Ensemble Model Decision RuleNote. The red lines present witnesses' decision criterion in culprit-absent lineups. The purple lines present witnesses' decision criterion in culprit-present lineups.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(a) A fair lineup with dissimilar members (b) A fair lineup with similar members (c) An unfair lineup with dissimilar members (d) An unfair lineup with similar members</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Relating to this challenge, previous eyewitness models generally present identification tasks in a twodimensional decision space, neglecting to fully integrate filler memory signals. The 3D-SDT model addresses this issue by incorporating the joint distributions of suspect and filler memory signals and presenting the distributions in a three-dimensional decision space. The visual format of the model is particularly important because it allows for the incorporation of all eyewitness responses, including suspect identifications, filler identifications, and lineup rejections in both culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>In a fair culprit-absent lineup, all lineup members have equal chance to be identified. This</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. The volume of each segment corresponds to the probability of each of the three eyewitness outcomes in culpritpresent lineups.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>Figure 6 (</head><label>6</label><figDesc>in manuscript) Contour Plot for the Joint Distribution of Guilty Suspect and Max Filler Memory Signals From the above model, one can derive the probabilities of the three eyewitness outcomes in culprit-present lineups. Unlike culprit-absent lineups, one cannot easily derive all probabilities from their conceptual definitions. One may only do so for deriving rejection rates but not for deriving suspect and filler identification rates in culprit-present lineups. Below we derive the probabilities using integral calculus.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head>Equation 2. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Decision criterion γ in culprit-absent lineups in the unequal-</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>Figure A1 Assume</head><label>A1</label><figDesc>Unequal Variances and a Criterion Shift between Culprit-Present and Culprit-Absent LineupsNote. The blue contours are more spread out than the green contours in the x-axis direction because the guilty suspect distribution is assumed to have a larger variance than the innocent suspect distribution. The red lines present witnesses' decision criterion in culprit-absent lineups, and the purple lines present witnesses' decision criterion in culprit-present lineups. derive the probability density function (pdf) of the joint distribution of suspect and max filler distributions. We derive the pdf for the more generic situation of culprit-present lineups, as its distribution allows for flexible mean and variance.For memory signals in culprit-present lineups,In the above assumption, m denotes the lineup size, and (m-1) denotes the filler size. The variance and covariance matrices are,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Because this conditional distribution is a multivariate normal distribution, the marginal conditional distribution of each filler would be a normal distribution.Conditional Distribution of Max Filler SignalsWe then derive the pdf for the conditional distribution of the max filler signals given the suspect signal. According to Corollary 5 in Arellano-Valle and Genton(2008), one can derive the pdf of the max filler signals as all filler signals are an exchangeable random vector with a multivariate normal distribution. of the marginal conditional distribution of one filler conditioning on suspect signals, and is the cdf of the joint distribution of ( − 2) fillers. Joint Distribution of Suspect and Max Filler Signals With knowledge of the conditional distribution of max filler signals and the marginal distribution of suspect signals, one can obtain their joint distribution. of the marginal conditional distribution of one filler conditioning on suspect signals, is the cdf of the joint distribution of ( − 2) fillers, and is the pdf of the marginal distribution of suspect signals.When the suspect signals come from an innocent suspect (i.e., culprit-absent lineups), the joint pdf is a special case of the above joint pdf with = 0 and = 1. In other words, the joint pdf will reduce to, of the marginal conditional distribution of one filler conditioning on innocent suspect signals, is the cdf of the joint distribution of ( − 2) fillers, and is the pdf of the marginal distribution of innocent suspect signals.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the MAX decision rule to the difference between the max filler's memory signal and the average memory signal, one would have, In the above derivation, m denotes the lineup size. denotes the population mean of suspect memory signals. Specifically, = for culprit-absent lineups, and = for culprit-present lineups. denotes the population mean of filler memory signals, and = 0 according to the model assumptions. ′ denote the random errors of memory signals. According to the model assumptions, ~ (0, ). Therefore, the random errors are approximated as zeros in the above derivation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Eyewitness Identification Outcomes in Culprit-Present and Culprit-Absent Lineups</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Witness response</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Suspect identification</cell><cell cols="2">Filler identification</cell><cell cols="2">Rejection</cell></row><row><cell>Lineup</cell><cell>Culprit present (suspect guilty)</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>| )</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>| )</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>| )</cell></row><row><cell>status</cell><cell>Culprit absent (suspect innocent)</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>| )</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>| )</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>| )</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The joint distributions provide a more precise account for presenting the distributions of witness decision variables-one distribution that presents lineup member memory signals from culprit-present lineups and one distribution that presents memory signals from culprit-absent lineups. The 3D-SDT model develops the joint distributions from a set of simple assumptions. The model further expands the assumptions to accommodate more sophisticated considerations such as unequal variances, criterion shifts, and correlated memory signals. Identifying and modeling the proper joint memory distributions for a lineup task has important implications on how to estimate model parameters (e.g., discriminability) and</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="7">that the area under the guilty suspect distribution beyond the decision criterion should</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">correspond to the guilty suspect identification rate, Pr (</cell><cell>| ), and the area under the innocent</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">suspect distribution beyond the decision criterion should correspond to the innocent suspect</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">identification rate, Pr (</cell><cell cols="3">| ). But which areas correspond to filler identification rates? There is</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">only one filler distribution in the model but two filler identification rates in reality, Pr (</cell><cell>| )</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">and Pr (</cell><cell cols="5">| ). The same dilemma occurs with rejection rates. Which areas correspond to</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">rejection rates? If the areas under the guilty and innocent suspect distributions below the decision</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">criterion correspond to the rejection rates, clearly, the model would violate the mathematical</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">constraint that the response rates sum to 1 under the same ground truth (i.e., Pr(</cell><cell>| ) +</cell></row><row><cell>Pr(</cell><cell cols="2">| ) + Pr(</cell><cell cols="2">| ) = 1 and Pr(</cell><cell>| ) + Pr(</cell><cell>| ) + Pr(</cell><cell>| ) = 1). These</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">discrepancies, again, suggest that the 2D application of SDT may not provide a precise</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">mathematical account for understanding eyewitness decisions.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="6">In sum, previous eyewitness models make significant theoretical contributions by</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">applying SDT to eyewitness decisions. Yet, such applications are generally verbally oriented and</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">lack a rigorously defined mathematical model that is consistent with actual lineup decisions. A</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">rigorously defined mathematical model that could properly incorporate all lineup recognition</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">items would greatly benefit the understanding of eyewitness decisions, just like the classic SDT</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">benefits the understanding of binary decisions. The current paper intends to fill this gap.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">A Three-Dimensional Signal Detection Model</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="6">Such data-model consistency, however, does not exist in the 2D application of SDT to This paper proposes a three-dimensional signal detection theory (3D-SDT) model to</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">lineup decisions. If the 2D lineup models had the same level of data-model consistency as the understand eyewitness decisions. The 3D-SDT model has two unique features. First, it constructs</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">binary SDT model, the areas under the 2D presentations of the three memory distributions a rigorously defined mathematical model that examines the joint distributions of both suspect</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">should correspond to the response rates of the six lineup outcomes (see Table 1). One may think and filler memory signals.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Distributions of Max Filler Signals in Lineups with Different Sizes Joint Distributions of Suspect and Max Filler Memory Signals Because a lineup contains not only a suspect but also fillers, one must consider a joint distribution that can incorporate all memory signals. As discussed above, multiple filler signals</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Discriminability and Response Criterion Used for and Estimated from the Simulated Data</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Parameters used in simulations</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Lineup</cell><cell>Estimation</cell><cell>Estimated</cell><cell>= 0.5</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>= 1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>= 1.5</cell></row><row><cell>size</cell><cell>method</cell><cell>parameter</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>= 0.5</cell><cell>= 1</cell><cell>= 1.5</cell><cell>= 0.5</cell><cell>= 1</cell><cell>= 1.5</cell><cell>= 0.5</cell><cell>= 1</cell><cell>= 1.5</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.476</cell><cell>0.492</cell><cell>0.498</cell><cell>0.944</cell><cell>0.983</cell><cell>0.997</cell><cell>1.403</cell><cell>1.469</cell><cell>1.492</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.046)</cell><cell>(0.052)</cell><cell>(0.064)</cell><cell>(0.047)</cell><cell>(0.050)</cell><cell>(0.058)</cell><cell>(0.050)</cell><cell>(0.052)</cell><cell>(0.058)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>0.641</cell><cell>1.054</cell><cell>1.519</cell><cell>0.641</cell><cell>1.054</cell><cell>1.519</cell><cell>0.641</cell><cell>1.054</cell><cell>1.518</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.025)</cell><cell>(0.031)</cell><cell>(0.042)</cell><cell>(0.024)</cell><cell>(0.031)</cell><cell>(0.042)</cell><cell>(0.024)</cell><cell>(0.031)</cell><cell>(0.042)</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>0.499</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>1.001</cell><cell>1.001</cell><cell>1.001</cell><cell>1.502</cell><cell>1.502</cell><cell>1.501</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.076)</cell><cell>(0.076)</cell><cell>(0.088)</cell><cell>(0.071)</cell><cell>(0.066)</cell><cell>(0.072)</cell><cell>(0.072)</cell><cell>(0.065)</cell><cell>(0.067)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>3D</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>1.000</cell><cell>1.502</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>1.001</cell><cell>1.502</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>1.000</cell><cell>1.501</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.033)</cell><cell>(0.035)</cell><cell>(0.044)</cell><cell>(0.032)</cell><cell>(0.035)</cell><cell>(0.044)</cell><cell>(0.032)</cell><cell>(0.035)</cell><cell>(0.044)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.452</cell><cell>0.479</cell><cell>0.493</cell><cell>0.895</cell><cell>0.953</cell><cell>0.986</cell><cell>1.328</cell><cell>1.423</cell><cell>1.476</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.043)</cell><cell>(0.048)</cell><cell>(0.057)</cell><cell>(0.041)</cell><cell>(0.045)</cell><cell>(0.051)</cell><cell>(0.042)</cell><cell>(0.044)</cell><cell>(0.049)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>0.868</cell><cell>1.152</cell><cell>1.552</cell><cell>0.868</cell><cell>1.152</cell><cell>1.552</cell><cell>0.868</cell><cell>1.152</cell><cell>1.552</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.012)</cell><cell>(0.019)</cell><cell>(0.028)</cell><cell>(0.012)</cell><cell>(0.019)</cell><cell>(0.028)</cell><cell>(0.012)</cell><cell>(0.019)</cell><cell>(0.028)</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.498</cell><cell>0.497</cell><cell>0.496</cell><cell>1.001</cell><cell>0.998</cell><cell>0.999</cell><cell>1.503</cell><cell>1.501</cell><cell>1.500</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.124)</cell><cell>(0.105)</cell><cell>(0.110)</cell><cell>(0.106)</cell><cell>(0.085)</cell><cell>(0.081)</cell><cell>(0.104)</cell><cell>(0.075)</cell><cell>(0.069)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>3D</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>1.000</cell><cell>1.501</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>1.000</cell><cell>1.500</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>1.000</cell><cell>1.501</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(0.029)</cell><cell>(0.027)</cell><cell>(0.032)</cell><cell>(0.029)</cell><cell>(0.027)</cell><cell>(0.032)</cell><cell>(0.028)</cell><cell>(0.027)</cell><cell>(0.032)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table A1</head><label>A1</label><figDesc>Mean and Variance for Max Filler Distributions in Different-Sized Lineups</figDesc><table><row><cell>Lineup size</cell><cell>Filler size</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>1.000</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>0.564</cell><cell>0.682</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>0.846</cell><cell>0.559</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>1.029</cell><cell>0.492</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>1.163</cell><cell>0.448</cell></row><row><cell>12</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>1.586</cell><cell>0.333</cell></row><row><cell>20</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>1.844</cell><cell>0.280</cell></row><row><cell>30</cell><cell>29</cell><cell>2.029</cell><cell>0.248</cell></row><row><cell>40</cell><cell>39</cell><cell>2.151</cell><cell>0.229</cell></row><row><cell>50</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>2.241</cell><cell>0.217</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A: Max Filler Probability Distribution</head><p>The MAX decision rule implies that a witness's decision process involves the memory signal of the filler that has the strongest memory strengths ("max filler"). Therefore, multiple filler signals in a lineup can be reduced to one-the max filler signal. We can derive the probability density function of the max filler distribution.</p><p>In the model, we assume that a lineup's filler memory signals are independent random draws from a standard normal distribution,</p><p>Therefore, the cumulative density function (cdf) of the max filler signal follows,</p><p>Here m denotes the lineup size (i.e., number of lineup members). Correspondingly, ( − 1) denotes the filler size (i.e., number of fillers). Φ( * ) denotes the cdf of a standard normal distribution. From the cdf, one can derive the probability density function (pdf) of the max filler signal,</p><p>Here ( * ) denotes the pdf of a standard normal distribution.</p><p>The close forms of the distribution mean and variance are not easy to derive <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(David &amp; Nagaraja, 2003</ref>). Yet we were able to obtain their numeric approximations (see <ref type="table">Table A1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix B: Derive Probabilities of Eyewitness Outcomes</head><p>With the joint distributions of suspect and filler memory signals, one can derive the probabilities of the three eyewitness outcomes in both culprit-present and culprit-absent lineups.</p><p>Unlike the order in the manuscript, we first examine culprit-absent lineups because of the relative ease in its derivations. We then turn to culprit-present lineups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Culprit-Absent Lineups</head><p>In culprit-absent lineups, a witness's signal detection task can be described by a joint distribution of innocent suspect and max filler memory signals. <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> in the manuscript displays this joint distribution in a contour plot. Note that for this joint distribution, the mean of the innocent suspect marginal distribution is zero. This joint distribution is partitioned into the three segments by the MAX decision rule, shown as the three red lines in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>. The volume of each segment corresponds to the probability of each of the three eyewitness outcomes in culprit-absent lineups. The original model assumes independence among memory signals. This assumption, though, may not hold because lineup members often share some common features <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Wixted et al., 2018</ref> </p><p>In the above assumptions, ρ denotes the correlations among lineup members' memory signals. denotes the unstandardized difference between the marginal means of guilty suspect and innocent suspect memory distributions. denotes the variance of the guilty suspect memory distribution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix F: Ensemble Model Approximation</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why eyewitnesses fail</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Albright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1706891114</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1706891114" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7758" to="7764" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the exact distribution of the maximum of absolutely continuous dependent random variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Arellano-Valle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Genton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.spl.2007.04.021</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spl.2007.04.021" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistics &amp; Probability Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision rules in the perception and categorization of multidimensional stimuli</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0278-7393.14.1.33</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-7393.14.1.33" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a unified theory of similarity and recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Perrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.95.1.124</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.95.1.124" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="150" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Varieties of perceptual independence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.93.2.154</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.93.2.154" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="179" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signal detection theory and human memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Banks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0029531</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0029531" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="1970" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Standards for evaluating the fairness of photograph lineups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Brigham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ready</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Spier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15324834basp1102_3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15324834basp1102_3" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Statistical inference (2 nd ed)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Casella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Duxbury Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A memory and decision model for eyewitness identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/acp.891</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/acp.891" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="654" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimizing the selection of fillers in police lineups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Colloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Seale-Carlisle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2017292118</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2017292118" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">118</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Nagaraja</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Order statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bias in police lineups: Partial remembering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Doob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kirshenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Police Science and Administration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="293" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">No. TR2006-256). Defence Research and Development Canada</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Duncan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. Rep.</note>
	<note>A signal detection model of compound decision tasks</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of suspect-filler similarity on eyewitness identification decisions: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Price</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Oriet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Charman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0030618</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0030618" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, Public Policy, and Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="164" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Friendly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Härdle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Unwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">A brief history of data visualization</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of data visualization</title>
		<editor>C. Chen, W. K. Härdle, &amp; A. Unwin</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Signal detection theory and psychophysics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Swets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<publisher>John Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Showups versus lineups: An evaluation using ROC analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gronlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Neuschatz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Goodsell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wetmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wooten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Research in Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="228" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jarmac.2012.09.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jarmac.2012.09.003" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Why are formal models useful in psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hintzman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>W. E. Hockley, &amp; S</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Relating theory and data: Essays on human memory in honor of</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Bennet B. Murdock</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Erlbaum</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A meta-analysis of lineup size effects on eyewitness identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Juncu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, Public Policy, and Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/law0000311</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/law0000311" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visualizing knowledge and information: An introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Tergan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Knowledge and information visualization</title>
		<editor>T. Sigmar-Olaf &amp; T. Keller</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Springer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ROC analyses in eyewitness identification research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lampinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Research in Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jarmac.2015.08.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jarmac.2015.08.006" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Simulation modeling and analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Law</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kelton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Validity of mock-witness measures for assessing lineup fairness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mansour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Penrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, Crime &amp; Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="245" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/1068316X.2021.1905811</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/1068316X.2021.1905811" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New signal detection theory-based framework for eyewitness performance in lineups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Penrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="436" to="454" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000343</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000343" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Four tensions concerning mathematical modeling in psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eyewitness identification and the selection of distracters for lineups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A E</forename><surname>Luus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF01044829</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF01044829" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Detection theory: A user&apos;s guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Macmillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Creelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">3d-Sdt</forename><surname>Model</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eyewitness decisions in simultaneous and sequential lineups: A dual-process signal detection theory analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Meissner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Tredoux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Maclin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03193074</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03193074" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="783" to="792" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Identifying the culprit: Assessing eyewitness identification</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>The National Academies Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Research Council</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The visualization of mathematics: Towards a mathematical exploratorium</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Palais</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Notices of the</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>American Mathematical Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="647" to="658" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential lineup presentation promotes less-biased criterion setting but does not improve discriminability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Brewer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0093923</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0093923" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="247" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Methodological considerations in eyewitness identification experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Quigley-Mcbride</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>A. M. Smith, M. Toglia, &amp; J. M. Lampinen</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="112" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Methods, measures, and theories in eyewitness identification tasks</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Routledge/Taylor &amp; Francis</forename><surname>Group</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling face similarity in police lineups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Colloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Vul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="432" to="461" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000408</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000408" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Independence and separability in the perception of complex nonspeech sounds. Attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Silbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lentz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/APP.71.8.1900</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/APP.71.8.1900" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1900" to="1915" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fair lineups are better than biased lineups and showups, but not because they increase underlying discriminability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C L</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Penrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="145" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000219</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000219" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eyewitness identification performance on showups improves with an additional-opportunities instruction: Evidence for present-absent criteria discrepancy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C L</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Myerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000284</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000284" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="226" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing between investigator discriminability and eyewitness discriminability: A method for creating full receiver operating characteristic curves of lineup identification performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691620902426</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691620902426" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="589" to="607" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the accuracy of diagnostic systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Swets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.3287615</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.3287615" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">240</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1285" to="1293" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Signal detection theory and ROC analysis in psychology and diagnostics: Collected papers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Swets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological science can improve diagnostic decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Swets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dawes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Monahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1529-1006.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1529-1006.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science in the Public Interest</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of lineup identifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1559-1816.1984.tb02223.x</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1559-1816.1984.tb02223.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="103" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What do we know about eyewitness identification?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0003-066X.48.5.553</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.48.5.553" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="571" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guidelines for empirically assessing the fairness of a lineup</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Leippe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ostrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="293" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Policy and procedure recommendations for the collection and preservation of eyewitness identification evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kovera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Douglass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Brewer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Meissner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000359</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000359" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ROC analysis of lineups does not measure underlying discriminability and has limited value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Smalarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jarmac.2015.08.008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi:10.1016/j.jarmac.2015.08.008" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Research in Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dual-process theory and signal-detection theory of recognition memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.114.1.152</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.114.1.152" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The field of eyewitness memory should abandon probative value and embrace receiver operating characteristic analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mickes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691612442906</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691612442906" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A signal-detection-based diagnostic-feature-detection model of eyewitness identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mickes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="262" to="276" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0035940</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0035940" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models of lineup memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Vul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mickes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2018.06.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2018.06.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An expected cost model of eyewitness identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Smalarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Moody</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Cabell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Copp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="219" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000331</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000331" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">fullROC: An R package for generating and analyzing eyewitness-lineup ROC curves</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1259" to="1274" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-022-01807-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-022-01807-6" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Receiver operating characteristics (ROCs) in recognition memory: A review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Yonelinas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Parks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="800" to="832" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-2909.133.5.800</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.133.5.800" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
