<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Value certainty and choice confidence are multidimensional constructs that guide decision-making</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<email>douglasglee@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tel Aviv University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Zurich Center for Neuroeconomics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Zurich</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Neuroscience Center Zurich</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Zurich and ETH Zurich</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Value certainty and choice confidence are multidimensional constructs that guide decision-making</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:48+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>multi-attribute choice</term>
					<term>metacognition</term>
					<term>subjective value</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The degree of certainty that decision-makers have about their evaluations of available choice alternatives and their confidence about selecting the subjectively best alternative are important factors that affect current and future value-based choices. Assessments of the alternatives in a given choice set are rarely unidimensional; their values are usually derived from a combination of multiple distinct attributes. For example, the taste, texture, quantity, and nutritional content of a snack food may all be considered when determining whether to consume it. Here, we examined how certainty about the levels of individual attributes of an option relates to certainty about the overall value of that option as a whole and/or to confidence in having chosen the subjectively best available option. We found that certainty and confidence are derived from unequally-weighted combinations of attribute certainties rather than simple, equal combinations of all sources of uncertainty. Attributes that matter more in determining choice outcomes are also weighted more in metacognitive evaluations of certainty or confidence. Moreover, we found that the process of deciding between two alternatives leads to refinements in both attribute estimations and the degree of certainty in those estimates. Attributes that are more important in determining choice outcomes are refined more during the decision process in terms of both estimates and certainty. Although certainty and confidence are typically treated as unidimensional, our results indicate that they, like value estimates, are subjective, multidimensional constructs.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Most human behavior is guided, at some level, by subjective assessments of value or goal relevance. Explicitly evaluating options and/or choosing between two or more options according to their desirability are perhaps the most illustrative examples of this process. Even for decisions where the objective values are clearly defined and not malleable, the personal sense of the value of the options to individual decision-makers can nevertheless be subjective.</p><p>Decisions where no universal objective values existperhaps the most common varietymust rely solely on subjective values. Previous research has established that people often subjectively assess choice options in terms of specific individual value-related attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Amasino et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Barakchian et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bhatia &amp; Stewart, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Hare et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Harris et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Lee &amp; Hare, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Luce et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Maier et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Reeck et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Sullivan et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Weber &amp; Johnson, 2009)</ref>. It is assumed that such attribute assessments should aggregate to approximate subjective estimates of overall value, provided that a sufficient set of attributes is considered. However, recent work has shown that the subjective assessments of individual attributes that people report influence decision behavior beyond the influence of aggregated overall value estimates. Specifically, computational models that incorporate measures of individual attributes in addition to or instead of measures of overall value provide better accounts for choice outcomes, response times, response movement trajectories, and confidence reports <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Amasino et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Lee, D'Alessandro, et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Lee &amp; Hare, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Yang &amp; Krajbich, 2022)</ref>.</p><p>Confidence reports are often used to examine how people evaluate their own performance on cognitive tasks, including decision-making, based solely on their own internal cognitive processes (i.e., not on external feedback). This ability is generally referred to as metacognition. Metacognitive assessments of choices are thought to aid in both current <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Desender et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Lee, Daunizeau, et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">van den Berg et al., 2016)</ref> and future decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fleming &amp; Daw, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Yeung &amp; Summerfield, 2012)</ref>. For decisions with objectively correct responses, the degree to which confidence correlates with accuracy provides measures of metacognitive sensitivity and efficiency <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Fleming &amp; Lau, 2014)</ref>. Metacognitive skills have been linked to individual differences in psychiatric symptomatology, radical political beliefs, intelligence, and academic performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Atiya et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Hoven et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Ohtani &amp; Hisasaka, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Rollwage et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Rouault et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Thus, confidence and metacognition appear to have a substantial impact on a wide range of human thoughts and behaviors.</p><p>People can also report choice confidence for decisions that are subjective <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Brus et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">da Silva Castanheira et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">De Martino et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Folke et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Quandt et al., 2022)</ref>, as well as their level of certainty about self-reported estimates of subjective value (De <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Martino et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gwinn &amp; Krajbich, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Polanía et al., 2019)</ref>. The subjective measures of value certainty that people report have been shown to correlate systematically with key decision behavior such as choice outcomes, response times, and choice confidence levels <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref>. Specifically, when people report higher certainty about the sense of value that they have for the choice options (regardless of their actual value estimates), they choose more consistently, more quickly, and more confidently.</p><p>This could be due to value signals in the brain either being enhanced by certainty or degraded by uncertainty as the choice options are compared <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Brus et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Lee &amp; Usher, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Nearly all studies of certainty and confidence in relation to value-based decisions have treated these metacognitive constructs as unidimensional.</p><p>The importance and impact of metacognitive evaluations of the individual attributes of choice options on valuation and decision-making is relatively unknown. We posit that value certainty and choice confidence form at the level of the individual attributes. Here, we test if metacognitive evaluations of certainty about the overall value of an option or confidence in a decision outcome are based on equal aggregations of all sources of (un)certainty, or instead come from unequally-weighted combinations of certainty in option attributes. We also test if the certainty about option attributes increases over the course of deciding, and if so, whether that increase in certainty is equal for all attributes or if certainty about an attribute increases in proportion to the importance of that attribute for the decision outcome. We collected and analyzed data from two independent experiments. To briefly preview our results, we found that the contribution of an attribute to decision confidence as well as the amount of certainty that an attribute gains through the comparison process are both proportional to its importance in determining the decision outcome. Thus, like first-order constructions of value or goal relevance, second-order metacognitive evaluations of certainty or confidence are subjective combinations across attributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>A total of 107 people participated in the experiment (62 female; age: mean = 29 years, SD = 7, range 18-40). This sample size was chosen to be comparable to that used in previous studies based on a similar paradigm, while also allowing for sufficient sample sizes within each of the counterbalanced groups. All participants were recruited using Prolific (https://prolific.co). All were citizens of the United States or Canada, 101 were current residents of the United States or Canada, and 91 were native English speakers. Each participant received a payment of $10 as compensation for approximately one hour of time. Our experiments involved de-identified participant data, and protocols were approved by the Human Subjects Committee of the Faculty of Economics, Business Administration and Information Technology at the University of Zurich. All participants gave informed consent prior to commencing the experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>The experiments were constructed using the online experimental platform Gorilla (gorilla.sc). The experimental stimuli were drawn from a set of 200 digital images used in a previous study <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020)</ref>, each representing a distinct snack food item. Only the foods themselves were displayed in the images, no packaging or other materials were displayed. For this experiment, we used a subset of 100 stimuli, identical for all participants.</p><p>We used the identical set of stimuli as was used for Experiment 1 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>, which had been determined by selecting the 100 items for which ratings from the original study varied the least (within each item) across participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Procedure</head><p>The experiment consisted of a pre-exposure phase, followed by a rating phase, followed by a choice phase. No time limits were imposed for any of the constituent tasks, and a time limit of 140 minutes was imposed for the overall experiment (median completion time: 54 minutes). See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> for an illustrative depiction of the flow of the experiment.</p><p>In the pre-exposure phase, participants simply observed as all individual items were displayed in a random sequence for 1000 ms each. The purpose of the pre-exposure phase was to familiarize participants with the full set of items that they would later evaluate, allowing them to form an impression of the range of subjective values across the item set.</p><p>The rating phase comprised three sets of ratings: one for subjective overall value, and one for a subjective assessment of each of two individual attributes: pleasure and nutrition. In each rating task, all stimuli were displayed on the screen, one at a time, in a sequence randomized across participants. At the onset of each trial, the screen went blank for 100 ms, then a fixation cross appeared at the center of the screen for 300 ms, then the screen went blank again for 100 ms. Next, an image of a single food item appeared at the center of the screen. For the overall value rating, participants responded to the question, "How much would you want this as a frequent snack?" using a horizontal slider scale. This question was intended to motivate participants to think carefully while assessing the overall subjective quality of each option, as they should think more carefully when evaluating something they would consume frequently rather than just once. Specifically, participants were instructed: "Click anywhere on the scale according to your personal preferences regarding eating the snack on a daily basis. The furthest left end of the scale indicates that you strongly dislike the snack and would hate to eat it often.</p><p>The furthest right end of the scale indicates that you strongly like the snack and would love to eat it often. The middle of the scale indicates that you are neutral about eating the snack often.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Try to imagine committing to eating this item on a frequent basis, not just one single time."</head><p>The leftmost end of the scale was labeled "Hate it!", the center of the scale was labeled "Neutral.", and the rightmost end was labeled "Love it!" The scale appeared to participants to be continuous, and the data were captured in increments of 1 (ranging from 1 to 100). There were no other marks on the scale, and the cursor did not appear on the scale until after participants clicked on it. Participants could revise their rating as many times as they liked before finalizing it. Participants clicked a button labeled "Enter" to finalize their overall value rating response and proceed to the next screen. On the next screen, participants reported their subjective certainty about the overall value estimate that they had just reported. They responded to the question, "How sure are you about that?" using a continuous horizontal slider scale. The leftmost end of the scale was labeled "Not at all!" and the rightmost end was labeled "Absolutely!" The format of this slider scale was otherwise similar to the one for the overall value estimate, only half the overall length. Participants could revise their certainty as many times as they liked before finalizing it by clicking a button labeled "Enter". The next trial then began.</p><p>In addition to overall value ratings, attribute ratings were performed separately for pleasure and nutrition, with the order counterbalanced across participants. The order of the overall value or attribute ratings was also counterbalanced across participants. One attribute was rated for every option (in one task section), then the other attribute was rated for every option (in the next task section). In each attribute rating task, all stimuli were displayed on the screen, one at a time, in a random sequence (randomized across participants and across sections for each participant). The format of the attribute rating tasks was identical to that of the overall value rating task, except now participants responded to the question, "How pleasurable do you consider this item to be?" or "How nutritious do you consider this item to be?" For the pleasure ratings, participants were instructed: "You will now evaluate the snack foods according to how pleasurable you believe them to be. Pleasure here refers to sensory enjoyment, and can include whatever you think should be included, such as taste, smell, texture, appearance, etc." For the nutrition ratings, participants were instructed: "You will now evaluate the snack food items according to how nutritious you believe them to be. Nutrition can include whatever you think should be included, such as vitamins, minerals, protein, fat, carbohydrates, calories, etc." For both attribute ratings, the leftmost end of the slider scale was labeled "Very bad!", the center of the scale was labeled "Neutral.", and the rightmost end was labeled "Very good!". After finalizing their attribute rating for each option, participants then reported their subjective certainty about each attribute rating in a manner identical to that by which they reported the overall value certainty.</p><p>After completing all the rating task sections (overall value, pleasure, nutrition), participants completed the choice task. Prior to commencing the choice task, participants were instructed not to try to remember their earlier ratings, but rather to simply choose based on their current evaluations. For this task, 50 pairs of stimuli were displayed on the screen, one pair at a time, in a sequence randomized across participants. The pairings of items for each choice trial were identical to those used for Experiment 1 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>, which had been created so as make the choices relatively difficult, as assessed by small differences in overall value ratings between the two items in each choice pair in the original study <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020)</ref>. Each individual item occurred in a single choice pair only. At the onset of each trial, the screen went blank for 100 ms, then a fixation cross appeared at the center of the screen for 300 ms, then the screen went blank again for 100 ms. Next, a pair of images of food items appeared on the screen, one to the left and one to the right of the center of the screen. Participants responded to the question, "Which would you prefer as a frequent snack?" by clicking on the image of their preferred item. Participants then responded to the question, "How sure are you about your choice?" using a horizontal slider scale. The leftmost end of the scale was labeled "Not at all!" and the rightmost end was labeled "Absolutely!" Participants could revise their confidence report as many times as they liked before finalizing it. Participants clicked a button labeled "Enter" to finalize their confidence report and proceed to the next screen. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical analyses</head><p>Unless stated otherwise, all statistical effect sizes reported below were calculated based on mixed effects (MFX) general linear model (GLM) regression analysis. The regressors of interest (as reported for each analysis below) were included as fixed-effects variables, and all regressions also included random-effects slope and intercept terms for individual participants.</p><p>All reported p-values are based on two-tailed tests. All rating variables were rescaled to the (-1,1] interval and all certainty and confidence variables were rescaled to the (0,1] interval prior to entering the analyses. To assist with both readability and interpretation, for all regression analyses except those related to choice consistency, we coded all variables such that option 1 (for each choice) refers to the option with the higher overall value rating. We thus define overall value difference (dV) as the difference in overall value ratings (option 1 minus option 2). We define pleasure difference (dP) and nutrition difference (dN) in an analogous manner. For the regressions related to choice consistency, we defined dV as the overall value of the option displayed on the right of the screen minus the overall value of the option displayed on the left of the screen (and similarly for dP, dN, dVC, dPC, and dNC), and defined consistency as the probability of choosing the option on the right. All response times (RTs) were log-transformed prior to entering the analyses. Within participant, we excluded trials with outlier RT (which we defined as log(RT) &gt; median(log(RT)) + 3 * median_average_deviation(log(RT)) or log(RT) &lt; median(log(RT)) -3 * median_average_deviation(log(RT))).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overall value estimates and certainty are composed of attribute estimates and certainty</head><p>How are attribute-level estimates and their certainty related to estimates and certainty for overall value? We addressed this question by first regressing overall value ratings on pleasure and nutrition ratings. The MFX coefficients for both attributes were significantly greater than zero (pleasure: 0.78, p &lt; .001; nutrition: 0.14, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.68; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure   2A</ref>). This demonstrates that pleasure and nutrition together explain a large amount of overall value, but that there are likely other attributes that also influence subjective assessments of overall value. Next, we regressed overall value certainty on pleasure certainty and nutrition certainty. Both MFX coefficients were significantly greater than zero (pleasure certainty: 0.30, p &lt; .001; nutrition certainty: 0.12, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.45; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2B</ref>). Note that more of the variance in overall value and overall value certainty is explained by pleasure (R 2 from regression of overall value on pleasure alone = 0.63) and pleasure certainty (R 2 from regression of overall value certainty on pleasure certainty alone = 0.43), respectively, than by nutrition (R 2 from regression of overall value on nutrition alone = 0.27) and nutrition certainty (R 2 from regression of overall value certainty on nutrition certainty alone = 0.35). In other words, the rank order of the contributions of attribute certainty to overall value certainty matches the rank order of the attribute contributions to overall value, indicating that both overall value and overall value certainty are subjective constructs and that lower-level attributes contribute similarly to the estimation of each construct. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Choice behavior can be explained by attribute estimates and certainty</head><p>As a basic validation of the overall value rating and choice data, we tested how well choices could be explained by the difference in the overall value ratings of the options in each choice pair. We found that choices were highly aligned with overall value difference: across participants, 77% of all choices were made in accordance with the overall value ratings. We also regressed (logistic) choice on overall value difference and found the MFX coefficient to be significantly greater than zero (0.83, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.32). Next, we tested how well choices could be explained using differences in pleasure and nutrition, instead of overall value difference. The MFX coefficients for each attribute were significantly greater than zero (pleasure difference: 0.87, p &lt; .001; nutrition difference: 0.14, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.31).</p><p>Previous studies have demonstrated associations between dependent variables related to choiceconsistency (choosing the option with the higher overall value rating), response time (RT), and choice confidenceand independent variables related to overall valuesum and difference of value estimates and sum and difference of value certainty of the options within each choice pair. Specifically, each of these independent variables correlated positively with consistency and confidence, and negatively with RT <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Lee &amp; Usher, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Shevlin et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Another previous study has shown that, in addition to the independent variables related to overall value, an independent variable related to individual attributesdisparityshows the same qualitative relationships <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>. Attribute disparity accounts for the fact that choice options could be composed of very different attribute estimates, even if they were rated with similar overall values (see Supplementary Material for details). We replicated most of the associations between the aforementioned independent and dependent variables in our data (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Material)</ref>. The fact that attribute disparity has clear associations with the dependent choice variables already indicates that information about attributes contributes to the decision process beyond the information contained in general assessments of overall value.</p><p>Next, we examined how attribute-level measures might directly relate to choice consistency, RT, and confidence. We thus tested the associations between these three dependent variables and the sums of attribute estimates (both pleasure and nutrition), as well as the differences (which were previously examined in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>). We also went beyond previous work to determine if, in addition to attribute estimates, attribute certainty was also associated with choice consistency, RT, and confidence. Specifically, we tested the associations between these dependent variables and the sums of pleasure and nutrition certainty and the differences in pleasure and nutrition certainty (higher overall-valued option minus lower overall-valued option). We used three separate regression models to test for the effects of all eight independent variables on the three dependent variables ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>; <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). In the regression with choice consistency as the dependent variable, we found significant positive associations with pleasure sum, pleasure difference, nutrition difference, and pleasure certainty difference ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3A)</ref>. When RT was the dependent variable, there were significant negative associations with pleasure sum, nutrition sum, pleasure difference, and nutrition difference, but no significant associations with any of the certainty measures ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3B</ref>). When choice confidence was the dependent variable, there were significant positive associations with all attribute-level independent variables except nutrition certainty difference ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3C</ref>). Thus, we found that choice confidence was the most sensitive of the three dependent variables to measures of attribute certainty. , difference in pleasure (dP), difference in nutrition (dN), sum of pleasure certainty (sPC), sum of nutrition certainty (sNC), difference in pleasure certainty (dPC), and difference in nutrition certainty (dNC) of the options on each trial on choice consistency (choosing the option with the higher overall value rating; A), response time (B), and choice confidence (C). Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, ** p &lt; .01, *** p &lt; .001. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Effects of rating estimates and certainty on choice consistency, response time, and confidence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consistency log(RT) Confidence</head><p>Pleasure sum (sP) 0.04 (p = .041) -0.13 (p &lt; .001) 0.13 (p &lt; .001)</p><p>Nutrition sum (sN) -0.01 (p = .307) -0.02 (p = .048) 0.02 (p &lt; .001)</p><p>Pleasure difference (dP) 0.55 (p &lt; .001) -0.29 (p &lt; .001) 0.24 (p &lt; .001)</p><p>Nutrition difference (dN) 0.09 (p &lt; .001) -0.05 (p = .003) 0.03 (p = .002)</p><p>Pleasure certainty sum (sPC) -0.02 (p = .335) 0.00 (p = .863) 0.09 (p &lt; .001)</p><p>Nutrition certainty sum (sNC) -0.04 (p = .101) -0.02 (p = .298) 0.03 (p = .003)</p><p>Pleasure certainty difference (dPC) 0.09 (p &lt; .001) -0.03 (p = .286) 0.03 (p = .019)</p><p>Nutrition certainty difference (dNC) 0.00 (p = .880) 0.02 (p = .421) 0.00 (p = .882)</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">R 2 = 0.16 R 2 = 0.56 R 2 = 0.45</formula><p>This table lists the mixed-effects regression coefficients from three separate regressions using either choice consistency, response time, or confidence as the dependent variable. All regressions included random intercepts and slopes for each variable by participant.</p><p>We also tested for effects specific to the individual options on each trial (chosen or rejected), rather than sums or differences across options. Specifically, we tested the associations between the same three dependent variables (consistency, RT, and confidence) and the pleasure and nutrition estimate and certainty for the chosen and rejected options. We used three separate regression models to test for the effects of all eight independent variables on the three dependent variables <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Figure 4</ref>; <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref>). In the regression with choice consistency as the dependent variable, we found significant positive associations with pleasure and nutrition for the chosen option, and significant negative associations with pleasure and nutrition for the rejected option, but no significant associations with any of the certainty terms ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4A</ref>). The magnitudes of the weights for chosen options were roughly equal to the weights for rejected options. When RT was the dependent variable, there were significant negative associations with pleasure and nutrition for the chosen option, and significant positive associations with pleasure and nutrition for the rejected option, but no significant associations with any of the certainty terms (although there appears to be a trend following the same pattern as for the other dependent variables; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4B</ref>). Interestingly, now the magnitudes of the weights for the chosen options were greater than the weights for the rejected options. When choice confidence was the dependent variable, there were significant positive associations with pleasure and nutrition for the chosen option, and significant negative associations with pleasure and nutrition for the rejected option; there were also positive and mostly significant associations with all the certainty terms ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4C</ref>). It is interesting that choice confidence always increased with attribute certainty, regardless of whether it was for the chosen or rejected option. As with RT, the magnitudes of the weights for the chosen options were greater than for the rejected options. Predictive effect of the pleasure, nutrition, pleasure certainty, and nutrition certainty for the chosen option (Pc, Nc, PCc, NCc) and for the rejected option (Pr, Nr, PCr, NCr) on each trial on choice consistency (choosing the option with the higher overall value rating; A), response time (B), and choice confidence (C). Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, ** p &lt; .01, *** p &lt; .001. nutrition of rejected (Nr) -0.11 (p &lt; .001) 0.06 (p = .005) -0.02 (p = .038) pleasure certainty of chosen (PCc) 0 (p = .985) -0.03 (p = .479) 0.11 (p &lt; .001)</p><p>pleasure certainty of rejected (PCr) -0.04 (p = .157) 0.01 (p = .679) 0.04 (p = .022) nutrition certainty of chosen (NCc) -0.03 (p = .411) -0.06 (p = .076) 0.04 (p = .014) nutrition certainty of rejected (NCr) -0.05 (p = .117) 0.01 (p = .673) 0.03 (p = .076) R 2 = 0.16 R 2 = 0.56 R 2 = 0.48</p><p>This table lists the mixed-effects regression coefficients from three separate regressions using either choice consistency, response time, or confidence as the dependent variable. All regressions included random intercepts and slopes for each variable by participant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In this first experiment, we examined participants' subjective estimates of overall value, pleasure, and nutrition for a variety of different snack foods, as well as their subjective feelings of certainty about both their overall value estimates and their assessments of the individual attributes. Our results replicate the well-established finding that attributes are subjectively weighted when computing an overall value for an option. Beyond that, they also demonstrate that certainty about overall value is an unequally-weighted combination of attribute-level certainty rather than an equal combination of certainty across the individual attributes. This indicates that metacognitive assessments, such as feelings of certainty about the subjective overall value estimates that one provides, originate with respect to individual attributes instead of, or in addition to, being derived from an aggregated overall value. Furthermore, in the context of our snack food choice paradigm, we showed that the rank order of the contributions of the pleasure and nutrition attribute estimates to overall value estimates matches the rank order of pleasure certainty and nutrition certainty to overall value certainty. This result further indicates that overall value judgments are a subjective agglomeration of attribute judgements, even at the metacognitive level.</p><p>Attribute judgements and their certainty are also subjectively related to binary choice consistency, response time, and confidence. We replicated previous findings that consistency,</p><p>RT, and confidence relate to differences in the pleasure and nutrition attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref> in the same way that many previous studies have shown that they relate to differences in overall value <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Lee &amp; Usher, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Shevlin et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2019)</ref>. Furthermore, we showed that other aspects of individual attribute evaluations, such as the sum of estimates, correlated with all three dependent variables. In particular, choice confidence was enhanced by both the sums and differences of the attribute estimates, as well as by the sums and differences of the attribute certainty. Moreover, the regression weights for and variance explained (R 2 ) by variables related to pleasure were greater than those for variables related to nutrition, which parallels the results showing the relative contributions of these attributes to overall value estimates and certainty.</p><p>Together, these results suggest that reported levels of confidence about choices are at least partially determined by unequally-weighted subjective feelings of certainty about attribute estimates, in a manner similar to how choices themselves are driven to a greater extent by specific attributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2 Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>A total of 93 people participated in the experiment (44 female; age: mean = 28 years, SD = 6, range 18-40). This sample size was chosen to be comparable to that used in previous studies based on a similar paradigm, while also allowing for sufficient sample sizes within each of the counterbalanced groups. All participants were recruited using Prolific </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>The experiments were constructed using the online experimental platform Gorilla (gorilla.sc). For this experiment, we used a subset of 60 stimuli (out of the 100 used in Experiment 1), identical for all participants. We used the identical set of stimuli as was used for Experiments 2-5 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>, which had been determined by selecting from the larger subset of 100 (Experiment 1 of this study and Experiment 1 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b</ref>)) the 60 items appearing in the 30 choice pairs that generated the highest overall spreading of alternatives (SoA) across participants in Experiment 1 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Procedure</head><p>The experiment consisted of a pre-exposure phase, followed by an initial rating phase, followed by a choice phase, followed by a final rating phase. No time limits were imposed for any of the constituent tasks, and a time limit of 140 minutes was imposed for the overall experiment (median completion time: 51 minutes).</p><p>The pre-exposure phase was identical to that in Experiment 1, except with fewer stimuli. The initial rating phase was identical to the rating phase in Experiment 1, except with fewer stimuli. The choice phase was identical to that in Experiment 1, except with fewer pairs of stimuli (identical to those used for Experiments 2-5 in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>).</p><p>After completing the choice task, participants completed the final rating task. The final rating task was identical in format to the initial rating task. The sequence of rating sections (overall value, pleasure, nutrition) for each participant was the same in the final rating task as it had been in the initial rating task. For each participant, the stimuli were presented in a different random order than in the initial rating task. Prior to commencing the final rating task, participants were instructed not to try to remember their earlier ratings, but rather to simply rate the stimuli as they now evaluated them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical analyses</head><p>All statistical analyses were performed in an identical manner as in Experiment 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Before testing for additional effects beyond those that we observed in the data from the first experiment, we first verified that each of the results that we reported for Experiment 1 replicated for Experiment 2:</p><p>Overall value estimates and certainty are composed of attribute estimates and certainty</p><p>We replicated the finding that both overall value estimates and certainty are subjectively-weighted combinations of attribute estimates and certainty, respectively. Once again, we first regressed overall value ratings on pleasure and nutrition ratings. The MFX coefficients for both attributes were significantly greater than zero (pleasure: 0.72, p &lt; .001; nutrition: 0.21, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.66; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5A</ref> in red). We then repeated the same regression analysis, this time using post-choice ratings instead of pre-choice. Post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to (and slightly greater than) those for prechoice ratings, and the post-choice ratings explained more of the variance (pleasure: 0.75, p &lt; .001; nutrition: 0.24, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.75; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5A</ref> in blue). This supports the idea that participants refined their evaluations during choice deliberation and maintained those refined representations throughout the remainder of the experiment <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021a)</ref>. To test whether the increase in R 2 was statistically significant, we repeated the same regressions separately for each participant and examined the crossparticipant R 2 values for the regressions based on post-choice ratings versus those based on pre-choice ratings. The R 2 values based on post-choice ratings were significantly greater, according to a Wilcoxon signed rank test (mean difference in R 2 = 0.11, p &lt; .001).</p><p>We then regressed overall value certainty on pleasure certainty and nutrition certainty.</p><p>Both MFX coefficients were significantly greater than zero (pleasure certainty: 0.30, p &lt; .001; nutrition certainty: 0.11, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.42; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5B</ref> in red). Repeating the same regression analysis using post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to (and slightly greater than) those for pre-choice ratings, and the post-choice ratings explained more of the variance (pleasure certainty: 0.36, p &lt; .001; nutrition certainty: 0.17, p &lt; .001;</p><p>adjusted R 2 = 0.52; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5B</ref> in blue). To test whether the increase in R 2 was statistically significant, we repeated the same regressions separately for each participant and examined the cross-participant R 2 values for the regressions based on post-choice ratings versus those based on pre-choice ratings. The R 2 values based on post-choice ratings were significantly greater, according to a Wilcoxon signed rank test (mean difference in R 2 = 0.05, p = .005).</p><p>Consistent with Experiment 1, more of the variance in overall value and overall value certainty is explained by pleasure (adjusted R 2 from regression of overall value on pleasure alone = 0.57 or 0.64, using pre-or post-choice ratings, respectively) and pleasure certainty (adjusted R 2 from regression of overall value certainty on pleasure certainty alone = 0.41 or 0.47, using pre-or post-choice ratings, respectively), respectively, than by nutrition (adjusted R 2 from regression of overall value on nutrition alone = 0.26 or 0.30, using pre-or post-choice ratings, respectively) and nutrition certainty (adjusted R 2 from regression of overall value certainty on nutrition certainty alone = 0.32 or 0.42, using pre-or post-choice ratings, respectively). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Choice behavior can be explained by attribute estimates and certainty</head><p>Choices were highly aligned with overall value differences. Across participants, 78%</p><p>of all choices were made in accordance with the pre-choice overall value ratings. We regressed (logistic) choice on overall value difference and found the MFX coefficient to be significantly greater than zero (0.82, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.39). We also regressed (logistic) choice on pleasure difference and nutrition difference in the place of overall value difference. The MFX coefficients for each attribute were significantly greater than zero (pleasure difference: 0.79, p &lt; .001; nutrition difference: 0.19, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.36). We then repeated the same analysis, this time using post-choice ratings. Choices were slightly more aligned with postchoice overall value difference (80% of all choices, across participants). Post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to those for pre-choice ratings, and they explained more of the variance (overall value difference: 0.85, p &lt; 0.001; adjusted R 2 = 0.43; pleasure difference: 0.84, p &lt; .001; nutrition difference: 0.15, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.40). To test whether the increase in R 2 was statistically significant, we repeated the same regressions separately for each participant and examined the cross-participant R 2 values for the regressions based on post-choice ratings versus those based on pre-choice ratings. For the regressions based on overall value, the R 2 values were higher when using post-versus pre-choice ratings (mean difference = 0.08, p = .002). For the regressions based on individual attributes, the R 2 values were not significantly different, according to a Wilcoxon signed rank test (mean difference = 0.02, p = .246).</p><p>Lastly, we note that our data replicate many previous results regarding the relationships between overall value sum and difference, overall value certainty sum and difference, and attribute disparity, and the dependent choice variables: consistency, RT, and confidence (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Material)</ref>. We also note that for these regressions based on overall value ratings and certainty as well as attribute disparity, the cross-participant R 2 values were significantly greater for regressions based on post-versus pre-choice ratings, according to Wilcoxon signed rank tests (consistency: mean difference in R 2 = 0.09, p = .015; RT: mean difference in R 2 = 0.07, p = .009; confidence: mean difference in R 2 = 0.04, p = .014).</p><p>Choices were also strongly associated with attribute ratings and certainty. We regressed choice consistency, RT, and confidence (separately) on pleasure sum and difference, nutrition sum and difference, pleasure certainty sum and difference, and nutrition certainty sum and difference (Figure 6 in red; <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref>). For choice consistency, we found positive associations with pleasure difference, nutrition difference, and pleasure certainty difference. For RT, we found negative associations with pleasure sum and difference, nutrition sum, and nutrition certainty sum. For confidence, we found positive associations with all variables except nutrition certainty difference. We then repeated the same regression analyses, this time using post-choice ratings. Post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to those for pre-choice ratings (with a few changes in significance; Figure 6 in blue; <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref>). Across participants, the R 2 values based on pre-or post-choice ratings were not significantly different, according to Wilcoxon signed rank tests (p &gt; .354 for all dependent variables). of nutrition certainty (sNC), difference in pleasure certainty (dPC), and difference in nutrition certainty (dNC) of the options on each trial on choice consistency (choosing the option with the higher overall value rating; A), response time (B), and choice confidence (C). Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, ** p &lt; .01, *** p &lt; .001. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Effects of rating estimates and certainty on choice consistency, response time, and confidence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consistency log(RT) Confidence</head><p>Pleasure sum (sP) 0.02 (p = .297) -0.11 (p &lt; .001) 0.11 (p &lt; .001) Nutrition sum (sN) 0 (p = .868) -0.05 (p = .004) 0.03 (p = .003) Pleasure difference (dP) 0.50 (p &lt; .001) -0.26 (p &lt; .001) 0.25 (p &lt; .001) Nutrition difference (dN) 0.11 (p &lt; .001) -0.02 (p = .377) 0.04 (p &lt; .001) Pleasure certainty sum (sPC) 0.02 (p = .554) 0.02 (p = .644) 0.7 (p &lt; .001) Nutrition certainty sum (sNC) -0.05 (p = .097) -0.07 (p = .040) 0.03 (p = .035) Pleasure certainty difference (dPC) 0.10 (p = .003) -0.04 (p = .298) 0.04 (p = .041) Nutrition certainty difference (dNC) 0 (p = .885) 0.02 (p = .533) -0.02 (p = .410) R 2 = 0.19 R 2 = 0.29 R 2 = 0.42 Pleasure sum (sP) 0.01 (p = .589) -0.11 (p &lt; .001) 0.11 (p &lt; .001) Nutrition sum (sN) 0.01 (p = .624) -0.03 (p = .104) 0.02 (p = .013) Pleasure difference (dP) 0.52 (p &lt; .001) -0.24 (p &lt; .001) 0.26 (p &lt; .001) Nutrition difference (dN) 0.08 (p = .002) 0 (p = .899) 0.03 (p = .018) Pleasure certainty sum (sPC) 0.02 (p = .435) -0.05 (p = .182) 0.14 (p &lt; .001) Nutrition certainty sum (sNC) -0.01 (p = .853) 0.04 (p = .355) 0 (p = .935) Pleasure certainty difference (dPC) 0.14 (p &lt; .001) -0.08 (p = .041) 0.06 (p = .028) Nutrition certainty difference (dNC) 0.02 (p = .487) 0 (p = .950) -0.02 (p = .332) R 2 = 0.21 R 2 = 0.28 R 2 = 0.45 This table lists the mixed-effects regression coefficients from six separate regressions using either choice consistency, response time, or confidence as the dependent variable, using either pre-choice (in red) or post-choice (in blue) ratings. All regressions included random intercepts and slopes for each variable by participant.</p><p>We also tested the associations between the same three dependent variables (consistency, RT, and confidence) and the pleasure and nutrition estimate and certainty for the chosen and rejected options. We used three separate regression models to test for the effects of all eight independent variables on the three dependent variables <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Figure 7</ref>; <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 4</ref>). In the regression with choice consistency as the dependent variable, we found significant positive associations with pleasure and nutrition for the chosen option, and significant negative associations with pleasure and nutrition for the rejected option, but no significant associations with any of the certainty terms; the results were similar whether using pre-or post-choice ratings ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 7A</ref>). The magnitudes of the weights for chosen options were roughly equal to those for rejected options. When RT was the dependent variable, there were significant negative associations with pleasure and nutrition for the chosen option, and significant positive associations with pleasure (but not nutrition) for the rejected option, and mostly no significant associations with the certainty terms; the results were similar whether using pre-or post-choice ratings ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 7B</ref>). The magnitudes of the weights for the chosen options were greater than for the rejected options. When choice confidence was the dependent variable, there were significant positive associations with pleasure and nutrition for the chosen option, and significant negative associations with pleasure and nutrition for the rejected option; these results were similar whether using pre-or post-choice ratings. There were also significant positive associations with pleasure certainty of the chosen option (based on pre-or post-choice ratings) and pleasure certainty of the rejected option (based on post-choice ratings; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 7C</ref>).</p><p>The magnitudes of the weights for the chosen options were greater than for the rejected options.  nutrition of rejected (Nr) -0.17 (p &lt; .001) 0 (p = .971) -0.04 (p = .006) pleasure certainty of chosen (PCc) 0.07 (p = .195) 0 (p = .966) 0.11 (p &lt; .001)</p><p>pleasure certainty of rejected (PCr) 0.01 (p = .869) 0.01 (p = .857) 0.02 (p = .355) nutrition certainty of chosen (NCc) 0 (p = .993) -0.12 (p = .033) 0.02 (p = .426) nutrition certainty of rejected (NCr) -0.05 (p = .206) -0.02 (p = .621) 0.04 (p = .110) nutrition of rejected (Nr) -0.15 (p &lt; .001) 0.01 (p = .666) -0.3 (p = .023) pleasure certainty of chosen (PCc) 0 (p = .953) -0.18 (p = .007) 0.22 (p &lt; .001) pleasure certainty of rejected (PCr) 0.06 (p = .162) 0.05 (p = .361) 0.07 (p = .002) nutrition certainty of chosen (NCc) 0.05 (p = .306) 0.05 (p = .394) -0.02 (p = .371) nutrition certainty of rejected (NCr) -0.04 (p = .377) 0.02 (p = .677) 0.03 (p = .310) R 2 = 0.17 R 2 = 0.31 R 2 = 0.47</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">R 2 =</formula><p>This table lists the mixed-effects regression coefficients from six separate regressions using either choice consistency, response time, or confidence as the dependent variable, using either pre-choice (in red) or post-choice (in blue) ratings. All regressions included random intercepts and slopes for each variable by participant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Choices induce preference refinements</head><p>The purpose of soliciting evaluations both prior to and after the choice task was to test for choice-induced preference refinements. These preference refinements are thought to occur during the comparison process itself because decision makers process information more precisely and/or evaluate additional information beyond the information that they process when required to evaluate options in isolation <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref>. Such preference refinements are typically quantified as the spreading of alternatives (SoA) because post-choice ratings of option pairs tend to be further apart relative to their pre-choice ratings. For each choice trial, SoA is defined as the change in overall value rating (from pre-to post-choice) for the option that was chosen minus the change in overall value rating for the other (rejected) option. SoA is traditionally computed as a difference-in-differences metric, calculated as postminus pre-choice rating for the chosen option minus the post-minus pre-choice rating for the rejected option, which is then averaged across all choices that a participant made. In line with previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Izuma et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Izuma et al., , 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Izuma &amp; Murayama, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">, 2021b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Sharot et al., 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Sharot et al., , 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Sharot et al., , 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Voigt et al., 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Voigt et al., , 2019</ref>, we observed a significant spreading of overall value ratings for the chosen relative to rejected options (cross-participant mean of within-participant mean SoA = 0.02, p = .023). We also observed a significant analogous spreading of ratings of both pleasure (mean = 0.02, p = .031) and nutrition (mean = 0.02, p &lt; .001), which replicates recent work <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>. In addition to testing the averaged difference-in-difference scores, we also used mixed-effects regressions to test post-choice ratings (separately for overall value, pleasure, and nutrition) against 1) a constant intercept term, 2) pre-choice ratings, and 3) an indicator variable for whether or not the option was chosen in the choice task. As expected, the pre-choice ratings were strongly correlated with post-choice ratings in all regressions. The coefficients for the intercept terms in the MFX regressions for all three ratings were negative, although this coefficient was only statistically significant in the regression for overall value, and not pleasure or nutrition ratings. In the MFX regression specifications we used, the intercept term measures the change in ratings for rejected options. Therefore, this result shows that ratings for rejected items were generally lower after choices relative to before, which is in line with previous studies. As expected, in all three MFX regressions, the coefficients for the chosen indicator variable were positive and significant, indicating that ratings increased substantially more for items that were chosen relative to those that were rejected (overall value = 0.14, p &lt; .001; pleasure = 0.11, p &lt; .001; nutrition = 0.05, p &lt; .001; <ref type="figure">Figure 8A</ref>-C).</p><p>Figure 8: Change in rating estimates and certainty before versus after choices. Rating estimates (top row; V = overall value, P = pleasure, N = nutrition) are highly correlated between first and second rating sessions (pre-choice V, P, and N all have large MFX regression coefficients for post-choice V, P, and N, respectively). The intercept terms have negative coefficients, showing that rejected options tended to decrease in rating estimate. The indicator variables isChosen have positive coefficients, showing that chosen options increased in rating relative to rejected options. Rating certainty (bottom row) is also highly correlated between first and second rating sessions. The positive intercept coefficients show that, in contrast to rating estimates, both chosen and rejected options gained in certainty, on average. The positive isChosen coefficients show that chosen options increased in certainty more than did rejected options. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, *** p &lt; .001.</p><p>If the changes in rating estimates that occur between pre-and post-choice ratings (captured by SoA) are indeed due to refinements in option evaluations that occur during choice because of effortful deliberation, we would also expect an increase in rating certainty between the two rating sessions <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021)</ref>. To test for such an effect, we regressed post-choice certainty (separately for overall value, pleasure, and nutrition) on 1) a constant intercept term, 2) pre-choice certainty, and 3) an indicator variable for whether or not the option was chosen in the choice task. We examined the intercept coefficients (i.e., certainty gain for rejected options) and the chosen item indicator coefficients (i.e., choiceinduced certainty gain). The coefficients for the intercept terms in all three MFX regressions were positive and significant, indicating that participants felt more certain about their ratings (overall value = 0.52, p &lt; .001; pleasure = 0.45, p &lt; .001; nutrition = 0.44, p &lt; .001; <ref type="figure">Figure 8D</ref>-F above) after having made choices between the options relative to before. In contrast to rating estimates, certainty increased for both chosen and rejected options. Furthermore, all three MFX coefficients for the isChosen indicator variable were positive and significant, indicating that participants gained more certainty for options that they chose relative to those that they rejected (overall value = 0.01, p = .017; pleasure = 0.03, p &lt; .001; nutrition = 0.02, p &lt; .001; <ref type="figure">Figure 8D</ref>-F above).</p><p>To test whether changes in either value estimates or certainty were systematically greater for the pleasure attribute compared to the nutrition attribute, we performed an additional MFX regression of post-choice attribute ratings (certainty) on pre-choice attribute ratings (certainty), an intercept term, an indicator variable (isP) to designate whether the rating (certainty) was for pleasure, an indicator variable (isChosen) to designate whether the option was chosen, and the interaction of isChosen and isP. We found that the pleasure ratings for chosen options increased significantly more than did the nutrition ratings (MFX coefficient for isChosen*isP = 0.06, p &lt; .001) and the pleasure certainty for chosen options tended to increase significantly more than did the nutrition certainty (MFX coefficient for isChosen*isP = 0.01, p = .056).</p><p>The amount of spreading of ratings between chosen and rejected alternatives is related to differences in pre-choice ratings and the sum of the pre-choice certainty across option pairs.</p><p>For example, previous work reported negative associations between SoA, in terms of overall value, and overall value difference and overall value certainty sum <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref>, as well as a positive association between SoA and attribute disparity <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>. Our data replicated most of these findings (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary   Material)</ref>, and also showed similar patterns with respect to a novel variable that we call the spreading of alternatives' certainty (SoAC, calculated in a manner analogous to SoA). Recent work has shown similar associations for SoA in terms of pleasure and nutrition attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>. Our data also replicated these findings (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Material)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Choice-induced preference refinements facilitate choice</head><p>Previous work postulated that the SoA phenomenon is a cognitive process that occurs during choice deliberation <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Schonberg &amp; Katz, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Voigt et al., 2019)</ref> or potentially any other situation in which additional information is processed about the available options <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>. Specifically, the "spreading of alternatives" should result in a decision becoming easier as the overall value estimates of the choice options become more distinct. According to this theory, SoA occurs during the choice task even though it is calculated by the experimenter using ratings obtained before and after the choice task.</p><p>Previous work has shown that SoA that occurs during the choice task remains observable in post-choice ratings <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021a)</ref>. It thus follows that choice variables impacted by overall value difference (RT and confidence 1 ) should be associated with SoA in a manner that suggests the choice has become easier (i.e., faster RT and higher confidence), and indeed this result has been reported in previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">, 2021b</ref>. We replicated the previous findings with respect to SoA for overall value and observed similar results with respect to SoAC (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary   Material</ref>). We also tested for associations between SoAP and SoAN and RT or confidence.</p><p>Specifically, we regressed RT and confidence (separately) on the differences in pleasure, nutrition, pleasure certainty, and nutrition certainty, as well as on SoAP, SoAN, SoACP, and <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>). For RT, all variables related to pleasure showed a negative association, but none of the associations with nutrition-related variables were significant. For confidence, pleasure and nutrition difference both had positive associations, as did pleasure certainty difference and both SoAP and SoAN.  </p><formula xml:id="formula_2">SoACN (Figure 9C-D;</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>log(RT) Confidence</head><p>Pleasure difference (dP) -0.25 (p &lt; .001) 0.25 (p &lt; .001) Nutrition difference (dN) -0.03 (p = .129) 0.06 (p &lt; .001) Pleasure certainty difference (dPC) -0.10 (p = .016) 0.05 (p = .020) Nutrition certainty difference (dNC) 0.06 (p = .213) -0.03 (p = .225) Spreading of alternatives: pleasure (SoAP) -0.09 (p = .034) 0.10 (p &lt; .001) Spreading of alternatives: nutrition (SoAN) -0.08 (p = .114) 0.06 (p = .021) Spreading of alternatives' certainty: pleasure (SoACP) -0.10 (p = .013) 0.03 (p = .219) Spreading of alternatives' certainty: nutrition (SoACN) 0.05 (p = .269) -0.01 (p = .632) R 2 = 0.30 R 2 = 0.35 This table lists the mixed-effects regression coefficients from two separate regressions using either response time or confidence as the dependent variable. All regressions included random intercepts and slopes for each variable by participant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>This second experiment indicates that the act of making a choice leads to refinements in evaluations (both estimates and certainty) of options with respect to specific attributes as well as overall value. Comparing the pre-and post-choice ratings allowed us to determine how the various effects that we examined in Experiment 1 differed after participants had made choices between pairs of options. We found that across all eight regression models that we tested using either pre-or post-choice ratings, all but one yielded greater explanatory power (adjusted R 2 ) when including post-choice ratings. This supports the hypothesis that decisionmakers refine their assessments of value during choice deliberation, so that they are more (subjectively) accurate and precise after choices than they were before <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref>.</p><p>Contrasting post-versus pre-choice ratings, and their associations with choice behavior, revealed choice-induced preference refinements. These refinements were quantified as the spreading of alternatives (SoA), where the differences in value estimates (overall, pleasure, and nutrition) for the chosen option versus the rejected option were significantly larger after the choices relative to before, in line with previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Izuma et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">, 2021b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Voigt et al., 2019)</ref>. We also showed the novel result that choices induced an asymmetrical gain in rating certainty (overall value, pleasure, and nutrition). Our results indicate that both the subjective sense of attributes and overall value as well as the subjective sense of certainty about those ratings are refined during choice deliberation. Options that are ultimately chosen appear to undergo more refinement than rejected options. Interestingly, the pleasure attribute seemed to undergo greater refinement than the nutrition attribute, in line with the greater weights for pleasure relative to nutrition in all the rating and choice regression analyses that we conducted. Furthermore, both types of refinement (SoA and SoAC) are associated with reduced response times and increased choice confidence, indicating that the process that leads to refinement is also instrumental to choice. Finally, beyond the increase in certainty about the value of the chosen option relative to the rejected one, we found a clear gain in certainty (on average) across all options. This replicates previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021)</ref>, and suggests that the observed changes in value estimates are more likely due to true preference refinements rather than simply random fluctuations in the estimates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>In this study, we examined how subjective feelings of certainty about subjective assessments of individual decision-relevant option attributes contribute to key aspects of choice behavior: the consistency between choices and isolated ratings of value, deliberation time during a decision, and reports of confidence about having chosen the preferred options.</p><p>Previous work has demonstrated that people possess the metacognitive ability to assess their certainty in their value estimates for choice options, and that levels of certainty influence decision and learning behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Cortese, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Cortese et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">De Martino et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gwinn &amp; Krajbich, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Polanía et al., 2019)</ref>. Thus far, studies of metacognition in judgement and decision-making have focused on the overall value or percept of a stimulus. Here, we expand upon previous findings in two main ways, as follows.</p><p>First, in both of our experiments, we show that the influence of the certainty about an attribute on evaluations of and decisions between snack foods is proportional to the influence of the value of that attribute on the evaluation or decision. In particular, across participants, the associations of pleasure-related variables with all dependent variables related to either overall value or choice were greater than the associations of nutrition-related variables. Thus, metacognitive assessments of value certainty or choice confidence are not equally-weighted assessments of the total amount of (un)certainty across all attributes and options. Instead, our results suggest that metacognitive computations are influenced by unequally-weighted combinations of information about the different attributes. In this way, metacognition is similar to computations of overall value and choices themselves, which are known to be influenced by subjectively-weighed combinations of attribute estimates.</p><p>Second, in Experiment 2, we demonstrate that metacognitive evaluations of both overall value and individual attributes are refined during choice deliberation. Previous work has shown that value estimates systematically change from pre-to post-choice rating sessions <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Izuma et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Izuma et al., , 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Izuma &amp; Murayama, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Sharot et al., 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Sharot et al., , 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Sharot et al., , 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Voigt et al., 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Voigt et al., , 2019</ref>, and that post-choice estimates are more closely aligned with choice behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">, 2021b</ref>. We replicate these findings at the level of both overall value and individual attributes.</p><p>We also demonstrate similar effects with respect to value certainty. Previous work showed that certainty about overall value increases with choices or additional rating sessions <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021)</ref>. Here, we show that certainty also increases at the level of individual attributes, but that these increases are greater for attributes that had a greater impact on the decisions (i.e., pleasure &gt; nutrition). Gains in certainty are also related to the choice outcome: chosen options show a greater increase in certainty than do rejected options.</p><p>Furthermore, we show that spreading of alternatives with respect to value and/or certainty reduces response time and increases choice confidence, suggesting that the evaluation refinements are instrumental to choice. Together, these findings support the hypothesis that subjectively-weighted combinations of individual attributes (both estimates and certainty) directly contribute to both cognitive and metacognitive processes in value-based decisionmaking.</p><p>Metacognition is thought to aid decision-makers in choosing the best option from among alternatives <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Desender et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Lee, Daunizeau, et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">van den Berg et al., 2016)</ref>. It is also believed that metacognition about choices that have already been made can be beneficial for future decisions of a similar nature <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fleming &amp; Daw, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Yeung &amp; Summerfield, 2012)</ref>. More generally, the ability to monitor one's own performance is thought to be important for efficient learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Cortese, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Cortese et al., 2020)</ref>. It has been shown that people can unconsciously learn the relative importance of different decision features or attributes via a reinforcement learning process modulated by choice confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Cortese et al., 2020)</ref>. While that previous work operationalized the multiattribute nature of the decision as abstract multi-dimensional patterns of brain activity, the finding may hold for explicit attribute dimensions such as the pleasure and nutrition of snack foods as well. Pleasure and nutrition (or "tastiness" and "healthiness") have previously been decoded from brain activity using multivariate pattern analysis, even when participants were not instructed to explicitly consider those attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Schubert et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Suzuki et al., 2017)</ref>.</p><p>It could be that choice confidence levels are both informed by such latent neural representations of option attributes, and that the relative contribution of the value certainty for each attribute matches the relative contribution of the value estimates for each attribute because both types of information originate in the same neural representations.</p><p>When interpreted in the light of the previous findings on metacognition and learning mentioned above, our current results suggest that repeatedly choosing between options with a specific ordering of attribute importance would reinforce that ordering and one's confidence in choices that align with it. Recall that confidence increased more in the more choice-relevant attribute, pleasure, relative to the less important attribute, nutrition. This type of internal feedback loop would benefit future choice behavior if it were based on an appropriate ranking of attribute importance (i.e., if attribute ranks align with the context and current goal).</p><p>However, if the context or goal were to change, having confidence constructed in proportion to a now suboptimal ranking of attribute importance would instead impair efficient learning and behavior. Thus, it will be important for future studies to examine how readily confidence judgements can be adapted to match changes in goals or environments.</p><p>Neuroimaging studies have revealed both domain-specific and domain-general representations of attributes and overall values as well as decision confidence. Many brain regions show domain-specific correlations with the values of specific types of rewards <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Chib et al., 2009)</ref>. On the other hand, the medial prefrontal cortex (mPFC), striatum, and posterior cingulate cortex have been shown to correlate with the overall value of a wide range of goods <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bartra et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chib et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Clithero &amp; Rangel, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Levy &amp; Glimcher, 2012)</ref>, and overlapping voxels in mPFC have also been shown to correlate with ratings for distinct individual attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Hare et al., 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Hare et al., , 2011</ref>. In contrast, lateral prefrontal cortex and amygdala have been found to correlate only with a subset of attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Hare et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Maier et al., 2015)</ref>. In terms of metacognitive representations, activity in the mPFC also correlates with unidimensional confidence ratings in value-based choice paradigms <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(De Martino et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Folke et al., 2016)</ref>, and shows a domain-general association with confidence across perceptual judgements and memory tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Molenberghs et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Morales et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>However, lateral prefrontal regions once again show domain-specific associations with either perception or memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Morales et al., 2018)</ref>. Thus, it may be that the certainties about individual attributes within the same option are represented in either overlapping or distinct circuits within the brain. This will be an important question to address in future studies.</p><p>In this study, we conceptualized "pleasure" as an attribute that directly contributes information related to overall value estimation as well as value-based decisions. However, one could argue that "pleasure" might instead describe the overall impression that a decision-maker forms about each option while thinking about them. In the latter case, the pleasure and overall value ratings would be redundant and thus highly correlated, which might confound our results.</p><p>In our experimental instructions, we attempted to forestall such a confound by explicitly describing pleasure as an attribute, not a feeling of affect. In our data, the correlations between pleasure ratings and overall value ratings (across participants) are 0.65 in Experiment 1 and 0.62 and 0.66 (pre-and post-choice) in Experiment 2 (see Supplementary Material for matrices of correlations between all variables). Thus, pleasure is a substantial component of overall value, but it explains less than half of the variance in overall values. Moreover, if pleasure and overall value were somehow capturing the same affective state, we would expect to find similar correlations between nutrition and either pleasure or overall value. Instead, we find that the correlations between pleasure and nutrition (0.05 in Experiment 1 and -0.09 and 0.05 in Experiment 2) are significantly different (p &lt; .001) from the correlations between overall value and nutrition are positive (0.17 in Experiment 1 and 0.17 and 0.26 in Experiment 2). Together, these data demonstrate that pleasure and overall value are not measuring the same subjective impressions in our experiments.</p><p>There are some limitations of the current work that should be addressed in future studies. First, we examined choices over snack food items because foods are familiar, multiattribute goods that humans evaluate and make choices between on a regular basis. However, future work should test if our findings extend to other types of goods or experiences. Second, we had participants rate and report confidence for only two separate attributes, and tests using a larger number of attributes are necessary to further examine the relationship between an attribute's influence on evaluations of overall value, choices, and certainty or confidence.</p><p>Lastly, participants did not actually receive the snack foods that they chose in this study, which might have reduced motivation to rate and choose (subjectively) accurately. The high correlations and consistency between rating types and choices in our data set indicate that participants generally rated and chose carefully. Nevertheless, studies using incentivized ratings and choices may provide additional motivation, and consequently, more sensitivity to detect subtle behavioral effects.</p><p>In conclusion, we have provided strong initial evidence that just like first order (cognitive) evaluations of multi-attribute choice options, second order assessments of decision confidence are subjective and more influenced by highly choice-relevant attributes compared to attributes that are only marginally important in determining decision outcomes. These findings provide a basis and impetus for additional investigation into the nature of multiattribute confidence and its implications for beneficial and detrimental forms of cognition and behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Open Practices Statement</head><p>The data and primary analysis code for this study are available in the Open Science Forum at http://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/NEPX5. The experiments were not preregistered. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Value certainty correlates with value estimate and estimate extremity</head><p>Previous studies have shown that feelings of certainty about overall value estimates correlate with the overall value estimates themselves <ref type="bibr">(Lebreton et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020)</ref>. Specifically, reported levels of certainty about overall value are higher when the overall value estimates are higher, as well as when they are farther away from the point of neutrality (in either direction). To test this association in our data, we regressed overall value certainty on overall value and overall value extremity (|overall value|), separately for data from Experiments 1 an 2. For both datasets, both MFX coefficients were significantly greater than zero (Exp1: overall value: 0.08, p &lt; .001; overall value extremity: 0.42, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.46; Exp2: overall value: 0.07, p &lt; .001; overall value extremity: 0.46, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.47). For Experiment 2, we repeated the same regression analysis, this time using postchoice ratings. Post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to those for prechoice ratings, and they also explained more of the variance (overall value: 0.06, p &lt; .001; overall value extremity: 0.50, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.54). We then tested whether the same pattern holds at the level of individual attributes by regressing pleasure certainty on pleasure and pleasure extremity, and nutrition certainty on nutrition and nutrition extremity. All MFX coefficients were significantly greater than zero (Exp1: pleasure: 0.08, p &lt; .001; pleasure extremity: 0.42, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.48; nutrition: 0.05, p &lt; .001; nutrition extremity: 0.61, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.56; Exp2: pleasure: 0.09, p &lt; .001; pleasure extremity: 0.46, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.50; nutrition: 0.04, p &lt; .001; nutrition extremity: 0.68, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.52). For Experiment 2, we repeated the same regression analysis, this time using postchoice ratings. Post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to those for prechoice ratings, and they also explained more of the variance (pleasure: 0.08, p &lt; .001; pleasure extremity: 0.45, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.53; nutrition: 0.04, p &lt; .001; nutrition extremity: 0.64, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.55).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2">Attribute estimates and certainty explain overall value estimates</head><p>To tie together the findings reported above, we tested how well overall value estimates could be explained by a combination of attribute estimates and attribute certainty. Specifically, we regressed overall value on pleasure, nutrition, pleasure certainty, and nutrition certainty.</p><p>For both experiments, the MFX coefficients for pleasure, nutrition, and pleasure certainty were positive and significant, but the MFX coefficient for nutrition certainty was not statistically significant (Exp1: pleasure: 0.76, p &lt; .001; nutrition: 0.14, p &lt; .001; pleasure certainty: 0.06, p &lt; .001; nutrition certainty: 0.01, p = .669; adjusted R 2 = 0.69; Exp2: pleasure: 0.71, p &lt; .001; nutrition: 0.20, p &lt; .001; pleasure certainty: 0.05, p = .006; nutrition certainty: 0.02, p = .241;</p><p>adjusted R 2 = 0.67). For Experiment 2, we repeated the same regression analysis, this time using post-choice ratings. Post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to those for pre-choice ratings, and they also explained more of the variance (pleasure: 0.74, p &lt; .001; nutrition: 0.24, p &lt; .001; pleasure certainty: 0.03, p = .027; nutrition certainty: 0, p = .893;</p><p>adjusted R 2 = 0.76).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3">Attribute congruence influences overall value certainty</head><p>We hypothesized that one factor that should support subjective certainty about the overall value of an option would be the congruence of its attributes. For example, an option with a very high rating for one attribute but a very low rating for another attribute might have a medium overall value estimate with low certainty. An option with moderate ratings for both attributes (i.e., congruent attribute ratings) might also have a medium overall value estimate, but with higher certainty. To test this hypothesis, we regressed overall value certainty on pleasure certainty, nutrition certainty, and attribute congruence. We defined attribute congruence as the interaction between the pleasure and nutrition ratings for each item (so congruence is greatest when both ratings are -1 or both ratings are 1, least when one rating is -1 and the other is 1). All MFX coefficients were positive and significant (Exp1: pleasure certainty: 0.30, p &lt; .001; nutrition certainty: 0.12, p &lt; .001; attribute congruence: 0.03, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.46; Exp2: pleasure certainty: 0.31, p &lt; .001; nutrition certainty: 0.11, p &lt; .001; attribute congruence: 0.03, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.43; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>). For Experiment 2, we repeated the same regression analysis, this time using post-choice ratings. Post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to those for pre-choice ratings, and they also explained more of the variance (pleasure certainty: 0.37, p &lt; .001; nutrition certainty: 0.16, p &lt; .001; attribute congruence: 0.05, p &lt; .001; adjusted R 2 = 0.54; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>). also has a positive association with VC. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: *** p &lt; .001.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4">Choice behavior can be explained by value estimates and certainty plus attribute disparity</head><p>We then tested whether our current data replicate previous findings reported in the literature regarding the relationships between three dependent variables 1) choice consistency (choosing the option with the higher overall value rating), 2) response time (RT), and 3) choice confidence, and five previously-established independent variables. These five independent variables are 1) the difference and 2) sum of overall value estimates, 3) the difference and 4) sum of overall value certainty, and 5) attribute disparity. Many studies have shown that the difference in overall value estimates (defined as higher-valued option minus lower-valued option) across options in a choice pair has a positive association with consistency and confidence and a negative association with RT, and similar associations have also been shown with respect to the sum of overall value estimates <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Lee &amp; Usher, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Shevlin et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2019)</ref>. Furthermore, the sum of overall value certainty and the difference in overall value certainty (defined as certainty of the option with higher overall value minus the certainty of the option with lower overall value) have been shown to have positive associations with consistency and confidence, and negative associations with RT <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref>). Finally, it has been shown that attribute disparity correlates positively with choice consistency and confidence, and negatively with RT <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b</ref>). Attribute disparity accounts for the fact that choice options could be composed of very different attribute estimates, even if they were rated with similar overall values. We calculated disparity as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">, ≜ | [ ] * [ − ]−[ ] * [ − ] ‖ − ‖ | , for options , .<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where pleasure and nutrition are the pleasure and nutrition ratings for the specific options being compared, and bP and bN are the GLM coefficients from a regression of overall value on pleasure and nutrition (within participants). Using this measure of disparity, one can transform the space representing choice options from attribute space (i.e., a two-dimensional space composed of pleasure and nutrition axes) to a new two-dimensional space in which one dimension is overall value difference and the other is disparity <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>.</p><p>We used three separate regression models to test for the effects of all five of these independent variables on each of the three choice-related dependent variables in our data. For the dependent variable choice consistency, we replicated the associations with overall value difference in both experiments, and the associations with overall value certainty difference and disparity in Experiment 1 only ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S2</ref>, <ref type="table">Table S1</ref>). When using choice RT as the dependent variable, we replicated the associations with disparity and overall value sum and difference in both experiments, and the sum of overall value certainty in Experiment 2 only ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S2</ref>, <ref type="table">Table S1</ref>). Lastly, when using choice confidence as the dependent variable, we found a trend for overall value certainty difference in Experiment 1, and replicated all other associations in Experiment 1 and all associations in Experiment 2 ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S2</ref>, <ref type="table">Table S1</ref>). Note that, for Experiment 2, post-choice ratings yielded MFX coefficients that were similar to those for prechoice ratings, but now more variables showed significant associations and the overall percentage of variance explained was greater.  <ref type="table">Table S1</ref>. Effects of rating estimates and certainty and attribute disparity on choice consistency, response time, and confidence. Consistency log(RT) Confidence Overall value sum (sV) 0.01 (p = .658) -0.14 (p &lt; .001) 0.14 (p &lt; .001) Overall value difference (dV) 0.53 (p &lt; .001) -0.32 (p &lt; .001) 0.27 (p &lt; .001) Overall value certainty sum (sVC) -0.02 (p = .303) -0.04 (p = .116) 0.07 (p &lt; .001) Overall value certainty difference <ref type="bibr">(dVC)</ref> 0.07 (p = .018) -0.04 (p = .080) 0.03 (p = .060) Attribute disparity (D) 0.10 (p = .003) -0.12 (p &lt; .001) 0.10 (p &lt; .001) R 2 = 0.12 R 2 = 0.55 R 2 = 0.46 Overall value sum (sV) 0.01 (p = .538) -0.11 (p &lt; .001) 0.13 (p &lt; .001) Overall value difference (dV) 0.56 (p &lt; .001) -0.30 (p &lt; .001) 0.29 (p &lt; .001) Overall value certainty sum (sVC) 0.03 (p = .285) -0.07 (p = .052) 0.08 (p &lt; .001) Overall value certainty difference <ref type="bibr">(dVC)</ref> 0.05 (p = .188) -0.02 (p = .618) 0.02 (p = .270) Attribute disparity (D) 0.01 (p = .678) -0.13 (p &lt; .001) 0.10 (p &lt; .001) R 2 = 0.15 R 2 = 0.29 R 2 = 0.41 Overall value sum (sV) 0.02 (p = .302) -0.12 (p &lt; .001) 0.13 (p &lt; .001) Overall value difference (dV) 0.63 (p &lt; .001) -0.20 (p &lt; .001) 0.21 (p &lt; .001) Overall value certainty sum (sVC) -0.03 (p = .209) -0.08 (p = .042) 0.13 (p &lt; .001) Overall value certainty difference <ref type="bibr">(dVC)</ref> 0.05 (p = .133) -0.02 (p = .549) 0.05 (p = .038) Attribute disparity (D) -0.07 (p = .098) -0.18 (p &lt; .001) 0.11 (p &lt; .001) R 2 = 0.23 R 2 = 0.30 R 2 = 0.46 This table lists the mixed-effects regression coefficients from nine separate regressions using either choice consistency, response time, or confidence as the dependent variable, for Experiment 1 (in black), Experiment 2 using pre-choice ratings (in red), and Experiment 2 using post-choice ratings (in blue). All regressions included random intercepts and slopes for each variable by participant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.5">Choice-induced preference refinements</head><p>In the data from Experiment 2, we tested whether spreading of alternatives' estimates (SoA) and the spreading of alternatives with respect to certainty (SoAC, calculated in a manner analogous to SoA) were associated with the five independent variables that we examined above: sum and difference in overall value estimates, sum and difference in overall value certainty, and attribute disparity, when those variables were defined using pre-choice ratings.</p><p>Previous studies reported negative associations between SoA and overall value difference and overall value certainty sum <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref>, as well as a positive association between SoA and attribute disparity <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2021b)</ref>; tests of the other variables have not been reported previously. We regressed SoA and SoAC (separately) on these five independent variables. When testing the spreading of alternatives' estimates, we replicated the associations with overall value difference and disparity, but did not find any significant associations with the other variables ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S3A</ref>; <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table S2</ref>). When testing the spreading of alternatives' certainty, we found positive associations with overall value sum and disparity, and a negative association with overall value certainty difference ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S3B</ref>; <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table S2</ref>). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S3</ref>: Explanatory power of value estimates and certainty on the spreading of alternatives. Predictive effect of the sum of overall value (sV), difference in overall value (dV), sum of overall value certainty (sVC), difference in overall value certainty (dVC), and attribute disparity (D) of the options on each trial on the spreading of alternatives with respect to overall value estimates (SoA; A) and overall value certainty (SoAC; B). Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, *** p &lt; .001. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table S2</ref>. Effects of rating estimates and certainty and attribute disparity on the spreading of alternatives' estimates and certainty.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spreading of Alternatives (SoA)</head><p>Spreading of Alternatives' Certainty (SoAC) Overall value sum <ref type="bibr">(sV)</ref> 0 (p = .901) 0.06 (p &lt; .001) Overall value difference (dV) -0.35 (p &lt; .001) -0.03 (p = .249) Overall value certainty sum (sVC) -0.03 (p = .167) 0.03 (p = .274) Overall value certainty diff. <ref type="bibr">(dVC)</ref> 0.01 (p = .492) -0.37 (p &lt; .001) Attribute disparity <ref type="bibr">(D)</ref> 0.15 (p &lt; .001) 0.05 (p = .025) R 2 = 0.16 R 2 = 0.22 This table lists the mixed-effects regression coefficients from two separate regressions using either the spreading of alternatives or the spreading of alternatives' certainty as the dependent variable. All regressions included random intercepts and slopes for each variable by participant.</p><p>We next tested whether our data replicate the previously-reported associations between pleasure difference and SoA in terms of pleasure ratings (SoAP), and between nutrition difference and SoA in terms of nutrition ratings (SoAN). We also included novel tests for associations between pleasure sum, pleasure certainty sum, and pleasure certainty difference and the spreading of alternatives in terms of pleasure certainty (SoACP), and analogous regressions for nutrition certainty (SoACN). We regressed each SoA term on the four related independent variables (i.e., pleasure-related variables in the same regressions, nutrition-related variables in the same regressions). For SoAP and SoAN, we replicated the associations with pleasure difference (MFX coefficient = -0.21, p &lt; .001) and nutrition difference (MFX coefficient = -0.05, p &lt; .001), respectively, but did not find any significant associations between attribute certainty and the spreading of attribute ratings. For SoACP and SoACN, we found the expected negative associations with pleasure certainty difference and nutrition certainty difference, repsectively (MFX coefficient for SoACP = -0.34, p &lt; .001; MFX coefficient for SoACN = -0.29, p &lt; .001).</p><p>Finally, we checked whether preference refinements seemed to facilitate choices. To test this, we regressed RT and confidence, separately, on pre-choice overall value difference and overall value certainty difference, as well as SoA and SoAC. We found that all MFX coefficients in both regressions were significantly different than zero in the expected directions ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure S4</ref>; <ref type="table">Table S3</ref>). Notably, the regression coefficients for SoA and SoAC resembled those for pre-choice overall value difference and overall value certainty difference, supporting the view that SoA measures a true increase in overall value difference and SoAC measures a true increase in overall value certainty difference before choice deliberation is concluded. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure S4</ref>: Explanatory power of value estimates, certainty, and spreading of alternatives on response time and confidence. Predictive effect of the difference in overall value (dV), difference in overall value certainty (dVC), spreading of alternatives (SoA), and spreading of alternatives' certainty (SoAC) of the options on each trial on response time (RT; panel A) and confidence (panel B). Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, ** p &lt; .01, *** p &lt; .001. <ref type="table">Table S3</ref>. Effects of rating estimates, certainty, and spreading of alternatives on response time and confidence. log(RT) Confidence Overall value difference (dV) -0.37 (p &lt; .001) 0.37 (p &lt; .001) Overall value certainty difference (dVC) -0.07 (p = .052) 0.10 (p &lt; .001)</p><p>Spreading of alternatives (SoA) -0.12 (p &lt; .001) 0.14 (p &lt; .001) Spreading of alternatives' certainty (SoAC) -0.08 (p = .027) 0.08 (p &lt; .001) R 2 = 0.28 R 2 = 0.36 This table lists the mixed-effects regression coefficients from three separate regressions using either choice consistency, response time, or confidence as the dependent variable. All regressions included random intercepts and slopes for each variable by participant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Data summary</head><p>Below, we provide graphical summaries of all of the empirical variables that we examined in this study. We provide histograms for each variable, separately for data from Experiment 1, Experiment 2 based on pre-choice ratings, and Experiment 2 based on postchoice ratings. We then provide matrices showing the correlations between all rating variables and between all choice variables, separately for data from Experiment 1, Experiment 2 based on pre-choice ratings, and Experiment 2 based on post-choice ratings. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure S5</ref>: Empirical distributions of ratings and certainty. Histograms of the rating (first three rows) and certainty (last three rows) data from Experiment 1 (first column), Experiment 2 pre-choice (second column), and Experiment 2 post-choice (third column). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure S6</ref>: Empirical distributions of rating sums and differences within choice pairs. Histograms of the rating sums (first three rows) and differences (last three rows) data from Experiment 1 (first column), Experiment 2 pre-choice (second column), and Experiment 2 post-choice (third column).   Matrices of the correlation between each of the variables from Experiment 1 (first column), Experiment 2 pre-choice (second column), and Experiment 2 post-choice (third column). The top row contains variables related to the rating task, the bottom row contains variables related to the choice task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Task illustration. An example of what participants saw on the screen during each experimental section.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Contribution of attribute estimates and certainty to overall value estimates and certainty. A) Pleasure and nutrition ratings have a predictive effect on overall value ratings. B) Pleasure certainty and nutrition certainty have a predictive effect on overall value certainty. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: *** p &lt; .001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Explanatory power of attribute estimates and certainty on choice, response time, and confidence. Predictive effect of the sum of pleasure (sP), sum of nutrition (sN)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Explanatory power of attribute estimates and certainty on choice, response time, and confidence.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>https://prolific.co). All were citizens of the United States or Canada, 88 were current residents of the United States or Canada, and 76 were native English speakers. Each participant received a payment of $10 as compensation for approximately one hour of time. Our experiments involved de-identified participant data, and protocols were approved by the Human Subjects Committee of the Faculty of Economics, Business Administration and Information Technology at the University of Zurich. All participants gave informed consent prior to commencing the experiments.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Contribution of attribute estimates and certainty to overall value estimates and certainty. A) Pleasure and nutrition ratings have a predictive effect on overall value ratings. B) Pleasure certainty and nutrition certainty have a predictive effect on overall value certainty. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: *** p &lt; .001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Explanatory power of attribute estimates and certainty on choice, response time, and confidence. Predictive effect of the sum of pleasure (sP), sum of nutrition (sN), difference in pleasure (dP), difference in nutrition (dN), sum of pleasure certainty (sPC), sum</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Explanatory power of attribute estimates and certainty on choice, response time, and confidence. Predictive effect of the pleasure, nutrition, pleasure certainty, and nutrition certainty for the chosen option (Pc, Nc, PCc, NCc) and for the rejected option (Pr, Nr, PCr, NCr) on each trial on choice consistency (choosing the option with the higher overall value rating; A), response time (B), and choice confidence (C). Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, ** p &lt; .01, *** p &lt; .001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Explanatory power of attribute estimates and certainty, spreading of alternatives, and spreading of alternatives' certainty on response time and confidence. Predictive effect of the difference in pleasure (dP), difference in nutrition (dN), difference in pleasure certainty (dPC), difference in nutrition certainty (dNC), spreading of alternatives with respect to pleasure (SoAP), spreading of alternatives with respect to nutrition (SoAN), spreading of alternatives' certainty with respect to pleasure (SoACP), and spreading of alternatives' certainty with respect to nutrition (SoACN) of the options on each trial on response time (A) and choice confidence (B). Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, *** p &lt; .001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure S1 :</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Explanatory power of attribute certainty and congruence to overall value certainty. Beyond the explanatory power of pleasure certainty (PC) and nutrition certainty (NC) for overall value certainty (VC), the congruence of the attributes (AC, within options)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure S2 :</head><label>S2</label><figDesc>Explanatory power of value estimates and certainty on choice, response time, and confidence. Predictive effect of the sum of overall value (sV), difference in overall value (dV), sum of overall value certainty (sVC), difference in overall value certainty (dVC), and attribute disparity (D) of the options on each trial on choice consistency (choosing the option with the higher overall value rating; left column), response time (center column), and choice confidence (right column). Top row shows results for Experiment 1, bottom row shows results for Experiment 2. Error bars represent 95% confidence intervals. Significance stars: * p &lt; .05, ** p &lt; .01, *** p &lt; .001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure S7 :</head><label>S7</label><figDesc>Empirical distributions of certainty sums and differences within choice pairs. Histograms of the certainty sums (first three rows) and differences (last three rows) data from Experiment 1 (first column), Experiment 2 pre-choice (second column), and Experiment 2 post-choice (third column).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure S8 :</head><label>S8</label><figDesc>Empirical distributions of attribute disparity within choice pairs. Histograms of the attribute disparity data from Experiment 1 (first column), Experiment 2 pre-choice (second column), and Experiment 2 post-choice (third column).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure S9 :</head><label>S9</label><figDesc>Correlations between variables.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Effects of rating estimates and certainty on choice consistency, response time, and confidence.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>MFX coefficients</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Consistency</cell><cell>log(RT)</cell><cell>Confidence</cell></row></table><note>pleasure of chosen (Pc) 0.58 (p &lt; .001) -0.44 (p &lt; .001) 0.40 (p &lt; .001) pleasure of rejected (Pr) -0.52 (p &lt; .001) 0.18 (p &lt; .001) -0.14 (p &lt; .001) nutrition of chosen (Nc) 0.09 (p &lt; .001) -0.11 (p &lt; .001) 0.07 (p &lt; .001)</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Effects of rating estimates and certainty on choice consistency, response time, and confidence.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>MFX coefficients</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Consistency</cell><cell>log(RT)</cell><cell>Confidence</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">pleasure of chosen (Pc) 0.44 (p &lt; .001) -0.46 (p &lt; .001) 0.41 (p &lt; .001)</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">pleasure of rejected (Pr) -0.42 (p &lt; .001) 0.22 (p &lt; .001) -0.16 (p &lt; .001)</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">nutrition of chosen (Nc) 0.17 (p &lt; .001) -0.11 (p &lt; .001) 0.11 (p &lt; .001)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Effects of rating estimates, certainty, and spreading of alternatives on response time and confidence.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Material for Value certainty and choice confidence are multidimensional constructs that guide decision-making</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Douglas G. Lee 1 and Todd A. Hare 2,3</cell></row><row><cell>1 Tel Aviv University, School of Psychological Sciences</cell></row><row><cell>2 Zurich Center for Neuroeconomics, Department of Economics, University of Zurich</cell></row><row><cell>3 Neuroscience Center Zurich, University of Zurich and ETH Zurich</cell></row><row><cell>1. Supplementary Results.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">We do not include consistency here, because some choices can be classified as changes of mind (i.e., dV1 and dV2 would have opposite signs). These cannot be classified as errors, however, as value refinements might have caused decision-makers to update their preferences on these trials. For such trials, choice consistency would be anti-correlated with SoA.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Amount and Time Exert Independent Influences on Intertemporal Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Amasino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kranton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Huettel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-019-0537-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0537-2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explaining distortions in metacognition with an attractor network model of decision uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A A</forename><surname>Atiya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">J M</forename><surname>Huys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1009201</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1009201" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Healthy decisions in the cued-attribute food choice paradigm have high test-retest reliability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Barakchian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Beharelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-021-91933-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-91933-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The valuation system: A coordinate-based meta-analysis of BOLD fMRI experiments examining neural correlates of subjective value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bartra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mcguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2013.02.063</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2013.02.063" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="412" to="427" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Naturalistic Multiattribute Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2018.05.025</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.05.025" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">179</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="88" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sources of confidence in value-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Aebersold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grueschow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polania</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-021-27618-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-27618-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for a common representation of decision values for dissimilar goods in human ventromedial prefrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Chib</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shimojo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12315" to="12320" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informatic parcellation of the network involved in the computation of subjective value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clithero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1289" to="1302" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognitive resources for adaptive learning⋆</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cortese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neures.2021.09.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neures.2021.09.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroscience Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">178</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unconscious reinforcement learning of hidden brain states supported by confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cortese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kawato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-020-17828-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-17828-8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence in risky valuebased choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Da Silva Castanheira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Otto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1021" to="1028" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-020-01848-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-020-01848-y" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence in value-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">De</forename><surname>Martino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.3279</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3279" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic expressions of confidence within an evidence accumulation framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Desender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Donner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Verguts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2020.104522</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2020.104522" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">207</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-Evaluation of Decision-Making: A General Bayesian Framework for Metacognitive Computation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000045</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000045" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to measure metacognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnhum.2014.00443</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2014.00443" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explicit representation of confidence informs future value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Folke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Jacobsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Martino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-016-0002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-016-0002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attitudes and Attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gwinn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103892</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103892" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103892</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-Control in Decision-Making Involves Modulation of the vmPFC Valuation System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">324</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5927</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="646" to="648" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1168450</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1168450" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Focusing Attention on the Health Aspects of Foods Changes Value Signals in vmPFC and Improves Dietary Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Malmaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.6383-10.2011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.6383-10.2011" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11077" to="11087" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accounting for Taste: A Multi-Attribute Neurocomputational Model Explains the Neural Dynamics of Choices for Self and Others</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clithero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hutcherson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7952" to="7968" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3327-17.2018</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3327-17.2018" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Abnormalities of confidence in psychiatry: An overview and future perspectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hoven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Denys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Luigjes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41398-019-0602-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41398-019-0602-7" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Translational Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A causal role for posterior medial frontal cortex in choice-induced preference change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Izuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Akula</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D.-A</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Iacoboni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Adolphs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4591-14.2015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4591-14.2015" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3598" to="3606" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of cognitive dissonance and choice-induced preference change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Izuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Samejima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sadato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22014" to="22019" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1011879108</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1011879108" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice-Induced Preference Change in the Free-Choice Paradigm: A Critical Methodological Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Izuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00041</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00041" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Empirical Test of the Role of Value Certainty in Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Coricelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.574473</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.574473" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>D'alessandro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Iodice</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Calluso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rustichini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Risky Decisions Accumulate Information for Individual Attributes as a Function of Salience and Risk Preference</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/h3r6x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/h3r6x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Choosing what we like vs liking what we choose: How choice-induced preference change might actually be instrumental to decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0231081</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0231081" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trading mental effort for confidence in the metacognitive control of value-based decision-making. ELife, 10, e63282</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.63282</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.63282" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evidence or Confidence: What Really Accumulates During a Decision?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/2021.04.02.438275</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.04.02.438275" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>p. 2021.04.02.438275). bioRxiv</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evidence Accumulates for Individual Attributes during Value-Based Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/2021.08.05.455296</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.08.05.455296" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>p. 2021.08.05.455296). bioRxiv</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Transient Value Refinements during Deliberation Facilitate Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Holyoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/7pmgh</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/7pmgh" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coherence shifts in attribute evaluations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holyoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dec0000151</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/dec0000151" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="276" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Changes in Preferences Reported After Choices Are Informative, Not Merely Statistical Artifacts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/btj95</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/btj95" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value certainty in drift-diffusion models of preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000329</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000329" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>No Pagination Specified-No Pagination Specified</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The root of all value: A neural common currency for choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Glimcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Neurobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1027" to="1038" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.conb.2012.06.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2012.06.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attribute Identities Matter: Subjective Perceptions of Attribute Characteristics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bettman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1008159022055</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1008159022055" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Acute Stress Impairs Self-Control in Goal-Directed Choice by Altering Multiple Functional Connections within the Brain&apos;s Decision Circuits</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Makwana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="621" to="631" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2015.07.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2015.07.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Raja Beharelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polanía</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Dissociable Mechanisms Govern When and How Strongly Reward Attributes Affect Decisions</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-020-0893-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-0893-y" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="949" to="963" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of metacognitive ability and of feeling confident: A large-scale fMRI study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Molenberghs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F.-M</forename><surname>Trautwein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Böckler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kanske</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1942" to="1951" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/scan/nsw093</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/scan/nsw093" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain-General and Domain-Specific Patterns of Activity Supporting Metacognition in Human Prefrontal Cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Morales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2360-17</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2360-17" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3534" to="3546" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative decision by sampling: A model of decision making constrained by process data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Noguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="512" to="544" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000102</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000102" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Beyond intelligence: A meta-analytic review of the relationship among metacognition, intelligence, and academic performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ohtani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hisasaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11409-018-9183-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11409-018-9183-8" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="212" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Metacognition and Learning</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient coding of subjective value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polanía</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41593-018-0292-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-018-0292-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence in evaluations and value-based decisions reflects variation in experienced values</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Quandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Figner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Holland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Veling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">151</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="820" to="836" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xge0001102</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0001102" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Search Predicts and Changes Patience in Intertemporal Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Reeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1707040114</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1707040114" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11890" to="11895" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognitive Failure as a Feature of Those Holding Radical Beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rollwage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cub.2018.10.053</idno>
		<idno>4014-4021.e8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2018.10.053" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">24</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychiatric Symptom Dimensions Are Associated With Dissociable Shifts in Metacognition but Not Task Performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rouault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Seow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.12.017</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.12.017" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Neural Pathway for Nonreinforced Preference Change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schonberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="504" to="514" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2020.04.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2020.04.002" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decoding explicit and implicit representations of health and taste attributes of foods in the human brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rosenblatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Eliby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kashima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hogendoorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2021.108045</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2021.108045" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">162</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How choice reveals and shapes expected hedonic outcome</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sharot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>De Martino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4972-08.2009</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4972-08.2009" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3760" to="3765" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is Choice-Induced Preference Change Long Lasting?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sharot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Koster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1123" to="1129" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797612438733</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797612438733" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do Decisions Shape Preference? Evidence From Blind Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sharot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Velasquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1231" to="1235" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-value decisions are fast and accurate, inconsistent with diminishing value sensitivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R K</forename><surname>Shevlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hausfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2101508119</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2101508119" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">119</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaze Amplifies Value in Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797618810521</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797618810521" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dietary Self-Control Is Related to the Speed With Which Attributes of Healthfulness and Tastiness Are Processed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hutcherson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797614559543</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797614559543" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="134" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A common mechanism underlies changes of mind about decisions and confidence. ELife, 5, e12192</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Berg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Anandalingam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zylberberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wolpert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41593-017-0008-xvanden</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.12192" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Elucidating the underlying components of food valuation in the human orbitofrontal cortex</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Endogenous formation of preferences: Choices systematically change willingness-to-pay for goods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Voigt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Murawski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bode</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1872" to="1882" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Memory, and Cognition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xlm0000415</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000415" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hard Decisions Shape the Neural Coding of Preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Voigt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Murawski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Speer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bode</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="718" to="726" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1681-18.2018</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1681-18.2018" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mindful Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev.psych.60.110707.163633</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.60.110707.163633" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic computational model of gaze and choice in multiattribute decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000350</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000350" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metacognition in human decision-making: Confidence and error monitoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Summerfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2011.0416</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2011.0416" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1310" to="1321" />
			<date type="published" when="1594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
