<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">&quot;Better&quot; Help? Ethical Considerations for Therapists Using Telehealth Matching Platforms</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colette</forename><surname>Delawalla</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Emory University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lorenzo</forename><surname>Lorenzo-Luaces</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indiana University-Bloomington</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">&quot;Better&quot; Help? Ethical Considerations for Therapists Using Telehealth Matching Platforms</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:49+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Mental health care in the United States is prohibitively difficult to access. Barriers of entry include a shortage of licensed providers (Butryn et al., 2017), high cost of services, insufficient insurance coverage (Walker et al., 2015), and layers of inefficient bureaucracy. This problem of low supply and high demand has created a unique environment for capitalist problem solvers to enter the therapeutic market. The Federal Trade Commission&apos;s (FTC) recently filed a complain against BetterHelp (FTC, 2023), a so-called &quot;therapy matching&quot; platforms. The FTC complaint is a timely example of the risks associated with these companies and lends itself well to an examination of ethical considerations for therapists considering use of such services. This commentary focuses directly on the ethical dilemma of a therapist choosing to become an independent contractor for companies such as BetterHelp (e.g., growtherapy, TalkSpace). The Good &quot;Therapy matching platforms&quot; began to emerge in the early 2010s, providing the lay public a low-cost platform whereby prospective clients are paired with licensed clinicians, usually within a couple of days (e.g., BetterHelp&apos;s maximum is 48 hours). Clients gain &quot;24/7&quot; access to their assigned clinician through an easy-to-use smart phone application and all communication with the therapist-messaging, calls, and virtual sessions-occurs within the application. Therapists are employed as independent contractors, providing flexibility to manage client load. Likewise, these companies do not oversee the quality of the care provided by the clinicians in any way. At face, BetterHelp and their competitors have addressed substantial gaps in access to mental health services in the United States. Because they have a wide network of clinicians</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>across the United States, prospective clients are paired with a provider usually after less than 10 minutes of electronic paperwork. Further, services often cost clients less than the cost of a copay for a traditional, insurance covered mental healthcare service. BetterHelp was ahead of its time in terms of accessibility, as it has always offered virtual services. Finally, hosting all aspects of therapy (i.e., onboarding, payment, scheduling, sessions) on one application lightens the cognitive load of clients-who may have difficulty navigating traditional forms of onboarding.</p><p>Thus, such platforms have the potential to make mental health care a more just marketplace, serve as a line of preventative care, and help reduce the long-term societal burdens of mental illness (e.g., cost; Kazdin et al., 2013)-a mission most, if not all clinicians can get behind.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Bad</head><p>Unfortunately, BetterHelp has received attention for happenings greatly at odds with their lofty mission. In March 2023, the FTC released eight charges against BetterHelp including: unfair privacy practices, misrepresentation of HIPAA compliance, and failure to obtain consent.</p><p>The FTC commission report revealed that between 2013 and 2020, BetterHelp handed over or sold email addresses, intake questionnaire data, and IP addresses to third parties, including Facebook, Snapchat, and Pinterest, without any restrictions on how the third-party companies could use the data (FTC, 2023)-despite their terms and conditions promising otherwise. The FTC banned BetterHelp from sharing any client data with third parties and required the company to pay $7.8 million to clients who used the platform between 2017 and 2020. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The (Ethical Dilemmas That Could Get) Ugly</head><p>At the crux of ethical matters, BetterHelp and related companies are not required to operate under the umbrella of the APA and do not have to comply with HIPAA. Unlike traditional therapeutic practices, because communication and sessions happen within the company's platform, the therapist does not "own" the client data, the company does. Although some companies are HIPAA compliant (e.g., Talk Space, Growtherapy), they are still allowed to use data collected from clients (e.g., through cookies) to develop new products and for tailored marketing. The issue of data ownership introduces a third party into the therapeutic relationship, thus there is a need to consider the ethical handling of such data.</p><p>The most immediate ethical standard called into question is Standard 3.06 (Conflict of Interest). When clinicians use for-profit therapeutic platforms their professional role as an independent contractor may expose clients to exploitation. In the case of BetterHelp, the company allegedly shared client data that under traditional circumstances would have been protected. While BetterHelp's issues resulted in a slightly more stringent data protection policy, one key caveat is that should the company file for bankruptcy or be sold, the data belongs to a new party. So, while therapists may be protected at present, the solution does not guarantee such protections in the future. Further, even for companies that are HIPAA compliant, privacy policies allow data to be used in ways that lead to the company profiting unless the client explicitly contacts the company to request exclusion from data collection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BETTERHELP ETHICAL CONSIDERATIONS FOR CLINICANS 5</head><p>Relatedly, introduction of a profit motivated, data-owning third party into the therapeutic relationship calls into question whether a clinician can abide by APA Standard 4.01 (Maintaining Confidentiality). While clinicians can "take reasonable precautions" internally, against breaches of confidentiality, conducting therapy on the platform inherently risks breaches of confidentiality of their client's private information in ways that cannot be controlled by the clinician. What constitutes "reasonable precautions", as cited in the APA Ethics Code, in this case?</p><p>A final important ethical consideration is regarding APA Standard 3.10 (Informed Consent). Practicing on a "therapy matching" platform must be accompanied by appropriate informed consent. Unlike a traditional informed consent, informant consent for a platform like BetterHelp would need to cover important additional information. First, put bluntly, matching platforms terms and conditions are set up to bury pieces of key information that may be uncomfortable to the consumer. Thus, to ensure each client truly understands the risks of participating in therapy on platforms such as BetterHelp (e.g., loss of confidentiality), clinicians should include this information in their own informed consent process with clients. Second, in addition to the usual limits of confidentiality (e.g., mandated reporting) the clinician should include an additional limit in their informed consent process, regarding data ownership. Finally, the clinician should explicitly cite their conflict of interest in the informed consent-namely that they are an independent contractor of a company that exists to profit from its clientele.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Considerations for Proceeding</head><p>When it comes to the matter of whether it is ethical to practice on therapy matching platforms, the answers may lie among two secondary questions. First, does one think the benefits to society and individuals outweigh the cost of the risks such as breaching confidentiality?</p><p>Second, is the clinician willing to accept the ethical risks to themselves? BETTERHELP ETHICAL CONSIDERATIONS FOR CLINICANS 6 Thinking through these questions may require clinicians to consider possible adverse effects for individuals whose data could be exposed or who would otherwise be negatively impacted by their platforms. For example, BetterHelp also does business as Pride Counseling, where it focuses on LGBTQ+ individuals-in sharing emails, Pride Counseling may also inadvertently disclose their sexual orientation. Moreover, all therapy matching platforms house some degree of sensitive data in the form of intake information, within-application journals, mood trackers, or messages with the clinician. In the age of telehealth and mammoth data collection efforts by companies, one should consider if the risk of data breaches are more elevated at baseline. Clinicians may weigh the benefit of imperfect iterations of progress in making therapeutic services more widely accessible-falling in line with APA General Principal D: Justice.</p><p>Until the APA releases guidelines on such entities, individual clinicians must decide how comfortable they are with the risks associated with using these platforms. For clinicians who tend to lean more ethically conservative, allowing a third party into the therapeutic relationship is likely misaligned with their approach. However, for clinicians who lean more ethically liberal, then with careful informed consent and quality administration of care, therapy matching platforms could be an option that is well aligned with their ethics. In such cases, clinicians should understand that these platforms are not "plug and play" and require a significant time commitment on the front end to ensure they 1) understand the company's terms and conditions, 2) develop an informed consent that is specific to the and 3) consider extra steps they may need to take to ensure they are able to abide by the ethical code (e.g., recommend clients explicit reach out to the company to opt out of data collection and use).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BETTERHELP ETHICAL CONSIDERATIONS FOR CLINICANS 7</head><p>Forward progress in the area of accessible, affordable mental health care services comes with new challenges to navigate. While the FTC's case against BetterHelp represents possible adverse outcomes related to forward progress, open and continued dialogue in the field regarding best practices when using therapy matching platforms is imperative to this progress. Therapy matching platforms may have a clear benefit to individual patients. However, compared to traditional therapy, they may incur increased risks especially in regard to confidentiality and informed consent, and existing training models may not equip psychologists to consider these risks. As such, there is a great need for ethical standards around the involvement of third parties like therapy matching platforms in the therapy process.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The findings against BetterHelp represent a relatively mild scenario of the risks associated with "therapy matching" platforms. The scale of ethical questions related to BetterHelp's platform are wide ranging including issues surrounding validating clinician BETTERHELP ETHICAL CONSIDERATIONS FOR CLINICANS 4 licenses, confirming clinicians work within their jurisdiction, ensuring safety in the event of suicidality, and challenges related to mandated reporting in a virtual space.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ethical principles of psychologists and code of conduct</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.apa.org/ethics/code" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002-06-01" />
			<publisher>American Psychological Association</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The shortage of psychiatrists and other mental health providers: causes, current state, and potential solutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Butryn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bryant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Marchionni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sholevar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Academic Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Decision</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Order</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Inc</forename><surname>Betterhelp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Docket</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>No. 2023169</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023-03-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Consent Order</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Novel Models for Delivering Mental Health Services and Reducing the Burdens of Mental Illness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kazdin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rabbitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinical Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="170" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/2167702612463566</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/2167702612463566" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-Cultural Barriers to Mental Health Services in the United States</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">T L</forename><surname>Leong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Kalibatseva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cerebrum: The Dana Forum on Brain Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Insurance Status, Use of Mental Health Services, and Unmet Need for Mental Health Care in the United States</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cummings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hockenberry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Druss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1176/appi.ps.201400248</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ps.201400248" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatric Services</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="578" to="584" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
