<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Personal relative deprivation negatively predicts engagement in group decision-making</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Rotella</surname></persName>
							<email>arotella@uwaterloo.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Waterloo</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandeep</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Guelph</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Lang School of Business and Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Waterloo</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Sandeep Mishra</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Guelph</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Waterloo</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>N2L 3G1</postCode>
									<settlement>Waterloo</settlement>
									<region>ON, Canada</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Personal relative deprivation negatively predicts engagement in group decision-making</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T11:52+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Relative deprivation</term>
					<term>groups</term>
					<term>social comparisons</term>
					<term>individual differences</term>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>participation</term>
					<term>engagement</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Inequality has been linked with numerous negative consequences at the societal and individual levels. The detrimental effects of inequality are proposed to operate at the individual level through social comparisons, where perceived unfair disadvantage leads to the experience of personal relative deprivation (i.e., subjective feelings of anger and resentment), which in turn causes psychosocial stress. To date, little empirical work has investigated how individual differences in personal relative deprivation influences group dynamics. In a simulated highpressure hypothetical scenario, first-year business students (n = 150) in groups of four to six were tasked to reach a consensus decision despite being assigned roles with competing interests, then they individually completed a survey. Greater feelings of personal relative deprivation were associated with reduced group engagement. Personal relative deprivation explained 9% of variance in group exercise engagement over and above demographic and situation-related variables (e.g., stress, perceived competition, role fit), and the overall regression model accounted for 58% of total variance in group. These findings suggest that such negative socioemotional comparison reactions as personal relative deprivation have important implications for group-based decision making and small group dynamics.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Human organizations, like human societies, are almost universally defined by social hierarchy. Hierarchy necessitates inequality, and inequality creates potential for interpersonal conflict. In navigating social hierarchy, people inevitably engage in social comparison processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Festinger, 1954;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Garcia, Tor, &amp; Schiff, 2013)</ref>, leading to the experience of personal relative deprivation for some: anger and frustration in response to perceiving that one is unfairly disadvantaged relative to others <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Smith, Pettigrew, Pippin, &amp; Bialosiewicz, 2012)</ref>. The three components of personal relative disadvantage-social comparison, perceived unfairness/injustice, and a negative emotional reaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Smith et al., 2012</ref>)-together index sensitivity to being victimized by inequality <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Callan et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Smith &amp; Huo, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>The experience of personal relative deprivation has been associated with numerous potentially harmful outcomes, including increased risk-taking, gambling, and delay discounting <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Callan, Ellard, Shead, &amp; Hodgins, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Mishra &amp; Novakowski, 2016)</ref>; poorer mental and physical health <ref type="bibr">(Beshai, Mishra, Meadows, Parmar, &amp; Huang, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Beshai, Mishra, Mishra, &amp; Carleton, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Mishra &amp; Carleton, 2015)</ref>; and diminished prosociality <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Callan, Kim, Gheorghiu, &amp; Matthews, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Zhang, Liu, &amp; Tian, 2016)</ref>. Put simply, the experience of personal relative deprivation is associated with damaged social relationships, increased risk-taking and antisocial behavior, reduced cooperation, and increased interpersonal conflict. These findings are consistent with research more broadly linking inequality with a wide range of deleterious social effects in social collectives <ref type="bibr">(Wilkinson &amp; Pickett, 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Social collectives in the form of small groups are fundamental to human organization.</p><p>However, surprisingly little is known about how the (ubiquitous) social comparison experience of personal relative deprivation influences group dynamics. To begin to fill this knowledge gap, we examined if individual differences in personal experience of relative deprivation (resulting RELATIVE DEPRIVATION IN GROUPS 4 from comparison to other group members) reduced engagement in a university-level classroom group decision-making exercise with tangible stakes (i.e., significant attached grades). Given growing evidence that personal relative deprivation is associated with a wide array of damaging social outcomes, we predicted that the experience of personal relative deprivation would be associated with lower engagement with one's social collective in a small group context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Of 192 undergraduates in a first-year business course who participated in this study, 150 completed all variables of interest (37% female, Mage = 21.9, SD = 5.1). Informed consent was obtained for all participants. Post-hoc power analysis indicated 80% power to detect an effect of R 2 = 0.12 with 10 predictors. Data and materials are available at https://osf.io/6r8xc/. Analyses were conducted in R 3.6.0 (R Core Team, 2019). Additional sample and methodological details are provided in Appendix S1.</p><p>Students were randomly assigned to groups of four-to-six participants. In a class exercise, each group had to reach a consensus decision in a hypothetical product recall scenario. Each group member was assigned one of six roles with specific instructions: human resources manager, risk manager, production manager, plant controller, engineering manager, or marketing manager (see Appendix S2). Participants first read the instructions, then all participants assigned to a specific role were given verbal instructions. Students were given one hour to deliberate and reach a decision.</p><p>The exercise was designed such that roles had competing interests and a consensus would be hard to reach. Consensus was considered achieved when all group members recorded an identical (signed) decision outcome. Not all groups achieved consensus. After the exercise was complete, the survey below was distributed and completed individually.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures</head><p>Additional measures administered but not addressed in the present paper are included in Supplement B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Personal relative deprivation. The five-item Personal Relative Deprivation Scale,</head><p>Revised (PRDS-R) assesses feelings of deprivation, resentment, and anger in response to perceived inequality. We adapted the scale to specifically reference group members (e.g., "I felt deprived when I thought about what I had compared to the other group members"). Participants responded using a seven-point scale (1 = strongly disagree, 7 = strongly agree).</p><p>Group competition. On a seven-point scale (1 = strongly disagree, 7 = strongly agree), participants indicated agreement with the following statements/questions: (1) "There was an imbalance of power in the group" and (2) "To what extent do you feel that you were competing with the other group members?". Each item was investigated separately.</p><p>Attitudes toward group experiences. Participants rated: (1) their agreement with the objective of their role; (2) how stressful they found the group activity; (3) how valuable they found the group activity; and (4) how seriously they took the exercise. Each rating was provided on a scale from 1 (not at all) to 7 (very much). All items were investigated separately.</p><p>Group engagement. To assess overall group engagement, we created a compound variable by averaging responses to the following three questions: (1) "How much of a role did you play in the final decision making?", (2) "Overall, how much did you participate in the exercise?", and (3) "Were you as vocal as you would have liked to be?". Responses were RELATIVE DEPRIVATION IN GROUPS 6 provided on a scale from 1 (not at all) to 7 (very much). This composite had good reliability, α = .86, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[.82, .89]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>To determine if feelings of personal relative deprivation predicted group engagement beyond demographic and exercise-related variables, we entered the following items in a threeblock sequential regression analysis: <ref type="formula">1</ref> The sequential regression analysis <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref> showed demographic variables (Block 1) explained 3% of variance in engagement scores, F(3,146) = 1.63, p = .19, R 2 = .03; exerciserelated variables (Block 2) accounted for 46% of variance, F(6,140) = 20.90, p &lt; .001, R 2 = .46.</p><p>Personal relative deprivation (Block 3) significantly predicted 9% of unique variance over and above the two previous blocks, F(1,139) = 28.63, p &lt; .001, R 2 = .58. This finding suggests that feelings of relative deprivation are a unique and surprisingly strong predictor of group engagement in the present study. The overall model accounted for 58% of variance in group engagement scores. When all variables were entered simultaneously into a regression analysis, personal relative deprivation scores accounted for 17% of variance in group engagement (see Supplementary B, Table SB.1). Zero-sum correlations between all relevant variables are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>We provide novel evidence that personal relative deprivation is significantly associated with diminished group engagement. Individual differences in personal relative deprivation strongly predicted group engagement (r = -.39; <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Funder &amp; Ozer, 2019)</ref>, and relative deprivation explained a meaningful amount of variance in group engagement above and beyond demographics and subjective assessments of the group context (9%). These assessments included subjects' role fit, whether the group task was stressful, valuable and/or taken seriously, and the perceived degree of competition and power imbalance within the group. Finally, personal relative deprivation explained 17% of variance in group engagement when entered in a simultaneous regression along with all group context-specific attitudes and perceptions. Taken together, evidence from this study suggests that personal relative deprivation is an underappreciated predictor of poorer social relations (and downstream consequences) in small groups.</p><p>Consistent with previous research, we found strong and consistent associations between personal relative deprivation and damaged social perceptions, relations, and outcomes. More specifically, those who report greater personal relative deprivation experience poorer outcomes in small group context. To date, surprisingly little research has examined the consequence of personal, subjective, and emotional reactions to inequality in group context. Some research has suggested that objective inequality in small groups leads to poorer social outcomes (e.g.,</p><p>Christine &amp; Barling, 2010), but it is clear that further study of subjective, emotional processes in group dynamics is necessary.</p><p>The results of this study have some potentially important implications. Groups are regularly formed in schools and in industry to work together on projects, deliberate, or to make decisions. In these contexts, it is impossible to escape social comparison and its resultant RELATIVE DEPRIVATION IN GROUPS 8 emotional consequences, leading to poorer outcomes if left unchecked. These results make clear that individual members of social collectives are of consequence; for example, from our results we may predict that a jury may experience relatively greater engagement in deliberations if status differences were reduced. There is a growing awareness of the damaging effects of inequality and a consequent appetite for interventions that may ameliorate these damaging effects; our results provide further evidence that consideration of emotions tied to inequality, like personal relative deprivation, may be fruitful in these endeavors. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Sequential regression of demographics, group situation-specific perceptions and attitudes, and personal relative deprivation on group engagement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B SE β t p</head><p>Step 1 (Demographics): R = .18, R 2 = .03 </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Age</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>demographics (age, gender, income); (2) situationspecific perceptions and attitudes (agreement with role objective [role fit], stress experienced during group exercise, value of the exercise, how seriously the exercise was taken, perceived competition within group, and imbalance of power within group); and (3) personal relative deprivation scores. The compound group engagement variable was used as the dependent measure.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Correlations between group engagement, subjective relative deprivation, group competition, and attitudes toward the group exercise.Numbers in brackets are 95% confidence intervals.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>.13</cell><cell>.06</cell><cell>.16</cell><cell>1.95</cell><cell>.053</cell></row><row><cell>Gender</cell><cell>-.18</cell><cell>.65</cell><cell>-.02</cell><cell>-.28</cell><cell>.782</cell></row><row><cell>Income</cell><cell>-.03</cell><cell>.02</cell><cell>-.10</cell><cell>-1.24</cell><cell>.216</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Step 2 (Situation-Specific Perceptions and Attitudes): R = .70, ΔR 2 = .46***</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Role fit</cell><cell>.61</cell><cell>.16</cell><cell>.24</cell><cell>3.76***</cell><cell>&lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell>Exercise was stressful</cell><cell>-.30</cell><cell>.14</cell><cell>-.13</cell><cell>-2.05*</cell><cell>.042</cell></row><row><cell>Exercise was valuable</cell><cell>.66</cell><cell>.21</cell><cell>.23</cell><cell>3.18**</cell><cell>.002</cell></row><row><cell>Took exercise seriously</cell><cell>.80</cell><cell>.20</cell><cell>.29</cell><cell>3.92***</cell><cell>&lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell>Competition in group</cell><cell>.57</cell><cell>.15</cell><cell>.26</cell><cell>3.83***</cell><cell>&lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell>Imbalance of power in group</cell><cell>-.17</cell><cell>.13</cell><cell>-.08</cell><cell>-1.35</cell><cell>.179</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Step 3 (Personal Relative Deprivation): R = .76, ΔR 2 = .09***</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PRDS-R</cell><cell>-.28</cell><cell>.05</cell><cell>-.31</cell><cell cols="2">-5.35*** &lt; .001</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">Notes. *p &lt; .05; **p &lt; .01; ***p &lt; .001. PRDS-R = Personal Relative Deprivation Scale-</cell></row><row><cell>Revised.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personal relative deprivation associated with functional disorders via stress: An examination of fibromyalgia and gastrointestinal symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Beshai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Carleton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">189666</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minding the gap: Subjective relative deprivation and depressive symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Beshai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J S</forename><surname>Meadows</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Parmar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc. Sci. Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">173</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gambling as a search for justice: Examining the role of personal relative deprivation in gambling urges and gambling behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ellard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Shead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hodgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1514" to="1529" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The interrelations between social class, personal relative deprivation, and prosociality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gheorghiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychological and Personality Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="660" to="669" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond status: relating status inequality to performance and health in teams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Christie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Barling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">920</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of social comparison processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Festinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Relations</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating effect size in psychological research: Sense and nonsense</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Funder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ozer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Methods and Practices in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="168" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of competition: A social comparison perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garcia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Schiff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="634" to="650" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subjective relative deprivation is associated with poorer physical and mental health</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Carleton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Science &amp; Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="144" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personal relative deprivation and risk: An examination of individual differences in personality, attitudes, and behavioral outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Novakowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.R-project.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<pubPlace>Vienna, Austria</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relative deprivation: How subjective experiences of inequality influence social behavior and health. Policy Insights from the</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Huo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relative deprivation: A theoretical and meta-analytic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Pettigrew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pippin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bialosiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pers. Soc. Psychol. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="232" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual-based relative deprivation (IRD) decreases prosocial behaviors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Motivation and Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="666" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">PRDS-R = Personal Relative Deprivation Scale-Revised. *p &lt; .05</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&lt;</forename><surname>**p</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>***p &lt;</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
