<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Attribution of Responsibility Between Agents in a Causal Chain</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vanessa</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Mengxuan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Qiao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Teneille</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">S.J. Quinney College of Law</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Utah</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Maximilian</roleName><forename type="first">Yvonne</forename><forename type="middle">Mcdermott</forename><surname>Rees</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Attribution of Responsibility Between Agents in a Causal Chain</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:02+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>moral judgment</term>
					<term>moral decision-making</term>
					<term>blame attribution</term>
					<term>causal responsibility</term>
					<term>causal chain</term>
					<term>proximate cause</term>
					<term>superseding cause</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>When ordinary people hear about a &apos;hired gun&apos; killing, who do they judge to be more responsible-the person who instigated the killing or the person who executed it? In this paper, we explored the attribution of causal and moral responsibility in a causal chain of events, where an agent A instructs an intermediate agent B to execute some harmful action which leads to a bad outcome to a victim V. In Study 1, participants judged B to be more of a cause, more blameworthy, and more deserving of punishment than A. In Study 2, we explored the effect of proximity by adding a third, subsequent contributing cause, such that B&apos;s action no longer as closely and directly caused the final bad outcome. Across three vignettes, participants judged both agents to be less causal, blameworthy, and deserving of punishment when they were less proximal to the outcome, but still judged B to be more morally and causally responsible than A in all conditions. In Study 3, we varied whether each of the two agents (A and B) intended for the final outcome to occur. We found an interaction between role and intent, where participants only mitigated causal and moral judgments for A when A did not intend for the outcome to occur-regardless of B&apos;s intent. We discuss possible explanations for our findings and its implications for moral and legal decision-making.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attribution of Responsibility Between Agents in a Causal Chain</head><p>In February 2022, Jennifer Faith, who had instructed her boyfriend Darrin Lopez to kill her husband, pleaded guilty to a murder-for-hire charge. This offense carries a potential death sentence in the state of Texas 1 . Darrin Lopez was later also convicted of murder 2 .</p><p>While there are a number of considerations for how the two defendants are sentenced in court, many of them specific to the situation, we are interested in understanding folk perceptions of causal responsibility in such cases where an individual commits harm 'by proxy'. Do ordinary people consider Faith and Lopez to be equally responsible and blameworthy for the victim's death? Do they think that the two deserve equal punishment? These questions relate to how people attribute responsibility to multiple agents when they have each contributed differently to an outcome.</p><p>One key difficulty in evaluating causality in many situations, including the one mentioned above, is that different factors can interact and combine in various ways to cause an outcome. Causal judgments are often graded instead of binary, and people attribute responsibility differently depending on how causal factors interact with each other <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Gerstenberg &amp; Lagnado, 2010)</ref>. The causal structures of scenarios can take many forms <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(DeScioli &amp; Kurzban, 2013)</ref>; and in cases that feature multiple agents, it is often difficult to determine which agent is more responsible for the outcome, and by how much.</p><p>There are at least three causal structures in which two agents A and B might be responsible for a single outcome: (1) both agents independently contribute to cause an outcome; (2) the actions of A cause the actions of B which directly cause the outcome, and</p><p>(3) the group, of which A and B are both part of, jointly causes the outcome <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kaiserman, 2021)</ref>. While many studies have explored how people attribute responsibility in (1) (e.g., <ref type="bibr">1</ref> https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndtx/pr/jennifer-faith-pleads-guilty-murder-hire-husband-s-death 2 https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/ darrin-lopez-jennifer-faith-love-triangle-murder-army-veteran-rcna117945 <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Gerstenberg &amp; Lagnado, 2010)</ref>, fewer have explored situations such as (2) where B's actions depend on A in a causal chain (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). This is a case of joint causation, where both agents are necessary for the outcome and mutually interdependent. While A did not directly cause the outcome, it would not have occurred but for their instigation; on the other hand, while B physically caused the outcome to occur, they would not have done so in the first place had it not been for A's initial solicitation or instigation. Consider the case described earlier: Do people consider Faith more responsible as none of the subsequent events would have happened but for her actions? Or do they consider Lopez more responsible because he directly and physically caused the victim's death? </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(i) A attacks V B attacks V V dies (ii) A instructs B to attack V B attacks V V dies</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Joint Responsibility in a Causal Chain</head><p>In a causal chain, while prior events do not directly cause the outcome to occur, transitivity of causation implies that if some event A causes B, and B causes an outcome (O), it follows that A had in some way caused O <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Hilton et al., 2010)</ref>. According to the force dynamics theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Wolff &amp; Thorstad, 2017)</ref>, this process involves a 'transmission' of force from A to B to O. However, people do not judge these events to be equally causal: they tend to attribute more causality to the proximal cause than the distal cause <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lagnado &amp; Channon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Reuter et al., 2014)</ref>. These causal evaluations allow people to make moral judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Sloman et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Waldmann et al., 2017)</ref>, in that they often judge the proximal cause to be less morally permissible <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Engelmann &amp; Waldmann, 2022)</ref>. In this article, we use 'proximity' to refer to the location of the cause in a causal chain of events <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lagnado &amp; Channon, 2008)</ref>; a more proximal cause is a cause that is more direct and temporally close to the outcome <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Hart &amp; Honoré, 1985)</ref>.</p><p>Situations with multiple agents are invariably more complex, especially in moral or legal contexts where a variety of factors come into play. Legal theorists have proposed that if there is a 'free and deliberate' human action in the causal chain, it is more likely to be selected as an explanation for an outcome than a physical cause (e.g., natural causes, like wind or an earthquake; <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Hart and Honoré, 1985)</ref>. Imagine a scenario where two agents, A and B, jointly cause an outcome: A deliberately throws a lighted cigarette into a shrub which catches fire, and the fire is exacerbated by B pouring petrol on the flames. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Hart and Honoré (1985)</ref> argue that people are more likely to attribute causality to the proximal cause (B) since it is a human action that intervened in the causal chain, regardless of whether the distal cause (A) is a human action or a physical cause. Conversely, if the proximal cause was a physical cause (e.g., instead of B pouring petrol, the wind had exacerbated the flames), then people are more likely to attribute causality to A's actions.</p><p>Other studies have supported this theory, finding that people prioritise voluntary actions as explanations over physical causes <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Hilton et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">McClure et al., 2007)</ref>.</p><p>However, note that each agent acted independently in the above example: B did not act in concert with A, nor did A's actions bring about B's actions <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(McClure et al., 2007)</ref>.</p><p>As such, this chain of events may be better described as a collider with a temporal delay between causes rather than a causal chain. Of those studies that do investigate causal chains rather than colliders, they have either mainly focused on using more abstract materials that do not involve human agents <ref type="bibr">(Engelmann &amp; Kirfel, in press</ref>), or situations where B acts unknowingly or under some situational constraint brought about by A <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Fincham &amp; Shultz, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Phillips &amp; Shaw, 2015)</ref>. To our knowledge, no research has focused on causal and moral judgments in situations where A and B act in concert with each other, but take on different roles and at different times -such as that of instigator and executor of a criminal act. Therefore, we aim to investigate how people make causal and moral judgments on agents taking two different roles (i.e., instigator and executor) in a causal chain of events.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Causal Chains in the Law</head><p>To be found guilty of a crime, the defendants' actions must have caused the alleged harm. Criminal statutes often require that the defendant intend or at least know about the consequences of their conduct, which usually makes it easier to tie the accused's actions to causing the victim's injury. However, this is not always the case. In the case of the 'hired gun' killing discussed above, or when multiple defendants agree to carry out different parts of a drug trafficking cartel, it can often be difficult to determine whether and to what extent each is causally responsible. Evaluating comparative responsibility when multiple criminal actors contribute either independently, collectively, contemporaneously, or serially requires more sophisticated concepts of causation.</p><p>Because criminal activities are often quite complex, multiple actors often contribute in different ways, or at different times, to a harmful outcome. How do courts deal with this scenario, where subsequent acts or events 'intervene' between an original actor's criminal conduct and the injury? The intervening cause (or novus actus interveniens) might be human action such as an accomplice who carries out a murder-for-hire, or it might be the victim's underlying heart condition or even a natural event such as wind.</p><p>For an intervening act to relieve the original actor of legal liability, the key question, in both the United States and the United Kingdom, is whether the second-in-time 'individual's conduct is so unusual, extraordinary, or bizarre that the policy of law will relieve the defendant of any liability' (People v. <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Cervantes, 2001)</ref>. That is, just as with regular proximate cause cases, the foreseeability of the harm often determines whether an intervening act breaks the causal chain. If it does, it is considered a superseding cause, relieving the original actor of liability. For example, if A tells B to set V's house on fire, and V returns to the burning building to save some of his property and dies, this is a foreseeable intervening act and does not break the chain of causation for V's death <ref type="bibr">(State v. Leopold, 1929)</ref>. Or, assume that A attacks V, and while the attack by itself would not have caused death, it reasonably induced V to jump out of a window to flee. If V dies as a result, that could result in a criminal homicide <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Regina v. Halliday, 1889)</ref>.</p><p>Let us reconsider the 'hired gun' murder example. While we typically do not foresee criminal conduct, 'criminal acts are not superseding causes per se' <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Blum, 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kemper v. Deutsche Bank AG, 2018)</ref>. Courts will ask if the intervening criminal conduct 'is a normal and reasonably foreseeable result of the defendant's original act' such that it will not relieve the defendant of liability (People v. <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Brady, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">People v. Cervantes, 2001</ref>).</p><p>As another example, let us examine a type of case that comes up frequently in the United Kingdom and the United States, and raises similar questions related to the responsibility of actions in the causal chain. Imagine that A delivers heroin to B's house, and then B prepares the drugs for B and his friend V to inject. B injects the drugs first in his arm, and then gives the syringe to V, who injects himself with the same amount.</p><p>Shortly after B and V inject the heroin into their arms, V loses consciousness and collapses on the floor. Sometime later, V dies from a heroin overdose. Who is a legal cause of V's death?</p><p>In these kinds of cases, the foreseeability of the intervening act no longer serves as the sole factor when assessing causation and responsibility. Divergent responses to this type of case reveal inconsistencies in the legal tests employed as well as the importance of case-specific facts. Typically, V's voluntarily injecting himself is an intervening act that does not in itself break the chain of causal responsibility for either A or B, who can both be found guilty of manslaughter <ref type="bibr">(State v. Wassil, 1995)</ref>. However, a substantial number of cases also go in the opposite direction because they employ different tests for intervening causation. For example, one court found that V's voluntary taking of the drugs did break the chain of causation because it was not 'reasonably foreseeable to the defendant that the victim would die if he gave her the medication at issue' <ref type="bibr">(State v. Wade, 2008)</ref>. On very similar facts, the court in Kennedy (No. 2) in the United Kingdom found that the victim's overdose was completely foreseeable because A knew that V was already inebriated, but it was the voluntariness of V's self-injection that broke the chain of causation. Still, other courts have found the defendant guilty of manslaughter for prescribing one of many drugs that were in the victim's system, and which the victim foreseeably but voluntarily took at much higher doses than prescribed. 3</p><p>While an intervening, voluntary act is often sufficient to break the chain of causation, this is not always the case. When the different factors (voluntariness, criminality, or foreseeability of the intervening act) conflict with one another, courts tend to apply them inconsistently <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Firkins, 2023a)</ref>. This may be because it can be unclear whether an act is truly voluntary or informed <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Firkins, 2023b)</ref>, or whether an outcome was foreseeable to a person who contributed to its cause. Naturally, in a straightforward 'hired gun' murder, the victim's death is a foreseeable outcome to the instigator. But imagine a scenario where A only instructs B to attack V, not necessarily intending V's death (as in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). How do people make judgments in cases where they do not know the agents' intentions and whether they could have reasonably foreseen the outcome? In such cases, can A serve as a legal cause of V's death? Can B? Does the action of B relieve A of criminal liability?</p><p>There are various tests courts employ when determining whether an intervening act relieves the initial actor of criminal liability. The foreseeability of the intervening act remains the touchstone, but even foreseeability can be interpreted in many ways. Further, in addition to lack of foreseeability, if the intervening act is considered voluntary, independent, criminal, extraordinary, remote or indirect, this can also serve to break the chain of causation. Sometimes these factors point in the opposite direction of foreseeability.</p><p>When there are inconsistencies in the law or multiple, competing tests that can be employed, this often points to there being conflicting moral intuitions at work. It is therefore important to investigate folk perceptions of causality and how they apply to legal cases, as the question of causation in the court of law 'must be decided as a properly instructed and reasonable jury would decide it,' rather than using a 'logical or scientific theory of causation <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">' (Stapley v Gypsum Mines, 1953)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Intentionality and Foreseeability in Causal Chains</head><p>In the psychological literature, there is strong evidence that intentionality and foreseeablility are crucial for determining whether an agent should be held accountable for their actions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Critcher et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Malle et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Shaver, 1985)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Alicke (2000)</ref> argues that intentional actions include two components: intention of action and intention of outcome. The former refers to whether the agent behaved knowingly, purposefully, and without external constraint, whereas the latter refers to whether the agent caused outcomes that they desired or predicted <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Alicke et al., 2015)</ref>. Indeed, people tend to attribute higher blame to agents who intend and plan to harm others compared to those who cause accidental or uncontrollable harm, and also attribute higher blame for actions with highly foreseeable outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Ames &amp; Fiske, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lagnado &amp; Channon, 2008)</ref>.</p><p>Agents therefore can be held differentially accountable for joint causation of an outcome if there is variation in how intentional or foreseeable their actions were.</p><p>Prior research using causal chains with two agents acting independently has found that causal judgments are not typically influenced by whether the distal agent intended to bring about the outcome <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Brickman et al., 1975;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Hilton et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">McClure et al., 2007)</ref>.</p><p>In contrast, <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lagnado and Channon (2008)</ref>  Another critical question arises as to whether a subsequent act by a third party (e.g., the victim themselves) may break the causal chain between the defendants' act and the outcome. Previously, we have discussed how in the law, such interruptions to the causal chain can relieve responsibility of the distal agent(s). But do laypeople make judgments of responsibility consistent with these legal assumptions?</p><p>We aim to answer these questions in this paper, and build on existing work on how folk and legal ascriptions of causation are similar and where they differ (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Güver &amp; Kneer, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Knobe &amp; Shapiro, 2021)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview of Studies</head><p>Because of the multiplicity of potentially conflicting factors present in these cases, we designed a series of experiments to see how laypeople would assess blame and punishment between multiple agents who contributed to the ultimate harm in a causal chain of events (in different ways and at different times). These were shown to participants in the form of vignettes (sometimes based on real criminal cases) in which two defendants, an instigator (A) and an executor (B) of the criminal act contribute jointly to kill a victim <ref type="bibr">(V)</ref>. In all the scenarios that we use, A does not directly harm V but instructs B to do so.</p><p>We manipulated the extent to which the agents' conduct was proximate (i.e., temporally close and direct) and intentional. Across three studies, we investigated how people attribute causality, blame, and punishment to the two agents in a causal chain.</p><p>In Study 1, we investigate the effect of an agent's role in the causal chain on causal and moral judgments using a short scenario based on a criminal case. Further, we explore the role of proximity and intent using variations of this scenario. Specifically, we vary the proximity of the two agents' contributions to the outcome (i.e., how much B directly, and in a temporally closer manner, caused the outcome; Study 2) and whether each agent intended for the outcome to occur (Study 3), to explore how these factors influence laypeople's causal and moral judgments. All materials, data, and analyzes are available at the OSF repository (https://osf.io/bg5xz/?view_only=f2449a0d07ce4844ae1343b34eecc5c4).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>First, we investigated whether people would assign the same or different levels of causal responsibility, blame, and punishment depending on an agent's role in a causal chain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>The study was approved by the UCL Psychology Ethics Committee (EP/2018/005) and we obtained informed consent from all participants. To achieve 80% power for detecting a medium effect size at an alpha-level of 0.05, 36 participants were required. We recruited 90 UK participants from Prolific (M age = 38.5, SD age = 13.2, 45 male, 45 female; paid £0.70). Participants were pre-screened to only include those who were fluent in English, had an approval rate of ≥ 95% on the platform, and had previously participated in at least five studies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design</head><p>The study used a within-subjects design. We measured participants' judgments of causal responsibility, blame, and punishment for the two agents (A and B). They were shown two scales for each measure on a scale of 0-100, one for giving a response for A, and the other for B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and Procedure</head><p>We presented an original vignette in an online experiment on Qualtrics. This described a legal case, loosely based on R v. <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Rook (1993)</ref>, where A ('Adam') instructed an intermediate agent B ('Ben') to attack V ('Veronica'), which led to her death. Both parties admitted to their actions to reduce ambiguity about credibility. The vignette ('Killing') is</p><p>shown below: Responses to the first two questions was made on a scale of 0 (Not at all) to 100 (Completely), and for punishment on a scale of 0 (No punishment) and 100 (Maximum punishment [i.e., life imprisonment]). The order of the agents' names was displayed in counterbalanced order between participants.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Adam</formula><p>To ensure robustness of our findings, participants made their judgments using two different kinds of measures. Each participant gave judgments twice with two sets of instructions presented in counterbalanced order. In one version of the questions, participants could freely give ratings to each defendant (i.e., free allocation; 'You may use any number on the scale that accurately reflects your judgments for each defendant, i.e., there are no restrictions.'). In the other version, participants were told that for each measure, their responses for the two defendants could only total 100 (i.e., fixed sum; 'The judgments you give for the two defendants must add up to 100 for each question.'). The purpose was to control for potential effects driven by different instructions, and to see whether causal attribution is conceived of as a zero-sum phenomenon <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kaiserman, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Lastly, we also asked three open questions related to their reasoning process. For brevity, we do not report this data in the current paper, but it is available in the online repository.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>First, we adjusted the free allocation ratings to be comparable with the fixed sum ratings by re-scaling the former to show the proportion of scores given to each agent. For each participant, we then averaged across the fixed sum and re-scaled free allocation ratings to obtain one rating for each agent. We conducted paired t-tests to compare mean judgments for agents A and B. These tests were conducted separately for each judgment measure (cause, blame, and punishment).</p><p>Overall, participants were more severe in their moral judgments for B compared to  We find similar results in an analysis of only free allocation responses, showing that participants intuitively make similar judgments without being prompted to compare the two agents. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>We found that participants tended to rate the executor (B) as significantly more causal, more blameworthy, and more deserving of severe punishment than the instigator (A). This is in line with findings from the psychological literature, which showed that people tend to consider the proximal agent to be more of a cause (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Engelmann &amp; Waldmann, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lagnado &amp; Channon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Reuter et al., 2014)</ref>. Considering that the intentions of both agents are vague in this scenario, there are two explanations as to why participants tended to attribute more responsibility to B: (1) B physically produced the outcome in a temporally closer manner <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Lagnado &amp; Gerstenberg, 2017)</ref> and <ref type="formula">2</ref>assumptions about intent and foreseeability. In other words, it may be because B's actions directly produced the outcome, or because participants inferred that B developed his own motives for wanting to kill the victim (A might have merely wanted to attack V, and not necessarily for V to die). We explore these two explanations in Studies 2 and 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>Study 1 revealed that participants judged the proximal agent (the executor, B) to be more causal, more blameworthy, and more deserving of more severe punishment than the distal agent (the instigator, A). We further explored this proximity effect in Study 2.</p><p>We manipulated the directness of B's actions by adding in a third contributing factor (V's own behaviour) that is more proximal. In other words, the most proximal cause is the last in time and the direct cause of the final outcome (V's death). We investigated people's judgments of the two agents when B's actions are no longer most proximal to the final outcome.</p><p>This study was a preregistered replication of the Study 2 presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cheung et al. (2024)</ref>. We also extended the original study by including two more vignettes that follow the same general causal chain structure of the 'Killing' vignette. However, here, we varied the severity in the final outcome, such as injury instead of death, to improve the generalizability of our previous findings. We preregistered the study at https://osf.io/bg5xz/?view_only=f2449a0d07ce4844ae1343b34eecc5c4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>The study was approved by the UCL Psychology Ethics Committee (EP/2018/005) and we obtained informed consent from all participants. To achieve 80% power for detecting a medium effect size at an alpha-level of 0.05, 216 participants were required. We recruited 270 UK participants from Prolific using the same exclusion criteria as in Study 1 (paid £0.75 for the 5-minute study). As preregistered, we excluded 14 participants for failing the attention check, which asked what they just read in the vignette. The final sample size was N = 256 (M age = 42.4, SD age = 14.0, 127 male, 129 female).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Materials</head><p>This study used a 2 (between-subjects; Proximity) × 2 (within-subjects; Role) × 3 (between-subjects; Vignette) design. Participants were randomised into two groups (Low vs. High Proximity) and saw one of three possible vignettes. For example, in the 'Killing'</p><p>vignette, in the High Proximity condition, participants saw the same vignette as in Study 1</p><p>where B directly causes the final outcome. In the Low Proximity condition, participants saw a similar vignette except V survives the attack. V's leg is permanently damaged by the attack, and she later dies from falling down a flight of stairs due to this injury. We included two other vignettes, 'Lake' and 'Trespasser' (loosely based on Republic of Hawaii v. Oishi, 1895). We include full materials for all vignettes in the Appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>We used the same measures and procedure as Study 1, except with only free allocation instructions so as not to explicitly encourage comparison between the two agents. We asked participants two multiple-choice attention check questions after they made all judgments about what happened in the passage (e.g., which agent physically and directly carried out the attack). Participants also rated the causal responsibility and blameworthiness of the victim (V). They also answered the question 'How foreseeable do you think V's death was to each person?' on a scale of 0-100. We included this question in Study 2 because, given the addition of the victim's action later in the causal chain, participants may now judge the final outcome to be less foreseeable to the agents. This may be a possible explanation as to why they may reduce judgments of responsibility for the agents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>We conducted 2 (Proximity) × 2 (Role) × 3 (Vignette) mixed ANOVA for judgments of cause, blame, and punishment separately using afex <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Singmann et al., 2022)</ref>, and pairwise comparisons using emmeans <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Lenth, 2022)</ref> with Tukey adjusted p-values. As we did not hypothesize differences between vignettes, the preregistered main analyses focused on testing the main effects of Proximity and Role averaged across all three vignettes. All data and code are available on the online repository.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Main Analysis</head><p>Our results showed a significant main effect of Proximity for all measures when responses are averaged across all three vignettes (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4)</ref>. We replicated the finding that participants judged both agents to be more of a cause, F (1, 250) = 4.83, p = .029, and deserved more severe punishment, F (1, 250) = 5.38, p = .021, when they directly caused the outcome (i.e., in the High Proximity condition). However, we found no effect of Proximity on judgments of blame, F (1, 250) = 1.40, p = .238. Participants in the High Proximity condition also judged the outcome to be more foreseeable to both agents, F (1, 250) = 15.27, p &lt; .001. In other words, we found a similar pattern of results as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cheung et al. (2024)</ref>.</p><p>We again found a significant overall main effect of Role.  responses for Vignettes 2 and 3, whereby B is judged to be more of a cause, more blameworthy, more deserving of severe punishment, and more able to foresee the outcome than A. Participants also judge the agents to be more morally and causally responsible in the High Proximity compared to the Low Proximity condition, but again B more so than A. For Vignette 1, while visual inspection of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure B1</ref> in the Appendix shows a pattern of results that is in line with the predicted direction, there was less of an effect of Role in the Low Proximity condition, similar to results of <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cheung et al. (2024)</ref>. However, here we did not find a significant main effect of Role on any measures in Vignette 1 (cause:</p><p>F (1, 84) = 0.94, p = .336; blame: F (1, 84) = 0.01, p = .939; punishment:</p><p>F (1, 84) = 1.41, p = .239; foreseeability: F (1, 84) = 0.24, p = .624). For full results by vignette, please see the Appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Judgments of the Victim</head><p>In the High Proximity condition, while the victim (V) is the agent who is closest in time to the outcome in this causal chain of events, participants judged V almost completely not to be a cause (M = 2.9, 95% CI [−0.1, 5.9]) and only slightly to blame (M = 11.4, 95%</p><p>CI [8.4, 14.4]).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Overall, the presence of a subsequent contributing cause mitigated judgments for both A and B: both agents were more of a cause and more deserving of punishment when they more directly caused the outcome. This suggests that participants may have attributed more responsibility to B in Study 1 because he was the most proximal cause.</p><p>This is consistent with previous findings that actions are more morally permissible in a longer chain of events, because they are considered to be less likely and less foreseeable <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Engelmann &amp; Waldmann, 2022)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cheung et al. (2024)</ref> had found that when proximity was reduced, participants judged A and B to be equally causal and deserving of punishment for the outcome. Rather, we replicated this only in the one vignette in that study, but not in the two additional vignettes, which showed that participants continued to judge B more severely than A. One explanation is due to the idiosyncrasies in the vignettes: in Vignette 1, B was a 'hired gun' who A hired, and not someone he knew personally. In some sense, being a 'hired gun' might have actually mitigated some responsibility for B, as he may be seen as having extrinsic motivation to carry out A's wishes (e.g., monetary gain). In Vignettes 2 and 3, B</p><p>was a friend or acquaintance of A's. Therefore, it is possible that participants drew different inferences about the proximal agent when he was a 'hired gun' (e.g., he has no moral compass) compared to when he was doing something for his friend (e.g., he may have acted out of loyalty, or felt pressured to do so). Prior research has found that inferred bad moral character and bad motives can increase judgments of blame <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Nadelhoffer et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr"></ref> for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Carlson et al., 2022)</ref>, especially in situations where information is limited <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Cheung &amp; Lagnado, 2023)</ref>, such as in short vignettes typically used in psychology experiments.</p><p>Further, both agents were highly blameworthy regardless of proximity to the outcome. This is supported by previous findings that people tend to blame others for having bad intentions or desires even if they did not directly cause a harmful outcome <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Young &amp; Tsoi, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Young &amp; Saxe, 2011)</ref>. By extending the causal chain, we also find an effect of foreseeability on moral judgments: both A and B are less responsible when participants think they did not foresee the outcome. This is consistent with previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Engelmann &amp; Waldmann, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Fincham &amp; Shultz, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Lagnado &amp; Channon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Margoni &amp; Brown, 2023)</ref> showing that foreseeability mitigates responsibility judgments.</p><p>One question that follows is whether agents would also be considered less responsible if they did not intend for the final outcome to occur -as unintended outcomes are usually less foreseeable than intended ones <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kovacevic et al., 2024)</ref>. In our vignettes, the agents' intentions were ambiguous: we only mentioned that A instructed B to attack V, and it is therefore unclear whether either agent had intended for V to die. It is possible that inferences about both agents' intentions would influence moral judgments. Variance in these assumptions may have also contributed to why we could not replicate results from Study 1. We therefore aimed to further explore this in Study 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>In Study 3, we explored the interaction between intent and role by making intent unambiguous and directly manipulating the intent of each agent. We showed participants the same causal chain scenario as Study 1 -A instructs B to attack V, which directly leads to her death. However, we varied whether each defendant intended for the final outcome to occur (i.e., the victim's death). We explored (1) whether people would judge the agents differently depending on their intent, and (2) whether the causal chain between A and the outcome would weaken when B acts in a way that is not intended by A (and therefore less foreseeable).</p><p>This study also investigated how participants represented the events in causal models. The first purpose of this was a manipulation check, to see whether participants accurately interpreted the causal structure of scenario to be a causal chain. The second purpose was to explore whether differences in how people represented the events was associated with differences in how they attribute responsibility to the two agents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>The study was approved by the UCL Psychology Ethics Committee (EP/2018/005) and we obtained informed consent from all participants. To achieve 80% power for detecting a medium effect size at an alpha-level of 0.05, 136 participants were required. We recruited 145 UK participants from Prolific with the same exclusion criteria as the previous studies (paid £2.90 for the 19-minute study). We excluded nine participants (one for failing the attention check and eight for not answering all questions). The final sample size was N = 136 (M age = 38.7, SD age = 13.2, 65 male, 71 female).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Materials</head><p>This study used a 2 (between-subjects; A's Intent) × 2 (between-subjects; B's Intent) × 2 (within-subjects; Role) design. Note that 'intent' refers to intending the final outcome (i.e., killing V), not just intending the act (i.e., attacking V). In other words, 'High Intent' refers to intending to kill V, whereas 'Low Intent' refers to merely wanting to injure V. We showed a modified version of 'Killing' with four different variations of Intent. We chose this vignette (1) for consistency, as we had used it in Study 1;</p><p>(2) because it is quite similar to the 'Lake' vignette, and (3) because it is more straightforward to manipulate the intent of each agent compared to 'Trespasser', where the agents' intentions can be somewhat inferred and it is less believable why either agent would want to kill the victim. In all versions, the outcome is the same: V dies as a result of B's actions, which were brought about by A. For the within-subjects measure (Role), participants gave moral judgments for both defendants as in the previous studies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>First, participants were instructed how to use Loopy (https://ncase.me/loopy/), an online web tool used to create causal models by drawing nodes and arrows. They engaged in two practice tasks where they constructed causal models from simple scenarios. Then, participants saw the experimental vignette, and were asked to first represent the scenario using Loopy. Then, they gave causal and moral judgments as in the previous studies.</p><p>Finally, we asked participants to write a few lines about to explain their judgments for the two agents in two separate questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Main Analysis</head><p>To test the effects of Role and Intent, we conducted a mixed 2 (A's Intent) × 2 (B's Intent) × 2 (Role) ANOVA for each measure (cause, blame, and punishment) separately.</p><p>We We found that B's Intent did not influence moral judgments between the two agents (cause: F (132) = 0.61, p = .436; blame: F (132) = 0.33, p = .568; punishment: F (132) = 1.88, p = .173). However, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref>, we found a significant interaction between A's Intent and Role for judgments of cause, F (1, 132) = 13.10, p &lt; .001, blame, F (1, 132) = 7.98, p = .005, and how much they deserved to be punished, F (1, 132) = 22.09, p &lt; .001. We conducted pairwise comparisons between judgments for A and B at different levels of A's Intent.</p><p>The top plot in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref> shows participants' causal judgments, and the two panels on the right show how they attributed cause differently to A and B when A had Low Intent. <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 2</ref> shows the mean judgment scores for each agent at each level of A's Intent.</p><p>Pairwise comparisons revealed that, when A had Low Intent, participants judged A to be less of a cause than B, t(132) = 6.27, p &lt; .001. Although there is a ceiling effect present in these judgments as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref>, where some participants attributed maximal cause for both agents, the density plots show that many more participants attributed maximal scores to B than for A.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5A</ref>. Here, there was no significant difference in judgments between A and B, t(132) = 1.26, p = .592.</p><p>We show a similar pattern of results for blame judgments as depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref> and <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 2</ref>. Pairwise comparisons revealed that participants judged A to be significantly less blameworthy than B when A had Low Intent, t(132) = 4.13, p &lt; .001. When A had High Intent, judgments of blame did not significantly differ between A and B, t(132) = 0.19, p = .998.</p><p>For punishment judgments, shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref> and <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 2</ref>, participants again mitigated judgments for A when A had low intent. Participants judged A to be less deserving of punishment than B when A had Low Intent, t(132) = 6.16, p &lt; .001. When A had High Intent, judgments again did not significantly differ between A and B, t(132) = 0.41, p = .977.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Causal Models</head><p>Further, as an exploratory measure and partially as a manipulation check, we investigated whether participants identified and correctly represented the events as a causal chain (across all conditions). One participant's response was excluded here due to a technical error with the Loopy link provided. As seen in <ref type="table">Table ?</ref>?, the majority of participants (72%; N = 98) represented the events as a causal chain (A→B→V). Of those participants, 67% represented the events using only the causal chain, and 33% also included an arrow between A and V (A→B→V, A→V), suggesting that they considered A's actions to be a direct (and also indirect) cause of the outcome.</p><p>We conducted a two-way ANOVA to test the effect of Causal Structure, Intent, and</p><p>Role on participants' causal judgments. We found no significant interaction between the type of causal structure participants drew and how much cause they attributed to each agent, F (3, 120) = 0.90, p = .444, and no interaction effect when also taking intent into Note. Incorrect responses are those that do not constitute a causal model (e.g., no arrows).</p><p>account, F (9, 120) = 1.20, p = .303. In other words, whether they attributed causation to A does not appear to be impacted by whether they included the direct arrow from A to V.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>We again showed that the executor (B) was generally more responsible, blameworthy, and deserving of punishment than the instigator (A). We also found an interaction between Role and Intent, such that people only mitigate judgments for the instigator when he did not intend the outcome -regardless of the executor's intentions.</p><p>The executor's intent seemed to have only little to no impact on causal and moral judgments.</p><p>These results are consistent with the doctrine of novus actus interveniens in criminal law, where a voluntary intervening cause only breaks the chain of causation when it was not reasonably foreseeable to the distal agent. When A intended for V to die, then B's actions were reasonably foreseeable to him. Conversely, when A only intended for B to harm V and not kill her, then B's subsequent killing of V (regardless of whether it was intentional) could be deemed less foreseeable, making A less responsible for V's death. Put simply, this lack of intent for the outcome weakened the causal chain between A and the outcome. This is consistent with the findings of previous studies on how extending the causal chain can reduce causal judgments of an agent because their actions are perceived to be less reasonably foreseeable <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Engelmann &amp; Waldmann, 2022)</ref>. In addition, our finding that A is judged more harshly for intentional actions is consistent with the legal realist view that intentional wrongfulness lengthens the reach of legal cause for the distal agent <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Knobe &amp; Shapiro, 2021)</ref>. According to this view, moral wrongness of the action is taken into account when assessing proximate causation <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Knobe &amp; Shapiro, 2021)</ref>, and intentional wrongfulness is regarded as more morally wrong than unintentional actions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>In three studies, we explored how laypeople attribute causal responsibility in a causal chain where an agent (A) instructs an intermediate agent (B) to execute a harmful action resulting in the death of a victim (V). Study 1 showed that participants tended to judge B to be more of a cause, more blameworthy, and more deserving of severe punishment than A. Study 2 revealed that when the proximity for A and B decreases, attributions of causal responsibility and punishment reduced for both agents, highlighting the role of proximity in these attributions. Further, Study 3 showed that irrespective of B's intent, participants mitigated their judgments for A when A did not intend for the outcome to occur.</p><p>Some might argue that the person who solicits or instigates the crime is the 'mastermind' and therefore more causal or blameworthy for the victim's injury than the person who merely executes it -the executor would never have committed the crimes if not for the instigator's direction. However, our findings show that overall, participants judged the executor to be more causal, blameworthy and deserving of greater punishment than the instigator.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Why Do Participants Assign More Cause to the Proximal Agent?</head><p>According to process theories of causation (e.g., the force dynamics model; Wolff and Thorstad, 2017), causality involves an interaction between a causal 'agent' (not necessarily a sentient, agentic being) and an event. In our scenarios, both A and B could be considered a cause by this definition, as both contributed to the outcome: A enabled B's actions to occur, and B physically caused the outcome. In contrast, according to dependency theories (REFS), an event is only a cause if it made a difference to the outcome -for example if it raises the probability that the event would occur <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Davis, 1988)</ref>.</p><p>One way to evaluate this is through counterfactual simulations <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Gerstenberg et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Quillien &amp; Lucas, 2023)</ref>. When evaluating causal responsibility, people often consider alternative possibilities of how the events could have occurred. Usually, people imagine likely counterfactual worlds where some action or event had changed and evaluate whether, or how, the outcome would have occurred.</p><p>One model that considers this is the Counterfactual Simulation Model (CSM; <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Gerstenberg et al., 2021)</ref>, which makes predictions about how much each different candidate cause is viewed as having caused an outcome (or prevented it from happening) in physical settings. It assumes that people do this by simulating the outcomes of different counterfactual alternatives, and proposes that causal judgments are sensitive to four different aspects of causation: (1) whether-causation, (2) how-causation, (3) sufficient-causation, and (4) robust-causation. One limitation of this model is that it has only been tested on causes that are inanimate, physical objects, so it may not have the same predictions for intentional agents like the ones in our scenarios. However, it may still be helpful to consider these different criteria in relation to our results to infer how participants may be making causal judgments.</p><p>To assess whether something is a whether-cause, one must consider whether the outcome would have happened if the candidate cause is removed (i.e., whether the cause was necessary). In the law, this is referred to as factual or 'but-for' causation. In our scenarios, both A and B can be considered a whether-cause as removing either of them would not have led to the final outcome (the victim's death). To judge whether something is a how-cause, one must evaluate what would have happened if the candidate cause had been changed (but not removed) -how would the outcome then change? If the outcome changes when the cause does, then the cause is a how-cause. In our causal chain example, B seems to be more of a how-cause than A, because changes to B's actions -such as the exact way in which he attacked the victim -would have led to changes in the way that the victim died, whereas changes to how A ordered B's killing would have had less impact on the precise details of the killing. This is supported by our finding that participants attribute more cause to B than A.</p><p>To determine sufficient-causation for A, one must consider whether the outcome would still have occurred if B had been removed (i.e., if B is a whether-cause). In our scenario, removing A would very likely have prevented the outcome from occurring, as B</p><p>would not have the information or intention to attack V without A's instruction. However, removing B would not necessarily have prevented the outcome, as A could have hired or asked somebody else to carry out the attack, or carried it out himself. Considering this, A is more of a sufficient cause than B. This is not supported by our finding that participants are attributing more cause to B.</p><p>To determine robust-causation, one must consider whether one believes that a cause, A, would have been a whether-cause in an alternative world where other candidate causes or background conditions have been perturbed; the more certain that A would have been a whether-cause, the more robustly it brought about the outcome <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Gerstenberg et al., 2021)</ref>.</p><p>When imagining counterfactual alternatives in our vignettes, there are many things that could have been changed between A and the outcome (e.g., A might not have developed the intention to attack V; A could have asked somebody else to execute the criminal action; A could have failed to communicate to B; A could have changed his mind and retracted the request), whereas comparatively fewer events could be changed between B's physical action and the outcome (e.g., B could have failed to execute the harm). Thus, it is possible that alternative possibilities for A's actions are more readily available to our participants, leading them to attribute less causal strength to A's actions (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Kahneman, 1995)</ref>.</p><p>Overall, our findings suggest that lay causal attributions goes beyond a 'but-for' test of causation. One explanation for our findings according to the CSM is that, in the causal chain of events in our studies, participants are attributing more cause to B because they are weighing robust-causation and how-causation more heavily than whether-causation and sufficient-causation. Indeed, the model itself is agnostic about how much each aspect influences people's judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Gerstenberg et al., 2021)</ref>.</p><p>This opens up several venues for future research. One idea is to test robust-causation more explicitly, such as by manipulating and testing the counterfactual alternatives that participants are considering. Second, future research could also test whether other theories can explain why people attribute more responsibility to the proximal cause. For instance, it is also possible that they are evaluating the strength of causal relation based on how much each agent's action raises the probability of the outcome occurring <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Davis, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Spellman, 1997)</ref>. According to this line of reasoning, presumably A increases the probability of the outcome from a low baseline (perhaps above 50%), then B's involvement increases it even more. Future research could investigate the relationship between causality and probability judgments in more detail by explicitly asking participants to give these judgments as they read through the scenario.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants' Judgments are Somewhat Consistent with the Law</head><p>Overall, we show that laypeople's moral judgments are somewhat consistent with what the law presumes: (relatively) unforeseeable, more proximal causes weaken, but do not break, the chain of causation. In Study 1 we found higher causal responsibility for the proximal over the distal cause, which aligned with past research <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Lagnado &amp; Channon, 2008)</ref>. Studies 2 and 3 further illuminate this pattern: when a third, intervening cause contributes to the outcome, the responsibility of the two initial agents diminishes.</p><p>Similarly, once B's behaviour goes beyond what A intended, the causal chain between A and V is weakened by B's intervention. In both cases, proximity mitigates responsibility for the outcome. This is also generally consistent with prior work on how physical indirectness (i.e., intermediation) mitigates moral judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Cushman et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Engelmann &amp; Waldmann, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Paharia et al., 2009)</ref>. Therefore, in situations where the resulting harm is beyond what was intended by the instigator, people might intuitively be more lenient.</p><p>In the criminal law, those who solicit a crime are not punished more than those who carry it out. This might be because executors must voluntarily choose to adopt and go along with the instigator's plan for the victim to be injured. While a plan might be condemnable, it remains just a plan -existing only in one's thoughts -until the instigator makes a substantial step in furtherance of it (e.g., directing the executor), or the executor picks up the reins and implements the plan. This is why the law treats the solicitation or planning phase as distinct from the attempt or completed crime (i.e., to encourage lighter sentencing if someone abandons the criminal plan before executing it). From our studies, we see that the executor's role as last-in-time actor, who is more directly and proximally connected to the harm, renders them more causal, blameworthy and deserving of severe punishment. According to our participants, the ultimate harm is also more foreseeable from their perspective. The outcome is less foreseeable from the solicitor's perspective, as it is entirely possible that the executor might not go ahead with the plan for a multitude of reasons (e.g., they might change their mind, lose their nerve, or get interrupted). In this sense, our studies of lay attitudes track the criminal law doctrine that finds greater causation and responsibility for more foreseeable harms.</p><p>However, when we introduced a novel, additional intervening act taken by the victim, this attenuated the directness of B's actions (the Low Proximity condition) and put A and B on more equal footing as it relates to the foreseeability of the ultimate harm. But despite there being no significant differences in foreseeability judgments between A and B in this Low Proximity condition, B was still considered more of a cause, more blameworthy, and more deserving of severe punishment than A. How could this be? This likely has to do with the ability to toggle from foreseeability to different bases for responsibility when foreseeability is absent.</p><p>Foreseeability judgments are often correlated with judgments of blame and punishment. However, in cases such as our Low Proximity vignettes -or the example where drugs are given to someone who unexpectedly overdoses -foreseeability judgments may be decoupled from assessments of causation and blame. This is where the many other subordinate tests for intervening cause may come in -such as the voluntariness of defendant's actions or the closeness of the connection between the defendant's conduct and victim's injury. But what is driving the intuition to find the executor to be more of a cause?</p><p>While we cannot be sure, it could be that where the executor's conduct is particularly morally reprehensible, participants might be able to look past their judgment that the harm is not foreseeable. Instead, they can pivot to relying on how the executor's behavior was voluntary and a more direct, temporally close, and substantial factor in bringing about the injury. That is, higher foreseeability is sufficient but not necessary to increase assessments of causation and blame.</p><p>Finally, while the analysis of intervening causes under legal causation should be distinct from the analysis of 'but-for' factual causation, participants might be blurring the two concepts together. When analysing legal causation, they might be considering the fact that the executor had the last opportunity to adopt the counterfactual and prevent the victim's harm. Future research could seek to better understand the reasons for our results and to test them in different kinds of cases where at least a few of the people who caused the harm are not brought before the court (and thus participants cannot engage as much in zero-sum thinking about causal roles). Further research can also investigate responsibility attribution in scenarios with more complex causal structures and with other types of actions (e.g., negligence from omissions). In addition, conducting a qualitative study asking participants their reasoning process (e.g., a thought-listing task) could be valuable for identifying common themes people consider when making moral judgments.</p><p>Nonetheless, by bridging the gap between psychological theories of causation and real-world applications, our findings provide important insights into folk attribution of causal responsibility in cases involving multiple agents who contribute in different ways.</p><p>These results also reveal why judges in these complex cases might be toggling between different tests for when intervening causes should be superseding. We hope that our research can contribute to broader debates about moral responsibility and justice. F (1, 84) = 3.65, p = .059. We also did not find a significant effect of Proximity on judgments of blame, F (1, 84) = 1.80, p = .183, nor punishment, F (1, 84) = 2.59, p = .112.</p><p>Visual inspection of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure B1</ref> shows very similar judgments for the two agents in the Low Proximity condition. This partially explains why we did not observe a main effect of Role on judgments of cause, F (1, 84) = 0.94, p = .336, blame, F (1, 84) = 0.01, p = .939, punishment, F (1, 84) = 1.41, p = 239, and foreseeability, F (1, 84) = 0.24, p = .624.</p><p>For Vignette 2, participants judged B to be more of a cause, F (1, 82) = 34.87, p &lt; .001, more blameworthy, F (1, 82) = 24.45, p &lt; .001, and more deserving of severe punishment, F (1, 82) = 18.82, p &lt; .001, and more able to foresee the final outcome than A F (1, 82) = 17.46, p &lt; .001. We observed a significant main effect of Proximity on punishment, F (1, 82) = 5.35, p = .023, and foreseeability, F (1, 82) = 10.03, p = .002, but not on cause, F (1, 82) = 0.21, p = .650, or blame, F (1, 82) = 0.14, p = .709. We found a significant main effect of Role on cause,  <ref type="figure">Figure B3</ref> showed that participants tended to judge B more harshly than A in both High and Low Proximity conditions in Vignette 3, and this difference was similar across the two conditions. As such, we did not find significant a main effect of Proximity in this vignette for all judgment measures (cause:</p><p>F (1, 84) = 1.83, p = .180; blame: F (1, 84) = 0.74, p = .391; punishment:</p><p>F (1, 84) = 0.25, p = .615; foreseeability: F (1, 84) = 0.56, p = .455). We did find a </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Illustration of Causal Relationships BetweenA, B, and V. The left model (i) is a common-effect model (i.e., a collider), where A and B jointly and independently contribute to the outcome of V's death. The right model (ii) is a causal chain model, where A causes an intermediate event B contributing to the outcome of V's death.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Proportions of Cause, Blame, and Punishment Ratings Distributed to Each Agent in Study 1. Jitters show individual participant responses. Error bars indicate 95% CI.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3visualizes mean judgment scores and how each participant allocated judgments between the two agents. Participants judged B (M = 89.9, 95% CI[86.5, 93.4]) to be more of a cause than A (M = 75.0, 95% CI [69.1, 80.9]), t(89) = 5.35, p &lt; .001, d = 0.56. They also judged B (M = 91.0, 95% CI [87.8, 94.2]) to be more blameworthy than A (M = 83.4, 95% CI [78.4, 88.5]), t(89) = 3.79, p &lt; .001, d = 0.40. Further, they judged B (M = 87.7, 95% CI [83.5, 91.9]) to deserve more severe punishment than A (M = 79.9, 95% CI [75.0, 84.8]), t(89) = 3.99, p &lt; .001, d = 0.42.Free response judgments of cause, blame, and punishment ratings distributed to each agent in Study 1. Means and 95% CIs are indicated in black. Jitters show individual participant responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, and Punishment Ratings Distributed to Each Agent in Study 2. Means and 95% CIs are indicated in black. Jitters show individual participant responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Moral and Causal Judgments for Each Agent at Different Levels of Intent in Study 3.Means and 95% CIs are indicated in black. Jitters show individual participant responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Participants then gave their responses to the questions 'To what extent was each defendant the cause / blameworthy / deserving of punishment for the victim's death?'</figDesc><table /><note>Smith and Ben Parker are on trial for the death of Veronica Brown. In the trial, it was stated that Ben caused severe injuries to Veronica in her home on Thursday 10 November 2022. According to the forensic report, Veronica died soon from the injuries, and her body was found in the early hours of the following day. Evidence showed that Adam used an online platform to initiate contact with Ben prior to the victim's death. On Monday 7 November (three days before the victim's death), the pair had met in person. During their conversation, Adam provided specific instructions for the attack, and told Ben to cover it up so it would look like an accident. At the trial, Ben admitted to attacking Veronica, but stated that he would not have done so if Adam had not instructed him to. Adam insisted that despite his involvement, the killing was ultimately executed by Ben and that Ben's actions were the main cause of Veronica's death.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>A. Participants judged B (M = 58.4, 95% CI [55.6, 61.1]) to be more of a cause than A (M = 41.6, 95% CI [38.9, 44.4]), t(89) = 5.88, p &lt; .001, d = 0.62. They also judged B</figDesc><table><row><cell>(M = 54.2, 95% CI [52.2, 56.1]) to be more blameworthy than A (M = 45.9, 95% CI</cell></row><row><cell>[43.9, 47.8]), t(89) = 4.09, p &lt; .001, d = 0.43. Further, they judged B (M = 54.4, 95% CI</cell></row><row><cell>[52.5, 56.3]) to deserve more severe punishment than A (M = 45.6, 95% CI [43.7, 47.5]),</cell></row><row><cell>t(89) = 4.67, p &lt; .001, d = 0.49.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Within each Proximity condition, we found the same pattern of results for cause, blame, and punishment judgments as in Study 1.Table 1shows the mean judgments for and more deserving of severe punishment, t(250) = 7.11, p &lt; .001. In the Low Proximity condition, participants also judged B to be more of a cause than A, t(250) = 6.23, p &lt; .001, more blameworthy, t(250) = 5.05, p &lt; .001, and more deserving of severe punishment,</figDesc><table><row><cell>t(250) = 6.33, p &lt; .001.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Figure 4 visualizes the interaction between Proximity and Role, but this was not</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">significant for all judgments except foreseeability, F (1, 250) = 11.21, p &lt; .001 (cause:</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">F (1, 250) = 2.71, p = .101; blame: F (1, 250) = 2.37, p = .125; punishment:</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Participants judged B High Proximity Low Proximity</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">(M = 89.8, 95% CI [88.0, 91.7]) to be more of a cause than A (M = 74.6, 95% CI [71.4, Cause A 75.8 [71.3, 80.3] 73.3 [68.8, 77.9]</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">77.8]), F (1, 250) = 110.81, p &lt; .001. They also judged B (M = 92.2, 95% CI [90.3, 94.1]) to B 93.5 [90.9, 96.1] 86.2 [83.6, 88.8]</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">be more blameworthy than A (M = 81.4, 95% CI [78.5, 84.3]), F (1, 250) = 76.21, p &lt; .001, Blame A 81.7 [77.7, 85.8] 81.1 [77.0, 85.2]</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">and judged B (M = 88.6, 95% CI [86.7, 90.6]) to be more deserving of severe punishment B 94.4 [91.8, 97.1] 90.0 [87.3, 92.7]</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">than A (M = 76.8, 95% CI [74.0, 79.5]), F (1, 250) = 90.25, p &lt; .001. They also judged that</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">the final outcome was more foreseeable for B (M = 66.7, 95% CI [63.1, 70.3]) than for A Punishment A 78.9 [75.0, 82.8] 74.7 [70.7, 78.6]</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">(M = 59.2, 95% CI [55.5, 62.9]), F (1, 250) = 43.27, p &lt; .001. B 91.3 [88.6, 94.0] 85.9 [83.2, 88.7]</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Foreseeability A 64.2 [59.0, 69.3]</cell><cell>54.3 [49.0, 59.5]</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell>75.5 [70.5, 80.6]</cell><cell>58.0 [52.8, 63.1]</cell></row></table><note>each agent. In the High Proximity condition, participants judged B to be more of a cause than A, t(250) = 8.67, p &lt; .001, more blameworthy, t(250) = 7.32, p &lt; .001,F (1, 250) = 0.23, p = .634). In the Low Proximity condition, we found no significant difference in foreseeability judgments between A and B, t(250) = 2.27, p = .109; however, in the High Proximity condition, participants judged the outcome to be more foreseeable to B, t(250) = 7.07, p &lt; .001. Table 1 Mean Scores and 95% Confidence Intervals for Cause, Blame, and Punishment by Role and Proximity Condition in Study 2Figures B1, B2, and B3 in Section B of the Appendix visualizes participants' judgments for each individual vignette. As shown in the figure, we see a similar pattern of</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Means and 95% CIs for cause, blame, and punishment judgments across Role and levels of A's Intent in Study 3</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Agent High Intent (A) Low Intent (A)</cell></row><row><cell>Cause</cell><cell>A</cell><cell>88.9 [83.8, 94.0]</cell><cell>80.3 [75.1, 85.5]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>B</cell><cell>91.8 [88.7, 95.0]</cell><cell>95.4 [92.1, 98.7]</cell></row><row><cell>Blame</cell><cell>A</cell><cell>91.9 [87.6, 96.1]</cell><cell>85.2 [80.8, 89.6]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>B</cell><cell>92.3 [89.0, 95.5]</cell><cell>94.0 [90.7, 97.4]</cell></row><row><cell>Punishment</cell><cell>A</cell><cell>90.3 [86.0, 94.6]</cell><cell>81.8 [77.4, 86.2]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>B</cell><cell>89.5 [86.2, 92.8]</cell><cell>94.4 [91.0, 97.8]</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 3 Most Participants Depict the Scenario as a Causal Chain Type of Causal Structure Frequency</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>A→B→V</cell><cell>66 (49%)</cell></row><row><cell>A→B→V, A→V</cell><cell>32 (24%)</cell></row><row><cell>A→V←B</cell><cell>18 (13%)</cell></row><row><cell>Other or Incorrect</cell><cell>20 (15%)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Brad admitted to attacking Victoria, but stated that he would not have done so if Alex had not instructed him to. Alex insisted that despite his involvement, the attack was ultimately executed by Brad and that Brad's actions The slip knot was too tight around Vernon's neck, which restricted his oxygen intake. After a while, despite being quite weak, Vernon somehow managed to loosen the knot and escape. Vernon suffered permanent vascular injury due to the strangulation and the loss of oxygen.] Two months after the incident, Vernon was moving things around in his house.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Vignettes for Study 2 Adam Smith and Ben Parker are both on trial for their offence against Veronica 'Killing' Brown. also included the following sentence: The defense argued that Veronica's actions had caused the fall that led to her death.] 'Lake' Alex Smith and Brad Parker are both on trial for their offence against Victoria Brown. At the trial, were the main cause of Victoria's injuries. [The Low Proximity condition also included the following sentence: The defense argued that Victoria's actions (visiting someone in hospital) had caused the pneumonia that led to her [Low Proximity condition: When he strained to lift something heavy, he had a brain aneurysm rupture Evidence showed that Adam used an online platform to initiate contact with Evidence showed that on Monday 7 November (three days before the attack), death.] which led to a traumatic brain injury. A medical expert stated that straining Ben prior to the victim's death. On Monday 7 November (three days before the attack), Adam and Ben had met in person. During their conversation, Adam Alex told his friend Brad to take Victoria out to a lake and gave Brad specific would not usually cause an aneurysm in a young and healthy adult, and that it 'Trespasser' instructions on how to 'rough Victoria up' to 'teach her a lesson.' very likely occurred in part due to the previous vascular injury. provided specific instructions for attacking Veronica, and told Ben to cover it up Alan Smith and Bill Parker are both on trial for their offence against Vernon On the day of the incident, Brad called Victoria and pretended he wanted to At the trial, Bill admitted to capturing Vernon, but stated that he would not so it would look like an accident. Brown. take her out on a date, to go for a boat ride around the local lake. Once the sun have done so if Alan had not instructed him to. Alan insisted that despite his On Thursday 10 November 2022, Ben attacked Veronica in her home which started to set, Brad beat Victoria with an oar, and then swam to the shore, Alan owned a coffee plantation. Evidence showed that on 7 November 2022 involvement, the act was ultimately executed by Bill and that Bill's actions were caused severe injuries. leaving Victoria in the boat as the sun went down. She lay there for several (three days prior to the incident), Alan told his friend and neighbour, Bill, that the main cause of Vernon's brain injury.</cell></row><row><cell>[High Proximity condition: According to the forensic report, Veronica died hours, unconscious. he would not be around for the next few days, and that if Bill sees any</cell></row><row><cell>[The Low Proximity condition also included the following sentence: soon from the injuries, and her body was found in the early hours of the suspicious individuals loitering near the property, he should catch them and [High Proximity condition: According to the forensic report, Victoria soon The defense argued that Vernon's actions (moving the box) had caused the following day.] teach them a lesson. Alan gave Bill specific instructions on how to tie up the bled to death from the injuries.] aneurysm that led to his brain injury.]</cell></row><row><cell>[Low Proximity condition: Reports showed that soon after Veronica was [Low Proximity condition: When Victoria came to, she started to swim suspected trespassers and where he could lock them up until Alan returned.</cell></row><row><cell>attacked, she was found by a neighbour and sent to the hospital. Veronica back to the shore. Due to her injuries, Victoria struggled while swimming and On the evening of 10 November, a man (later identified as Vernon) was walking</cell></row><row><cell>survived her injuries but the sciatic nerve in her leg was permanently damaged. inhaled water in her lungs. This caused her lungs to become inflamed, and near the property and stopped outside the gate. He stood still for a moment and</cell></row><row><cell>Two months after the incident, Veronica was walking to work on her usual infected. She later recovered from the inflammation, but her lungs became looked around. Bill saw Vernon, and captured him and tied him up. He placed a</cell></row><row><cell>route. When she reached the top of a long flight of stairs, her leg buckled and permanently weakened.] loose bag over Vernon's head so he did not know where he was, and put him in</cell></row><row><cell>she fell down the stairs. Veronica died from the fall. A medical expert stated Two months after the incident, Victoria was visiting a sick family member in Alan's barn. Bill had tied a kind of slip knot around Vernon's neck to keep the</cell></row><row><cell>that Veronica's damaged sciatic nerve very likely induced her fall.] hospital. During her visit, she caught bacterial pneumonia. She subsequently bag on his head and stop him from escaping.</cell></row><row><cell>At the trial, Ben admitted to attacking Veronica, but stated that he would not died of the disease. A medical expert stated that pneumonia would not usually [High Proximity condition: The slip knot was too tight around Vernon's</cell></row><row><cell>have done so if Adam had not instructed him to. Adam insisted that despite his cause any serious trouble for a young and healthy adult, and that Victoria very neck. According to the forensic report, this had quickly restricted oxygen to</cell></row><row><cell>involvement, the attack was ultimately executed by Ben and that Ben's actions likely was susceptible to developing severe pneumonia and subsequently dying of Vernon's brain. He ended up with a traumatic brain injury due to this loss of</cell></row><row><cell>were the main cause of Veronica's injury. [The Low Proximity condition it because her lungs were weak from the previous lung inflammation. oxygen.]</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>F (1, 82) = 34.87, p &lt; .001, blame, F (1, 82) = 24.45, p &lt; .001, punishment, F (1, 82) = 18.82, p &lt; .001, and foreseeability, F (1, 82) = 17.46, p &lt; .001. For Vignette 3, participants again judged B to be more of a cause, F (1, 84) = 81.54, p &lt; .001), more blameworthy, F (1, 84) = 59.76, p &lt; .001, more deserving of punishment, F (1, 84) = 72.75, p &lt; .001, and more able to foresee the outcome than A, F (1, 84) = 42.19, p &lt; .001. Visual inspection of</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>significant main effect of Role on cause, F (1, 84) = 81.54, p &lt; .001, blame, F (1, 84) = 59.76, p &lt; .001, punishment, F (1, 84) = 72.75, p &lt; .001, and foreseeability, F (1, 84) = 42.19, p &lt; .001. During the trial, it was stated that Ben attacked Veronica in her home on Thursday 10 November 2022. According to the forensic report, Veronica died soon from the injuries, and her body was found in the early hours of the next day. Ben denied allegations of murder but admitted that he only intended to physically harm Veronica. Ben stated that he would not have done any of this if Adam had not told him to attack the victim. During Adam's hearing, he admitted to having instructed Ben to harm Veronica. Details of why Adam wanted to harm the victim were omitted but he insisted that he did not intend for her to die. Adam insisted that despite his involvement, the killing was ultimately executed by Ben, meaning that Ben's actions were the main cause of Veronica's death. Adam Jones, aged 56, and Ben Parker, aged 42, are on trial for the death of Veronica Brown, aged 50, on 24 November 2022. The two defendants are charged with murder. During the trial, it was stated that Ben attacked Veronica in her home on Thursday 10 November 2022. According to the forensic report, Veronica died soon from the injuries, and her body was found in the early hours of the next day. Evidence showed that Adam used an online platform to initiate contact with Ben. On Monday 7 November (3 days before the victim's death), the pair had met in person and Adam instructed Ben to kill Veronica. During their conversation, Adam provided specific instructions for the attack, and told Ben to cover it up so that it would look like an accident. On the witness stand, Ben denied allegations of murder but admitted that he only intended to physically harm Veronica. Ben stated that he would not have done any of this if Adam had not told him to attack the victim. During Adam's hearing, he admitted to having instructed Ben to kill Veronica. Details of why Adam wanted to kill Veronica were omitted. Adam insisted that despite his involvement, the killing was ultimately executed by Ben, meaning that Ben's actions were the main cause of Veronica's death. Adam Jones, aged 56, and Ben Parker, aged 42, are on trial for the death of Veronica Brown, aged 50, on 24 November 2022. The two defendants are charged with murder. During the trial, it was stated that Ben attacked Veronica in her home on Thursday 10 November 2022. According to the forensic report, Veronica died soon from the injuries, and her body was found in the early hours of the next day. Evidence showed that Adam used an online platform to initiate contact with Ben. On Monday 7 November (3 days before the victim's death), the pair had met in person and Adam instructed Ben to physically injure Veronica by 'roughing her up a little bit' without killing her. During their conversation, Adam provided specific instructions for the attack, and told Ben to cover it up so that it would look like an accident. On the witness stand, Ben confessed to killing Veronica with intention not in accordance with Adam's instructions. Ben stated that he would not have done any of this if Adam had not told him to attack the victim. During Adam's hearing, he admitted to having instructed Ben to harm Veronica. Details of why Adam wanted to harm the victim were omitted but he insisted that he did not intend for her to die. Adam insisted that despite his involvement, the killing was ultimately executed by Ben, meaning that Ben's actions were the main cause of Veronica's death.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Evidence showed that Adam used an online platform to initiate contact with</cell></row><row><cell>Ben. On Monday 7 November (3 days before the victim's death), the pair had</cell></row><row><cell>met in person and Adam instructed Ben to physically injure Veronica by</cell></row><row><cell>'roughing her up a little bit' without killing her. During their conversation,</cell></row><row><cell>Adam provided specific instructions for the attack, and told Ben to cover it up</cell></row><row><cell>so that it would look like an accident.</cell></row><row><cell>On the witness stand, Condition 3: A intended to kill V but B did not</cell></row></table><note>Condition 4: A did not intend to kill but B intended to kill V</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">'The fact that the patient took the substances defendant prescribed in a greater dosage than prescribed was neither an intervening, independent agency nor unforeseeable'(People v. Stan XuHui Li, 2019).</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Culpable control and the psychology of blame</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Alicke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">126</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="556" to="574" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causal conceptions in social explanation and moral evaluation: A historical tour</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Alicke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gerstenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="790" to="812" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691615601888</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691615601888" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intentional harms are worse, even when they&apos;re not</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ames</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797613480507</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797613480507" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1755" to="1762" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Blum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">American jurisprudence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>second edition, update on negligence</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomson</forename><surname>Reuters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causal chains: Attribution of responsibility as a function of immediate and prior causes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Brickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Wortman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1060</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How inferred motives shape moral judgements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bigman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s44159-022-00071-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s44159-022-00071-x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defendant character influences mock juror judgments of blame, guilt, and punishment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="page">45</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attribution of responsibility between agents in a causal chain of events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Qiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
			<biblScope unit="page">46</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral character evaluation: Testing another&apos;s moral-cognitive machinery</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Critcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Helzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tannenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103906</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103906" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of conscious reasoning and intuition in moral judgment: Testing three principles of harm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1082" to="1089" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic theories of causation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Probability and causality: Essays in honor of wesley c. salmon</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="160" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A solution to the mysteries of morality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Descioli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kurzban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">477</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Who caused it? different effects of statistical and prescriptive abnormality on causal selection in chains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kirfel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>K. Tobia</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The cambridge handbook of experimental jurisprudence</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How causal structure, causal strength, and foreseeability affect moral judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Engelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Waldmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">226</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105167</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intervening causation and the mitigation of responsibility for harm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Fincham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Shultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="120" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking causation in english criminal law</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Firkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Criminal Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking causation in english criminal law</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Firkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Criminal Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A counterfactual simulation model of causal judgments for physical events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gerstenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">936</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spreading the blame: The allocation of responsibility amongst multiple agents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gerstenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="166" to="171" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causation and the silly norm effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Güver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kneer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Experimental Philosophy of Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="168" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Causation in the law</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L A</forename><surname>Hart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Honoré</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<publisher>OUP</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Selecting explanations from causal chains: Do statistical principles explain preferences for voluntary causes?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcclure</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="400" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Varieties of counterfactual thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">What might have been: The social psychology of counterfactual thinking</title>
		<editor>N. J. Roese &amp; J. M. Olson</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="375" to="396" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Responsibility and the &apos;pie fallacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kaiserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deutsche Bank AG, 911 F.3d</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kemper V</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">383</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">393</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Proximate cause explained: An essay in experimental jurisprudence. The University of Chicago Law Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Knobe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="236" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The importance of epistemic intentions in ascription of responsibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kovacevic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bonalumi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Heintz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1183</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causation in legal and moral reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gerstenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Oxford handbook of causal reasoning</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="565" to="602" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgments of cause and blame: The effects of intentionality and foreseeability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Channon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="754" to="770" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2008.06.009</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2008.06.009" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Emmeans: Estimated marginal means, aka least-squares means</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lenth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=emmeans" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 1.8.1-1</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of blame</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Malle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Guglielmo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Monroe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/1047840X.2014.877340</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/1047840X.2014.877340" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="186" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jurors use mental state information to assess breach in negligence cases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Margoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">236</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105442</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgments of voluntary and physical causes in causal chains: Probabilistic and social functionalist criteria for attributions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcclure</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="879" to="901" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bad acts, blameworthy agents and intentional actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nadelhoffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Knobe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Experimental philosophy</title>
		<editor>S. N. Joshua Knobe</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="67" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dirty work, clean hands: The moral psychology of indirect agency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Paharia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kassam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bazerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="141" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">People</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cal. Rptr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1314</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">286</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Cal. App.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">People</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Cervantes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cal. Rptr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">860</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">111</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Cal. 4th. 2d 148, 29 P.3d 225</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manipulating morality: Third-party intentions alter moral judgments by changing causal reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Phillips</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1320" to="1347" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counterfactuals and the logic of causal selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Quillien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lucas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">131</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1208" to="1234" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Rook</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">2 All ER 955</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Halliday</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">61 Law T.R</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">701</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">702</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1889" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Republic of Hawaii v. Oishi, 9 Haw</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1895" />
			<biblScope unit="page">641</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The good, the bad, and the timely: How temporal order and moral judgment influence causal selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Reuter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kirfel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Van Riel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Barlassina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1336</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The attribution of blame: Causality, responsibility, and blameworthiness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Shaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Afex: Analysis of factorial experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Singmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bolker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Westfall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Aust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ben-Shachar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 1.1-1</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causal models: The representational infrastructure for moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sloman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fernbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ewing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology of Learning and Motivation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crediting causality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Spellman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">126</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="348" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gypsum</forename><surname>Stapley V</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mines</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1953" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="663" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Conn. App</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">467</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">477</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">State v. Wassil, 233 Conn</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">174</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="191" to="192" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causal models mediate moral inferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Waldmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Moral Inferences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="55" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Force dynamics. The Oxford Handbook of Causal Reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Wolff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thorstad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="168" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">When mental states matter, when they don&apos;t, and what that means for morality. Social and Personality Psychology Compass</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tsoi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/spc3.12044</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/spc3.12044" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="604" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When ignorance is no excuse: Different roles for intent across moral domains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Saxe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="202" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2011.04.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2011.04.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
