<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Parenting Behavior as the Result of a Decision-Making Process</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>BS</roleName><forename type="first">Isabel</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aks</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychiatry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>San Diego</addrLine>
									<postCode>92093</postCode>
									<settlement>La Jolla</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>PhD</roleName><forename type="first">Herry</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychiatry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>San Diego</addrLine>
									<postCode>92093</postCode>
									<settlement>La Jolla</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>PhD</roleName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Pelham</surname><genName>III</genName></persName>
							<email>&lt;wpelham@ucsd.edu&gt;</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychiatry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>San Diego</addrLine>
									<postCode>92093</postCode>
									<settlement>La Jolla</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychiatry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>San Diego, 9500 Gilman Dr., La Jolla</addrLine>
									<postCode>92093</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Parenting Behavior as the Result of a Decision-Making Process</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper proposes a new paradigm for studying parenting behavior. We argue that parenting behavior can fruitfully be conceptualized as the result of a decision-making process. When faced with a decision point, parents appraise choices in light of decision factors and decide which parenting behavior to perform. This &quot;parenting-as-decision-making&quot; (PaDM) paradigm is historically absent and forges an untapped connection between the science of parenting and the cognitive science of decision-making, pointing to new ideas, evidence, and methods of use for studying parenting.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Existing Paradigms for Studying Parenting Behavior</head><p>How should parenting behavior be conceptualized? Why do parents perform the behaviors they do? These are questions of paradigm. The answers guide what scientists focus upon, how they design their studies, and how they interpret and organize their findings.</p><p>There are many paradigms for studying parenting behavior. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> lists some of the major paradigms in use today, their historical origins, and how they conceptualize parenting behavior. For example, attachment theorists conceptualize parenting as the result of the parent's own attachment history. Learning theorists conceptualize parenting as the result of operant conditioning. Family systems theorists conceptualize parenting as resulting from the structure of intrafamily relationships. Ecological systems theorists conceptualize parenting as the result of bidirectional transactions between the parent and different levels of their environment. Each paradigm tends to focus on different research questions, use different methods, and achieve different findings, and together they enlighten our broader understanding of parenting.</p><p>The paradigm most relevant to this paper is the cognitions paradigm, which conceptualizes parenting behavior as the result of cognitions. The cognitions paradigm emerged later than the aforementioned paradigms, in the 1980s, with <ref type="bibr">Sigel's 1985</ref> book Parental Belief Systems often cited as the first major treatment. The timing is a bit surprising. The Cognitive Revolution in psychology unfolded 30 years earlier, in the 1950s. Yet cognitive approaches to parenting took awhile to penetrate, perhaps because the already-existing paradigms (e.g., learning, attachment, ecological systems) had been so successful.</p><p>Interest in cognitive approaches to parenting intensified across the 1980s and 1990s. By 2000, the cognitions paradigm had yielded sufficient literature to merit a review of "parenting cognitions" in the Annual Review of Psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bugental &amp; Johnston, 2000)</ref>. However, the term "parental cognitions" is revealing. As the field took shape, it did not come to develop complete models of the cognitive activity of parents -of the thinking process. Rather, it became organized primarily around the study of different types of cognitions -attitudes, attributions, beliefs, values, perceptions, and expectations, for example -and how each cognition relates to parenting behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Holden &amp; Smith, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Johnston et al., 2018)</ref>. A typical study might, for example, investigate how parental attitudes about discipline predicted the use of spanking, or parental expectations of the child's cognitive capability drive the level of demand parents place PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING on the child. While some researchers attempted to synthesize multiple cognition types into broader social-information processing models (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Azar, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Milner, 1993)</ref>, these integrative efforts were not widely adopted.</p><p>Today, the cognitions paradigm for studying parenting has converged on a standard model shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, Panel A. Parent cognitions cause parenting behavior, then parenting behavior causes youth outcomes. Adaptive cognitions lead to better parent behavior, benefiting youth, or maladaptive cognitions lead to worse parent behavior, harming youth. There are many published examples of this standard model (e.g. <ref type="bibr">Bornstein et al 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, Bornstein et al 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, Bailes &amp; Leerkes 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">, Darling &amp; Steinberg 1993</ref>.</p><p>However, the standard model remains an incomplete account of parenting behavior, faltering upon three puzzles. First, how do parental cognitions become parenting behavior? The standard model does not articulate how mental events in a parent's mind become behavior performed in the external world. For example, suppose a parent has a value of supporting their teen's autonomy. How does that value -a mental object -actually translate into the parent performing an autonomy-supportive parenting behavior?</p><p>Second, how are multiple parental cognitions integrated? Parents have many cognitions and they are often in conflict, but the standard paradigm does not articulate how these conflicts are resolved. For example, suppose a parent has a value supporting youth autonomy and also has an attitude toward cannabis use that is negative. When the parent finds out their 15-year-old smoked cannabis, how will a parent reconcile their value and their attitude?</p><p>Third, what explains intraindividual variation in parenting behavior? Parents change their parenting behavior frequently. When a parent's 6-year old disobeys a command at 7:00pm and then again at 7:10pm, the parent's response to these two behaviors may well be different. The standard paradigm has difficulty explaining this phenomenon because cognitions like attitudes, values, or beliefs are unlikely to have changed over the course of 15 minutes. This paper argues that introducing a decision-making process to the standard model, as depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, Panel B, resolves all three puzzles and yields several potential payoffs. The payoffs result mainly from the fact that there is a mature cognitive science of decision-making that remains almost entirely disconnected from the science of parenting, and making this connection points to new ideas, evidence, methods of use for studying parenting behavior.</p><p>We call the result the "parenting-as-decision-making" (PaDM) paradigm. Like the cognitions paradigm, it is a cognitive approach to studying parenting. Unlike the cognitions paradigm, it centers a decision-making process and is focused on proximal determinants of individual instances of parenting behavior.</p><p>The PaDM generalizes and extends preceding work that has begun to explore a decision-making perspective on parenting. In psychology, the closest precursor is work on how parents make decisions about medical care for their children -for example, looking at how parents decide to give their child a treatment for Autism Spectrum Disorder (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Saez et al., 2023)</ref> or allow their child to undergo anesthesia (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Rosenblatt et al., 2022)</ref>. This work in 5 PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING psychology has focused narrowly on medical decision-making rather than conceptualized everyday parenting behaviors as decisions. Another close precursor is work in economics that has considered parents as making rational decisions about things like how many children to have, how to divide caregiving responsibilities, or whether to maximize the happiness of their children or themselves (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Becker, 1981)</ref>. This work in economics has not invoked the cognitive processes underlying the decisions, regarding a parent like a firm making business decisions rather than as a cognitive agent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">A New Paradigm: Parenting as Decision-Making (PaDM)</head><p>This section explains what it looks like to take a decision-making perspective on parenting. We take structures and ideas from the cognitive science of decision-making and show they can be used to conceptualize parenting behavior in particular. Cognitive science offers many possible models for decision-making and there are many possible parenting behaviors. This section is not meant to offer a specific model or theory to be tested, but to illustrate a general way of thinking about parenting behavior -the PaDM paradigm.</p><p>The first step in conceptualizing parenting behavior within the PaDM paradigm is to think about a single instance of behavior performed by a single parent: in other words, a decision point. Thus, rather than try to explain general patterns in parenting behavior, we try to explain why a parent performed a certain behavior at a certain moment in time.</p><p>The second step in the PaDM paradigm is to think about three basic building blocks: (1) choices, (2) decision factors, and (3) a decision-making process. Choices are potential outputs: the set of behaviors the parent could choose to perform in response to a given stimulus or in a given situation. Choices can differ in what the parent does or how the parent does it. For example, the parent might choose whether to ignore or try to redirect a toddler having a tantrum at the store (what) or the parent might choose whether to check-in with a teenager who's out with friends for the night once, hourly, or constantly (how).</p><p>Decision factors are factors the parent uses to evaluate the choices and reach a decision. The parent may consider just a few decision factors or many. Some examples of common decision factors include the expected outcomes, effort, or opportunity cost of performing a given behavior.</p><p>The decision-making process takes choices and decision factors as inputs and returns a decision of which behavior the parent will perform. The parent searches for and manipulates information about the current situation and information stored in long-term memory to appraise the choices, in light of the decision factors. The decision-making process could be systematic or heuristic, following any procedure, algorithm, or model (citation).</p><p>Let us be more concrete by giving an example. Our explanation will follow the flowchart in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, which we find useful when conceptualizing a given parenting behavior in the PaDM paradigm. Suppose that a teenager arrives home one evening after the set curfew (trigger) and the parent must decide how to respond. The parent considers some choices, such as whether to ignore it, to start a calm conversation with their teen about the importance of the curfew, or to impose a negative consequence such as grounding the teenager for the rest of the weekend. The parent identifies some decision factors to guide their choice, such as how concerned they are about what the teen does while out past curfew, the probability that the teen will repeat this behavior if it is ignored, or how much effort would be involved in executing each choice. To guide this process, the parent draws on information both from the triggering situation (e.g., the teen's apparent mood earlier in the day) and the parent's longer-term information stores (e.g., personal values about teenage alcohol use, schema of the parent-child relationship, memories of previous times they grounded the teen). The parent may think for a while and choose to initiate a calm conversation, seeing this choice as striking the best balance between competing concerns.</p><p>Of course, the choices available, the decision factors being considered, and the decision-making process being used will differ by the parent, the parenting behavior, the situation, and over time. To illustrate, <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows how we would use this paradigm to conceptualize how a parent may behave in response to three distinct situations: a toddler throwing a tantrum at a grocery store, a child getting an "A" on an exam, and a teenager coming home after curfew. While the details differ, the common structure of choices, decision factors, and a decision-making process are present in each example.</p><p>Thinking about choices, decision factors, and the decision-making process forms the main backbone of the PaDM paradigm. This basic structure can be elaborated with further elements from cognitive science to build more thorough, realistic, and useful accounts of parenting behavior. Next, we describe some especially useful elaborations: varying the depth of deliberation before reaching a decision, incorporating emotions and stress, accounting for co-parents, and considering the sequence of decisions made over time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Depth of deliberation</head><p>Parents make hundreds of decisions per day and not all decisions are equal. Depending on the situation, how much parents deliberate before reaching a decision will fall somewhere along the continuum from slow, deliberate, and systematic to quick, habitual, and heuristic.</p><p>When the situation is novel, challenging, or important, parents will be more likely to engage in goal-oriented and deliberate decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Ferreira et al., 2006)</ref>. The parent might wish to expend cognitive energy on conscious contemplation, identification, and iterative assessment of possible choices and decision factors. For example, if a child acts out in a surprising and severe way, the parent is more likely to deliberately think through an effective punishment that teaches them a lesson, enables them to grow, but also doesn't cause a rift.</p><p>When the situation is familiar, simple, or less important, parents will be more likely to engage in quick decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Ferreira et al., 2006)</ref>. Most parenting behaviors are likely decided this way, since frequent deliberative decision-making would be too time-consuming. If a child walks out into the street during a red light, most parents would instinctively grab their child and pull them back onto the sidewalk with little thought. If a child is crying, a parent may hug them. To produce behaviors like saving a child from a dangerous situation or showing support, very quick and simple processing of decision factors (namely, how dangerous it is for the child to go into the street, and how the parent likes to show support, respectively) occurs, and this processing may lack thought and conscious awareness. PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING Low depth of deliberation or quick processing can rely on heuristic reasoning and produce habitual behavior. Heuristics are associative processes that are based on a very simple rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Ferreira et al., 2006)</ref>. For example, if a parent praises their youth for getting a good grade, and their youth gets a good grade again, the parent may quickly resort to praise just because that behavior was effective the last time they enacted it.</p><p>Habitual behaviors, or actions frequently and mindlessly performed under certain circumstances, aren't produced by an elaborate decision-making process. Rather, over time a mental representation of decision factors and the resulting choice become associated with a situation, which are made accessible to the decision-making process in response to situational cues <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Aarts et al., 1998)</ref>. For example, when a youth gets home from their first day of school the parent may decide to ask about their day, influenced by the desire to establish healthy bonding and communication. Soon, every time the youth comes home after school, the parent asks how their day was automatically, without thinking about why they ask each time they do.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Emotions and stress</head><p>Parenting is an emotional and stressful job. The PaDM paradigm conceptualizes emotions and stress as states that affect parents' depth of deliberation and inform decision factors and choices. Prior research on how emotion and stress influence decision-making can be applied to parenting-specific situations.</p><p>It has been shown that emotion influences the depth of processing. Research shows that being in a positive mood gives the impression of a safe environment and thus leads to more heuristic processing, whereas being in a negative mood may give the impression of a threatening environment and thus lead to more cautious systematic processing <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lerner et al., 2015)</ref>. For example, if a parent is in a good mood when their teen walks in after curfew, they may be less inclined to attend to the situation. Conversely, if this parent was in a negative mood, they may be more inclined to systematically think through a punishment.</p><p>Stress also influences the decision making process. High amounts of stress have been shown to lead to "lower level automatic" responses and less controlled cognitive processing <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Starcke &amp; Brand, 2012)</ref>. Thus, if a parent is experiencing high levels of stress, they may engage in a more heuristic and quick decision making process. For example, if a parent has a lot of work to do, needs to plan dinner, and is getting ready to go to their friend's house when their teen walks in after curfew, their stress may soak up the cognitive energy they could be expending on coming up with consequences for their teen.</p><p>Decision factors and choices can also be influenced by acute emotions and stress, which can be related to the parenting situation or unrelated. Integral emotions and parenting stress are attached to the specific decision at hand <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lerner et al., 2015)</ref>. For example, a parent may have fear associated with their younger youth staying out past curfew if an older sibling got into a car accident when staying out past curfew. Thus, if the youth stays out past curfew, fear may arise when they walk through the door. This fear may amplify the parents' perception of how dangerous it is to stay out past curfew (a decision factor), and it could bring to fruition a low sense of control thus swaying the parent away from punishing their youth (choice).</p><p>Incidental emotions and stressed parenting are unattached to the specific decision at hand, rather they are attached to a separate situation and carry over to the current decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lerner et al., 2015)</ref>. To take the previous example, the parent may have had a nice date night with their spouse, and be in a great mood when their youth walks in the door. Their happiness may lower the parents' perceived danger of the youth staying out late (decision factor), and sway the parent's attention away from possible negative consequences for their youth (choices). On the other hand, the parent could be stressed about their job, which would influence how much the parent wants to get involved (decision factor), and may cause them to be distracted and more likely to ignore the teen's behavior (choice).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Co-parents and joint decision-making</head><p>Most parenting is co-parenting. 85% of children in the U.S. live with married or cohabiting caregivers (United States Census Bureau, 2023) and caregiving teams differ in composition and relation to the child (McHale &amp; Sirotkin, 2019). There may be two or more caregivers of one youth, and caregivers could live together or not. Some families have a long distance caregiver due to involvement in the military or work commitments <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Dittman, 2018)</ref>, or the caregivers may be separated or divorced <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Halford et al., 2018)</ref>. In the PaDM paradigm, we can approach co-parenting using the concept of "joint" decision-making as described in the decision science literature <ref type="bibr">(Raiffa, 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Co-parents must reach joint decisions about some parenting behaviors. For example, if the co-parents are living together, there can only be one curfew set for the teenager. Adding another agent adds more variability to the decision making process than if there were only one caregiver involved. Joint co-parent decision processes would involve more decision factors and more choices, possibly heightened emotion, and could lead to efficient or excessive deliberation.</p><p>A major distinction for couples' joint decision making is whether the co-parents are cooperative or conflictual. When co-parenting is cooperative, adding a second agent could be an asset to the decision making process. For example, supportive parenting has been shown to enhance the parenting of a less capable or stressed out parent <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(McHale &amp; Sirotkin, 2019</ref>). If we look at this through a PaDM paradigm, it is conceivable that when faced with a tough decision, and one parent is inclined to rely on faster processing due to a distressed affective state, the other parent can slow the process down and mitigate emotions. More generally, co parenting could be useful if the parents are able to work together to converge on a final decision, align in their decision factors, and collaboratively exercise the other's choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Godwin &amp; Scanzoni, 1989)</ref>.</p><p>When co-parenting is conflictual, adding a second agent could be a liability for the decision making process. Given that each parent may have a completely different set of decision factors and choices, an imbalance of control or coerciveness by one of the parents could make it difficult to achieve consensus for a decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Godwin &amp; Scanzoni, 1989</ref>). There may be more heightened acute emotion and rift, which could either lead to longer deliberation or a rash resort. Longer deliberation could be productive, or unnecessary and result in a suboptimal decision.</p><p>Co-parents can also reach independent decisions about parenting behaviors, either by choice or necessity. For example, if a child gets a good grade on a test, the parent will likely PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING respond without consulting their co-parent. Even when a parent is making a decision alone, their co-parent might be reflected in decision factors, choices, or the decision-making process. For example, the parent might consider how their co-parent would react to a potential parenting choice, wanting to avoid displeasing the co-parent. The parent might consider choices that are available only because of the existence of the co-parent, such as deferring delivering a negative consequence until the co-parent is also home and can support them. If the co-parent tends to be domineering, the subordinate parent may have a longer deliberation process before making a choice when they aren't able to consult their co-parent and make the decision jointly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">The sequence of decisions made over time</head><p>Parents face similar parenting situations over time, with each situation comprising a new decision point. Though the situation may be repeated, the parent's decision could change for three reasons.</p><p>First, an acute difference in the parent's state or the situation could affect decision factors, in turn resulting in a different decision. Suppose a parent is at the playground with their child and every few minutes, the child is straying too close to the road. Being calm at first, the parent might choose to respond with a patient warning each time the child gets too close to the road. If the child continues to get too close despite the feedback, the parent might become irritable and eventually yell at the child when it happens next.</p><p>Second, something may happen in between one situation and a similar subsequent situation that alters the parent's decision factors, choices, or decision making process. In between two decisions, the parent might acquire new information, observe a change in their child, or spend time reflecting on their parenting. For example, if a child is straying close to the road playground on Monday, and their parent has a conversation about strategies to promote safety with their co parent on Wednesday, the parent may make a different decision if their child goes close to the road on Friday given their new set of choices.</p><p>Third, a parent may observe the consequences of a decision and remember that when faced with the next decision. If the decision worked well, the parent might repeat it, or if the decision backfired, the parent might avoid it. For example, if a parent yells at their child for straying close to the road, and their child starts to cry, the next time their child goes close to the road the parent may instead take a softer tone in light of their child's previous response.</p><p>Cognitive scientists have proposed many models and theories to explain how humans learn from and make sequences of decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Horvath, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Tartaglia et al., 2017</ref>) that could be applied to parenting behavior. For example, one model is an "anchor-and-adjust" strategy. When assessing a particular situation, people typically recall information from a similar decision, "anchor" their judgment and preliminary decision in that previous situation, and then "adjust" their decision from there to suit the current situation <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Chapman &amp; Johnson, 2002)</ref>. If a parent usually stands in between the playground and the road while their older child is playing, they may "anchor" in this strategy if their youngest child asks to go to the playground, and "adjust" the amount of attention they pay to their youngest child based on what they observe from this child's behavior at the playground.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10">PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">Summary</head><p>The PaDM paradigm conceptualizes each instance of parenting behavior as the result of a decision-making process. Adopting the paradigm requires thinking about three basic building blocks: choices of possible behaviors to perform, decision factors that guide choice, and a decision-making process for appraising the choices and reaching a final decision. Extensions to account for varied depth of deliberation before deciding, emotions, co-parents, and sequential decision-making over time are all straightforward to make.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Payoffs of the PaDM Paradigm</head><p>The purpose of a paradigm is to structure scientific activity -to guide the questions we ask and how we ask them. Much progress in the science of parenting has been made without the PaDM paradigm, raising the question of why a new paradigm is needed. This section describes six potential payoffs -promising new ideas or approaches for studying parenting behavior that fall out naturally when parenting is conceptualized as the result of a decision-making process. The primary source of these new ideas is the newly forged connection between the science of parenting and another mature, rich field: the cognitive science of decision-making</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">A focus on moment-to-moment parenting</head><p>The first potential payoff of the PaDM paradigm is that it encourages thinking about and studying moment-to-moment, day-to-day variability in parenting behavior. For existing paradigms, the primary unit of analysis is typically global, stable, between-person differences in parenting behavior. They seek to explain why some parents nurture and others reject, why some parents are consistent in their discipline and others are not. They conceptualize parents as having "styles" (e.g., authoritarian vs. permissive) and study the consequences of these general patterns for long-term youth development.</p><p>In contrast, the unit of analysis in the PaDM is not a general pattern but a single instance of behavior, or decision point. Everyone recognizes that we make decisions in an acute, personalized way, and that decisions change. Thus, a decision-making orientation draws our attention to the local, variable, and proximal factors that determine day-to-day, moment-to-moment variability in parenting behavior. These factors may be quite different from those that determine long-term, between-person differences and thus could be neglected by existing paradigms.</p><p>The PaDM paradigm is especially compatible with intensive longitudinal data, which are becoming increasingly popular for the study of parenting (zheng goulter SI RCAP 2024). Ecological momentary assessment and daily diary designs can reduce recall bias, improve ecological validity, and study the short-term dynamics that capture parenting as it really happens (zheng goulter SI). These designs need a way of conceptualizing parenting behavior that can match the way they are measuring it. Global, stable patterns can't explain moment-to-moment changes. In contrast, changes in malleable decision factors are excellent candidates for explaining the moment-to-moment changes in parenting that are observed in intensive longitudinal studies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11">PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">A focus on decision factors (vs. cognition types)</head><p>The second potential payoff of the PaDM paradigm is that it draws our attention to the decision factors that guide parenting behavior. Today, the cognitive science of parenting is focused on and organized around not decision factors but cognition types. Largely independent literatures have developed that study a single cognition type, such as parental beliefs <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Sigel et al., 1992)</ref>, attitudes <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bertrand et al., 2023)</ref>, attributions <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bertrand et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Corpuz, 2019)</ref>, or appraisals <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Martin et al., 2017)</ref>, and how that cognition type relates to parenting behavior.</p><p>Focusing on decision factors has three potential advantages over focusing on cognition types. First, decision factors are the proximal determinants of parenting behavior. Beliefs, attitudes, or other cognitions in the parent's mind produce real-world behavior by first affecting a decision factor the parent considered when choosing that behavior. When two constructs have greater causal and temporal proximity, they typically have greater explanatory power for one another.</p><p>Second, a focus on decision factors encourages thinking about multiple cognition types simultaneously. A single cognition type -e.g., attributions -will rarely be sufficient to explain parenting behavior, yet cognition types are often studied in isolation. This is because it is natural to think of cognition types as independent. However, decision factors are influenced by more than one cognition type. For example, if a child gets an A, a decision factor for the parent's reaction might be how much perceived power the parent has in influencing their grades. This decision factor is supported by many cognitions -e.g. the parent's locus of control, attributions, attitudes toward school. Thus, focusing on decision factors could force the field to consider multiple cognition types simultaneously and understand how they interact to produce parenting behavior.</p><p>Third, a focus on decision factors brings the field into closer alignment with parents' moment-to-moment experience of parenting. When faced with a parenting situation, parents aren't experiencing, for example, global beliefs about adolescent autonomy. Rather, they experience decision factors -e.g. how their child will react to their behavior, or how important it is for them to enact parenting behavior given a particular situation. The field should match this reality, organizing inquiry around the way parents are making decisions in daily life rather than any particular type of cognition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">A focus on costs (versus benefits) of parenting behaviors</head><p>The third potential payoff of the PaDM paradigm is that it draws our attention to the costs of parenting behaviors, an under-researched topic. Today, the field typically conceptualizes parenting behavior it views to be suboptimal as resulting from a lack of knowledge or a lack of skills. For example, if a parent doesn't give a 4-year-old a brief time-out when they hit their sibling, it is because the parent doesn't know that consequences are important or doesn't know how to provide a good consequence.</p><p>The PaDM paradigm suggests another explanation: that the parent judges the costs of the parenting behavior as outweighing the benefits, or the cost-benefit calculus to be preferable for another chosen behavior. Parenting behaviors have many potential costs: for example, the time and effort required to perform them; the opportunity cost of how that time and effort could be used instead (e.g., to parent a sibling, to handle household tasks, to relax); the aversive experience of a child's reaction to a disliked parenting behavior (e.g., tantrum in response to an enforced bedtime); the disapproval received from others who disagree with the parent's chosen behaviors (e.g., conflict with co-parent).</p><p>However, parents' perceptions of the costs of parenting behaviors is not a significant topic of research. Cost ideas show up in pockets of the literature, such as research on parenting stress and daily hassles <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Crnic &amp; Coburn, 2019)</ref>, motivational interviewing of parents <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Dishion &amp; Kavanagh, 2003)</ref>, or efforts to increase the acceptability of parenting programs <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Chase &amp; Peacock, 2017)</ref>. However, even at the descriptive level, there is very little empirical evidence on the magnitude and type of costs parents perceive in daily, regular parenting decisions, and how those affect their decision-making. For example, we are aware of no study sampling parents' everyday choices and the perceived effort they associate with each, a natural and basic question for understanding why parents do what they do.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">A focus on uncertainty</head><p>The fourth potential payoff of the PaDM paradigm is that it draws our attention to the role of uncertainty in parenting behavior. Today, uncertainty is not a topic of explicit study in parenting science. Yet parents make choices about their parenting under tremendous uncertainty. Parents are unsure how their child or co-parent will react when they perform a given behavior. Parents are unsure who to trust among the many competing sources advising them what comprises "good" parenting (e.g., clinicians, media, other parents). Parents are unsure how their parenting choices today will affect their child's longer-term development.</p><p>Decision science can offer relevant ideas and evidence because decision-making under uncertainty has been a major and enduring interest of that field. Much empirical literature has explored how decision-making is governed by complex interactions between factors like the delay between the choice and receiving its outcome (temporal discounting), the extent to which the outcome is probabilistic (probability discounting), or whether the outcome is expected to be a benefit (i.e., "gains" vs. "losses").</p><p>These concepts are readily applied to parenting and can explain seemingly puzzling behavior. For example, consider a parent's decision about whether to perform nightly 1:1 reading with their X-year-old who is struggling to learn to read. The costs of choosing to do 1:1 reading are certain and immediate. The parent must devote the attention and effort required to do the 1:1 reading and will lose that time for other activities, such as to do a shared activity the child prefers or to relax. In contrast, the benefits of choosing to do 1:1 reading are uncertain and far into the future. The parent does not know for sure that their efforts will make a difference, and they won't know whether it is helping until several months or years have passed.</p><p>Understanding the sources of parents' uncertainty about parenting behaviors and how that uncertainty is incorporated in the decision-making process could help us understand why parents do as they do and support them in making better parenting decisions. For example, suppose that research showed that the primary source of uncertainty of the benefit of doing 1:1 reading is 13 PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING doubt that the program will help their child. Parents could then be provided psychoeducation specifically tailored to dispel this concern, reducing the extent to which the parent discounts a potential long-term benefit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">New methodologies</head><p>The fifth potential payoff of the PaDM paradigm is that it points us toward new methodologies that could be useful for studying parenting behavior. Today, the field typically studies the determinants of parenting behavior using observational designs that measure potential determinants of parenting behavior with rating scales and link them to parenting behavior in longitudinal data. These designs suffer from two major weaknesses. The first is low internal validity. Because the potential determinants of parenting behavior are not under experimental control, it is difficult to know whether they are being correctly identified or reflect an unknown confounding bias. The second weakness is that these designs are difficult to scale and iterate upon. Recruiting a sufficient sample of parents and following them for months and years is resource-intensive and time-consuming, so rapidly identifying determinants and following up on preliminary findings can quickly become infeasible.</p><p>The PaDM paradigm suggests a complementary design that addresses both weaknesses: laboratory-based experiments. Decision scientists have created and validated many experimental paradigms for studying decision-making in a laboratory setting. Participants complete a task in which they repeatedly make hypothetical or real decisions. Across trials, the experimenter manipulates various features of the task to study their impact on participants' decisions. For example, the experimenter might manipulate the information given to the participant, a time constraint, or the responses available.</p><p>These laboratory experiments are well-suited for studying parenting behavior. For example, suppose we wished to study the determinants of the curfew that parents set for their teenager. One option would be a vignette design <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Aguinis &amp; Bradley, 2014)</ref> in which parents are presented with a series of brief vignettes describing a parenting scenario -here, choosing a curfew -and asked what they would do. Across scenarios, the experimenter could manipulate factors like the age of the child, the anticipated reaction of the child, or the history of curfew-related interactions to study whether and how these factors interactively determine the parent's curfew-setting behavior. In contrast to the standard observational designs in use today, because the potential determinants were under experimental control, we could be certain that the identified factors are what truly drives parents' stated choices of parenting behavior. And because such an experiment can be performed in a single session and without child involvement, findings could be obtained and followed-up on rapidly in a series of experiments.</p><p>Decision science offers clues about how these experiments are best performed and analyzed, as well as techniques for increasing their ecological validity and prediction of real-world decision behavior (citation). For example, one might contend that many parenting decisions are made while the parent is actually emotional, so findings from a laboratory study might not generalize. To address this possibility, we could repeat our vignette study of responses to curfew violations with an emotional induction to place parents in an angry mood before they complete the task (citation to emotional inductions). This approach could better capture parents' typical affective state when performing this parenting behavior and also provide an experimental test of the role of emotions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6">New approaches to clinical intervention</head><p>The sixth potential payoff of the PaDM paradigm is that it points to new approaches to clinical intervention. Once we conceptualize parenting behavior as resulting from a decision-making process, that process becomes a natural target for cognitive intervention. The field already has many efficacious cognitive therapies and techniques, but they are used to treat depression or schizophrenia, not to improve parenting behavior.</p><p>Many presented problems in children are best treated by intervening with parents to change their parenting behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Weisz &amp; Kazdin, 2017)</ref>. For externalizing problems like defiance and aggression, clinicians typically seek to increase positive attention, praise, loving acts, and use of effective discipline strategies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">McMahon &amp; Forehand, 2005)</ref>. For internalizing problems like depression or anxiety, clinicians typically seek to reduce accommodation of avoidant behavior and support behavioral activation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Ehrenreich-May et al., 2018)</ref>. These approaches assume that the parent's behavior is suboptimal because the parent lacks knowledge or skills, which the clinician provides and coaches during intervention.</p><p>An alternative explanation is that the suboptimal parenting behavior is explained by a suboptimal decision, or cognitive error. The parent might be hyper-focused on a single decision factor, over-weighting it during the decision-making process, or making decisions too quickly, with too little exploration of alternative choices. Under this explanation, decision factors and the decision-making process become intervention targets for cognitive intervention.</p><p>Yet today, popular manuals for treating pediatric psychopathology contain little in the way of cognitive therapy for parents. Sessions are not typically devoted to helping parents notice, track, and restructure automatic thoughts, cognitive distortions, or maladaptive beliefs that may be driving suboptimal parenting behavior. Clinical techniques, modules, and worksheets to do so could be readily adapted from existing manuals for treating depression, anxiety, and other problems with a cognitive component and instead used to modify the cognitions and cognitive processes driving suboptimal parenting behavior. For example, we can imagine an augmented form of behavioral parenting training that provides the same psychoeducation, teaches the same behavioral skills, and also provides 2-3 sessions of cognitive therapy modifying the decision factors or decision-making patterns that are determined to be driving a given parent's suboptimal parenting behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Placing the PaDM within the Broader Parenting Literature</head><p>This paper has advocated for the parenting-as-decision-making (PaDM) paradigm because it is historically absent and, as outlined in Section 3, potentially useful. But our approach is pluralistic, not prescriptive-we aim to complement prior paradigms, not replace them. There are many ways to conceptualize parenting behavior <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 1)</ref>, and the most fruitful choice will always depend on the question being studied. Only with time and experimentation will it become clear when the PaDM paradigm is more or less useful, relative to other paradigms. The potential payoffs sketched in Section 3 have yet to be explored. But we can offer some preliminary thoughts in anticipation.</p><p>The value-added of the PaDM is clearest when the goal is to study parenting behavior at the point of performance, as a series of discrete behaviors occurring from moment to moment. Suppose a parent faces three identical parenting situations, all within 10 minutes of each other, and performs a different behavior in each case. These differences are clunky to explain with appeal to the parent's learning history (learning paradigm), internal working model (attachment paradigm), or stressors and support system (ecological systems paradigm). But they are easy to explain with appeal to a decision-making process. These were three different decision points, and the responses changed because a decision factor changed.</p><p>Indeed, we believe this is a more realistic account of parenting. Parents are inconsistent; they change their minds; they respond thoughtfully to immediate contextual conditions; they bargain over time; they weigh pros against cons. Parenting science has focused almost entirely on the global, stable behavioral patterns that emerge from this reality, rather than try to understand what parents are actually doing: making decisions.</p><p>We can also anticipate research questions for which the PaDM is less useful. When the goal is to explain global, stable, patterns in parenting behavior, then the marginal value of the PaDM is less obvious. For example, when studying how cultural factors determine parenting styles (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Mogro-Wilson et al., 2021)</ref> or how adverse experiences during childhood determine one's parenting practices as an adult (e.g., Lange et al., 2019), introducing a decision-making process to the conceptualization may be superfluous rather than illuminating. Questions like these are about between-parent differences at a level of analysis far removed from a single decision point or instance of parenting behavior. It may be simpler to leave decision-making out of the picture.</p><p>Another approach would be to combine the PaDM paradigm with other paradigms, rather than choose one or the other. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Belsky's (1984)</ref> popular model states that parenting behavior is multiply determined by three factors: (1) the personal psychological resources of the parent, (2) characteristics of the child, and (3) contextual sources of stress and support. Notions of decision and choice do not appear in Belsky's model, but they are a natural fit. The parent's psychological resources, the child's characteristics, and contextual stressors and supports can each be understood as constraining or expanding choices, as inputs to decision factors, or as affecting the decision process. The synthesis of multiple paradigms may prove the most effective lens for studying parenting behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>Humans make decisions about behavior, parents are humans, yet our field has not fully recognized parents as making decisions about their parenting behavior. The omission is curious and repairing it could yield advances. We believe the cognitive science of decision-making has much to offer the science of parenting and have outlined what we see as the most promising next steps. Much progress has been made in the past 75 years without a decision-making perspective on parenting, but we believe more progress can be made in the next 75 by adding it to our </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2024">-</head><p>As resulting from a decision-making process</p><p> Which choices do parents consider when choosing a parenting behavior? How do parents identify their choices?  Which factors do parents consider when making decisions about parenting behavior? Which factors are more or less important?  How do parents assess and integrate multiple decision factors to make a decision about parenting behavior?</p><p>Note. The information shown reflects our best attempt to identify the most popular paradigms and distill each into its core elements. However, we recognize that not all important paradigms are included and that there is heterogeneity in views among scientists operating within each listed paradigm. See <ref type="bibr">Holden (1997)</ref> for an overview.</p><p>a We view the parenting as decision-making (PaDM) as a successor to the parenting cognitions (PC) paradigm listed immediately above. Both the PC and PaDM paradigms conceptualize parenting behavior as resulting from the cognitive activity of the parent. However, the PaDM paradigm introduces a decision-making process as the most proximal cause of behavior and the mechanism by which diverse parenting cognitions are integrated to drive behavior <ref type="figure">(Figure 1</ref> ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>The Standard Parental Cognitions Paradigm versus the Parenting as Decision-Making (PaDM) Paradigm Note. Panel A shows the standard model in the cognitions paradigm for studying parenting <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 1)</ref>. Panel B shows the parenting-as-decision-making (PaDM) paradigm proposed in this paper, which introduces a decision-making process as the proximal determinant of parenting behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="24">PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2</head><p>Parenting Behavior as the Result of a Decision-Making Process Note. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows a structure for how a parent behavior may be produced, using the PaDM paradigm. The decision-making process is set off by a trigger, which is an external or internal event related to parenting that sets off the parent's consideration of engagement in parenting behavior. The decision making process enumerates, assesses, and consolidates decision factors and choices into a final choice. It does so by cycling though what we call the "parent's information stores," referring to all the information (e.g. cognitive, observational, reflective) a parent has about parenting or the situation at hand. After iteratively narrowing down decision factors and choices, the parent will make a final choice. They will then enact that choice, resulting in parent behavior.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Major Historical Paradigms for Conceptualizing Parenting Behavior What types of contextual factors influence parenting?  How does the situational context of the family and personal context of each member interact?  How does each level of context (i.e. microsystem, mesosystem, exosystem, macrosystem) relate to child development and parenting? What is the heritability of parenting behavior?  Which parenting behaviors are more or less heritable?  How is parenting behavior affected by the genetic inheritance passed on to their offspring? How do different types of cognitions (e.g., beliefs, attitudes, attributions) affect parenting behavior?  Which types of cognitions are more strongly linked to parenting behavior in which contexts?  How are parenting cognitions organized into schemas and how schemas in turn drive parenting behavior?</figDesc><table><row><cell>Paradigm</cell><cell cols="2">Origins Major</cell><cell>How is parenting behavior</cell><cell>Typical questions asked about parenting behavior</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>advocates</cell><cell>conceptualized?</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Ethology</cell><cell>1940s</cell><cell>Lorenz,</cell><cell>As the result of evolution</cell><cell> Why did a parenting behavior evolve?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Tinbergen</cell><cell></cell><cell> Is a parenting behavior adaptive today?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell> What are the similarities and differences between parenting</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>behaviors across species?</cell></row><row><cell>Learning</cell><cell>1950s</cell><cell>Skinner, Bijou,</cell><cell>As the result of operant</cell><cell> How are parenting behaviors learned over time?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Patterson</cell><cell>conditioning</cell><cell> What are the salient reinforcers and punishments of parenting</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>behavior?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell> How do children condition their parents' behavior?</cell></row><row><cell>Attachment</cell><cell>1950s</cell><cell>Bowlby,</cell><cell>As the result of parent's own</cell><cell> How does a parent's attachment to their own parent shape their</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Ainsworth,</cell><cell>attachment history and</cell><cell>own parenting behavior?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Main</cell><cell>internal working model</cell><cell> Which aspects of the parent's internal working model shape</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>their parenting behavior?</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Family systems 1960s</cell><cell>Bowen,</cell><cell>As resulting from the</cell><cell> What is the function of a given parenting behavior in the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Minuchin,</cell><cell>structure of intrafamily</cell><cell>family system or subsystem?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Haley</cell><cell>relationships</cell><cell> How does parenting behavior differ across subsystems?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell> How do co-parents interact to affect each other's parenting</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>behavior?</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Ecological systems  Genetics 1970s Bronfenbrenner, Belsky As resulting from reciprocal transactions between the parent and their environment at multiple levels of analysis 1980s Rowe, As resulting from the </cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Plomin</cell><cell>parent's genetic inheritance</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">PARENTING AND DECISION-MAKING toolbox. Parenting remains too important a topic to leave the full breadth of psychological science unleveraged.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Acknowledgments. We thank the labs of Laurie Chassin, PhD, Bridget Callahan, PhD, Steve Lee, PhD, and Jennifer Silvers, PhD for the opportunity to present this work and their helpful feedback.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Adolescents (3rd ed.). The Guilford Press. Think about the parent's decision-making process</p><p> Decision tree: Can we stop shopping early? If not, which strategy to calm the toddler has worked best in the past? Try that.  If the parent is easily embarrassed by public misbehavior, a decision might be dominated by public noticeability of the toddler's behavior.</p><p> Anchor-and-adjust: If the parent gave the child praise the last time they got an A, they might anchor on their previous successful action to continue this pattern of good grades.  If the parent is disappointed and expects an A+ instead, they might systematically think through a plan to motivate their child further.</p><p> If this is unprecedented behavior, the parent might be more inclined to carefully consider the child's perspective or consult a co-parent.  If the parent is currently stressed, they may want to reach a decision quickly.</p><p>Note. <ref type="table">Table shows</ref> possible ideas about choices, decision factors, and decision-making processes for three example parenting situations. The ideas are not meant to be an exhaustive list, but rather to be examples of how we might analyze a given parenting behavior from a PaDM perspective.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Behavior From Actions in the Past: Repeated Decision Making or a Matter of Habit?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Aarts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Verplanken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Van Knippenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1559-1816.1998.tb01681.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1559-1816.1998.tb01681.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1355" to="1374" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Best Practice Recommendations for Designing and Implementing Experimental Vignette Methodology Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Aguinis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bradley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1094428114547952</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1094428114547952" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Treatise on the Family</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Determinants of Parenting: A Process Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Belsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1129836</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/1129836" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="96" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maternal executive function, authoritarian attitudes, and hostile attribution bias as interacting predictors of harsh parenting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bertrand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Deater-Deckard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/fam0001065</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/fam0001065" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Family Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="397" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Link to external site</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The nature of the child&apos;s tie to his mother</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bowlby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The International Journal of Psychoanalysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="350" to="373" />
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parental and child cognitions in the context of the family</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bugental</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev.psych.51.1.315</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.51.1.315" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="315" to="344" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating the Irrelevant: Anchors in Judgments of Belief and Value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/CBO9780511808098.008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511808098.008" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Heuristics and Biases</title>
		<editor>T. Gilovich, D. Griffin, &amp; D. Kahneman</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="138" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1st ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Investigation of Factors that Influence Acceptability of Parent Training</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Chase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Peacock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10826-016-0644-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10826-016-0644-x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Child and Family Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1184" to="1195" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parental Attributions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B B</forename><surname>Corpuz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Randy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Parenting</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd ed.). Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress and parenting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Crnic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Coburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Parenting</title>
		<editor>M. H. Bornstein</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd ed.). Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intervening in Adolescent Problem Behavior: A Family-Centered Approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dishion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long-distance parenting: The impact of parental separation and absence due to work commitments on families</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dittman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Parenting and Child Development Across the Lifespan</title>
		<editor>M. R. Sanders &amp; A. Morawska</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="533" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-94598-9_22</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-94598-9_22" />
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Unified Protocols for Transdiagnostic Treatment of Emotional Disorders in Children and Adolescents: Therapist Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ehrenreich-May</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kennedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bilek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Buzzella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Barlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic and controlled components of judgment and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Ferreira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Garcia-Marques</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.91.5.797</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.91.5.797" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="797" to="813" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Link to external site, this link will open in a new tab</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Couple Consensus during Marital Joint Decision-Making: A Context, Process, Outcome Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Godwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Scanzoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marriage and Family</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="943" to="956" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Parenting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Decision-Making</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/353207</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/353207" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of the parents&apos; relationship on children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Halford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rhoades</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-94598-9_5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-94598-9_5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Parenting and Child Development Across the Lifespan</title>
		<editor>M. R. Sanders &amp; A. Morawska</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Holden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Parenting</title>
		<editor>M. H. Bornstein</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Parenting cognitions. 3rd ed.). Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Computational characterization of human sequential decision making under uncertainty: Model-free, model-based, exploitative and explorative strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Horvath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.17169/refubium-30866</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.17169/refubium-30866" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parental Cognitions: Relations to Parenting and Child Behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-94598-9_17</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-94598-9_17" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Parenting and Child Development Across the Lifespan</title>
		<editor>M. R. Sanders &amp; A. Morawska</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="414" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Valdesolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kassam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev-psych-010213-115043</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-psych-010213-115043" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="799" to="823" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mothers&apos; Implicit Appraisals of their Adolescent as Unlovable: Explanatory Factor Linking Family Conflict and Harsh Parenting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Sturge-Apple</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Romero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dev0000334</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/dev0000334" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1344" to="1355" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coparenting in diverse family systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mchale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sirotkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Parenting</title>
		<editor>M. H. Bornstein</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd ed.). Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Helping the Noncompliant Child: Family-Based Treatment for Oppositional Behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcmahon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Forehand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Patterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Coercive Family Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Negotiation Analysis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parental Decision-Making for Surgery and Anesthesia in Young Children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rosenblatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kremer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Paun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Swanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/01939459211021622</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/01939459211021622" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Western Journal of Nursing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="904" to="911" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factors Affecting Parent Treatment Decisions for Children with Autism Spectrum Disorders: A Brief Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Saez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kazemi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fields</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s40617-022-00716-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s40617-022-00716-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Analysis in Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Parental Belief Systems: The Psychological Consequences for Children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Sigel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Mcgillicuddy-Delisi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Goodnow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision making under stress: A selective review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Starcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2012.02.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2012.02.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1228" to="1248" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What to Choose Next? A Paradigm for Testing Human Sequential Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tartaglia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Herzog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00312</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00312" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">312</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Table A3. Parents With Coresident Children Under 18, by Living Arrangement, Sex, and Selected Characteristics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="page">2023</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>United States Census Bureau.. data table</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evidence-Based Psychotherapies for Children and</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Weisz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kazdin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>A. E.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
