<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffery</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pisklak</surname></persName>
							<email>pisklak@ualberta.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Alberta</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nottingham</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elliot</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcia</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Alberta</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pisklak</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Alberta</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Christopher R. Madan</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ariel</forename><surname>Greiner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Elliot A. Ludvig</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Marcia L. Spetch</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Nottingham</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Alberta</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Elliot A. Ludvig</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Marcia L. Spetch</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Nottingham</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Alberta</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nuha</forename><surname>Mahdi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Elliot A. Ludvig</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Marcia L. Spetch</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Nottingham</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Alberta</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vivian</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Elliot A. Ludvig</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Marcia L. Spetch</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Nottingham</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Alberta</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josh</forename><surname>Yong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Elliot A. Ludvig</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Marcia L. Spetch</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Nottingham</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Alberta</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>P217</roleName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pisklak</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Biological Sciences Building</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Alberta</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>T6G, 2E9</postCode>
									<settlement>Edmonton</settlement>
									<region>Alberta</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>risky choice</term>
					<term>decisions from experience</term>
					<term>comparative cognition</term>
					<term>decision making</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>When making risky decisions, people and pigeons often show similar choice patterns. When people learn the reward probabilities through repeated exposure to the outcomes, their preference is disproportionately influenced by the extreme (highest and lowest) outcomes occurring in the decision context. Overweighting of these extremes increases preference for risky alternatives that lead to the highest outcome and decreases preference for risky alternatives that lead to the lowest outcome, termed the extreme-outcome rule. This rule predicts greater risk seeking for choices between safe and risky high-value outcomes than for choices between safe and risky low-value outcomes, when both choices occur in the same context. In a series of studies, we examine how this extreme-outcome rule generalizes within and across two evolutionary distant species: pigeons (Columba livia) and humans (Homo sapiens). Both species showed risky choices consistent with the extreme-outcome rule when a low-value risky option could yield an outcome of zero. When all outcome values were increased such that none of the options could lead to zero, people but not pigeons were still consistent with the extreme-outcome rule. Unlike people, pigeons no longer avoided a low-value risky option when it yielded a non-zero food outcome. These results suggest that, despite some similarities, different mechanisms underlie risky choice in pigeons and people.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 4</head><p>In common parlance, "risky" can describe a wide array of behaviours. At its core lies the notion of multiple possibilities. For instance, if there is a possibility of severe financial loss as well as great financial gain, then making an investment might be said to be "risky". Similarly, due to the remote possibility of the parachute not opening, skydiving is considered risky. For non-human animals, risky choices may result in various desirable or undesirable outcomes, not least of which could include starvation and predation. Thus, the study of risky choice in both humans and other animals is important, although in the laboratory, the stakes are rarely as severe as they can be in nature.</p><p>The animal risk-preference literature has shown inconsistencies, with many studies showing risk aversion (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bateson &amp; Kacelnik, 1995)</ref>, but some showing risk seeking (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Barnard, Brown, Houston, &amp; McNamara, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hayden, Heilbronner, Nair &amp; Platt, 2008)</ref> or risk neutrality (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mazur, 1989)</ref>. Even within a single species, such as pigeons, behavioural effects can vary across experiments <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Lagorio &amp; Hackenberg, 2012)</ref>. Moreover, risk preferences may depend on factors such as energy budget <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Caraco, Martindale, &amp; Whittam, 1980;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Stephens, 1981)</ref>, choice framing (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Constantinople, Piet, &amp; Brody, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Lakshminarayan, Chen, &amp; Santos, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Marsh &amp; Kacelnik, 2003)</ref>, and the most recent outcomes of a choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Marshall &amp; Kirkpatrick, 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Risky choice in humans is often studied using scenarios in which the probabilities and outcomes are explicitly described to them. Recent work has suggested, however, that behaviour observed for these described choices does not readily generalize to situations where people learn about the consequences of their risky choices through experience, a discrepancy that has become known as the description-experience gap (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barron and Erev, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Camilleri &amp; Newell,</ref> RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 5 2011; <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hertwig &amp; Erev, 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">, Ludvig &amp; Spetch, 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Ungemach, Chater, &amp; Stewart, 2009)</ref>. For example, with described choices, people tend to be more risk seeking for losses than for gains, a pattern termed the reflection effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Payne, Laughhunn, &amp; Crum, 1980;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Schoemaker, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1986)</ref>. In contrast, when outcomes are learned through experience, people sometimes show a reversal of the reflection effect and are more risk seeking for gains than for losses <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Ludvig &amp; Spetch, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Madan, Ludvig, &amp; Spetch, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsetsos et al., 2012)</ref>. This learning from experience is also more similar to the manner in which non-human animals make decisions (but see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Constantinople, Piet, &amp; Brody, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Heilbronner &amp; Hayden, 2016)</ref>.</p><p>One hypothesis put forward to explain the effect seen in experience-based choices is that the most extreme values encountered in a decision's context are being overweighted (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Ludvig, Madan, &amp; Spetch, 2014a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Madan, Ludvig, &amp; Spetch, 2017)</ref>. Referred to as the extremeoutcome rule, this bias can lead to more risk seeking for gains than for losses when the two types of choices are intermixed. For instance, consider an experiment where a person is given repeated choices of intermixed gain and loss scenarios such that the gain scenario presents a choice between a 'safe' guarantee of +20 points and a 'risky' 50/50 chance of +40 or 0 points, while the loss scenario presents a choice between a safe guarantee of −20 points and a risky 50/50 chance of −40 or 0 points. In this experiment, the best possible outcome for the gain scenario (+40) and the worst possible outcome for the loss scenario (−40) are located at the extrema of all the potential outcomes. Overweighting of these extremes would thus produce more risk seeking in the gain domain (where the extreme is good) and risk aversion in the loss domain (where the extreme is bad). This proposed extreme-outcome rule has been corroborated in experiments in RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 6 which participants repeatedly chose between images of doors that led to safe and risky gains and losses of points <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Ludvig, &amp; Spetch, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Madan, Ludvig, &amp; Spetch, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Madan, Spetch, &amp; Ludvig, 2015)</ref>. Moreover, when the decision context was restricted to all gains or all losses, people showed more risk seeking for choices involving relatively better outcomes, than for choices involving relatively worse outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Ludvig et al., 2014a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Madan et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>In a previous cross-species comparison, we found evidence supporting the notion that pigeons also follow this extreme-outcome rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Ludvig, Madan, Pisklak, &amp; Spetch, 2014b)</ref>.</p><p>Pigeons were tested in a foraging analogue of a human decision-making task in which they made a choice by walking behind one of two distinct panels to obtain food rewards. There were four possible panels, with two of them presented on each choice trial. Two of the panels provided high-value outcomes of equal expected value: a "high-value risky panel" leading to 1 or 3 food rewards, with a 50/50 chance of either, and a "high-value safe panel" always leading to 2 food rewards. The two other panels provided low-value outcomes of equal expected value: a "lowvalue risky panel" leading to 0 or 2 food rewards, with a 50/50 chance of either, and a "lowvalue safe panel" always leading to 1 food reward. The pigeons' choices were compared to those of humans who participated in a computer-based task with doors that similarly led to risky and safe amounts of points exchangeable for money. The results from both species nicely conformed to the predictions of the extreme-outcome rule, showing greater risk seeking for high-value gains relative to low-value gains. That is, given a choice between risky and safe options of equal value, both pigeons and people select the risky option more often when choosing between high-value outcomes than when choosing between low-value outcomes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 7</head><p>The extreme-outcome effect has now been demonstrated numerous times in research with humans and has been shown across several different sets of outcome values (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Madan, Ludvig, &amp; Spetch, 2018</ref>, for a review). For pigeons, however, the effect has only been shown with the single set of outcome values (0 to 4) used in the study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al. (2014b)</ref>. Thus it is not clear whether the effect would generalize to other values for pigeons. One possibility is that the strong extreme-outcome effect shown by pigeons in the Ludvig et al. study was due in part, or even largely, to an avoidance of zero outcomes. Although the pigeons showed risk seeking for high-value choices and risk aversion for low-value choices, the deviation from indifference for the low-value choices was more pronounced. In the <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al. (2014b)</ref> procedure, a zero outcome represented the absence of food reward, which meant that, in conventional operant conditioning terms, selection of the low-value risky option was only intermittently reinforced whereas the low-value safe option was continuously reinforced, albeit at a smaller magnitude.</p><p>Strong control of choice behaviour by reinforcement rate is well known <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(deVilliers, 1977)</ref>, and given findings establishing higher sensitivity towards reinforcement rate than magnitude in determining choice preference <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Davison &amp; Baum, 2003)</ref>, the results of the low-value choices are perhaps unsurprising. The occasional absence of food rewards altogether also, in effect, creates a situation of intertemporal choice, where pigeons are choosing between rewards with different delays. In that frame, one might predict, based on the steep hyperbolic decay rates of pigeons <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Stevens &amp; Stephens, 2009)</ref>, that the smaller certain outcome of one food cup might be preferred to two cups which occur half as often and are therefore sometimes delayed (for example, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mazur, 1989)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 8</head><p>With humans, the possibility that such an aversion to zero outcomes is responsible for the risk preferences was ruled out by eliminating any zero outcomes and still observing the same reversal of the reflection effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Ludvig et al., 2014a)</ref>. With pigeons, however, the contribution of zero outcomes to the extreme-outcome effect has not been systematically evaluated. Indeed, a recent review has suggested that animals likely process the concept of zero differently from humans <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Nieder, 2016)</ref>. The present set of experiments were thus designed to evaluate the correspondence between pigeon and human risky choice behaviour observed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al. (2014b)</ref> and to test whether the similar patterns of behaviour were produced by the same psychological mechanism. In Experiment 1, we created a conceptual replication of their results using a novel methodology that more fully equated some of the procedural details between species. For Experiment 2, we tested risk preferences in the absence of zero values using the original methodology found in <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al. (2014b)</ref> for pigeons and the novel methodology employed in Experiment 1 for humans. Experiment 3 sought to replicate the findings of Experiments 1 and 2 by specifically manipulating the occurrence of zero using the same experimental procedure in pigeons. Lastly, Experiment 4 examined pigeons' risk preferences after an evaluation of their capacity to discriminate between various received reward values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1</head><p>The first experiment developed a new operant task for comparing risky choice across pigeons and humans (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). Both pigeons and humans selected between pairs of four coloured circles presented on a computer screen. Each colour corresponded to a risky or a safe outcome of either high-or low-value rewards. Selection of a coloured circle led to a particular number of black circles (tokens) appearing on the screen. The safe low-value choice led to one RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 9 token, the risky low-value choice provided a 50/50 chance of zero or two tokens, the safe highvalue choice led to three tokens, and the risky high-value choice provided a 50/50 chance of two or four tokens. For pigeons, a response to each token resulted in 1 second of food access. For humans, a response to each token resulted in a 1-point increase in cumulative points that were later exchanged for money. According to the extreme-outcome rule, pigeons should select the risky option significantly more often when choosing between risky and safe high-value options than between risky and safe low-value options. Avoidance of zero values should also produce a difference in risk preference, driven by strong risk aversion for the low-value choices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1a: Pigeons</head><p>Subjects. Six adult pigeons (Columba livia) -four Racing Pigeons and two Silver King -selected from a University of Alberta pigeon colony were used. The birds all had extensive learning histories but none had served in studies of risky choice. The birds were individually housed in a temperature-controlled colony room with a 12-hour light-dark cycle. Free access to grit and vitamin-enriched water was provided, and each bird was maintained at approximately 85% of its free-feeding weight by post-session rations of Mazuri Gamebird (PMI Nutrition International LLC, Brentwood, MO) food pellets. All procedures were approved by the University of Alberta Biological Sciences Animal Care and Use Committee, following the guidelines of the Canadian Council on Animal Care. All pigeons passed the exclusion criterion and were included in the resulting analyses (see Data Analysis section below).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Apparatus.</head><p>A custom-built 71.1 × 33.0 × 44.5 cm sound-attenuating operantconditioning chamber, located in an isolated room, was used. A 17-in. ViewSonic LCD monitor was mounted centrally against the chamber's widest wall, equipped with a Carrol Touch infrared RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 10 touchscreen (Elo Touch Systems Inc., Menlo Park, CA). Two feeding ports, adjacent to both sides of the monitor, provided access to food pellets via a solenoid-controlled food hopper containing Mazuri food pellets. Each feeding port was equipped with a light that signalled when the hopper had been raised, and an infrared beam to detect entry into the port. Each chamber was connected to a computer in an adjacent room. E-Prime 2.0 software (Psychology Software Tools, Pittsburgh, PA) was used to control contingencies and detect responses.</p><p>Stimuli. Experimental stimuli consisted of coloured circles (white, black, purple, green, yellow, and orange) presented against a grey background on the chamber's internal monitor.</p><p>Each circle had a diameter of 100 pixels (approximately 2.5 cm).</p><p>Procedure. Sessions lasted for 45 min and were run six days a week at approximately the same time each day.</p><p>Training Phase 1. The pigeons were first exposed to an autoshaping paradigm that presented white circles either centrally on the screen or to the right or left of centre, or black circles in numerous spatial locations (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). Trials began with a single white or black circle that remained onscreen for 60 s or until it was pecked, at which point it disappeared and a randomly-selected hopper was raised allowing the pigeon 1 s of food access, followed by a 20-s inter-trial interval. There was approximately a 50% chance of either the white or black coloured circle being presented. The spatial location of each presented circle was selected randomly without replacement from a list of respective locations. Autoshaping lasted until the pigeons responded on more than 75% of the total stimulus presentations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 11</head><p>Training Phase 2. The pigeons were next trained on an operant procedure in which the inter-trial interval was shortened to 2 s and a peck at the circle was required to raise a hopper.</p><p>When the pigeons completed 50 trials within a 45-min session, they were moved to Phase 3.</p><p>Training Phase 3. Pigeons received sessions consisting of only 16 trials, and the stimuli appeared in a sequence that resembled the testing procedure. First, a white circle (the start stimulus) appeared centrally on the screen. A single peck to this produced another white circle on the left or right and erased the start stimulus. Pecking the new circle erased it and resulted in 1, 2, 3, or 4 black circles (tokens) appearing onscreen according to the layouts depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>Each token circle required a single peck for 1-s access to food. Once all the tokens had been selected, a 2-s inter-trial interval ensued. Pigeons remained on this phase until their weight stabilized to approximately 85% of its free-feeding value. The mean number (and range) of sessions for Phase 3 was 13.5 (10-15).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Training Phase 4.</head><p>The next phase consisted of four sessions, each containing 16 singleoption trials with the other four coloured circles: yellow, green, orange, and purple. This phase provided forced exposure to the stimuli and reward contingencies that would occur in testing (see Testing section below and <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>), with the order and side presentation randomized across the 16 trials in each session.</p><p>Testing. Testing was run for 80 sessions, with each lasting up to 60 minutes with 16 trials. A schematic of an example trial is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Each trial began with the white startstimulus appearing centrally on the screen. A single peck to this stimulus caused it to disappear and simultaneously produce either one or two coloured (choice) circles on either side of it. A single peck to a coloured circle erased the screen and produced 0, 1, 2, 3, or 4 tokens (black RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 12 circles), depending on which choice circle was pecked. Options were classified as: risky-high, risky-low, safe-high, or safe-low. The risky-high option led to 2 or 4 tokens with a 50% chance of either. The risky-low option led to 0 or 2 tokens with a 50% chance of either. The safe-high option always led to 3 tokens, and the safe-low option always led to one token. The spatial layout of the various black circles is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. A single peck to any one of the tokens caused it to disappear and a randomly selected food hopper to rise, allowing the bird to obtain 1-s of food access. The bird could then select any remaining token for another 1-s of food access until all the tokens were removed. After a 2-s inter-trial interval, a new trial began.</p><p>Three types of trial were included in each session. Risk-preference trials presented a choice between a risky-high and a safe-high option, or a risky-low and a safe-low option. Catch trials presented a choice between a high and low option, with all four choice combinations.</p><p>Single-option trials presented only one option that had to be selected, ensuring that all options were occasionally chosen and all outcome contingencies were experienced. Each session included four risk-preference trials (two high and two low), eight catch trials and four singleoption trials, with trial order randomized within the session and counterbalanced such that each choice stimulus appeared equally often in either the left or right spatial positions. All possible combinations of stimuli and reward outcomes were counterbalanced across every four sessions. approved by the appropriate University of Alberta research ethics board. Seven participants were excluded from the analysis due to failure to learn the contingencies (see Data Analysis).</p><p>Procedure. Participants first sat as a group in a large room where instructions were simultaneously read aloud and projected onto a projector screen (see Appendix A for instructions). The participants then entered small individual rooms to complete the computer task using a computer mouse to make choices. Visually, the task was identical to the one presented to the pigeons during testing, except that a cumulative point tally was displayed at the bottom of the screen. Each click on a token raised this tally by 1 point. The experimental session was divided into 8 blocks of 64 trials. To provide a break, participants performed a maze task between each block. The first block provided 64 single-option trials. All subsequent blocks consisted of 16 risk-preference trials, 32 catch trials, and 16 single-option trials. These trial types were randomly intermixed and accounted for every possible combination of choice stimulus, side, and reward.</p><p>Upon completion of the experiment, the participants' cumulative points were used to calculate a cash bonus of up to $5.00. Participants were not told the point-to-cash conversion rate prior to the experiment. The conversion rate was based on a constant linear increase from the lowest number of points that could be earned (744 points = $0.00), through the number of points expected by chance (1024 points = $2.50), to the highest number of points that could be earned (1304 points = $5.00). All cash bonuses were rounded up to the nearest $0.25.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>For consistency with prior work <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Ludvig et al., 2014b)</ref>, the last third of the total collected choices were selected for statistical analysis, which was conducted using R Software for statistical computing (R Core Team, 2018). Subjects, pigeons and humans, who chose the high-RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 14 value option across all catch-trial types less than 60% of the time were excluded from analyses. This exclusion criterion is consistent with prior studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ludvig &amp; Spetch, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al., 2014b)</ref>. The rationale is that if subjects do not reliably choose more reward (points/money or food) over less reward, then they either have not adequately learned the reward contingencies or are not motivated by the potential rewards, and their risk preference results are therefore difficult to interpret.</p><p>For risk-preference trials, a paired t-test was conducted on the mean proportion of risky option selections for the high-and low-value choice types. For catch trials, a paired t-test was conducted on the mean proportion of high-value option selections across trials with and without the lowest-extreme (i.e., 0) as a possible outcome. Additionally, a JZS Bayes factor (BF10) with a medium prior was computed for each comparison to obtain the relative odds in favor of the alternative hypothesis over the null using the BayesFactor R package <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Morey &amp; Rouder, 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">, 2018</ref>). An effect size of mean differences is also provided using an unbiased estimate of Cohen's d (i.e., Hedges' g) with corresponding 95% confidence intervals computed using the effsize package <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Torchiano, 2017)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2B</ref> (humans) show the mean proportion of times the risky option was selected for high-value and low-value choices, as well as the paired differences between these two choice types with appropriate 95% confidence intervals <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Franz &amp; Loftus, 2012)</ref>. For high-value choices, risky option selection refers to selecting the stimulus leading to either 2 or 4 instead of the stimulus leading to a guaranteed 3. For low-value choices, risky option selection refers to selecting the stimulus leading to 0 or 2 instead of the stimulus leading  Pigeons much more accurately chose the high-value option when the low-value option sometime led to the lowest extreme (i.e., the option leading to an outcome of 0 or 2) than when that lowest extreme was not possible (i.e., the option always leading to 1). Thus, catch trials containing an option that sometimes provided no food reward were learned the most readily. For pigeons, this difference between the two types of catch trials was found to be significant; t(5) = 4.35, p = .007, g = 1.64 [0.15, 3.13], BF10 = 8.7. The human catch-trial data revealed no such differentiation, as near-ceiling effects were observed across all types of catch trials; t(22) = 1.16, p = .257, g = 0.24 <ref type="bibr">[-0.36, 0.84]</ref>, BF10 = 0.4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2A (pigeons) and</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In this novel operant task, pigeons and humans exhibited similar levels and patterns of risk preference. Both species selected the risky option more often for high-value choices relative to low-value choices, providing further support for the extreme-outcome rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Ludvig et al., 2014a</ref>). The possibility of receiving 4 rewards seemed to pull preference towards the risky highvalue option, whereas the possibility of receiving 0 rewards pushed preference away from the risky low-value option. These results replicate and extend the core findings of Ludvig et al.</p><p>(2014b) to a novel experimental domain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 16</head><p>The catch-trial performance of the pigeons, however, suggests that their choices might have been driven more strongly by an avoidance of the zero reward than the humans. This observation raises the possibility that the risk aversion exhibited by pigeons on low-value trials may have been driven more by an explicit avoidance of a zero reward than by a general overweighting of the extreme outcomes (also in <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al., 2014b)</ref>. Humans, however, did not show the same asymmetry in their catch-trial performance. In addition, other experiments with humans have shown that eliminating the zero, or no-reward outcomes does not qualitatively change the results <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Ludvig et al., 2014a</ref>). Thus, it is possible that humans are sensitive to any extreme outcomes, whereas pigeons are more sensitive to zero outcomes. Experiment 2 set out to test this possibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2</head><p>This experiment tested risk preferences for high-and low-value rewards, but with all the values increased by one to make the lowest possible value a non-zero outcome. The experimental design was similar to Experiment 1, but the nature of the task used for pigeons differed. Because catch-trial performance of Experiment 1 and initial pilot data suggested that pigeons had more difficulty learning the necessary discriminations with the new values in an operant-chamber setting, the same type of foraging procedure described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al. (2014b)</ref> was used.</p><p>Humans were tested with the same operant procedure as in Experiment 1. Stimuli. Choice panels consisted of two 30.48 × 58.42 cm planks of 2.54 cm thick plywood set at a 90° angle and covered with laminated paper of distinct colours (green, orange, purple, and yellow) and designs (a hollow black triangle, three horizontal black lines, four white squares, and a black "X"; see <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> for an example). Two additional solid white training panels were used in Phase 2. The panels were centred inside the compartments and food rewards were concealed behind each choice panel. Each individual food reward consisted of two Mazuri Gamebird pellets on top of a small amount of grit inside a 6.99-cm diameter ceramic cup.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure. Preliminary training occurred over several days in three phases:</head><p>Training Phase 1. All pigeons were first trained via successively reinforced approximations to enter each compartment from the start-box, through either the left or right entry door (randomly chosen), walk to the furthest corner to obtain three food rewards, and then return to the start box.</p><p>Training Phase 2. In Phase 2, a white choice panel was placed in the centre of each compartment and pigeons were gradually shaped to walk around the panel to obtain food and return to the start-box. Once they reliably completed 16 trials within a session, with all food rewards concealed behind the panel, Phase 3 began.</p><p>Training Phase 3. Pigeons completed 64 single-option trials randomly distributed over four 16-trial sessions. At the start of each trial, the door to one of the compartments opened, and the barrier into the decision area from the start-box was removed. Once the pigeon entered a compartment, the door was closed to prevent re-entry into the decision area until all food rewards were consumed (from 1-5 food cups, contingent upon the panel). The door was then re-opened allowing the pigeon to return to the start-box, which now contained a food cup with 2 pellets.</p><p>The four panels indicated a risky or safe outcome of either high value or low value. The safe high-value panel always indicated 4 rewards, and the risky high-value panel indicated 3 or 5 rewards, with a 50% chance of either. The safe low-value panel always indicated 2 rewards, while the risky low-value panel indicated 1 or 3 rewards, with a 50% chance of either.</p><p>Presentation of the panels was counter-balanced and randomized across the 64 trials such that each panel and reward occurred equally often on each side.</p><p>Testing. Testing lasted for a total of 28 sessions that each contained four single-option trials, which exposed the bird once to each of the four panels, and 12 choice trials, which consisted of four risk-preference trials and eight catch trials. On risk-preference trials, pigeons chose between safe and risky options of the same expected value (e.g., risky high-value vs. safe RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 19 high-value). Catch trials required the pigeon to choose between one high-value (risky or safe) and one low-value panel (risky or safe); these assessed learning of the contingencies. Each session had two of each type of catch trial. Sessions were counterbalanced so that each stimulus appeared twice in both the right and left compartments on choice trials. Ordering of the trials was randomized each session.</p><p>The testing procedure was identical to Phase 3 except that both entry doors opened simultaneously on each trial. On single-option trials, one of the compartments was left empty. If the pigeon entered the empty side, both guillotine doors were left open until the pigeon entered the side with a panel.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2b: Humans</head><p>Participants and Methods.</p><p>Group 1: Forty-four participants (aged 20.3 ± 2.3 years old; 35 females) were recruited from the same participant pool as Experiment 1b; no individuals participated in more than one experiment. In this experiment, risky high-value options produced 3 or 5 rewards, whereas risky low-value options produced either 1 or 3 rewards. Safe high-value options guaranteed 4 rewards, and safe low-value options guaranteed 2 rewards. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows a schematic of the reward contingencies and spatial layout of the experiment. Except for the outcome values, Experiment 2b employed identical methods as those used in Experiment 1b. Twenty out of the forty-four participants were excluded from the analysis due to failure to learn the contingencies (&lt;60% correct on catch trials).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Group 2:</head><p>A second group of 24 participants (aged 19.4 ± 1.5 years old; 13 females) was run because so many participants in the first group failed the catch trials. Group 2 participants RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 20 were given the same procedure, but received more explicit instructions about the choice task (see Appendix A). All Group 2 participants passed the catch trials and were included in the analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>The data analysis was conducted as per Experiment 1. Additionally, two other post hoc tests were included to evaluate specific differences in Experiment 2b. A Pearson's Chi-squared test was performed to evaluate the difference in catch-trial pass frequency. To evaluate differences in median choice reaction time between people who passed or failed in Group 1, a randomization test performing 10,000 Monte Carlo re-samplings was conducted using the Coin R package <ref type="bibr">(Hothorn, Hornik, van de Wiel, Winell, &amp; Zeileis, 2006)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Pigeons. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> shows the mean proportion of times the risky option was selected for high-and low-value rewards along with the 95% confidence interval of the paired difference.</p><p>Contrary to the findings of Experiment 1, pigeons <ref type="figure">(Fig. 5A)</ref>  .53]) choice types, t(5)= 0.10, p = .928, g = 0.04 [-1.25, 1.32], BF10 = 0.37. Catch-trial performance (see <ref type="figure">Figure 5D</ref>) showed no clear difference between choices with and without the low-extreme outcome, t(5)= 1.68, p = .154, g = 0.63 [-0.69, 1.95], BF10 = 0.94.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Humans.</head><p>In Group 1, 20 participants failed the catch-trial criteria and were excluded from the risk-preference analysis (~45% of participants). In Group 2, with more explicit instructions, none of the participants failed the catch-trial criteria. A Pearson's Chi-squared test showed this difference between groups to be statistically significant, Although risk preference was highly similar across Group 1 and Group 2, the percentage of participants who passed the catch trials was strikingly different−only 55% of the 44 participants in Group 1 (who received minimal instructions) compared to 100% of the 20 participants in Group 2 (who received more detailed instructions). The subset of participants who passed the catch trials scored near-ceiling, while the subset of participants who failed the catch trials consistently scored near-chance, with virtually no intermediate between these two subsets.</p><p>One possibility is that some participants in Experiment 2b adopted a strategy of attempting to maximize rewards by responding as quickly as possible within the session's allotted time.</p><p>Indeed, those who failed the catch trials typically responded faster (Mdn = 488 ms, IQR <ref type="bibr">[460,</ref><ref type="bibr">569]</ref>) than those who passed the catch trials (Mdn = 738 ms <ref type="bibr">[679,</ref><ref type="bibr">874]</ref>). This difference was significant according to a post-hoc randomization test using subjects' median choice response time, Z = 4.91, p &lt; .001.</p><p>Among those subjects who passed the catch-trial criterion, no significant differences were observed in catch-trial performance for trials with and without the low-extreme outcome for either Group 1 (t(23)= 1.16, p = .256, g = -0.23 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-0.82, 0.35]</ref>, BF10 = 0.39) or Group 2 (t(5)= 1.11, p = .278, g = -0.22 <ref type="bibr">[-0.81, 0.36]</ref>, BF10 = 0.37).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 22</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>This experiment demonstrated a difference in how pigeons and humans make risky choices. When the outcomes did not include any zero values, humans continued to show choices in line with an extreme-outcome rule (selecting the risky option more for high than low values),</p><p>whereas the pigeons no longer showed a difference in risky choice for high and low value outcomes. This result suggests that humans may be more sensitive to extreme outcomes and pigeons may be more sensitive to zero outcomes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3: Pigeons</head><p>In view of the large methodological differences between the procedures used for pigeons in Experiment 1a and 2a, Experiment 3 sought to replicate the results using a refinement of the operant procedure from Experiment 1a.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Subjects</head><p>Subjects consisted of 16 racing pigeons (Columba livia). All, except one pigeon, had no prior experience in risky-choice experiments. One bird, 473, had previously been in Experiment 1. Outside of experimental sessions, the birds were housed in 165×69×178 cm group cages that contained 5-8 birds per cage. Cages were located inside a temperature-controlled colony room running a 12-hour light-dark cycle. Free access to grit and vitamin-enriched water was provided inside each cage. Experimental sessions were run daily, six days a week, at the same time each day, with each bird being maintained at approximately 80% of their free-feeding weight by postsession rations of Mazuri Gamebird food pellets (PMI Nutrition International LLC, Brentwood, MO). All procedures were approved by the University of Alberta Biological Sciences Animal Care and Use Committee, following the guidelines of the Canadian Council on Animal Care.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Apparatus</head><p>Six custom-built 29.2 × 35.6 × 38.1 cm operant-conditioning chambers, each equipped with the same monitors and touch screens used in Experiment 1a, were located inside a closed room. All the chambers contained an opaque barrier that blocked the lower third of touch screen from incidental contact by the pigeon's feet and chest. White noise was fed through each of the monitor's built-in speakers so that the internal sound pressure level of the boxes was 65db. Two feeding ports located on the side walls contained the same food hoppers described in Experiment 1a. As in Experiment 1a, each chamber was connected to a computer, located in an adjacent room, running E-Prime 2.0 software (Psychology Software Tools, Pittsburgh, PA).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimuli</head><p>Experimental stimuli consisted of coloured circles 110 pixels (approx. 3 cm) in diameter presented against a grey background on the chamber's internal monitor. All circles were aligned horizontally at the same vertical location on the screen (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). Circles were coloured white, black, blue, orange, green, or purple. To aid discrimination, the latter four colours were also inscribed with either a single black vertical line, a hollow black circle, a solid black "X", or three black horizontal lines respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Training Phase 1. Pigeons were first given three 90-minute sessions of an autoshaping procedure with a Fixed-Ratio (FR) 1 contingency built in. One randomly selected (without replacement) coloured circle was presented for 10 s. A peck to this circle immediately raised one randomly selected hopper, allowing the bird 1-s access to food. If no pecks were made to the stimulus within the allotted 10 seconds, the stimulus disappeared and the bird was still permitted RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 24 1 s of access to food via a randomly chosen hopper. Following each food delivery, a 240-s intertrial interval ensued.</p><p>Training Phase 2. After the three full sessions of Phase 1, a strict FR1 contingency with a 2-s inter-trial interval was instituted. Each randomly selected circle now remained onscreen until it was pecked or the session timed out. Phase 2 was deemed complete when a bird completed 72 trials in a single session and the average response time on each circle type for that session was less than 30 s. Sessions contained 72 trials, and the bird remained in the chamber for 90 minutes.</p><p>Training Phase 3. Pigeons were randomly assigned to either a Zero group (n=8) or a No-Zero group (n=8). For the Zero group, the choice circles provided values equivalent to those used in Experiment 1a. For the No-Zero group, those same values were increased by 1 (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6)</ref> for both this phase and for the testing phase. Procedurally, this phase was the same as Training Phase 4 of Experiment 1a except that it now consisted of only one session of 64 single-option trials. Following completion of the 64 trials, the birds were moved to the testing phase.</p><p>Testing. Testing lasted for 30 sessions, with each session consisting of 16 single-option trials, and 48 choice trials (16 risk-preference choices and 32 catch choices), with full counterbalancing of stimuli and values within each session presented in a randomized order.</p><p>Apart from the number of trials per session, testing proceeded in the same fashion as Experiment 1a.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>Main effects and interactions between choice (high-and low-value) and Group (Zero and No-Zero) manipulations were analyzed using linear mixed-effects modelling on the mean RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 25 proportion of choices made to the risky alternative during the last third of all trials. Models were fit by maximum likelihood with subjects treated as a random effect and computed with the nlme R package for R 3.5.1 statistical software <ref type="bibr">(Pinheiro, Bates, DebRoy, Sarkar, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">R Core Team, 2018</ref>). An effect size in terms of r 2 is reported for each fixed-effect in the full model. Bayes Factors (BF10) are also provided for each effect and tested against a null model that included only the intercept and an additive random effect of subject.</p><p>Simple-effects analysis on the difference between the high-and low-value choices for the Zero and No-Zero groups were analyzed using a paired t-test, with p-values Bonferroni corrected for multiple comparisons. For each simple effect, a corresponding effect-size (g) and JZS Bayes factor (BF10) is provided as per Experiment 1. Similar sets of analyses are provided for catchtrial assessment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Three birds in the No-Zero group failed to meet the 60% catch-trial criterion and were subsequently removed from the analysis; none of the birds in the Zero group failed to reach the criterion. <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> shows the mean proportion of risky option selections for high-and low-value choice types along with the 95% confidence interval of the paired difference for both the Zero (1) = 9.68, p = .002, r 2 = .11, BF10 &gt; 150, as well as a significant interaction between these RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 26 two variables, χ 2 (1) = 4.00, p = .045, r 2 = .25, BF10 &gt; 150. Consistent with our previous findings, simple-effects analysis showed a significant difference between the high-and low-value outcomes in the Zero group, t(7) = 5.33, p = .002, g = 1. <ref type="bibr">78 [0.51, 3</ref>.05], BF10 = 38.42, but not in the No-Zero group, t(4) = 2.01, p = .230, g = 0.81 <ref type="bibr">[-0.71, 2.33]</ref>, BF10 = 1.24. These results confirm that there was a larger and more reliable difference between the high-and low-value choices in the Zero group than the No-Zero group. <ref type="figure">Figures 7B and 7C</ref> show the overall catch-trial performance for the Zero and No-Zero groups. Similar to Experiment 1a, choices that contained the low-extreme value (i.e., a possibility of zero) were learned the most readily in the Zero group. Similar to Experiment 2a, however, this difference in catch-trial type was not observed in the No-Zero group (where zero was not a possible outcome). Corroborating this observation, statistical analysis revealed a significant interaction between catch-trial type and group, χ 2 (1) = 6.54, p = .011, r 2 = .4, BF10 &gt; 10.91. For the Zero group, analysis of the simple-effects revealed a large difference between choices with and without the lowest extreme; t(7) = 4.08, p = .009, g = 1.13 <ref type="bibr">[-0.03, 2.28]</ref>, BF10 = 11.88. By contrast, no such differentiation was seen in the No-Zero group; t(4) = 0.37, p = 1, g = 0.19 <ref type="bibr">[-1.27, 1.66]</ref>, BF10 = 0.42.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>To determine whether the results of Experiment 1a and 2a would replicate within the same procedure, Experiment 3 manipulated the occurrence of zeros between two groups of pigeons. Similar to Experiment 1a, the Zero group showed a pronounced difference between high-and low-value choices, whereas the No-Zero group revealed a highly variable, and nonsignificant differentiation. Additionally, whereas the Zero group showed clear risk aversion for RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 27 low-value choices, neither the high-nor the low-value choices in the No-Zero group showed preference levels that were significantly different than what might be predicted by chance. These observations, in conjunction with the imbalances between catch trials containing risky low-value and safe low-value outcomes, confirm the basic conclusion drawn from Experiment 1a and 2a that pigeons are more affected by a general avoidance of zero than by an overweighting of the extremes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 4</head><p>In Experiments 1-3, pigeons failed to show a significant extreme-outcome effect when none of the outcomes included a zero value. This insensitivity to the extremes may be due to an inability of the pigeons to discriminate between the outcomes when there are no zeros. Although the catch trial data suggested that pigeons did not completely fail to discriminate, the catch trials did not explicitly test a pigeon's ability to discriminate between all possible outcomes (e.g., 4 versus 5). Experiment 4 sought to verify the conclusions of Experiments 2 and 3 by first pretesting pigeons' ability to discriminate between all combinations of the No-Zero choice outcomes used in Experiment 3 (i.e., 1-5) and then testing those same pigeons using a variant of the Experiment 3 No-Zero procedure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Subjects and Apparatus. Subjects consisted of 8 racing pigeons (Columba livia)</head><p>selected from the colony with no prior experience in risky-choice experiments. Subjects were maintained as per Experiment 3 and run in the same experimental chambers described in Experiment 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 28</head><p>Reinforcer Magnitude Discrimination. Similar to Experiment 3, pigeons were presented with coloured choice circles that led to a horizontal array of token circles, each of which required a single peck to obtain 1 s of access to food. The procedure was modified, however, to enhance discriminability of the alternatives. Five choice circles, 2 cm in diameter, were presented in a horizontal array just beneath the location of the token array (see <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>).</p><p>Each choice circle had a fixed spatial location that was demarcated by a hollow black circle on a grey background. The choice circles were assigned a colour unique to their spatial location and had a number centrally inscribed, in black Times font, that corresponded to its particular outcome. For instance, if a bird selected a dark green circle with a number three inscribed inside, that circle would disappear, and three corresponding dark green tokens would appear above it, each of which could be pecked for 1-s access to food in any order. The colour of the tokens always matched the respective choice circle that was selected but no number appeared inside.</p><p>The outcome of each choice circle was fixed to a particular reward amount (not probabilistic), and the values ranged from 1 to 5.</p><p>Two different space-colour mappings were used for the choice circles. From the leftmost circle to rightmost circle, the colours for one mapping were golden brown, light blue, dark green, dark yellow, and magenta. For the other spatial mapping, these same colours were offset by 2 positions to the right. Two different spatial-number mappings were also used and from left to right were 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 4, 5, 1, 2, 3. Birds were randomly assigned to the resulting 4 colournumber combinations. Unlike the previous experiments, no start-stimulus was used at any point in Experiment 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 29</head><p>Initially the pigeons were tested on an FR1 condition that required only a single peck to select a choice stimulus. This produced weak discrimination across the full range of values (see Results section). Consequently, the birds were re-tested with the ratio requirement on the choice stimuli increased to FR40 because increased ratio requirements have been shown to improve accuracy in both simple and complex discrimination tasks (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Elsmore, 1971;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Wilkie &amp; Spetch, 1978)</ref>. Upon beginning the FR40 condition, all but one pigeon had their colour and number locations reassigned to different locations to ensure that the contingencies would have to be completely re-learned. Training and testing occurred as per Experiment 3, though the number of trials per session for Phase 2, Phase 3, and testing were adjusted to 65 trials to allow for complete within-session balancing of the stimuli. Each session consisted of 15 single-option trials and 50 dual-choice trials. All choice combinations across the outcome values were testede.g., 5 vs 4, 5 vs 3, 5 vs 2, 5 vs 1, 4 vs 3, and so on, in a randomized fashion.</p><p>The FR1 condition included training Phases 1, 2, and 3; however, the FR40 condition only included training Phase 3. During Phase 3 of the FR40 condition, the ratio requirement was shaped according to a geometric progression: <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2,</ref><ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr">6,</ref><ref type="bibr">9,</ref><ref type="bibr">12,</ref><ref type="bibr">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">25,</ref><ref type="bibr">32,</ref><ref type="bibr">40</ref>. The progression increased to its next value every five trials. If a pigeon did not complete all 65 trials in Phase 3's session, the pigeon would remain on Phase 3 with an FR40 requirement on all trials until the pigeon completed all 65 trials within a session or three sessions had elapsed.</p><p>During Phase 3 and testing of the FR40 condition, a total of 40 responses were always required to one of the alternatives to complete a trial and obtain that alternative's corresponding tokens. No changeover penalty was instituted for switching between alternatives, and the FR40 requirement was reset at the start of each trial. Because the high ratio requirement caused some RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 30 pigeons to not complete the full 65 trials per session, each pigeon was run until they had completed at least 1500 choice trials across the sessions. The mean number of total testing sessions was 36, ranging from 30 to 55.</p><p>Risky Choice. Following the reinforcer magnitude discrimination testing, the birds were moved to the risky-choice procedure. The procedure was similar to that used for the No-Zero group in Experiment 3 except that choice responding required completion of the FR40 schedule.</p><p>Training phases 1 and 2 were included. Four new colours were used for the choice circles and tokens: red, yellow, green, blue. Each choice circle was also inscribed with a specific letter A, B, C, or D, written in black Times font. The tokens matched the colour of the selected choice stimulus and were presented above the selected circle. The choice stimuli were mapped onto a risky-high outcome, a risky-low outcome, a safe-high outcome, and a safe-low outcome. The location-colour, location-letter, and location-outcome mappings were all randomized independently according to a Latin-square design. Each bird was randomly assigned to a specific mapping on the condition that blue and yellow circles did not correspond to the same values received during the FR40 discrimination testing. Each session consisted of a maximum of 64 trials: 16 single-option, 16 choice, and 32 catch trials in a randomized order. With the exception of one pigeon (#76), testing continued until each pigeon had completed 1440 choice trials. Bird #76, who ran for 123 sessions with a mean of 11 choice trials per session, only completed 1294 choice trials before the experiment was ended. Across all other pigeons, the mean number of sessions was 32, ranging from 30 to 40. Data Analysis. Analyses for risky choice proceeded as in the earlier experiments. For the discrimination task, first, we simply compared the proportion correct for the discrimination that RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 31 were only a single unit apart (e.g., 3 vs. 4), which should be the hardest discriminations for pigeons. In addition, to better quantify the pigeons' discrimination across the 10 possible choice types in the FR1 and FR40 conditions, relative preference in these conditions was evaluated in terms of the generalized matching relation <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Baum, 1974)</ref>, as applied to reinforcer magnitude <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Davison &amp; Baum, 2003)</ref>. Given the ubiquity of matching in choice and the straightforward application and interpretation of generalized matching relation <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(deVilliers, 1977)</ref>, the matching law offers a useful lens with which to evaluate the pigeons' choice behaviour across the full range of outcomes used in Experiment 4. Equation 1 shows the generalized matching relation applied to reinforcer magnitude:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">log $% &amp; ' &amp; ( = log $% , ' , ( + log $% ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where B refers to the number of responses emitted to a particular choice alternative, and M refers to the total amount of food delivered for a given choice outcome. Subscripts refer to the different options (1 or 2). The intercept parameter k, called bias, is a measure of preference for B1, relative to B2, independent of the reinforcer magnitudes. A positive bias parameter would indicate that pigeons have a general preference toward the higher reward magnitude, independent of the ratio of the items. The slope parameter a, referred to as sensitivity, indexes how the log response ratio grows with the log reinforcer magnitude. In situations where perfect matching to the log magnitude ratios is predicted, bias and sensitivity should take values of 0 and 1 respectively.</p><p>The matching relation was fit to the last third of each pigeon's data for both the FR1 and FR40 condition using least-squares linear regression with R 3.5.1 software (R Core Team, 2018).</p><p>Because pigeons sometimes showed exclusive preference towards one alternative, a correction of RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 32 0.1 was added to the numerator and denominator of each pigeon's response ratio to prevent the occurrence of zero inside the ratio and logarithm. Mean bias (intercept) and sensitivity (slope) parameters are reported with corresponding 95% confidence intervals. The results for risky choices were analyzed as per Experiment 1. <ref type="figure">Figure 9A</ref> shows the probability of selecting the high-value option for the four choices that contained outcomes only 1 token apart. Across all 8 pigeons, none of the four choice types in the FR1 condition exceeded chance levels; whereas, in the FR40 condition, all but one choice type (4 vs 3) exceeded chance. <ref type="figure">Figure 9B</ref> displays the overall fit of the generalized matching relation applied separately to the FR1 and FR40 conditions across all tested choices. For the FR1 condition, a very slight bias of 0.10 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-0.40, 0.61</ref>  <ref type="bibr">1.19, 3</ref>.99] to the log reinforcer magnitude ratio. Thus, as the log reinforcer magnitudes became more discrepant, the pigeons' preference became even more pronounced than would be expected had they just been matching relative responding to relative reinforcer magnitude. More critically, however, the FR40 condition also produced a heavy bias of 0.76 [0.22, 1.30] towards choices containing the larger reinforcement value that was significantly larger than would be predicted by either indifference or strict matching.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>During the risky-choice testing, only one bird (#76) failed to reach the 60% catch-trial criterion and was excluded from the remaining analyses. <ref type="figure">Figure 9C</ref> shows the mean proportion of risky option selections for high-and low-value rewards, along with the 95% confidence interval of the paired difference. Similar to the No-Zero groups in Experiments 2a and 3, there was no significant difference in the frequency with which the risky option was selected between the high-value (M = .41; 95% CI [0.09, 0.74]) and low-value (M = .34; [0.16, 0.52]) choice types, t(6)= 0.409, p = .697, BF10 = 0.38, g = 0.14 <ref type="bibr">[-1.02, 1.31]</ref>. Catch-trial performance (see <ref type="figure">Figure 9D</ref>) showed no clear difference between choices with and without the low-extreme outcome, t(6) = 0.82, p = .445, g = 0.29 <ref type="bibr">[-.88, 1.46]</ref>, BF10 = 0.46.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Experiment 4 confirmed that, even when pigeons can adequately discriminate between non-zero outcomes, they still show little evidence for an effect of the extreme outcomes on their risky choices. These findings corroborate the results from Experiment 2 and 3 and suggest that pigeons are more driven by the avoidance of zero outcomes than by avoidance of a low extreme.</p><p>The ratio requirement also played a significant role in determining the degree of discrimination exhibited by the pigeons. When the response requirement on the choice alternative required only a single response to make a choice (FR1), overall pigeon preferences seemed to follow basic predictions of matching, with discrimination being relatively weak at small ratios (e.g. 5:4) and getting progressively stronger at larger ratios (e.g. 5:1). When the response requirement on the choice alternative was increased to 40, bias in favor of the choice alternative with the larger reward outcome became very pronounced. This increase in bias was accompanied by an additional increase in overall sensitivity to the reinforcement ratio. The enhanced discrimination of reinforcer magnitude when the response requirement was increased RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 34 is consistent with previous findings that discrimination becomes more accurate as response effort increases (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Ellesmore, 1971;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Wilkie &amp; Spetch, 1978)</ref>.</p><p>Given that pigeons demonstrated good discrimination of the reward values at the higher FR40 ratio requirement, Experiment 4 evaluated the predictions of the extreme-outcome effect under this condition with no zero outcomes present. The results showed that, even with a high ratio requirement in place, pigeons still obtained results qualitatively similar to those seen in the No-Zero groups of Experiments 2 and 3: They exhibited similar levels for risk preference for both high-value and low-value choices (see <ref type="figure">Figure 7)</ref>. Considering the clear preference for the larger reward outcome in the reinforcer magnitude discrimination of Experiment 4, as well as the clear preference for the high-value outcome on catch trials, the pattern of choice results in Experiments 2-4 is probably not due to an inability to discriminate between non-zero outcomes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>The present set of results demonstrate the importance of zero, or non-rewarded options, in determining risky choice in pigeons but not people. Whereas people avoided risky options that might lead to the worst outcome in a context, pigeons primarily avoided options that led to zero or no reward. When the zero value was removed as a possible outcome, humans continued to select the risky option more often for high-value options than low-value ones, consistent with previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Ludvig et al., 2014a)</ref>. Pigeons, however, showed no consistent pattern in their risk preferences when the zero value was removed, despite accurate choice of high-value options over low-value options. Together, these results suggest that, in contrast to our previous suggestion in <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al. (2014b)</ref>, the strikingly similar patterns of risky choice seen by pigeons and humans are driven by different underlying mechanisms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 35</head><p>In humans, there is evidence that the greater risk seeking for high-value choices than for low-value choices is driven by an overweighting of extreme outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Ludvig et al., 2014a)</ref>. For example, manipulating the set of choices in the decision context can shift risk preferences: for the same choice between a safe 20-point option and a risky option leading to 0 or 40 points, people's choices range from risk seeking to risk neutrality to risk aversion depending on the other choices in the decision context <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Ludvig et al., 2014a;</ref><ref type="bibr">see Madan et al., 2018)</ref>. Moreover, memory tests given after the choice task reveal that people are more likely to recall the extreme outcomes first and to judge them as having occurred more frequently <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Madan et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">2017)</ref>.</p><p>Here, too, people were more risk seeking for high-value than low-value choices, even when no zeroes were present (Exp. 2a).</p><p>Pigeons, in contrast, were not driven by the relative extremes to the same degree. When zero (i.e., no reward) outcomes were present in Experiment 1 and 3, pigeons indeed selected the risky option more often in the high-value than low-value choices. When zero outcomes were removed in Experiments 2, 3, and 4, however, pigeons no longer showed consistently different patterns for high-and low-value choices. On the basis of these results, it would seem that the zero outcomes more strongly controlled behaviour in pigeons than people. Further research is needed to determine whether non-zero extreme outcomes play a role in pigeons' risk preferences in other situations. For example, performance could be directly compared between similarvalued choices with and without an extreme-outcome (as has been done with humans; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Madan et al., 2018)</ref>. Here, in 4 experiments, the risky options always potentially led to an extreme outcome (either high or low).</p><p>One possible reason that pigeons might be particularly driven by an avoidance of zero is suggested by the probability and delay discounting literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Green, Myerson, &amp; Calvert, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Hayden, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Hayden &amp; Platt, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mazur, 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Rachlin, Logue, Gibbon, Frankel, 1986)</ref>. When the low-value option provides either 2 or 0 food rewards, the pigeons may treat this probabilistic reward as a variable delay to reward. For all other options some reward is provided on every trial so, although the amount of reward varies probabilistically, the occurrence of reward is never delayed. In essence, this design may have become a self-control task where the pigeon chose between a smaller immediate reward, and a larger reward that sometimes occurs after a substantial delay. In these self-control tasks, pigeons typically show steep discounting functions with rewards losing most of their subjective value within a few seconds. This The pigeons' aversion to options that sometimes provide zero outcomes is interesting in relation to evidence from other procedures showing that pigeons are sometimes drawn to options that provide food less reliably (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Belke &amp; Spetch, 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dunn &amp; Spetch 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kendall, 1974;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Pisklak, McDevitt, Dunn, &amp; Spetch, 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">, Stagner &amp; Zentall 2010</ref>. In those studies, choice was followed by a lengthy delay (10 s or greater) during which the stimuli present indicated whether the food would or would not occur. Stimuli which provided clear signals for food functioned as a strong conditioned reinforcer of choice, whereas stimuli that provide ambiguous or redundant signals did not <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(McDevitt, Dunn, Spetch, &amp; Ludvig, 2016)</ref>. Given this importance of the conditioned reinforcer, an interesting question is what would happen if the zero outcomes used in Experiment 1 were preceded by a unique token that provided nothing for its selection. In this case, the zero outcome would no longer be marked by the absence of any feedback cues. It is possible that the strong effects of the zero outcome might become attenuated -or perhaps even reversed if the response requirement on them is increased to lengths analogous to those seen in studies of suboptimal choice.</p><p>An interesting test of the power of zero values in driving choice would be to provide pigeons with a risky option that offers food values of 0 or 4 over a safe option that offers a value of 1. In this case, the risky option would be the better choice in terms of overall expected value, raising the question: would an avoidance of zero still dominate the pigeons' choice behaviour? In the context of a basic two-alternative choice situation, the answer appears to be yes. In one of a series of manipulations, <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Menlove, Inden, and Madden (1979)</ref> gave pigeons a choice between a key that delivered a fixed 2 seconds of food and an alternative key that gave pigeons either 8 or zero seconds of food. All pigeons tested preferred the fixed option, suggesting an avoidance of zero would in fact dominate in our hypothetical experiment. What remains uncertain, however, is whether these results would generalize to a situation where the decision context contains additional higher-value choice alternatives (e.g., a choice between 0 or 4 versus 1 and a choice between 2 or 6 versus 3). Given that the current results suggest pigeons are not especially RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 38 sensitive to the extreme outcomes in such contexts, it might be predicted that the avoidance of zero would still occur.</p><p>The present research provides a stark example of how behavioural similarities across species need not be indicative of the same underlying mechanism. Although humans and pigeons responded the same to the choices presented in Experiment 1 that included a zero value (and in <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Ludvig et al., 2014b)</ref>, their patterns of responding were quite different when the zero outcome was removed in Experiment 2, 3, and 4. Avoiding the zero value played a very powerful role in controlling the risky choice behaviour of pigeons, but not humans. Comparative research between humans and other animal species has been remarkably successful in delineating many robust and highly important behavioural processes that generalize across numerous species−e.g., schedules of reinforcement, hyperbolic discounting, equivalence class formation, and generalized matching, to name just a few. This work, however, provides an important cautionary tale about the challenges of effective comparative research, whereby some similarities may, paradoxically, not actually be the same.  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>RISK</head><label></label><figDesc>1. On average, pigeons showed significantly higher selection of the risky option for the high-value choices (M = .58, 95% CI [0.45, 0.72]) than the low-value choices (M = .10 [−0.02, 0.22]), t(5) = 11.45, p &lt; .001, g = 4.31 [1.97, 6.67], BF10 &gt; 150. Similarly, the humans reliably selected the risky option more for the high-value (M = .57 [0.43, 0.71]) than the lowvalue choices (M = .29 [0.18, 0.41]), t(22) = 5.09, p &lt; .001, g = 1.04 [0.41, 1.68], BF10 &gt; 150.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>also depicts the aggregated learning curves for pigeons and humans on catch trials.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Subjects were six pigeons (Columba livia) (three Racers and three Silver King), all with substantial learning histories, but no experience in risky-choice experiments.RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 17They were housed and maintained as in Experiment 1. All the birds were run daily, five days a week, at the same time each day.Apparatus.Figure 3shows a photo of the experimental arena. The arena consisted of two compartments separated by a 50.8-cm central wall and enclosed by 91.4-cm front and rear walls and a single 82.5-cm side wall. Both the central and rear walls were built of 1.27-cm thick plywood painted white. The front and side walls were made from thin, white corrugated plastic.The arena floor was covered with a thin layer of aspen-chip bedding.Two 44.45 × 63.50 cm entry doors, each set at a 45° angle from the central wall, formed a small, triangular decision area against the front of the arena. Both doors were fashioned from white corrugated plastic and operated via a pulley system. A 16.51 × 20.32 cm entrance in the wall of the decision area led to a plastic 48.26 × 39.37 × 101.60 cm start box. Pigeon behaviour was monitored and recorded by a closed-circuit camera mounted centrally on the ceiling.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>showed little difference in risk selection between the high-value (M = .44; 95% CI [.36, .53]) and the low-value (M = .44 [.35,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>χ 2 (1) = 15.45, p &lt; .001, d = 1.08 [0.52, 1.63]. RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 21 In contrast to the pigeons, humans in Group 1 chose the risky option significantly more frequently for high-value choices (M = .62; 95% CI [.50, .74]) than low-value choices (M = .39 [0.27, 0.51]), t(23) = 2.99, p = .006, g = 0.60 [0.01, 1.20], BF10 = 6.97. Risk-preference levels were remarkably similar in Group 2, again showing more selection of the risky option for the high-value (M = .58 [0.42, 0.74]) than the low-value choices (M = .38 [.25, .50]), t(23) = 2.57, p = 0.017, g = 0.52 [-0.07, 1.11], BF10 = 3.09.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and No-Zero groups. Although both the Zero and No-Zero groups showed greater selection of the risky option for high-value outcomes, M =.48 95% CI [.35, .61] and M =.57 [.35, .79], than low-value outcomes, M =.10 95% CI [.04, .17] and M =.40 [.24, .57], this difference was more pronounced and less variable in the Zero than in the No Zero group. Statistical analysis showed a significant main effect of both choice, χ 2 (1) = 15.88, p &lt; .001, r 2 = .25, BF10 &gt; 150, and group, χ 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>probabilistic interpretation could account for the difference in risky choice for high-and lowvalue options seen in Experiment 1a, in the Zero group of Experiment 3, and may have contributed to the results seen in Ludvig et al. (2014b). The general risk neutrality seen in Experiment 2a, Experiment 3's No-Zero group, and Experiment 4, where all outcomes providedsome reward, is also consistent with this interpretation. Another possibility that merits future exploration is that zero may simply be functioning as an especially potent extreme (as opposed to delay) in certain species, such as pigeons, and certain contexts, such as all gains.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 1 .Figure 2 .</head><label>12</label><figDesc>(A) A schematic of a choice trial displaying a risky high-value option and a safe highvalue option, with possible outcomes in Experiment 1. (B) A schematic illustrating the various reward contingencies in effect. The colour of the choice circles relative to their outcome was counterbalanced across participants according to four different combinations of yellow, green, orange, and purple. RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 47 Probability of choosing the risky option for (A) pigeons and (B) humans on high-and low-value risk preference trials in Experiment 1. The mean difference is also shown on the right side of each plot. Catch trial learning curves for (C) pigeons and (D) humans in Experiment 1 that passed the 60% threshold. The curves depict the proportion of choices made to the highvalue option for catch trials containing the low-extreme outcome (i.e., a possibility of receiving zero) and catch trials that did not contain the low-extreme outcome (i.e., no possibility of receiving zero). All error bars indicate 95% confidence intervals. Dotted lines indicate chance levels of responding.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 3 .Figure 4 .Figure 5 .Figure 6 .Figure 7 .Figure 8 .Figure 9 .</head><label>3456789</label><figDesc>The testing arena during an example trial in Experiment 2a. (A) Pigeon entering the decision area via the open doors. (B) The pigeon eating from the food cups concealed behind the choice stimulus. RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 49 (A) A schematic of a choice trial displaying a risky high-value choice and a safe highvalue choice, with potential outcomes in Experiment 2b. (B) A schematic illustrating the various reward contingencies in effect. The colour of the choice circles relative to their outcome was counterbalanced across participants according to four different combinations of yellow, green, orange, and purple. RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 50 (A-C) Probability of choosing the risky option for pigeons and humans on high-and low-value choice trials in Experiment 2. G1 and G2 refer to Group 1 and Group 2, respectively. The mean difference is shown on the right side for each of the three plots. (D-F) Catch-trial learning curves for pigeons and humans in Experiment 2. The curves depict the proportion of choices made to the high-value option for catch trials with the low-extreme and catch trials without the low-extreme. All error bars indicate 95% confidence intervals. Dotted lines indicate chance levels of responding. RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 51 A schematic illustrating the various reward contingencies in effect for the Zero and No-Zero groups in Experiment 3. RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 52 (A) Probability of choosing the risky option for pigeons on high-and low-value choice trials for the Zero and No-Zero groups in Experiment 3. The mean difference between high-and low-value proportions for both the Zero and No-Zero groups is plotted on the right. Catch trial learning curves for Experiment 3 in the (B) Zero and (C) No-Zero groups for pigeons passing the 60% threshold. The curves depict the proportion of choices made to the high-value option for catch trials with and without the lowest extreme outcome. All error bars indicate 95% confidence intervals. Dotted lines indicate chance levels of responding. RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 53 A schematic of two choice trials on Experiment 4's reinforcer amount discrimination training. Panel 1 and 4 show two of ten possible choice scenarios pigeons would be confronted with. Panel 2 and 5 show the resulting token outcomes of each choice. Panel 3 corresponds to the inter-trial interval. RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 54 The top two panels (A-B) show the results of the reinforcer amount discrimination testing and contain data from all tested pigeons (n=8) in Experiment 4. (A) The probability of selecting the high-value option for choices that differed by only one token. (B) The matching relation between the log response ratio (high/low) on the left y-axis and the log reinforcer magnitude ratio (high/low) on the x-axis. The right-side y-axis displays the proportion of responses made to the high-value alternative on a logarithmic scale. The solid regression lines are fit to all subject data using the generalized matching equation (GME) and correspond to the FR1 condition (blue) and FR40 condition (orange), the dashed line indicates perfect matching. Squares and triangles correspond to mean responding in the FR1 and FR40 condition respectively. The bottom two panels (C-D) show the results of risky-choice testing and contain RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 55 data from only those pigeons that passed the 60% catch trial criterion (n= 7). (C) Probability of selecting the risky option for pigeons on high-and low-value choice trials along with the mean difference on the right. (D) Probability of selecting the high-value option for catch trials with and without the lowest extreme outcome. All error bars and regression confidence bands are calculated at a 95% level. Dotted lines indicate chance levels of responding.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Experiment 1b: Humans Participants.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES</cell><cell>13</cell></row><row><cell>Thirty participants (aged [M±SD] 20.5 ± 2.1 years old; 20 females)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">recruited from the University of Alberta undergraduate psychology participant pool participated</cell></row><row><cell>for course credit. Informed consent was obtained from all participants, and procedures were</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A</head><p>The following instructions were read aloud to the participants and projected onto a lecture screen:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions for Experiment 1b and Experiment 2b -Group 1</head><p>The experiment consists of a computer portion and a maze portion. For the computer portion use the mouse cursor to click on the circles that you see. Try and get as many points as possible. For the maze portion a message will appear on screen telling you when to complete a particular maze. Take a few minutes to complete the maze with a pen or pencil. All the mazes are solvable, but don't worry if you can't solve it. The experiment should take just under 2 hours to complete. You will earn 2 credits for participating, and receive a cash bonus of up to $5.00 depending upon the number of points you get in the computer portion. The more points you get the more money you will earn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions for Experiment 2b -Group 2</head><p>The experiment consists of a computer portion and a maze portion. For the computer portion your goal is to earn as many points as you can. After clicking on a white centre circle, you will see one or two coloured circles on the computer screen. You choose a coloured circle by clicking on it with the mouse. After clicking the coloured circle you will see one or more black circles, clicking each black circle will give you one point.</p><p>When there are two circles you should choose the one you think will win you the most black circles (i.e., the most points). If there is only one circle on the screen, you must click on that one circle to continue. For the maze portion a message will appear on screen telling you when to complete a particular maze. Take a few minutes to complete the maze RISK PREFERENCE AND ZERO OUTCOMES 57 with a pen or pencil. All the mazes are solvable, but don't worry if you can't solve it. The experiment should take just under 2 hours to complete. You will earn 2 credits for participating and receive a cash bonus of up to $5.00 depending upon the number of points you get in the computer portion. The more points you get the more money you will earn.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk-sensitive foraging in common shrews: An interruption model and the effects of mean and variance in reward rate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Barnard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Houston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mcnamara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF00299042</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Small feedback-based decisions and their limited correspondence to description-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Barron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.443</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="233" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preferences for fixed and variable food sources: Variability in amount and delay</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bateson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kacelnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="329" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On two types of deviation from the matching law: Bias and undermatching</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Baum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.1974.22-231</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="242" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Description-and experience-based choice: Does equivalent information equal equivalent choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Camilleri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.actpsy.2010.11.007</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">136</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="276" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical demonstration of risksensitive foraging preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Caraco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Martindale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Whittam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0003-3472(80</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80142" to="80146" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Analysis of Decision Under Risk in Rats. bioRxiv</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Constantinople</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Piet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brody</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>doi: 0.1101/446575</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page">446575</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Every reinforcer counts: reinforcer magnitude and local preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Davison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Baum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.2003.80-95</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice in concurrent schedules and a quantitative formulation of the law of effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Devilliers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Operant Behavior</title>
		<editor>W. K. Honig &amp; J. E. R. Staddon</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of response effort on discrimination performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Elsmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF03393984</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Record</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Standard errors and confidence intervals in within-subjects designs: Generalizing Loftus and Masson (1994) and avoiding the biases of alternative accounts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loftus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-012-0230-1</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="404" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pigeons&apos; discounting of probabilistic and delayed reinforcers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Myerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Calvert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.2010.94-113</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time discounting and time preference in animals: A critical review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hayden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-015-0879-3</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive influences on risk-seeking by rhesus macaques</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hayden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Heilbronner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Platt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="389" to="395" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal discounting predicts risk preferences in monkeys</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hayden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Platt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cub.2006.10.055</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gambling for Gatorade: Risk-sensitive decision making for fluid rewards in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hayden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Platt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10071-008-0186-8</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="207" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The description-experience gap in risky choice in nonhuman primates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Heilbronner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Hayden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-015-0924-2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="593" to="600" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The description-experience gap in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2009.09.004</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="523" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions from experience and the effect of rare events in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Barron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.0956-7976.2004.00715.x</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="534" to="539" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Coin: Conditional Inference Procedures in a Permutation Test Framework. R. package version 1.2-2</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hothorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hornik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Van De Wiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Winell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zeileis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://coin.r-forge.r-project.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory: An analysis of decision under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1914185</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="291" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risky choice in pigeons: Preference for amount variability using a token-reinforcement system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lagorio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hackenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.2012.98-139</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="154" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The evolution of decisionmaking under risk: framing effects in monkey risk preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lakshminarayanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2010.12.011</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="689" to="693" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">ez: Easy Analysis and Visualization of Factorial Experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=ez" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 4.4-0</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Of black swans and tossed coins: Is the descriptionexperience gap in risky choice limited to rare events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0020262</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extreme outcomes sway risky decisions from experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.1792</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="156" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward context determines risky choice in pigeons and humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pisklak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rsbl.2014.0451</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biology Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Remembering the best and worst of times: Memories for extreme outcomes bias risky decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-013-0542-9</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin and Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="636" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rapid makes risky: Time pressure increases risk seeking in decisions from experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/20445911.2015.1055274</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="921" to="928" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of memory in distinguishing risky decisions from experience and description</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17470218.2016.1220608</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2048" to="2059" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Comparative Inspiration: From puzzles with pigeons to novel discoveries with humans in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Under review</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Framing effects and risky decisions in starlings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Marsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kacelnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.042491999</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3352" to="3355" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Theories of probabilistic reinforcement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mazur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.1989.51-87</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of the previous outcome on probabilistic choice in rats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0030765</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology-Animal Behavior Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When good news leads to bad choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mcdevitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/jeab.192</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preference for fixed over variable access to food</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Menlove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Inden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Madden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03209709</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Learning and Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="503" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes Factor approaches for testing interval null hypotheses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Morey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rouder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0024377</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="419" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">BayesFactor: Computation of Bayes Factors for Common Designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Morey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rouder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=BayesFactor" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 0.9.12-4.2.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representing something out of nothing: The dawning of zero</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2016.08.008</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="830" to="842" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Translation of gambles and aspiration level effects in risky choice behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Laughhunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Crum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.26.10.1039</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1039" to="1060" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When good pigeons make bad decisions: Choice with probabilistic delays and outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pisklak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mcdevitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/jeab.177</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="251" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.R-project.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<pubPlace>Vienna, Austria</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognition and behavior in studies of choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Rachlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Logue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gibbon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Frankel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.93.1.33</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are risk-attitudes related across domains and response modes?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Schoemaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1451" to="1463" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Suboptimal choice behavior by pigeons</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Stagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Zentall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/PBR.17.3.412</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="412" to="416" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The logic of risk-sensitive foraging preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Stephens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0003-3472(81)80128-5</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="628" to="629" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The adaptive nature of impulsivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Stephens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Behavioral and Neurological Science of Discounting</title>
		<editor>G. J. Madden &amp; W. K. Bickel</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington, DC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>American Psychological Association</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="388" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">effsize: Efficient Effect Size Computation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Torchiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=effsize" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 0.7.1.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rational choice and the framing of decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1086/296365</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Business</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are probabilities overweighted or underweighted when rare outcomes are experienced (rarely)?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ungemach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-9280.2009.02319.x</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="479" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of sample and comparison ratio schedules on delayed matching to sample in the pigeon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wilkie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03209613</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Learning &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
