<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A race between Proactive and Reactive processes during perceptual decisions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lluís</forename><surname>Hernández-Navarro</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IDIBAPS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Rosselló 149</addrLine>
									<postCode>08036</postCode>
									<settlement>Barcelona</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ainhoa</forename><surname>Hermoso-Mendizabal</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IDIBAPS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Rosselló 149</addrLine>
									<postCode>08036</postCode>
									<settlement>Barcelona</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Duque</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IDIBAPS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Rosselló 149</addrLine>
									<postCode>08036</postCode>
									<settlement>Barcelona</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>De La Rocha</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Hyafil</surname></persName>
							<email>alexandre.hyafil@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IDIBAPS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Rosselló 149</addrLine>
									<postCode>08036</postCode>
									<settlement>Barcelona</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Brain and Cognition</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Universitat Pompeu Fabra</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Ramón Trias Fargas</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>25</addrLine>
									<postCode>08018</postCode>
									<settlement>Barcelona</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Center of Mathematical Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Campus UAB Edifici C</addrLine>
									<postCode>08193</postCode>
									<settlement>Bellaterra</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A race between Proactive and Reactive processes during perceptual decisions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Standard models of perceptual decision-making postulate that a response is triggered in reaction to stimulus presentation when the accumulated stimulus evidence reaches a decision threshold. This framework excludes however the possibility that informed responses are generated proactively at a time independent of stimulus. Here, we find that, in a free reaction time auditory task in rats, reactive and proactive responses coexist, suggesting that choice selection and motor initiation, commonly viewed as serial processes, are decoupled in general. We capture this behavior by a novel model in which proactive and reactive responses are triggered whenever either of two competing processes, respectively Action Initiation or Evidence Accumulation, reaches a bound. In both types of response, the choice is ultimately informed by the Evidence Accumulation process. By including the Action Initiation process, the model readily explains premature responses, urgency effects at long reaction times and the slowing of the responses as animals get satiated and tired during sessions. Moreover, it successfully predicts reaction time distributions when the stimulus was either delayed, advanced or omitted. Overall, these results fundamentally extend standard models of evidence accumulation in decision making by showing that proactive and reactive processes compete for the generation of responses.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>Our brains must constantly make perceptual decisions in the face of ambiguous and noisy stimuli. A very successful framework in cognitive psychology and neuroscience suggests that, under free response conditions, these perceptual decisions follow an accumulation to bound policy: sensory evidence is integrated over time until a given decision criterion is met <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Wald, 1947;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Good, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gold and Shadlen, 2002)</ref> . Computational models implementing this idea, such as the Drift-Diffusion Model (DDM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Ratcliff, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bogacz et al. , 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Ratcliff and McKoon, 2008)</ref> and race models <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Pike, 1971</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Pike, , 1973</ref> , provide a good quantitative account for reaction times (RTs) and choices in humans <ref type="bibr">(Milosavljevic et al. , no date;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Becker, 1958;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Ratcliff and Smith, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gold and Shadlen, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Simen et al. , 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Brunton, Botvinick and Brody, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Ratcliff et al. , 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Hanks and Summerfield, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Shevinsky and Reinagel, 2019)</ref> , non-human primates <ref type="bibr">Shadlen, 2001, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Ratcliff et al. , 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Hanks and Summerfield, 2017)</ref> , and rats <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Pardo-Vazquez et al. 2019)</ref>. A key assumption of the DDM and other accumulation models is that decision-making is essentially a serial process where the motor response is initiated reactively, only once the evidence accumulation has reached the decision boundary. Hence, choices and RTs are intrinsically coupled.</p><p>In real life, however, motor actions are not always triggered by a stimulus or external event. Proactive responses are at play in self-paced actions in the absence of stimuli <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Romo and Schultz, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Lee and Assad, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Murakami et al. , 2014)</ref> , like in foraging decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Jung et al. , 2014)</ref> , but they can also be particularly prevalent in sensory driven decisions when the stimulus onset can be anticipated <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Green, Smith and von Gierke, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Carpenter and Williams, 1995)</ref> or under strong time pressure <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Stanford et al. , 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Salinas et al. , 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Haith, Pakpoor and Krakauer, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Hardwick et al. , 2019)</ref> . Moreover, even when subjects accumulate a fixed amount of sensory evidence before eliciting a response, reaching this criterion may at times take too long <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Churchland, Kiani and Shadlen, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Drugowitsch et al. , 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Thura et al. , 2012)</ref> . In those circumstances, subjects may need to proactively terminate the accumulation process and trigger a response independently of the accumulated evidence. Therefore, although previous studies characterizing proactive and reactive responses have implicitly assumed that they represent distinct response modes deployed in different contexts, the two may actually coexist. The possible coexistence of proactive and reactive processes remains unknown, and so are the mechanisms describing their possible interactions.</p><p>To address these questions, we analysed the RTs and choices of rats in an auditory discrimination task <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Hermoso-Mendizabal et al. , 2020)</ref> . Our results show that, in addition to reactive responses triggered by sensory evidence accumulation, animals exhibit informed proactive responses whose timing is independent of the stimulus. This coexistence was captured by a novel model of perceptual decision-making, whereby responses can be triggered by either of two parallel dynamical processes: Action Initiation, yielding proactive responses; or Evidence Accumulation, yielding reactive responses. The model correctly captured reaction times distributions and choices, and their dependence on both stimulus characteristics as well as internal variables such as satiety and fatigue. Overall, these results extend standard models of decision-making by showing that, in freely-timed paradigms, both evidence accumulation and action initiation run in parallel and compete with each other to be the triggers of our actions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RESULTS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reaction time auditory task</head><p>We trained rats in two variants of a reaction-time auditory discrimination task <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Hermoso-Mendizabal et al. , 2020)</ref>  <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1</ref>). On each variant, an acoustic stimulus was played after a 300 ms fixation period at the center port, and interrupted once the animal withdrew from the center port to make a response by poking at one of the two side ports. Since the fixation period was constant, animals could predict the time of the stimulus onset. Withdrawal of the center port before stimulus onset, i.e. fixation breaks (FB), led to trial abortion. The stimulus was a superposition of two amplitude-modulated (AM) sounds and the animals were rewarded for correctly discriminating the sound with the higher average intensity. The two sounds were either two pure tones with different frequency ( frequency discrimination task, Group 1, n = 10) or two noise bursts coming from the left and the right speaker ( laterality discrimination task , for Groups 2-4, n= 16). The discrimination difficulty of each stimulus (i.e. stimulus strength s ) set the relative amplitude of each sound. Stimulus sequences included serial correlations to study expectation-mediated choice biases (see Supp. Methods). For our current analysis, we focus however on trials following an error, where we have previously shown that animals do not leverage on the serial correlations to bias their choices ( unbiased trials) (Hermoso-Mendizabal et al. , 2020) ( <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig.  1</ref>). The results obtained in this condition also held for expectation-biased trials (see below).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fig. 1 | Auditory discrimination task. a,</head><p>The initiation of each trial was cued by a center port LED. Following the cue, rats poked in the center port and the fixation period (300 ms) started. At the end of the fixation period, the stimulus was presented, consisting in a mixture of two AM sounds, each of which is associated with reward in the Left (L) or Right (R) port. The two sounds differed in frequency (frequency discrimination task) or in the location of the sound source (lateralization discrimination task). After stimulus onset, the rats were free to withdraw from the center port to elicit a response, causing the stimulus to stop. Correct responses were rewarded with water and incorrect responses were punished by a time-out. b, Task temporal scheme: RT denotes the time from stimulus onset to center poke withdrawal.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decoupling of reaction times and choices</head><p>Standard models of evidence-to-bound integration predict that, as the stimulus strength increases, accuracy also increases, while reaction time (RT) decreases <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Ratcliff, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bogacz et al. , 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Ratcliff and McKoon, 2008)</ref> . As expected, in the frequency discrimination task, RTs did indeed decrease with stimulus strength s, indicating that at least a fraction of responses were reactive, although the overall mean modulation was weak (~2% FOV explained). Surprisingly however, RTs shorter than~90 ms were independent of stimulus strength ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2a</ref>). To assess more precisely how stimulus strength modulates RTs, we computed time delay curves , which measured the advancement of responses below a given RT as stimulus strength increased ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2b</ref>; Methods and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Supplementary Fig. 2</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Pardo-Vazquez et al. , 2019)</ref> . The time beyond which RTs showed a significant modulation with s was consistent across rats (mean stimulus modulation onset M=95 ms, SD=20 ms; vertical line in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2b</ref>). We called express responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Carpenter and Williams, 1995)</ref> the responses occurring between stimulus onset and this modulation onset, which accounted for 35% (SD=25%) of all responses. We wondered whether express responses corresponded to rushed responses in which rats did not have time to process the stimulus, and made a guess choice based on stimulus-independent factors. We found however, that categorization accuracy for express responses was well above chance and increased with stimulus strength in all animals, demonstrating that rats used the stimulus to determine their choice even in express responses <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 2c</ref>). This dependence was well illustrated by the tachometric curve, representing how choice accuracy varies with RT ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2d</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Stanford et al. , 2010)</ref> . During the interval of express responses, accuracy increased, until it reached a maximum and a relative plateau for non-express responses. These results also hold for both expectation-biased trials and for the laterality version of the task ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Supplementary Figs. 3 and 9</ref>).</p><p>Overall, the timing of rat responses seemed to follow two modes: express responses, where the timing was independent of evidence accumulation but the choice did depend on the stimulus; and slower responses, where both the timing and the choice accuracy depend on the stimulus. Express responses are incompatible with standard models of evidence accumulation and their extensions, because these models inherently rely on evidence bounding to trigger the response and therefore, they invariably predict a coupling between RT and stimulus strength for all responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bowman, Kording and Gottfried, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Drugowitsch et al. , 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Thura et al. , 2012)</ref> . Slower responses in contrast, could in principle be triggered by the same evidence accumulation process giving rise to choice selection, and thus seem compatible with standard models of evidence accumulation. Because of this dichotomy, we next developed a general model for perceptual decision-making that could account for the full spectrum of rats' responses found in our task.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Stanford et al. , 2010)</ref> , for different stimulus strength s values, averaged across rats. Reaction times were binned in windows of 10 ms. Vertical line: mean RT-stimulus modulation onset. Shaded areas: s.e.m.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A parallel model of action initiation and sensory evidence integration captures RT-stimulus decoupling</head><p>To capture the partial stimulus-independence of rat reaction times, we introduced a novel model, the Parallel Sensory Integration and Action Model (PSIAM) composed of: (1) a standard Evidence Accumulation process (EA) that integrates stimulus evidence over time and that is bounded by left and right decision bounds, i.e. a standard DDM <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3b, top</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Ratcliff, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bogacz et al. , 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Ratcliff and McKoon, 2008)</ref> ; (2) an independent Action Initiation process (AI) which reflects the preparation of a response. Because the fixation period preceding the stimulus was fixed, rats could prepare the motor action during this period in order to respond rapidly after stimulus onset, while maintaining a reasonable accuracy. The AI process represented such proactive timing signal <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Simen et al. , 2011)</ref> , and was implemented as a one-bounded diffusive process that ramped until it reached the Go bound, independently of stimulus. The PSIAM can generate two types of responses, proactive or reactive, depending on which of the two processes, the AI or the EA, reaches a bound first. If the AI process hits the Go bound first ( proactive response ; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 3a</ref>, bottom) a response is triggered, and the choice is given by the sign of the total accumulated evidence, i.e. the sign of the EA process <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3a, top)</ref>. This procedure is equivalent to an instantaneous collapse of EA bounds at the time of response <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3a)</ref>. In proactive responses, the timing of the response is thus completely independent of the stimulus strength. Conversely, if EA reaches a decision bound first ( reactive response ), it sets both RT and choice, and AI plays no role, as in a standard DDM <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3b)</ref>. In this framework, express responses correspond to proactive responses that took place before the EA could start triggering any response: this time corresponds to the sum of EA latency t E and the minimal EA integration-to-boundary time <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3a)</ref>.</p><p>We assessed the capacity of the PSIAM to quantitatively capture rat behavior by fitting the model to the RTs. The model nicely captured the shape of the RT distributions for each animal by identifying the two underlying components, i.e. the proactive and reactive responses (Figs. 3c; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Supplementary Fig. 4</ref>). This separation allowed the model to readily account for the fixation breaks (FBs), interpreted as proactive responses occurring before stimulus onset <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3c)</ref>. The model also captured how the upward deflection in the RT distributions, reflecting the earliest reactive responses, increased with stimulus strength ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig.  3c</ref>; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Supplementary Fig. 4</ref>, last column). The agreement between data and model in the RT pdfs is also visible in the time delay curves, which, as previously shown for the data <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 2b)</ref>, were all collapsed for express RTs, and displayed increasing modulation by stimulus strength afterwards ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 3d)</ref>. Furthermore, the model also captured the shape of the experimental tachometric curves <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3e</ref>). Note that animal choices were not used to estimate the parameters of the model, so the tachometric curves are direct predictions from the model (see Methods). The model captured the increase in accuracy for fast RTs (RT&lt; 100 ms), followed by a relatively flat plateau for intermediate RTs (from 100 to 300 ms). More importantly, the model provided an explanation for the shape of the tachometric curves: for express responses, where the time of integration of the EA process is set by the AI process, longer RTs allow for longer integration of stimulus evidence, leading to higher accuracy. Intermediate RTs were dominated on the other hand by reactive responses caused by the EA reaching a decision bound. For such responses, the PSIAM is equivalent to the standard DDM with constant bounds, where the accuracy is independent of RT <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Ratcliff, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bogacz et al. , 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Ratcliff and McKoon, 2008)</ref> . This accounts for the relatively flat tachometric curves at each stimulus strength s for these intermediate RTs. Of note, the PSIAM also captured the RT distributions and reproduced the time delay and tachometric curves for biased trials (Supplementary Figs. 5 and 6). Overall, the PSIAM successfully captured rats' complex patterns of RTs and choices by stipulating that response times were controlled by parallel, independent evidence accumulation and action initiation processes. The action initiation process (AI, red trace) starts ramping up with afferent latency t A aff after the fixation onset, with mean drift A , until it hits the Go boundary A . The evidence accumulation process (EA, black trace) starts in response to the stimulus onset and after an afferent, sensory latency t E aff , with a stimulus-dependent mean drift E , and symmetric decision bounds ± E . Reaction time is determined by the first of the AI and EA processes reaching a bound. For this example, AI reaches the Go bound first, triggering a proactive response after a motor latency t motor . The stimulus is stopped at the response time (middle scheme). The choice (Right) is then determined by the final sign of the EA process, after the full stimulus has been integrated. This read-out is illustrated by an instantaneous collapse of the decision bounds. b, Example of a reactive response, where the EA process reaches a decision bound first, which triggers a response after the motor latency t motor , setting both RT and choice; the AI process plays no role. Because from the behavioral perspective the actual latency is only the sum of afferent and motor latencies, we define for each process the effective latencies t A = t A aff + t motor and t E = t E aff + t motor . c, RT distribution for an example rat (gray bars; rat #12) and model fit (blue line) for maximum stimulus strength s= 1. The distributions of proactive (red) and reactive (green) RTs generated by the AI and EA processes working in isolation are also shown. d, Simulated time delay curves, generated from the PSIAM fit to RTs for each animal, averaged across rats (Group 1, n =10). Shaded areas: s.e.m. e, Simulated tachometric curves, predicted from fitting the PSIAM to each animal's RTs, averaged across rats. RT bin width is 10 ms; shaded areas: s.e.m.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proactive responses prevent longer reaction times</head><p>While our AI process can be thought of as an independent urgency signal, urgency signals have been mostly hypothesized to play a role in avoiding very long reaction times, rather than promoting very fast responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Drugowitsch et al. , 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Thura et al. , 2012)</ref> . We thus wondered whether the AI could play a role beyond express responses, at long RTs. By construction, PSIAM responses are faster when both EA and AI processes are taken into account than when EA is considered in isolation <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 4a</ref>, blue, green and red curves, respectively; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Supplementary Fig. 7</ref>). Proactive responses dominated fast RTs, whereas reactive responses took over for intermediate RTs; however, proactive responses contributed as much as reactive responses at long RTs ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 4b; Supplementary Fig. 8</ref>). These long proactive responses imply that, in those trials, the EA process had still not reached the decision bound, and thus the AI process acted as an urgency signal that prevented very slow reactive responses. Moreover, because in those trials the evidence level is lower than the decision bound, their associated accuracy should also be lower than for reactive choices with the same RT. In other words, the increase in the fraction of proactive responses should thus be accompanied by a reduction in categorization accuracy. We tested this prediction by extending the tachometric curves to these very long, infrequent RTs. As predicted by the PSIAM, we found a significant decrease in accuracy for long RTs ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 4c-d</ref>). In sum, AI did not only promote express responses but it also shaped slow responses, hindering their occurrence at the expense of reduced accuracy for long RTs. To better resolve the tail of the distribution we used a logarithmic scale. Notice how the tail of the PSIAM distribution has been substantially trimmed with respect to the distributions of proactive alone (red) and reactive alone (green) RTs generated by the AI and EA processes working in isolation. For very long RTs (above 600 ms), lapse responses, modelled as random guesses, dominate the pdf (black curve; average 7±3 % of the total responses; see Methods and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Supplementary Fig. 7</ref>). Distribution of lapse RTs is shown in black. b, Proportion of proactive, reactive and lapse responses vs. RT for the same example rat as in a . c, Tachometric curves for different stimulus strength s values, averaged across rats. Open circles indicate accuracy for responses of RT&gt;600 ms. Shaded areas and error bars: s.e.m. d, Simulated tachometric curves up to 700 ms, averaged across rats; shaded areas: s.e.m.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Manipulating stimulus presentation uncovers proactive and reactive responses</head><p>The PSIAM core hypothesis is that, on each trial, animals prepare a proactive response which is executed independently of the presentation of the stimulus, unless a reactive response is triggered first. The model then predicts that, if the stimulus is removed, animal responses should all be proactive responses triggered by the AI process. We tested this in a new group of rats (Group 2, n =6; laterality discrimination task) where we omitted the presentation of the stimulus in a subset of trials ( silent catch trials, 10%), while the stimulus was normally played in the rest of the trials of the session ( standard trials , 90%) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5a</ref>, middle and top). The RT distributions for standard trials were very similar to those observed in Group 1 ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5b</ref>; <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 10</ref>, left column). Crucially, the distribution of proactive responses alone obtained from fitting the full PSIAM to RTs in standard trials predicted very accurately the distribution of RTs in silent trials ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5c</ref>; <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig.  10</ref>, right column). Removing the stimulus fully unveiled the RT distribution of proactive responses that was mixed with RTs from reactive responses in standard trials, providing evidence that within each trial the AI process evolves independently of the presentation of the stimulus.</p><p>The second basic hypothesis of the PSIAM is that proactive responses are triggered by a process time-locked to fixation onset, while reactive responses are triggered by a process locked to stimulus onset. The model predicts that varying the interval between fixation onset and stimulus onset should affect response timings by favoring one process over the other. In a second set of experiments, the stimulus was either advanced ( advanced stimulus trials, =-250 or -150 ms for Groups 2 or 3, respectively; 5% of trials), or delayed ( delayed stimulus trials, =+50 or +150 ms, Groups 2 or 3; 5% of trials) with respect to the standard condition ( =0, standard trials , 90%) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5a, bottom)</ref>. We first tested whether, in advanced and delayed stimulus trials, the RT distributions could be simply derived from the model fitted to standard trials but only shifting the onset of the EA process by the same amount . For delayed stimulus trials, the model with a shifted EA captured the RT distribution well: most responses were proactive, and the late stimulus onset caused a small bump of reactive responses at the tail of the RT distribution ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5e</ref>; <ref type="figure">Supplementary Figs</ref>. 11 and 12, right columns). This small impact of delayed stimulus was clearly visualized in time delay curves, which diverged from silent trials after an extra delay of compared to standard trials, as expected ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5f</ref>). In contrast, for advanced stimulus trials, simply advancing the EA by predicted faster responses than those observed in the rats <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 5d</ref>, solid blue curve; <ref type="figure">Supplementary Figs</ref>. 11 and 12, left columns, solid blue curves). This suggests that, when stimulus is presented ahead of the expected time, the EA process takes longer to reach the decision bounds than in standard trials. Indeed, simply allowing the latency t E to be longer in these advanced trials provided a much better fit of the RT distribution ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5d</ref>, dashed blue curve; Supplementary Figs. 11 and 12, left columns, dashed blue curves). This additional delay, which increased with the magnitude of the advancement <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 5g</ref>), could reflect attentional delays related to the unexpected timing of the stimulus onset <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Nobre, Correa and Coull, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Vangkilde, Coull and Bundesen, 2012)</ref> , or a signature of more complex interactions between AI and EA (see Discussion). Finally, adjusting the EA's drift v E instead of t E did not provide a better fit, and adjusting the two parameters together only caused a marginal average improvement ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 5h; Supplementary Fig. 13</ref>). Overall, these experiments revealed that the PSIAM could account for how RT distributions are affected by changes in stimulus timing, and showed that EA latency is increased when stimulus timing is unexpected. experiments with perturbed stimulus onset. a, In silent sessions, the stimulus was not presented in 10% of randomly selected catch trials (silent trial; Group 2, n =6). In advanced/delayed stimulus sessions, the stimulus was either advanced in 5% of trials ( =-150 ms for Group 2 and -250 ms for Group 3, n= 8) or delayed in 5% of trials ( =+150 ms in Group 2 and +50 ms in Group 3) with respect to the onset time in standard trials. Responses were valid if they occurred after stimulus onset in advanced stimulus trials, and after fixation offset in silent and delayed stimulus trials. b, RT distribution for an example rat (gray bars; rat #43) and model fit (blue line) for maximum stimulus strength ( s =1) in standard trials taken from sessions with silent catch trials. The distributions of proactive alone (red) and reactive alone (green) RTs generated by the AI and EA processes working in isolation are also shown. Vertical dashed line: stimulus onset. c, RT distribution in silent trials from the same rat shown in b (gray bars). Model prediction corresponds to the RT distribution of proactive alone responses obtained from standard trials (red line; same as in b ). d, Same as in panel b but for a different example rat in trials with advanced stimulus ( =-150 ms; rat #44). Model prediction corresponds to advancing the reactive alone density from standard trials by 150 ms (green line) while keeping the AI density (red line) unchanged (solid blue curve). Dashed blue curve shows model fit, where the EA parameter t E was fitted while keeping other EA and AI parameters unchanged. e, Same as in panel d for delayed stimulus trials, but delaying the isolated EA density by 150 ms in the model prediction. f, Time delay curves in standard and delayed ( =+150 ms) trials for maximum stimulus strength ( s =1) versus silent trials (reference), averaged across rats. Dotted black line is the same as the standard condition, shifted +150 ms for comparison. Vertical line marks the onset of the delayed stimulus. Shaded areas show s.e.m. g-h, Difference in the fitted values for t E (g) and v E (f) between standard and advanced/delayed trials at each stimulus onset delay . Line: average across animals; error bars: s.e.m.; diamonds (Group 2) and circles (Group 3): individual rats.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Slowing of the responses along the session is mediated by a decrease in AI speed</head><p>The existence of the dual mechanism for response timing in the PSIAM suggests that the speed of response could be regulated by two different mechanisms: by a change in the decision bounds of the EA process, as classically reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bogacz et al. , 2010)</ref> ; or by a modulation of the speed of the AI process, taking place independently of evidence accumulation. We assessed whether the systematic slowing of the RTs observed within each session in every animal <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 6a</ref>) was mediated by the modulation of AI, at odds with the classical account of slowing based on decision bounds. Cumulative RT distributions sorted by trial index showed that there were fewer fixation breaks and fewer express responses at the end compared with the beginning of the session <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 6b)</ref>. In other words, the slowing already occured for responses triggered even before any reactive response could be performed <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 6c</ref>). This suggested that the slowing was due at least in part to changes in the AI. We thus incorporated within-session slowing in the model by allowing the drift of the AI to decrease linearly with trial number within each session, while keeping the EA parameters constant across the session. Remarkably, this simple modification captured quantitatively the change in time delay curves observed within the session <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 6d)</ref>. The model reproduced the non-monotonicity of the curves with a dip around 130 ms, indicating that the slowing in RTs was not as severe in that range of reaction times. In the PSIAM, this corresponded to the range where reactive responses, which remained unchanged throughout the sessions, dominated over proactive responses <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figs. 3c and 6d</ref>, top inset; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Supplementary Fig. 8</ref>). Overall, the analysis suggests that the AI process, but not the EA, was affected by internal factors that changed consistently within each session, mediating a gradual slowing of responses. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fatigue and satiety cause within session slowing by modulating AI speed</head><p>The observed slowing of responses along the session could be linked to a change in two distinct internal variables of the animal <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Logue and Peña-Correal, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Richards et al. , 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Simon et al. , 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Reinagel, 2018</ref>) that increased as the session progressed: physical fatigue and satiety <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 7a, center and right)</ref>. The number of completed trials and the amount of consumed reward since the beginning of the session provided proxies for fatigue and satiety, respectively. In order to disentangle the contribution of each of these factors, we performed additional experiments where the size of the reward was varied across sessions (Group 4, n= 4; laterality discrimination task; see Methods). We first observed that the proportion of fast proactive responses (RT &lt; 50 ms) steadily decreased with trial index for all reward conditions, but the impact of reward size on RTs switched gradually along the session: while at the start of the session, a larger reward lead to a larger fraction of fast responses, the effect switched at the end of the session <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 7b</ref>). To explain this, we incorporated fatigue and satiety in the model by allowing the drift of the AI process to change linearly with trial number and with the amount of consumed reward within the session <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig.  7a, top row)</ref>. Moreover, since the reward size, fixed within a session, could also affect the rats' overall motivation and speed, we also let AI drift depend linearly with the reward size <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 7a, left column)</ref>. This extended model captured the impact of reward size on how the proportion of fast responses changed throughout the session <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 7c)</ref>. Trial index and consumed reward were found to have a negative impact on AI drift, i.e. slowed the AI process, whereas larger reward size had a positive impact, i.e. sped up the AI process. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig.  7d)</ref>. Thus, the gradual switch of the reward size dependence along the session arose from the opposite contributions of reward size and reward consumption: while at the start of the session, animals in large reward sessions were faster because they were more motivated, at the end of the session the effect reversed because they were also more satiated. In sum, the analysis shows that the AI process was subject to systematic variations within and across sessions by means of changes in three factors: while larger reward sped up the AI process, fatigue and satiety slowed it down. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DISCUSSION</head><p>We used an acoustic discrimination task to characterize the mechanisms underlying the timing and choices of rats' perceptual decisions. We found that the pattern of responses could not be solely explained by traditional models of perceptual decision making whereby responses are triggered in reaction to the accumulated evidence crossing the bound <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Carpenter and Williams, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Drugowitsch et al. , 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Verdonck and Tuerlinckx, 2016)</ref> . In addition to such reactive responses, animals generated proactive responses in which the timing was stimulus-independent but the choice was stimulus-dependent ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2)</ref>. A novel model, the PSIAM, proposes that each response type is triggered by one of two parallel processes: the Action Initiation, a proactive timing process that starts in anticipation of stimulus onset and ramps up until reaching a Go bound; and the Evidence Accumulation, a process initiated by the stimulus presentation that integrates sensory evidence until reaching one of the decision bounds <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3)</ref>. The two processes run in parallel and race to induce a response, which is triggered as soon as one of the two reaches its respective bound. The Action Initiation process not only mediated premature responses but also generated slow responses, effectively implementing an urgency to respond when the EA process took too long to hit a decision bound <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 4)</ref>. As predicted by the model, proactive and reactive responses, which are locked respectively on the fixation onset and the stimulus onset, were dissociated in a second set of experiments where stimulus onset was perturbed <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 5)</ref>.</p><p>In psychophysics, it is common to find a small fraction of responses which are too fast to be triggered by the stimulus <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Carpenter and Williams, 1995)</ref> . They are usually considered as random anticipated responses and removed from subsequent analysis. Here we showed compelling evidence that, in our task, those express responses represented the lower tail of a wide distribution of proactive responses, whose timing was independent of the stimulus. For intermediate RTs, these proactive responses were present but they were mingled with reactive responses <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3c)</ref>, as confirmed by experiments in which we omitted or shifted stimulus onset <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 5)</ref>. Three factors in our task could be promoting the anticipation of the Action Initiation process leading to a large fraction of proactive responses. First, the stimulus onset occurred at a fixed time interval after fixation onset (i.e. a fixed foreperiod), so that the rats could reliably time their withdrawal from the central port right after stimulus onset <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Green, Smith and von Gierke, 1983)</ref> . A random fixation period <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Roitman and Shadlen, 2002)</ref> would probably lead to a more conservative strategy where the proactive process is slowed to avoid too early responses. Of note, temporal expectations also led to a reduction of the non-decision time of the EA process when the stimulus appeared at the predicted time in comparison to when it appeared earlier or later <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 5g)</ref>, in agreement with a recent observation (van den Brink et al. , no date) . Second, because of sensory delays, and because the response involves a full orienting body movement lasting 300-500 ms, the rat had time for finishing stimulus integration between leaving the central port (which interrupts the stimulus) and poking at one of the lateral ports. This makes express responses a viable strategy in which subjects leave the port right after stimulus onset, before stimulus can influence the motor plan, and integrate the sensory information while executing the orienting movement. The same type of online updating strategy could be applied for responses performed by arm movements, which can be swiftly adjusted en route to the target point <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Resulaj et al. , 2009)</ref> ; but perhaps not for more ballistic responses such as saccades or button presses. And third, the structure of the trial sequence allowed rats to partially predict the category of the upcoming stimulus based on previous trials' responses and rewards <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Hermoso-Mendizabal et al. , 2020)</ref> . This partial predictability allowed animals to reach~65% accuracy for minimal stimulus durations in biased trials <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Supplementary Fig. 3</ref>; note however that most of our analyses were performed on unbiased analyses, where rats did not use trial history to predict the next stimulus category). These features allow achieving both very fast and accurate responses, especially for high stimulus strength where short stimuli provide enough evidence to reach high levels of accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Stanford et al. , 2010)</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 2d)</ref>. In other words, animals are fooling the speed-accuracy trade-off <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Smeets, Oostwoud Wijdenes and Brenner, 2016)</ref> .</p><p>The AI process allows modulating reaction times not only based on the structure of the task, but also depending on motivational factors. We found that RTs slowed down within the session in all our animals ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 6)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Davis, Roma and Hienz, 2016)</ref> . Previous literature has investigated whether the impact of session time on RTs reflects the accumulated fatigue (physical and/or cognitive) or the increase of satiety. One study found that, in a delay discounting task, the increase in uncompleted trials observed during the session was larger for aged rats compared to young animals <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Simon et al. , 2010)</ref> . Since food consumption did not differ between the two age groups, the authors argued that the main driving factor was fatigue rather than satiation. In humans too, responses slow down when the subject is fatigued <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Welford, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Faber, Maurits and Lorist, 2012)</ref> . On the other hand, other studies have found that food or water satiety increases the latency of responses in rats and pigeons <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Logue and Peña-Correal, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Richards et al. , 1997)</ref> . We disentangled the effect of fatigue and satiety by varying the reward size across sessions in new experiments, and found that both factors contributed to within-session slowing <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 7)</ref>. Furthermore, our model-based approach allowed us to identify the cognitive mechanisms underlying this effect: both fatigue and satiety impact the drift of the AI process, i.e. slow down the initiation of proactive responses. On the contrary, increasing reward size led to higher AI drift, and thus faster responses. This shows that internal states can modulate decision-making through the AI, without modulating Evidence Accumulation.</p><p>The idea that the timing of perceptual decisions depends on an internal sense of time pressure is not novel <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Churchland, Kiani and Shadlen, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bowman, Kording and Gottfried, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Drugowitsch et al. , 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Thura et al. , 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Hanks, Kiani and Shadlen, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Purcell and Kiani, 2016)</ref> . Several previous studies have proposed the existence of an urgency signal that interacts with the integration of sensory evidence in order to avoid slow responses. A popular idea is to incorporate urgency directly into the DDM, while keeping decision-making as a serial process where action initiation follows evidence integration. This can be done by gradually collapsing the decision bounds <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bowman, Kording and Gottfried, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Drugowitsch et al. , 2012)</ref> , or by a ramping evidence-independent signal that either increases the gain of evidence accumulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Thura et al. , 2012)</ref> or adds a non-specific input to all possible response activations, promoting motor actions <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Churchland, Kiani and Shadlen, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Hanks, Kiani and Shadlen, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Purcell and Kiani, 2016)</ref> . All these mechanisms account for the fact that very slow responses are usually less frequent in participants than what the DDM with fixed bounds would predict. However, in all these extensions of the DDM, RTs always depend on the evidence accumulation since all responses are triggered after reaching a decision bound, so these models cannot explain express responses, where RT is independent of stimulus strength whereas choice is contingent on stimuli (35% of all responses in our dataset, SD=25%; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2)</ref>. By contrast, the PSIAM provides an alternative approach where a single mechanism, i.e. proactive responses, can account for (1) express responses yielding stimulus-independent RTs and stimulus-dependent choices ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 3d-e)</ref>, and (2) the low probability of very slow responses found in the same dataset <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 4a)</ref>. In the PSIAM, AI sets a stimulus-independent internal deadline for triggering the response, avoiding long accumulation-to-bound processes in EA. As such, the action of the AI can be viewed as provoking the instantaneous collapse of decision bounds on the EA at a stochastic time defined by the AI bound crossing. While in our task the AI most often reached the Go bound shortly after stimulus onset, under other circumstances, a slower AI drift could be used to trigger proactive responses after a longer stimulus duration. Indeed, a slower and more precise AI process can shift the timing of proactive responses, from early to late responses, i.e. from causing express responses to ensuring an upper bound on integration time <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">(Fig. 8a)</ref>. Such a change also leads to a larger drop in accuracy associated with long RTs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">(Fig. 8b)</ref>, an effect that is commonly observed in the decay of tachometric curves <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Murphy, Boonstra and Nieuwenhuis, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Devine et al. , 2019)</ref> , but is usually attributed to either the variability in the drift of the evidence accumulation process or the gradual collapse of the decision bounds. Adjusting AI parameters in the PSIAM provided a more flexible way to set the speed-accuracy trade-off compared to modulating the decision bounds of the EA process <ref type="bibr">(Milosavljevic et al. , no date;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Reddi and Carpenter, 2000)</ref> . Hence, while rats may lay on the impatient side of AI, AI in humans and non-humans primates performing classical perceptual tasks may primarily be used to prevent very long reactive responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Murphy, Boonstra and Nieuwenhuis, 2016)</ref> . Lapse responses were not incorporated into the model. We also simulated tachometric curves for the proactive (pink) and reactive (purple) responses; these two tachometric curves are independent of AI manipulations, and provide lower and upper bounds on accuracy, respectively.</p><p>The PSIAM is also related to two previous models of sensory guided responses with a proactive component. In one study, human subjects were forced to respond "earlier-than-normal" in a visually guided reaching task <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Haith, Pakpoor and Krakauer, 2016)</ref> . A simple model separating the when and what decisions into two separate processes could elegantly explain RTs and choices: the Action Initiation process always determined the timing of response, whereas a second stimulus-dependent Action Preparation process determined the choice but never the timing <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Haith, Pakpoor and Krakauer, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Hardwick et al. , 2019)</ref> . While this model, like the PSIAM, can generate proactive responses where the choice is informed by the Evidence Accumulation process, it cannot explain that some reaction times depend on stimulus evidence, a clear signature of reactive responses present in our data <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figs. 3 and 5</ref>) and in many other studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Roitman and Shadlen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Pardo-Vazquez et al. , 2019</ref>) . An alternative model, based on data from monkeys performing an oculomotor visually-guided task under strong external time pressure, proposes a race between choice-selective Action Initiation processes which are accelerated or decelerated by the presence of a stimulus <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Salinas et al. , 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Stanford et al. , 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Shankar et al. , 2011)</ref> . By combining proactive and reactive processes into a single "stimulus-dependent race-to-bound" process, the model can capture the existence, like in our data, of two underlying components of the RT distribution: responses that are time locked to the onset of the foreperiod (the fixation onset in our task) and responses that are time-locked to the stimulus onset <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Stanford et al. , 2010)</ref> . The PSIAM differs however from this model in two important aspects. First, the PSIAM incorporates the classical mechanisms of Evidence Accumulation, which captures the dependency of RTs on stimulus strength in standard free response paradigms, something not present in the "accelerated race" model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Stanford et al. , 2010)</ref> . Second, the PSIAM grounds on separate accumulation-to-bound EA and AI processes, whereas the accelerated race model features proactive and reactive mechanisms in a single accumulation-to-bound process. A single accumulation-to-bound process is incompatible with responses where the stimulus impacts choice but not RT, such as express responses in our rats. Thus, our data support that reactive responses are mediated by a separate accumulation-to-bound process independent from the proactive AI process. A direct extension of the PSIAM, inspired by the accelerated race model, is to assume that EA does not trigger responses when reaching bound but rather accelerates the ongoing AI process towards the Go bound <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Stanford et al. , 2010)</ref> . This extension of PSIAM would reconcile the two models, and could account, for the increased EA latency found in advanced trials <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 5d,g</ref>).</p><p>Activity in multiple brain areas shows correlates of processes like the AI or EA of the PSIAM. Neurons showing slow ramping activity preceding proactive responses have been found in several brain areas such as the cortical supplementary motor area <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Romo and Schultz, 1992)</ref> , the frontal eye field <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Stanford et al. , 2010)</ref> , the secondary motor cortex <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Murakami et al. , 2014)</ref> , the lateral intraparietal area <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Maimon and Assad, 2006)</ref> and the basal ganglia <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Lee and Assad, 2003)</ref> . Interestingly, some neurons showed ramping activity specifically before proactive but not reactive responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Romo and Schultz, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Maimon and Assad, 2006)</ref> . Similarly, a large number of cortical and subcortical areas has been suggested to encode accumulated stimulus evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kim and Shadlen, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Roitman and Shadlen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gold and Shadlen, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ding and Gold, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Thura and Cisek, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Hanks et al. , 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Yartsev et al. , 2018)</ref> . There is conflicting evidence regarding whether neural markers of accumulated evidence are influenced by the level urgency <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Churchland, Kiani and Shadlen, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Park et al. , 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Thura and Cisek, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Steinemann, O'Connell and Kelly, 2018)</ref> . Thus, despite being a phenomenological model aimed to describe behavioral responses, by postulating the existence of race dynamics between proactive and reactive processes, the PSIAM model may become an instrumental tool to identify the underlying mechanisms of neural ramping dynamics during perceptual decisions.</p><p>In conclusion, our analyses support a model where decision-making is mediated by two separate processes, Action Initiation and Evidence Accumulation, which race to trigger a behavioral response. They also point to the AI process as a flexible mechanism allowing strategic and idiosyncratic adjustments of the action timing to multiple factors, such as temporal and choice predictability, motivation and urgency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>METHODS</head><p>All experimental procedures were approved by the local ethics committee (Comité d'Experimentació Animal, Universitat de <ref type="bibr">Barcelona,</ref><ref type="bibr">Spain,</ref><ref type="bibr">Ref 390/14)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Animal Subjects</head><p>Animals were male Long-Evans rats ( n = 26, 350-650g; Charles River), pair-housed during behavioral training and kept on stable conditions of temperature (23 o C) and humidity (60%) with a constant light-dark cycle (12h:12h, experiments were conducted during the light phase). Rats had free access to food, but water was restricted to behavioral sessions. Free access to water was provided on days with no experimental sessions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task description</head><p>Rats in Group 1 ( n = 10) performed an auditory reaction-time two-alternative forced choice task. Specifically, this group of rats performed a frequency discrimination version of the task <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Hermoso-Mendizabal et al. , 2020)</ref> . Briefly, at each trial, an LED on the center port indicated that the rat could start the trial by poking in <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1)</ref>. After a fixation period of 300 ms, the LED switched off and an acoustic stimulus consisting in a superposition of two amplitude-modulated frequencies was presented (see details below). Each frequency was associated with a specific side and reward was available at one of the two lateral ports, depending on the dominant frequency. Animals could respond any time after stimulus onset. Correct responses were rewarded with a 24 µL drop of water and incorrect responses were punished with a bright light and a 5 s time-out. Trials in which the rat did not make a side poke response within 4 seconds after leaving the center port were considered invalid trials and were excluded from the analysis (average of 0.4% invalid trials per animal). Withdrawal from the center port before stimulus onset cancelled stimulus presentation (Fixation Break, FB). After a FB, rats were allowed to initiate fixation again, with no time-out, and as many times as necessary until fixation was complete (indicated by center LED offset). Rats performed an average of 694 trials per session (range: 335 -1188), one session per day lasting 60-90 min, 6 days per week, during 9 months. The data presented in this study was taken from the period after training yielding an average of 56,506 valid trials per rat.</p><p>Rats in Group 2 ( n = 6), Group 3 (n=8) and Group 4 ( n =4) performed an intensity level discrimination version of the task <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Pardo-Vazquez et al. , 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Hermoso-Mendizabal et al. , 2020)</ref> . In this task, two speakers positioned at both sides of the box played simultaneously an amplitude-modulated white noise. Rats had to discriminate the side with the loudest sound (right or left) and seek reward in the associated port. The details of the task are exactly the same as in the previous one, but in these groups the time-out after error responses was of 2 s and was not associated with bright light. Rats in Group 2 performed sessions with silent catch trials (random 10% of trials without sounds; range: 45-50 consecutive sessions) in which they could respond any time after the 300 ms fixation offset, as in standard trials. Rats in Groups 2 and 3 performed sessions with advanced/delayed stimulus catch trials (random 10% of trials varying sound onset; 45-50 consecutive sessions). For 5% randomly selected trials, the stimulus onset time was advanced = -150 ms for animals in Group 2 and = -250 ms for rats in Group 3 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 5a</ref>, advanced stimulus trials); and for another 5% of trials, it was delayed =+ 150 ms for Group 2 and +50 ms for Group 3 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 5a</ref>, delayed stimulus trials). For these advanced/delayed catch trials, stimulus strength was always set to maximum ( s =1) to gain statistical power, and to enhance evidence-triggered, reactive responses. In advanced stimulus and standard trials, rats could respond any time after fixation offset (either at 150 or at 50 ms, and at 300 ms, respectively), which coincided with stimulus onset. In delayed stimulus trials, rats could respond any time after fixation offset (300 ms), which was dissociated of stimulus onset (either at 450 or at 350 ms). For rats in Group 2, which participated in silent and advanced/delayed stimulus sessions, the order of the sessions was balanced across animals, with 3 rats starting with the advanced/delayed catch trials sessions and 3 starting in the silent catch trials sessions. The overall fraction of catch trials was maintained low at 10% to avoid animals modifying substantially their original behavior during these sessions.</p><p>Rats in Group 4 performed sessions with a modified water reward size. In small-reward sessions, the amount of water obtained in each correct response (12 l) was half of the reward in standard sessions. In large reward size sessions, the amount of water obtained (48 l) was double the amount in standard sessions <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 7a, left)</ref>. The three types of sessions were randomly interleaved.</p><p>For Group 1, the behavioral setup (Island Motion, NY) was controlled by a custom software developed in Matlab (Mathworks, Natick, MA), based on the open-source BControl framework (http://brodylab.princeton.edu/bcontrol). For Groups 2-4, the behavioral setup was controlled by BPod electronic boards (by Sanworks) and the task was run using the Python-based open software package PyBPod (http://pybpod.com/).</p><p>Additional details on the acoustic stimulus and the stimulus sequence are provided in the Supplementary Information Methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reaction times</head><p>Reaction time (RT) was defined as the time elapsed from stimulus onset to center port withdrawal <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1b)</ref>. For standard trials, RT matched the stimulus duration, as stimulus was switched off at center port withdrawal. For silent, advanced stimulus and delayed stimulus trials, RT was measured with respect to standard stimulus onset. Fixation breaks (FBs; 16±5 % of total withdrawals, mean ± standard deviation) were defined as withdrawals from the center port during the fixation period (300 ms for standard, silent and delayed stimulus trials; either 150 or 50 ms for advanced stimulus trials). Only the first center port withdrawals of each trial, either FB or RT, were analyzed: after a FB, further FBs and the subsequent valid response were discarded to remove possible serial effects within a single trial. Trials with RTs longer than 1s were removed from the analysis (0.5±0.6 % of total withdrawals).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RT-evidence Modulation onset</head><p>The onset times for the modulation of the RT distributions by the stimulus strength ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig.  2a-b)</ref> were computed similarly as in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Supplementary Fig. 2b</ref> of <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Pardo-Vazquez et al. , 2019)</ref> . For each time t , we computed a one-tailed Kolmogorov-Smirnoff test comparing the RT cumulative distributions for trials with strongest and weakest stimulus evidence (stimulus strength s =1 versus stimulus strength s =0), including both biased and unbiased trials, and excluding all reaction times larger than t. For each rat, we defined the modulation onset as the minimal value of t at which this comparison became significant (p&lt;0.05).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time delay curves</head><p>Time delay curves assess how much faster or slower is a given stochastic time variable with respect to a reference distribution; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Supplementary Fig. 3</ref> of <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Pardo-Vazquez et al. , 2019)</ref> . Intuitively, it represents the horizontal distance at any time point between a given cumulative distribution and a reference cumulative distribution ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Supplementary Fig. 2)</ref>. At a given time point T , time delay value is defined as the time difference T r -T , where T r is the time at which the value of the reference cumulative matches the value of the cumulative of interest at T , i.e. C(T) = C r (T r ) . Positive time delay means that, at time T, there is a larger proportion of RTs lower or equal to T in the condition of interest than in the reference condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Parallel Sensory Integration and Action Model (PSIAM)</head><p>In order to characterize the patterns of rat RTs and choices, we built the Parallel Sensory Integration and Action model (PSIAM) by combining a standard DDM with constant bounds <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Ratcliff, 1978</ref>) (i.e. Evidence Accumulation process or EA process) with a second drift diffusion process modeling the timing of proactive responses (Action Initiation process or AI process; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 3a-b, bottom red traces)</ref>. EA is a Wiener process which integrates the evidence provided by the stimulus over time, following:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">•ξ(t), dt dx(t) = V E + σ E for − , ) x ∈ ( θ E + θ E (1) 0, dt dx(t) = for ±θ x = E</formula><p>where x(t) is the EA process representing the instantaneous accumulated evidence. The parameter V E is the drift which only depends on the stimulus evidence (see below); E is the noise variance, set to 1 to make the model identifiable; and is a white noise stochastic (t) ξ process which represents the stimulus temporal fluctuations as well as the internal noise associated with the accumulation process. The EA process is initiated at value x = z E (starting offset) with a delay of with respect to stimulus onset (afferent latency); x = t E af f t stim ± E are the two symmetric decision bounds <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3a-b, and see below)</ref>.</p><p>Action Initiation represents the preparation of a commitment to take a decision; it is modeled as an independent, one-bound DDM <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Wald, 1947)</ref> :</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">ζ(t), dt dy(t) = V A + σ A for y &lt; θ A (2) 0, dt dy(t) = for y = θ A</formula><p>where the parameter V A is the drift of the AI; A is the noise variance (always set to 1); and is a white noise stochastic process representing the internal variability associated with (t) ζ the precise timing of the Go action. The AI process is initiated at fixation onset with a delay of (afferent latency); and A is the action bound ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 3a-b)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">t A af f</formula><p>The PSIAM model distinguishes two types of responses, proactive and reactive, depending on the outcome of the "race" between the AI and the EA processes, i.e. depending on which process reaches the bound first. Reactive responses are generated when either of the two EA boundaries is reached first; the choice is then defined by which bound is hit (by convention, the upper bound corresponds to the rightwards choice, and the lower bound to the leftwards choice). Proactive responses are generated when the AI threshold is reached first; the choice is then defined as a direct read-out of the sign of the EA process after (t) x the interrupted stimulus is integrated. This is equivalent to an instantaneous collapse of both EA's decision thresholds, i.e. a vertical bound in the EA <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 3a)</ref>. The RT at each trial is thus set by the first of the two processes to reach the bound, and corresponds to the time elapsed from stimulus onset to first bound hit, with an additional efferent delay t motor representing motor latency. The probability density function (pdf) p ( t ) and the cumulative distribution function (cdf) c ( t ) of the RTs depend on the pdf and cdf of the RTs that would be generated by either the AI ( p A ( t ) and c A ( t )) or by the EA ( p E ( t ) and c E ( t )) in isolation, through <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fisher and Tippett, 1928)</ref> :</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">•(1 ) •(1 ) p = p A − c E + p E − c A (3) •c c = c A + c E − c A E<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where we have dropped the dependence on t to ease the notation. The distribution of the RTs generated in isolation by the AI is an Inverse Gaussian (IG) distribution (a.k.a. Wald distribution), so that the pdf and cdf for AI <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Tweedie, 1945;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Wald, 1947)</ref> are:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">(t |V , , ) xp p A A θ A t A = θ A • 1 √ 2π•(t−t ) A 3 • e − ( 2 V A 2 • (t−t ) A (t−t )−θ /V [ A A A] 2 ) (5) (t |V , , ) xp c A A θ A t A = Φ V ( A • √ t−t A (t−t )−θ /V A A A ) + e (− • V ) 2 A • θ A • Φ − ( V A • √ t−t A (t−t )+θ /V A A A )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where the parameter V A is the reduced drift ( A = 1) of the AI; A is the reduced single-threshold height from the starting value of the AI process; and is the t A = t A af f + t motor total AI latency, summing afferent and motor latencies. The independent RT pdf for the EA alone corresponds to that of the standard DDM with two constant bounds <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Wald, 1947;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Samuels and Feller, 1969)</ref> :</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">(t |V , , , ) p (t | , ,− , ) (t |V , , , ) p E E θ E Z E t E = E + + p E − = p E − − V E θ E Z E t E + p E − E θ E Z E t E (7) (t |V , , , ) p E − E θ E Z E t E = xp = π (2θ ) E 2 • e − • • ( V E (Z ) E + θ E − 2 V E 2 (t ) − t E ) • ∑ ∞ k=1 sin xp [ k•π• { 2θ E Z +θ E E } • e − • ( k π 2 2 2•(2θ ) E 2 (t ) − t E )] (8)</formula><p>where p E ± are the joint pdfs for RT and choice, with + and -for choice corresponding to upper bound and lower bound, respectively. The parameter V E represents the reduced drift ( E = 1); ± E represent the reduced upper and lower threshold values; Z E represents the reduced starting offset or bias; and represents the total response latency t E = t E af f + t motor time for the EA, summing afferent and motor latencies. The corresponding cumulative distribution c E is obtained by integrating Eq. 7 analytically over t .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model fit to reaction times data</head><p>The fit of the PSIAM to the experimental RTs data was performed under Maximum Likelihood Estimation (MLE), using simplex method (Matlab function fmincon ) with 20 random initial points in bounded parameter space to avoid local minima. Model parameters were estimated for each animal only based on RTs for all trials including FBs. The value of the EA starting point, EA drift and AI drift depended on trial conditions. EA drift V E scaled linearly with signed stimulus strength S (positive/negative sign for rightward/leftward evidence), and we fitted the proportionality parameter E , i.e. V E = E • S . For a given trial k , the signed stimulus strength S k was computed as the instantaneous evidence S k,f averaged across frames presented in this trial, i.e. &lt; S k,f &gt; f . To account for the slowing of the responses within each session <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 6a-b</ref>), AI drift scaled linearly with trial index k as V A,k = A0 + trial • k , and we fitted the parameters A0 and trial . EA initial offset Z E captured the animal's expectation of which response will be rewarded in the next trial. For unbiased trials, this offset was set to 0, i.e. no expectation. For biased trials ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Supplementary Figs. 3 and 5)</ref>, the value of the starting point was signed depending on the trial-dependent expectation of rewarded side b k = ±1 (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Methods)</ref>, so that Z E = z E • b k , where we fitted the parameter z E representing the magnitude of the animal's expectation. The rest of the parameters of the PSIAM were constant for each animal. Additionally, we included a Huber's -contamination model for MLE robustness <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Huber, 1964)</ref> . Contaminant responses were included to avoid estimation parameters to be biased by very early FBs (especially numerous after error trials) and very late RTs <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Ratcliff and Tuerlinckx, 2002)</ref> . Contaminant responses were modelled from the mixture of a decaying exponential distribution and a uniform distribution as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">p = c • p C + (1 ) − c • p model (9) •exp 1 ) tt p C (t |d, ) β = d • β (− •t) β + ( − d • c<label>(10)</label></formula><p>where p , p C and p model are the final, contaminant, and PSIAM densities respectively; the parameter c is the proportion of contaminant responses; d is the exponential-uniform mixture parameter; is the inverse of the exponential time constant; and ctt is the normalization constant for the uniform density alone. The PSIAM with contaminants has a total of 11 parameters: 4 for the AI (drift intercept A0 and trial-index weight trial , threshold A , and response latency time t A ); 4 for the EA (drift stimulus weight E , threshold E , response latency time t E , and starting offset z E ); and 3 parameters for the contaminant distribution (proportion of contaminant responses c , the exponential-uniform mixture parameter d , and the inverse of the exponential time constant ). We added lower bound and upper bounds in the parameter search, both to speed up the optimisation algorithm and to confine the search within a range of a priori defined values. The bounds in parameter space set for MLE were:</p><p>[0,12] s -1 for A0 ; [-2,1]•10 -2 s -1 •trial -1 for trial ; [0.1,10] for A ; <ref type="bibr">[-600,300]</ref>  There was one less parameter to fit for unbiased trials as we set z E to 0. The infinite series in the EA independent RT pdf (Eq. 8) and cdf were approximated numerically <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Navarro and Fuss, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Blurton, Kesselmeier and Gondan, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gondan, Blurton and Kesselmeier, 2014)</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model prediction for choice data</head><p>The PSIAM choice (Right/Left) corresponds to the sign of the final value of the EA process ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 3a-b</ref>). For each rat, we computed the choice prediction ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figs. 3e and 4d</ref>) by simulating the PSIAM (Eqs. 1-2) using MLE parameter values. It should be stressed that parameter MLE values were obtained using RTs data only, and not choices. We also included some trial-to-trial variability in the EA starting offset (otherwise choices for very short reaction times would always be determined by the side of Z E , i.e. the expectation, unlike what is observed in rats). The distribution of starting point was thus taken as a Beta distribution (stretched to cover the full domain of the EA process [-E , E ]). The parameters of the distribution were set such that it had mean z E and standard deviation equal to 10% of the interbound distance between bounds (i.e. 0.2• E ). Simulations were run by discretizing differential equations (Eqs. 1-2) using Euler method with a time step of 0.1 ms. We performed a total of 10 7 trial simulations per rat.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model prediction for reaction times in catch trials with manipulated stimuli</head><p>The density p silent of RTs in silent catch trials was predicted from the PSIAM using parameters fitted to the standard trials from the same sessions ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5b; Supplementary Fig.  10</ref>, left column). Since no stimulus was presented in silent trials, the prediction was that p silent = p A (Eq. 5), because responses were all proactive, i.e. were generated from the AI process operating in isolation ("AI alone" in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5b</ref> and <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 10</ref>).</p><p>For advanced/delayed trials, where the stimulus onset was advanced or delayed by , we first tested the prediction obtained from simply advancing or delaying the EA onset time t stim by . In a second analysis we fitted the value of the latency time t E and/or EA drift E separately for each delay condition, leaving other parameters unchanged ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 5d</ref>-e,g-h; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Supplementary Figs. 11 and 12</ref>, dashed blue curves, and 13) .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DATA CODE AVAILABILITY</head><p>Data and code will be made available on a public repository after the manuscript is published.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS:</head><p>during evidence accumulation', eLife , 7. doi: 10.7554/eLife.34929 .</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 2 |</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Decoupled reaction times and choices for express responses. a, RT cumulative distribution function (cdf) for different values of stimulus strength for an example animal (rat #11) in unbiased trials. Vertical line indicates the onset of the stimulus modulation on RT cdf computed for this rat (see Methods). b, Mean time delay curves for RT cdf in the frequency discrimination task, averaged across rats (Group 1, n = 10). Trials with uninformative stimulus (stim. strength s = 0) are used as reference (time delay ∆t = 0). Vertical line represents the mean modulation onset time (95 ms). Shaded areas: standard error of the mean (s.e.m). c, Accuracy on trials with RTs shorter than 50 ms as a function of stimulus strength s . Thick line denotes the group average; thin lines represent individual rats. Error bars represent s.e.m. d, Tachometric curves, i.e. accuracy as a function of reaction times</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 3 |</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Parallel Sensory Integration and Action model. a, Example of a proactive response generated by the PSIAM.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 4 |</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Reaction times and accuracy for long responses. a, RT distribution for an example rat (gray bars) and model fit (blue line) for medium stimulus strength ( s =0.5).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 5 |</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Reaction times in</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 6 |</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Within session slowing of responses. a, Mean RT as a function of trial position within the session. Thick line: group average, thin lines: individual rats (Group 1, n =10). Trials were grouped in 50 trial blocks. Error bars: s.e.m. b, RT cumulative distribution for different trial blocks for an example animal (rat #14). Color code in b-d indicates trial block. Vertical dashed line in b-d indicates stimulus onset. c, Time delay curves averaged across rats. Trial block 351-400 was taken as reference (i.e. corresponded to time delay ∆t = 0). d, Time delay curves simulated using the PSIAM fitted to the RTs for each animal, averaged across rats. Top inset: proportion of proactive vs reactive responses with RT as estimated by PSIAM for each animal, averaged across rats; shaded area: s.e.m. Left inset: sketch of the impact of trial index on AI's drift.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Fig. 7 |</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Internal factors impacting RTs. a, Reward size (left), fatigue (center) and satiety (right) as a function of trial position within session for low (green), middle (light blue) and high (strong blue) reward size sessions. Color code is shared for all panels a-d. Top equation illustrates the implementation in the model of these three features as linear regressors in AI drift. b, Proportion of rat's fast responses (faster than 50 ms after stimulus onset, or fixation break) as a function of trial position within session and reward size, for an example animal (rat #54). Dashed lines: linear fits. Insets: RT cumulative distribution for trial block 51-100 (bottom left) and 451-500 (top right); vertical dashed line: stimulus onset. c, Proportion of fast responses simulated using PSIAM fit to the RTs of the example rat in b.Insets: same as b, but simulated using PSIAM. d, Estimated weight for reward size (left), trial index (center) and reward consumption (right) regressors in AI drift (Group 4). Bars: mean across animals; symbols: individual rats; error bars: s.e.m.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig. 8 |</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Modulation of accuracy with manipulations of AI. a, Distribution of proactive alone RTs for three simulated manipulations varying the latency and the degree of temporal precision of the AI. b, Simulated tachometric curves obtained from the PSIAM using the AI processes shown in a and stimuli of intermediate strength ( s =0.5).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>ms for t A ; [2,10] s -1 for E ; [0.1,1.2] for E ; [35,75] ms for t E ; [-⅓,⅓] for z E ; [0,0.5] for c ; [0,1] for d ; and [0,50] s -1 for .</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We than k Jordi Pastor fo r excellent discussions and Lejla Bektic and Lorena Jiménez for help with training of the animals. We thank Dani Linares, Klaus Wimmer, Anke Braun, Juan R. Castiñeiras and Alfonso Renart for helpful comments on an earlier version of the manuscript. This research was supported by the Spanish <ref type="figure">Ministry</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>COMPETING INTERESTS</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential decision making: Wald&apos;s model and estimates of parameters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0046519</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="628" to="636" />
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast and accurate calculations for cumulative first-passage time distributions in Wiener diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Blurton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kesselmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gondan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2012.09.002</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="475" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The physics of optimal decision making: a formal analysis of models of performance in two-alternative forced-choice tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="700" to="765" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of the speed-accuracy tradeoff</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tins.2009.09.002</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Neurosciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal integration of olfactory perceptual evidence in human orbitofrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bowman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kording</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gottfried</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="916" to="927" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Temporal expectation hastens decision onset but does not affect evidence quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Van Den Brink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/2020.01.30.926337</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>no date</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rats and humans can optimally accumulate evidence for decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Brunton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brody</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">340</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural computation of log likelihood in control of saccadic eye movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">377</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6544</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-making with multiple alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Churchland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.2123</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="693" to="702" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Rodent Psychomotor Vigilance Test (rPVT): A Method for Assessing Neurobehavioral Performance in Rats and Mice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Roma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hienz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3791/54629</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Visualized Experiments</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The role of premature evidence accumulation in making difficult perceptual decisions under temporal uncertainty&apos;, eLife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Devine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/elife.48526</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Basal Ganglia&apos;s Contributions to Perceptual Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.042</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="640" to="649" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Cost of Accumulating Evidence in Perceptual Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/jneurosci.4010-11.2012</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3612" to="3628" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental fatigue affects visual selective attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Faber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Maurits</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lorist</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">48073</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Limiting forms of the frequency distribution of the largest or smallest member of a sample</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">H C</forename><surname>Tippett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/s0305004100015681</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical Proceedings of the Cambridge Philosophical Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="190" />
			<date type="published" when="1928" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural computations that underlie decisions about sensory stimuli</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Banburismus and the brain: decoding the relationship between sensory stimuli, decisions, and reward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="308" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Neural Basis of Decision Making&apos;, Annual Review of Neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev.neuro.29.051605.113038</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="535" to="574" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Even faster and even more accurate first-passage time densities and distributions for the Wiener diffusion model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gondan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Blurton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kesselmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2014.05.002</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Studies in the History of Probability and Statistics. XXXVII A. M. Turing&apos;s statistical work in World War II</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Good</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/biomet/66.2.393</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="396" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice reaction time with a random foreperiod</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Von Gierke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception &amp; psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="208" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Independence of Movement Preparation and Movement Initiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Haith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pakpoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Krakauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of neuroscience: the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3007" to="3015" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinct relationships of parietal and prefrontal cortices to evidence accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">520</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7546</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="220" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceptual Decision Making in Rodents, Monkeys, and Humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Summerfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2016.12.003</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A neural mechanism of speed-accuracy tradeoff in macaque area LIP&apos;, eLife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/elife.02260</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time-dependent competition between goal-directed and habitual response preparation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hardwick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature human behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1252" to="1262" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response outcomes gate the impact of expectations on perceptual decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hermoso-Mendizabal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1057</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust Estimation of a Location Parameter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1214/aoms/1177703732</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Annals of Mathematical Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bursts and heavy tails in temporal and sequential dynamics of foraging decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1003759</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of a decision in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex of the macaque&apos;</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Putaminal activity for simple reactions or self-timed movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Assad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2528" to="2537" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of food deprivation on self-control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Logue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Peña-Correal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0376-6357(85)90036-1</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Behavioural Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90036" to="90037" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A cognitive signal for the proactive timing of action in macaque LIP&apos;</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Maimon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Assad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="948" to="955" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Drift Diffusion Model Can Account for the Accuracy and Reaction Time of Value-Based Choices Under High and Low Time Pressure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milosavljevic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.1901533</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SSRN Electronic Journal</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>no date</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural antecedents of self-initiated actions in secondary motor cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Murakami</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1574" to="1582" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Global gain modulation generates time-dependent urgency during perceptual choice in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Boonstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nieuwenhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/ncomms13526</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast and accurate calculations for first-passage times in Wiener diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fuss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmp.2009.02.003</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The hazards of time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nobre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Correa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Coull</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current opinion in neurobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="465" to="470" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The mechanistic foundation of Weber&apos;s law&apos;, Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Pardo-Vazquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41593-019-0439-7</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1493" to="1502" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Encoding and decoding in parietal cortex during sensorimotor decision-making&apos;</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1395" to="1403" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The latencies of correct and incorrect responses in discrimination and detection tasks: Their interpretation in terms of a model based on simple counting&apos;, Perception &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Pike</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/bf03208951</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="460" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response latency models for signal detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pike</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0033871</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="68" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural Mechanisms of Post-error Adjustments of Decision Policy in Parietal Cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Purcell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="658" to="671" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295x.85.2.59</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion Decision Model: Current Issues and History</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diffusion decision model: theory and data for two-choice decision tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="873" to="922" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Comparison of Sequential Sampling Models for Two-Choice Reaction Time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295x.111.2.333</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="367" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating parameters of the diffusion model: approaches to dealing with contaminant reaction times and parameter variability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tuerlinckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic bulletin &amp; review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="481" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of urgency on decision time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A J</forename><surname>Reddi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H S</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/77739</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="827" to="830" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Training Rats Using Water Rewards Without Water Restriction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Reinagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in behavioral neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">84</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Changes of mind in decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Resulaj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nature08275</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determination of discount functions in rats with an adjusting-amount procedure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Richards</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the experimental analysis of behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="366" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response of neurons in the lateral intraparietal area during a combined visual discrimination reaction time task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Roitman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of neuroscience: the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9475" to="9489" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Role of primate basal ganglia and frontal cortex in the internal generation of movements. III. Neuronal activity in the supplementary motor area</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Romo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental brain research. Experimentelle Hirnforschung. Experimentation cerebrale</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Waiting is the Hardest Part: Comparison of Two Computational Strategies for Performing a Compelled-Response Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Salinas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in computational neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">153</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decoupling speed and accuracy in an urgent decision-making task reveals multiple contributions to their trade-off&apos;</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Salinas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnins.2014.00085</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Introduction to Probability Theory and Its Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Samuels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Feller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1267275</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">405</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technometrics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tracking the temporal evolution of a perceptual judgment using a compelled-response task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of neuroscience: the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8406" to="8421" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Interaction Between Elapsed Time and Decision Accuracy Differs Between Humans and Rats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Shevinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Reinagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward rate optimization in two-alternative decision making: empirical tests of theoretical predictions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Simen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of experimental psychology. Human perception and performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1865" to="1897" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Model of Interval Timing by Neural Integration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Simen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/jneurosci.3121-10.2011</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9238" to="9253" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Good things come to those who wait: attenuated discounting of delayed rewards in aged Fischer 344 rats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurobiology of aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="853" to="862" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Movement Adjustments Have Short Latencies Because There is No Need to Detect Anything</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smeets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Oostwoud Wijdenes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Brenner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Motor control</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="148" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceptual decision making in less than 30 milliseconds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Stanford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.2485</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="385" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions are expedited through multiple neural adjustments spanning the sensorimotor hierarchy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Steinemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>O'connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3627</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision making by urgency gating: theory and experimental support</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Thura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2912" to="2930" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deliberation and Commitment in the Premotor and Primary Motor Cortex during Dynamic Decision Making&apos;, Neuron</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Thura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cisek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2014.01.031</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1401" to="1416" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inverse Statistical Variates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C K</forename><surname>Tweedie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/155453a0</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="453" />
			<date type="published" when="1945" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Great expectations: Temporal expectation modulates perceptual processing speed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vangkilde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Coull</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bundesen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0026343</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1183" to="1191" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factoring out nondecision time in choice reaction time data: Theory and implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Verdonck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tuerlinckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sequential Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1947" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reaction Time, Speed of Performance, and Age</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Welford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1749-6632.1988.tb32958.x</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Causal contribution and dynamical encoding in the striatum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yartsev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
