<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">TAKING RISKS FOR OTHERS 1 Anti-Social Motives Explain Increased Risk Aversion for Others in Decisions from Experience</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Olschewski</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Economic Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Basel</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Economic Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Basel</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Dietsch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Economics, Finance and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Goethe University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Frankfurt</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Economics, Finance and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Goethe University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Frankfurt</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Economics, Finance and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Goethe University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Frankfurt</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Economics, Finance and Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Goethe University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Frankfurt</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elliot</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Economic Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Basel</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Missionsstrasse 62A</addrLine>
									<postCode>4056</postCode>
									<settlement>Basel</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Economic Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Basel</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">TAKING RISKS FOR OTHERS 1 Anti-Social Motives Explain Increased Risk Aversion for Others in Decisions from Experience</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:10+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>decisions from experience</term>
					<term>uncertainty</term>
					<term>decision making for others</term>
					<term>social interaction</term>
					<term>anti-social behavior</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>When deciding for others based on explicitly described odds and outcomes, people often have different risk preferences for others than for themselves. In two pre-registered experiments, we examine risk preference for others where people learn about the odds and outcomes by experiencing them through sampling. In both experiments, on average, people were more risk averse for others than for themselves, but only when the risky option had a higher expected value. Furthermore, based on a separate set of choices, we classified people as pro-or antisocial. Only those people classified as antisocial were more risk averse for others, whereas those classified as prosocial chose similarly for themselves and others. When the uncertainty was removed, however, all participants exhibited less antisocial behavior. Together, these results suggest that antisocial motives contribute to the observed limited risk-taking for others and that outcome uncertainty facilitates the expression of these motives.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Anti-Social Motives Explain Risk Aversion for Others in Decisions from Experience</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Many risky decisions that people make affect other people, which can effectively spread, share, or even offload the risk. Some situations are more obviously social, such as when a financial advisor invests a portfolio for a client, but others are less so, such as when people make career decisions that affect themselves, their families, and their friends. Though most studies of risky choice are devoid of an explicit social context (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Gneezy &amp; Potters, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Holt &amp; Laury, 2002)</ref>, several studies have examined risk taking for others. Findings in this literature are mixed: some studies have found that people tend to be more risk averse for others than themselves (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bolton &amp; Ockenfels, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Reynold, Joseph, &amp; Sherwood, 2009)</ref>, often attributed to a sense of responsibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Charness &amp; Jackson, 2009)</ref>. In contrast, other studies have found that people tend to be more risk seeking for others than themselves (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Chakravarty, Harrison, Haruvy, &amp; Rutström 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Pollmann, Potters, &amp; Trautmann, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Stone &amp; Allgaier, 2008)</ref>, sometimes attributed to a social norm of risk taking that is heeded more in choices for others than for oneself.</p><p>Irrespective of the direction of change in risk taking, the differences in choices for self and others are usually attributed to prosocial attitudes, assuming that people choose what they think would be best for the other person. This supposed ubiquitous prosociality, however, lies somewhat in conflict with the finding that people also have a competitive streak, such as when people are happier when their income exceeds those around them (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Clark &amp; Oswald, 1996)</ref> or even an anti-social streak, such as when they do not contribute to a public good even though it is in their self-interest <ref type="bibr">(Brandts, Saijo, &amp; Schram, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr">Saijo, 2008)</ref>.</p><p>This occasional anti-social behavior in social comparison suggests that differences in risk taking for self and other could also be due to anti-social motives. For example, people might choose the better of two lotteries (in terms of their expected utility) for themselves and the worse for another person. This pattern could then lead to more or less risk-taking for others, depending on the exact characteristics of those lotteries. Here, in two pre-registered experiments, we examine how decision making for others differs in an experience-based learning environment and test whether pro-or anti-social motives are connected to any observed differences.</p><p>People have strong social preferences about how to equitably distribute outcomes to others <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Fehr &amp; Schmidt, 1999)</ref>, which might also affect their risk taking for others. These social preferences, however, have mostly been tested under certainty. For example, in the dictator game, where participants decide how to distribute money between themselves and a second person, non-zero outcomes for others are typically selected <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kahneman, Knetsch, &amp; Thaler, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Engel, 2011)</ref>. To disentangle the different potential motives in these social games, a collection of dictator games with a fixed choice set has been developed into the social-value-orientation (SVO) scale (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Liebrand, 1984;</ref><ref type="bibr">Murphy, Ackerman, &amp; Handgraaf, 2011)</ref>. Based on the choices made, this scale provides both a quantitative estimate of prosociality (the SVO angle) as well as a discrete classification of people into competitive, selfish, prosocial, or altruistic groups based on this quantitative score. According to this measure, around 12% of people express competitive behavior, which can be considered as anti-social, whereas 46% behave in accordance with pro-social motives <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Au &amp; Kwong, 2004)</ref>.</p><p>These behavioral results have led to models of social preference which assume that people value equity in outcomes (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bolton &amp; Ockenfels, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Fehr &amp; Schmidt, 1999</ref>; but see <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Charness &amp; Rabin, 2002)</ref>.</p><p>Whereas laboratory studies often find prosocial tendencies and inequity aversion, field studies find that happiness increases with an increase in relative income rank compared to others in one's respective peer group (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Brown, Gardner, Oswald, &amp; Qian, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Clark &amp; Oswald, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Tideman, Frijters, &amp; Shields, 2008)</ref>. One potential interpretation of this finding is that people gain utility from having more than someone else, which resembles competitive behavior in the SVO classification. Consequently, there might be an inherent tension between people's pro-and anti-social tendencies and the expression of these tendencies might at least depend partly on the environment. One apparent difference between the laboratory experiments and real-world surveys is the degree of ambiguity between choice and outcome, which is typically absent in the former, but present in the latter. Simply introducing risk with pre-defined probabilities of rewards into the dictator game affects social preferences: People do still share chance outcomes with others, but to a lesser extent <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Brock, Lange, &amp; Ozbay, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Krawczyk &amp; Le Lec, 2010)</ref>. Moreover, across individuals, there is no correlation between social preferences under certainty and risk <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bolton, Ockenfels, &amp; Stauf, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bradler, 2009)</ref>. Given this anti-social streak, especially under uncertainty, it is potentially problematic that predominantly prosocial tendencies have been invoked to explain differences in risky decisions for self and others.</p><p>Almost all previous studies examining risky choice for others have used decisions from description, where the odds and outcomes are explicitly presented (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bolton &amp; Ockenfels, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Charness &amp; Jackson, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Raynold et al., 2009)</ref>. In contrast, in real life, the odds and outcomes are often not known when people make decisions for themselves or for other people. In this study, we developed a decisions-from-experience (DfE) design where people have no prior knowledge of the odds or outcomes, but can only learn them by sampling from the different options. This procedure makes the odds and outcomes more ambiguous compared to decisions with explicitly described risks and thus might affect the expression of social preferences. In decision-making without a social context, the same odds and outcomes can lead to different behavior when presented either in a described or experience-based format <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Hertwig, Weber, Barron, &amp; Erev, 2004)</ref>. For example, rare events are weighted differently in experience compared to description <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Wulff, Mergenthaler-Canseco, &amp; Hertwig, 2018</ref>; but also see <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Glöckner, Hilbig, Henninger, &amp; Fiedler, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Kellen, Pachur, &amp; Hertwig, 2016)</ref> and extreme outcomes gain more importance in experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Ludvig &amp; Spetch, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Ludvig, Madan, &amp; Spetch, 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">, Madan, Ludvig &amp; Spetch, 2017</ref>. Given these dissimilarities in individual risky choice, how social preferences under certainty and risk will generalize to an experience-based protocol is not clear.</p><p>In this paper, we present two experiments that examine how social preferences interact with outcome uncertainty, using a DfE design. The first experiment focuses on the following pre-registered question: How do risk preferences change in choices for others compared to oneself? Post-hoc, we classified people according to their social preferences and examined which motives correspond with risk taking for others. Furthermore, we compared social preferences in the DfE task with those under certainty. Then, in a second pre-registered experiment, using different rewarding outcomes, we replicate the core results and confirm the post-hoc findings from the first experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants 62 participants were recruited in 4 sessions of 10-20 participants from the University of Warwick paid participant pool via the Sona system-an online system for managing experimental participants (https://www.sona-systems.com/). The number of participants was determined prior to the experiment through a power analysis with 80% power to find a medium effect size (d = 0.5) at the 5% significance level with a two-sided, two-sample t-test. 4 participants were excluded, who could either not be matched to another participant in an individual session or failed at the catch trials, leaving 58 participants (M age = 21.4, SD age = 3.1, 42 female; 16 male). We did not collect other demographic details from the participants. The Warwick participant pool is run jointly by Psychology, Economics, and the Business School, and consists of both students (mostly) and staff from all disciplines as well as former students and members of the local community. Participants were paid a show-up fee of £4 plus a variable bonus depending on their own choices or the choices of a matched partner (ranging from £0.50 to £8.00, Mean = £4.82). All research was approved by the University of Warwick Humanities and Social Sciences Research Ethics Committee (HSSREC). All procedural details, including hypotheses, recruited participant numbers, exclusion criteria, and planned analyses were preregistered at the Open Science Framework: https://osf.io/2bts4. Code for experiments and analysis as well as the raw data are available at the same link.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure &amp; Material</head><p>Upon arrival to the laboratory, participants received an information sheet and then provided written informed consent to participate in the experiment. The experiment was performed at a computer and consisted of six blocks of trials. There were 3 sampling and 3 choice blocks, with each sampling block followed by a choice block. The experiment was programmed with PsychoPy 1.84 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Peirce, 2007)</ref>. Instructions were provided on the computer screen and could be read at the participant's own pace; questions could also be asked of the experimenter. The instructions described the task and framed it as a group decision-making experiment, where participants could choose between monetary lotteries for themselves and for another randomly selected participant in the room. The instructions stressed that the choice for oneself and the other person were independent from each other.</p><p>In the sampling blocks, participants distributed 40 samples among 8 decks of cards in whatever order or quantity they wished. Each deck had a unique symbol that was the same for a given distribution throughout the experiment (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> and <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>). The connection between a symbol and an underlying distribution was randomized for each participant. All distributions were continuous and uniform. There were 2 low-value decks (mean = £2.5), 4 medium-value decks (mean = £4.5), and 2 high-value decks (mean = £6.5). Draws from the decks were randomly distributed around these means with a uniform distribution. Half the decks for each mean value had a small range (i.e., low variance) [range of ± 0.5], and the other half had a medium range (i.e., high variance) [range of ± 2] (with a larger range only used in Study 2). In the choice blocks (see below), all the high-value and low-value decks appeared in the choices for both self and other. The 4 medium decks, however, were split such that 2 decks (one small and one medium range) appeared only in self choices, and the other 2 decks only appeared in choices for the other. This split aimed to examine whether people sample differently once they find out that some decks are only relevant in choices for themselves and some only for choices for other participants (see Supplemental Material for an analysis of sampling behavior, which did not provide evidence for this conjecture).</p><p>Participants could only learn about the range of possible outcomes from experience and were not told the means nor the ranges of the different decks. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1A</ref> shows a schematic of how, during the sampling blocks, the screen displayed all 8 decks as well as a decreasing count of the number of samples remaining. The 8 decks always appeared in the same locations during sampling, providing an additional memory cue for the symbol. Participants sampled from a given deck by left-clicking on it with the mouse.</p><p>The symbol for the selected deck then disappeared and, at its former position, a random draw from the corresponding distribution (see above) rounded to two digits appeared for 0.5 s.</p><p>After that, the symbol for the given deck re-appeared. While the outcome was displayed, no sampling was possible. Once participants had no samples left, they clicked on continue, and a choice block followed.  On each of the 21 trials, participants made two choices: They chose between two of the decks for themselves and between two (possibly different) decks for a second participant. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1B</ref> shows how the screen was divided down the middle by a line, and there were two decks of cards vertically positioned on each side (for a total of 4 decks). One side, indicated by the word "self", displayed the two decks to choose between for oneself, and the other side, indicated by the word "other", displayed the two decks to choose between for the other participant. The self/other location was counterbalanced across participants, but constant across trials for each participant.</p><p>Participants made choices by clicking on their preferred deck with the mouse. After a mouse-click on a deck, the deck's borders switched to green, indicating the deck had been clicked. Once a selection had been made both for self and other, the participant confirmed these choices by clicking on a continue button or by pressing enter on the keyboard.</p><p>Selections could be changed until they were confirmed. No additional feedback was provided during the choice blocks, and participants had to rely on what they had learned during the sampling blocks to guide their choices. choices examined whether the rewards potentially available to the other participant (higher or lower) influence risky choice (and vice versa). The next 6 choices examined inequity aversion (both advantageous and disadvantageous) by offering different potential reward levels for self and other. The next 2 choices were used as comparison to the inequity aversion choices without differences in the choice menu between self and other. The final two choices served as catch trials, with an obvious dominant alternative, and, post-hoc, as a means of classifying participants as pro-or anti-social based on how they chose for the other participant.</p><p>In anticipation of Experiment 2, we define dominant choice situations as ones where one option has a higher EV and the same or smaller range than the other option and where the choice sets were the same for self and other. Choices 18 and 19 also have this characteristic;</p><p>however, because they were used as comparisons for the inequity aversion analysis (see Supplemental Materials), they were not included in the primary classification. The first number of each option is the expected value, and the letter symbolizes outcome ranges: L = ± 0.5, M = ± 2.0. H for high is reserved for stimuli in Experiment 2.</p><p>As the task was self-paced, at the end of the experiment, some participants had to wait for the other participants to finish. Once all participants were finished, participants were matched in groups of two, and one participant from each pair was randomly determined as the decision-maker for that pair. One trial was randomly selected, and the selected distribution from the decision-maker was played out for themselves and for the other group member separately. The outcomes of these draws determined the variable payoffs for the two group members, respectively. Participants saw their own outcome on the computer screen and learned whether their own decision has been implemented or whether their outcome was determined by the other participant. Nobody, however, knew exactly with whom they had been paired. Payment for the participants was given individually at the end of the experiment.</p><p>While participants waited for the payment and before they saw their experimental gains, they filled out the paper-and-pencil 6-item version of the SVO-Slider <ref type="bibr">(Murphy, Ackerman, &amp; Handgraaf, 2011)</ref>. The slider consists of 6 mini-dictator games, and participants chose how to distribute money for themselves and someone else from 9 different distributions that were different in each of the 6 games. These choices were not incentivized. Depending on the choices people made, an SVO angle was computed, where higher numbers mean a higher degree of prosocial attitudes. The computed angle can then be divided into a discrete classification system that bunches people into four groups from low to high prosociality.</p><p>Competitive (with an angle below 12.04°) means people gain utility from their own income and from low income for someone else or by increasing the difference in outcomes between oneself and someone else. Selfish (with an angle between 12.04° and 22.45°) means that people gain utility only from their own outcomes and do not care about the outcome of others.</p><p>Prosocial (with an angle between 22.45° and 57.17°) means that people gain utility from their own and from someone else's outcome or by minimizing the distance between their own and someone else's outcome. Finally, altruistic (with an angle above 57.17°) means that people only gain utility from outcomes for others <ref type="bibr">(Murphy, Ackerman, &amp; Handgraaf, 2011)</ref>.</p><p>All data analysis was conducted in RStudio 0.99 (R studio team, 2015) based on R 3.3.0 (R core team, 2016), and regressions were performed with the packages lme4 <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bates, Maechler, Bolker, &amp; Walker, 2015)</ref> and lmerTest <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kuznetsova, Brockhoff, &amp; Christensen, 2017)</ref>. Regressions had subject random intercepts and used the logit link function with interaction and main effects as reported in the text. Effect sizes were calculated as Cohen's d from the choice proportion differences, and mean differences are presented with 95% confidence intervals. In general, the data analyses followed the pre-registered plan. Any deviations from this pre-registered analysis plan are clearly marked in the Results section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Risky Choices</head><p>First, we examined how risky choices differed when choosing for oneself or another participant from the same choice set. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2A</ref> shows the percentage of risky choices aggregated over all trials and all participants for choice situations 1-5 (left), 1-3 (middle) and 4-5 (right). For all choices 1-5 (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>), there was one smaller and one larger range option. Participants chose the larger range option 13.3 ± 6.5 percentage points (Mean ± 95% confidence interval) more often for themselves than for someone else. A Wilcoxon test confirmed a significant difference between choices for self and other (W(n = 58) = 1178.5, d = 0.52, p &lt; .001) 1 . Follow-up exploratory analyses showed that this effect, however, was entirely due to choices 4-5 which differed from choices 1-3 in that there was a risk-return trade-off between a small-range, low-expected-value (EV) option and a large-range, high-EV option. Here, people chose the safer option 35.3 ± 9.3% more often for others than themselves (W(n = 58) = 836, d = 0.94, p &lt; .001). There was little difference, however, between choices for self and other in choices 1-3 (-1.3 ± 6.9%), where the expected value was the same for both options (W(n = 58) = 579, d = 0.05, p &gt; .250). These results were confirmed by a logistic regression with random subject effects showing that there was a significant interaction between the choice type (1-3 vs. 4-5) and choices for self and other (β = 1.83, SE = 0.22, p &lt; .001).</p><p>Further exploratory analyses revealed that there was a strongly bimodal distribution of choice proportions when deciding for others in choices 20 and 21. These situations consist of options with one low-EV and one high-EV option with equal range for both self and other.</p><p>Thus, one option dominated the other, and in choices for oneself, these situations were used as catch trials. People used two clearly distinct strategies: <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2C</ref> shows how 25 participants chose the higher EV option for the other participants 5 or 6 out of 6 times they encountered the choice situation (green in figure), whereas 26 participants chose the higher EV option 0 or 1 out of 6 times (yellow). In line with the literature about distributional choices, we term these two choice patterns as pro-social, where people either try to maximize the outcome for the other participant or to minimize the difference between outcomes (as they chose the higher EV option for themselves most of the time), and anti-social where people try to minimize the outcome for the other participant or to maximize the difference between outcomes. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2B</ref> shows how those participants classified as anti-social chose the risky option 60.9 ± 13.3% more often for themselves than for others in choice situations (Choices 4-5) involving a risk-return trade-off (W(n = 26) = 323.5, d = 1.76, p &lt; .001) as compared to the prosocials who only did so 6.7 ± 7.5% more often (W(n = 25) = 42.5, d = 0.35, p = .134).</p><p>These anti-social participants consistently chose the lower-EV option for the other participant. This pattern was corroborated by a random-effects logistic regression where the interaction between choosing for oneself or other and being classified as either anti-social or prosocial was significant in the risk-return trade-off choices 4-5 (β = 2.49, SE = 0.45, p &lt; .001).</p><p>Moreover, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2C</ref> plots risky choice in risk-return trade-off choices 4-5 against the choices in situations 20-21: there was a strong correlation between the number of higher EV choices for others in the catch trials and the number of risky choices for others in the risk-return tradeoff choices (r(56) = 0.83, p &lt; .001).  <ref type="formula">20-21</ref>, where colors illustrate the classification scheme applied and vertical and horizontal jitter was applied to make all points visible. *** = p &lt; .001.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Classification Results Compared to the SVO Questionnaire</head><p>Using the standard classification borders, the SVO slider questionnaire classified 25 people as prosocial, 33 as selfish, and 0 as competitive or altruistic. For the choice task, SVO prosocials would be expected to choose the higher EV option for others consistently, because they benefit from minimizing the difference between themselves and another participant or because they want to maximize joint welfare. Those classified as selfish by the SVO should be indifferent with respect to the other participant's outcome. Thus, they should respond at a chance level with respect to choices for others with different expected values. In contrast, in the classification trials 20-21, 26 participants consistently chose the lower-EV option for the other participant-a strongly anti-social pattern, which may arise out of competitive motives.</p><p>Yet, none of these 26 participants were classified as competitive by the SVO. Due to the low numbers of observations in some groups (no competitive in SVO classification), we conducted a Fisher's exact test on the distributions based on the SVO and the main task, which resulted in p &lt; .001. This test rejects the independence of columns and rows in the classification table, meaning that the columns (categories) depend on the rows (classification schemes). We thus conclude that the classification based on the SVO differs from the classification according to the main experience-based task. Using the continuous scale of the SVO slider <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Figure 3</ref>), however, where higher values indicate more prosocial behavior, there was a slight, but not statistically significant, positive correlation between angle and percentage of high-EV choices for the other participant in the choice task (r (56) = .23, p = .077). The correlation of the SVO angle with choosing the risky (and high-EV) option for other was smaller in the risk-return trade-off choices (r(56) = .15, p &gt; .250).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Robustness</head><p>As a robustness check, we assessed a different classification criterion, using choices 18 and 19 (instead of 20 and 21; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1)</ref>, where there was also a dominant option. classified as prosocial are absent). As before, the anti-social participants chose the risky option 68.4 ± 14.3% more often for themselves than others when there was a risk return tradeoff in choices 4-5 (W(n = 19) = 171, d=2.15, p &lt;.001), whereas prosocials only did so 4.9 ± 7.0% of the time (W(n = 24) = 32. did the lower EV option have a higher experienced EV, and in only 5 comparisons, was the higher-EV option better by less than £0.5 (compared to a £2 difference in the generative distributions). In only 7 out of 464 relevant comparisons (risky choices 1-5), the low-variance option had the higher experienced variance, and in only 18 comparisons, the low-variance option had an experienced variance less than ¼ of the theoretical variance difference after the first round of sampling. The number of deviations between experienced and planned distributions was even lower after the second and third round of sampling.</p><p>To see whether these few trials affected our results, we excluded choices in all rounds where the previously experienced means or variances were much closer to each other than planned (given the criterion above) after the first round of sampling. This exclusion removed 63 out of 1218, or roughly 5% of the relevant choices (risky choices 1-5 and classification 20 &amp; 21). All the Wilcoxon tests performed above yielded qualitatively similar results after these exclusions.</p><p>In the pre-registration, we also asked questions about how the rewards of others influence risk preference (Choices 6-11), inequity aversion (Choices 12-19), and the sampling process. These analyses are included in the supplemental online materials for completeness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2</head><p>In Experiment 1, people were more risk averse when deciding for others than for themselves in an experience-based task. Exploratory analyses showed that this effect was related to anti-social motives: Some of the participants consistently chose lower EV options for others in risk-return trade-off situations. In addition, the experience-based task induced much more anti-social behavior than a classification based on the SVO slider would predict.</p><p>We pre-registered a second study to confirm the exploratory result by increasing the number of gambles examining risky choice and classifying participants (see <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>). In addition, we wanted to address two further open questions: First, participants were risk neutral in choices that differed only in the range. This pattern could reflect a genuine preference, but could also reflect a lack of learning about range differences between the decks. Therefore, we increased the range difference, reduced the number of decks, and explicitly asked participants about the ranges of outcomes. Second, we aimed to confirm the result that high levels of anti-social behavior were specific to choices under uncertainty:</p><p>Therefore, we used a computerized version of the SVO and an extra one-shot choice under certainty, both fully incentivized, so as to be more comparable to the main task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants 69 participants were recruited in 7 sessions of 4-12 participants from the same participant pool as Experiment 1. The number of participants was estimated prior to the experiment with a power analysis as in the first experiment. Two participants were excluded who either could not be matched to a partner or failed the exclusion criterion (i.e., sampled one option fewer then 5 times), which left 67 participants (M age = 23.6, SD age = 3.1, 40 female, 27 male). Participants were paid a show-up fee of £4 plus a variable bonus depending on their own choices or the choices of a matched partner (ranging from £1.50 to £8.59, Mean= £4.71).</p><p>Again, all methods and analyses were pre-registered and can be found together with all other material at: https://osf.io/2bts4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>The procedure was largely the same as in Experiment 1, with some changes in the reward distribution and the choice situations (see <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>). In particular, the number of distributions was reduced from 8 to 6, a third range level was introduced, and only 2 mean values were used. The uniform distributions had a mean value of either 4 or 6 and a range of either ±0.5 (low), ±2 (medium), or ±3.5 (high). <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> shows the revised choice situations, which were selected to best follow up the results from the first study. There were 9 choice situations assessing risk attitude of which 3 contained a risk-return trade-off. Furthermore, as in the first experiment, 9 choice situations assessed inequity aversion, and 3 additional situations were used for classifying participants and as a manipulation check. The number of samples in each sampling block was changed slightly to boost learning about the 6 decks after the first block. Hence, people sampled 80 times in the first block and only 30 times in each of the second and third sampling blocks. Again, participants could distribute these samples in any order they wanted among the 6 available decks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 2. Choice situations in Experiment 2</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Choice</head><p>Self-A Self-B Other-A Other-B Choose B Self in % Choose B Other in % <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Risk Attitude  1  4L  4M  4L  4M  40  42  2  4M  4H  4M  4H  47  45  3  4L  4H  4L  4H  37  39  4  6L  6M  6L  6M  44  50  5  6M  6H  6M  6H  54  52  6  6L  6H  6L  6H  54  49  7  4L  6M  4L  6M  84  62  8  4M  6H  4M  6H  89  62  9  4L  6H  4L  6H  87  65  Inequity Aversion  10  4L  6L  4L  4M  79  35  11  4M  6M  4M  4H  78  44  12  4H  6H  4M  4H  81  49  13  4L  4M  4L  6L  38  64  14  4M  4H  4M  6M  44  52</ref>  The first number of each option is the mean value, and the letter symbolizes the range: L = ± 0.5, M = ± 2, H = ± 3.5.</p><p>After the final choice block, there was an additional choice between two certain options (a certain £4 vs. a certain £6) both for oneself and for another participant. After that question, the computerized version of the SVO slider (6 items) was presented. Finally, a further 4 questions assessing the participants' knowledge about the ranges of the decks were presented. For each EV level two questions were asked: First, all three decks with the same EV were presented, and participants were asked which deck was the riskiest. Second, all three decks were again presented, and participants were asked which deck was the safest. The same two questions were then repeated with the other three decks with the other EV. The payment mechanism was the same as in the first experiment with the difference that a payoff relevant trial could also be chosen from the choice under certainty and from the SVO choices. Thus, all choices were incentivized, but the questions about the decks' variances were not.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Risky Choices</head><p>With more risky-choice situations (1-9 in Table 2), the pattern from Experiment 1 was confirmed. <ref type="figure">Figure 4A</ref> shows how, overall, people chose the risky option 8.0 ± 4.0% more often for themselves than for others (W(n=67) = 709, d = 0.48, p &lt; .001). This difference was again driven by choices with a risk-return trade-off (7-9), where people chose the risky option 23.7 ± 7.9% more often for themselves (W(n=67) = 780.5, d = 0.72, p &lt; .001), as opposed to those with equal expected value (1-6), where people only chose the risky option 0.2 ± 4.2% more often for themselves (W(n=67) = 2202, d = 0.01, p &gt; .250). This interaction in the percentage of risky choices for oneself and others in trade-off choices (7-9) as compared to choices with the same EV (1-6) was confirmed through a random-effects logistic regression (β = 1.37, SE = 0.17, p &lt; .001).</p><p>As pre-registered, situations where one option dominated the other in terms of EV and variance (19-21 in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>) were used as a measure of other-regarding preferences to classify the participants. Participants were classified as anti-social if they chose the dominating option for the other participant up to 2 out of 9 trials (13 participants) and as prosocial if they chose it at least 7 times (35 participants). This criterion left 19 participants unclassified (see <ref type="figure">Figure   4C</ref>). <ref type="figure">Figure 4B</ref> shows that those classified as anti-social chose the safe option 70.1 ± 12.9% more often for others than for themselves in the risk-return trade-off choice situations (W(n=13) = 169, d = 2.95, p &lt; .001), whereas those classified as prosocial did so only 5.1 ± 5.7% more often (W(n=35) = 685, d = 0.30, p = .108), which yielded a significant interaction in a random-effects logistic regression (β = 3.35, SE = 0.48, p &lt; .001). Thus, the main results of the first study were confirmed in this replication with different choice situations. In addition, in choices with the same EV where only the variance differed, people trended toward expressing slight risk-aversion; that is, they chose the high variance option slightly less than 50% of the time for themselves and others (Self: W(n=67) = 670.5, d = 0.23, p = .048; Other: W(n=67) = 745.5, d = 0.25, p = .071) <ref type="bibr">(19)</ref><ref type="bibr">(20)</ref><ref type="bibr">(21)</ref>, where colors illustrate the classification scheme applied and both vertical and horizontal jitter were used. *** = p &lt; .001</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4: (A) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of risky choices for self and other in all choice situations with different variances (choice situations 1-9, left) and separately for those with the same expected value (1-6, middle) and those with a risk-return trade-off (7-9, right). Grey points represent individual participants with horizontal jitter. (B) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of risky choices for self and other with a risk-return trade-off (7-9), split by participant classification. (C) Percentage of risky choices for others in the risk-return trade-off choices (7-9) correlated with the percentage of dominant choice for other in classification trials</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Classification Results</head><p>Because the SVO questionnaire in the first study did not capture the observed antisocial behavior, we implemented a computerized and incentivized version of the SVO in Experiment 2. Nonetheless, classification results in the SVO were comparable to Experiment 1: 22 prosocial, 44 selfish, and 1 competitive. The classifications from the SVO and experienced-task significantly differed from one another, as confirmed by independence from a Fisher's exact test (p &lt; .001). Using the continuous scale of the SVO slider ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 5</ref>), however, where higher values signify more prosocial behavior, there was a significant positive correlation between angle and percentage of high EV choices for the other participant (r (65) = .32, p = .008). Furthermore, there was a significant correlation between the SVO angle and the choice of risky (and high-EV) options for others in the risk-return trade-off choices (r (65) = .32, p = .007). This pattern indicates that the SVO fails to predict the amount of anti-social behavior present in the decision-from-experience task, but captures part of the inter-individual differences in this task.</p><p>In the two-choice distribution task under certainty, where people decided between taking either a certain £4 or £6 for themselves and then again for the other person, 17/67   <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>). As in Experiment 1, by this definition, there were additional choices with a dominant option, which served as a comparison for any potential inequity aversion (see supplemental material). As a robustness check, we re-did the analysis with these trials as the classification criteria. With these trials, 10 participants were classified as anti-social (of which two were not classified as anti-social according to the original classification trials and 5 were absent that were previously classified as anti-social) and 36 as prosocial (of which 5 were not classified as prosocial according to the original classification trials and 4 were absent that were previously classified as prosocial). On the risk-return trade-off choices (7-9), the antisocial individuals chose the risky (higher EV) option 72.2 ± 17.9% more often for themselves than others (W(n = 10) = 100, d = 2.51, p &lt; .001), whereas prosocials did so only 4.6 ± 4.1% As in Experiment 1, we also checked for robustness of the analyses with respect to sampling errors. To do so, we examined how the experienced outcomes matched the generative distributions. After the first round of sampling, the lower-value option had the higher experienced value in only 3 of 402 relevant comparisons (risk-return trade-off choices 7-9 and classification choices 19-21). In addition, this difference was smaller than £0.50 in only 5 additional comparisons (compared to the planned £2). In terms of the range, in the 804 relevant comparisons (risky choices 1-9 and classification choices 19-21), the smaller range option had the higher experienced range 10 times and the difference in ranges was smaller than ¼ of the planned difference a further 28 times after the first round of sampling. The numbers of such sampling errors were even lower after the second and third round of sampling. Excluding all these trials led to the exclusion of 90 out of 2412 choices, or 4% of the relevant choices, and the qualitative results for all statistical tests remained identical.</p><p>To check whether participants learned about the different levels of outcome ranges associated with the decks, we asked people to name the safest or riskiest out of each set of three decks with the same EV. There were 4 questions with 3 potential answers, thus the guessing rate was 1.33 correct answers. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> plots the frequencies of correct answers for all participants: 53 participants were above the guessing rate, and the average score was significantly better than this guessing rate (M = 2.10 ± 0.24). The correlation between percentage of choosing high EV option for others in classification trials and the number of To see whether the key effects were driven by participants who could not distinguish between the different levels of variances, we excluded participants who were below the guessing rate of 1.33 (14 participants with 0 or 1 correct answers excluded). There was still a significant difference between self and other for all risky choices 1-9 of 7.6 ± 4.3% (W(n = 53) = 454, d = 0.49 p &lt; .001). Furthermore, there was also a significant difference in the riskreturn trade-off choices 7-9: 24.5 ± 8.8% (W(n = 53) = 514, d = 0.75, p &lt; .001).</p><p>The pre-registered analyses concerning inequity aversion (choices 10-18) and the analyses of the sampling process are again included in the online supplemental materials for completeness. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. Scatterplot of people based on the number of correct answers given for the variance questions (4 total questions with three answer options for each).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Across two experiments, people were more risk averse for others, largely due to a subset of participants who showed reward-maximizing behavior for themselves, but not for others. This anti-social behavior only emerged when there was uncertainty around the actual outcomes, but not in the social-value-orientation (SVO) questionnaire where decisions were made between certain outcomes. This study represents one of the first examinations of risky choice for others in a task that uses decisions from experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Hertwig et al., 2004)</ref>, building on prior work that used explicit descriptions of the risky outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bolton &amp; Ockenfels, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Chakravarty, Harrison, Haruvy, &amp; Rutström 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Pollmann, Potters, &amp; Trautmann,</ref>   <ref type="bibr">Raynold, Joseph, &amp; Sherwood, 2009)</ref>. The results suggest that prior interpretations of differences in risk choices for self and other as an expression of prosocial motives (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Charness &amp; Jackson, 2009</ref>) may need to be reconsidered.</p><p>The anti-social behavior amongst a significant subset of the participants seems to be enabled by the outcome uncertainty in the experience-based task, which is not present with the SVO slider, where outcomes are certain. With uncertain outcomes, EV-minimizing choices for others might feel less severe because the consequences have not yet materialized.</p><p>Similarly, people are known to give less in dictator games if the relation between one's own choice and the outcome for the other person is uncertain or not transparent <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Dana, Weber and Kuang, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Haisley &amp; Weber, 2010)</ref>. This lack of transparency creates some mental wiggle room, which allows for maintenance of a positive self-image despite seemingly anti-social actions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Mazar, On, &amp; Ariely, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Rabin, 1995)</ref>. Thus, in the DfE task, people could justify their selecting the as-yet-materialized bad outcomes for the other person by engaging in wishful thinking and assuming that, despite the non-maximizing choice, a relatively high outcome might still occur. The experience-based task used here introduces empirical uncertainty about the possible outcomes into a social-choice task. Similarly, greater uncertainty about another person's motives is associated with less cooperative behavior; for example, introducing uncertainty about another person's previous choices into a repeated prisoner's dilemma leads to less cooperation <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Fudenberg, Rand, &amp; Dreber, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Güth, Mugera, Musau, &amp; Ploner, 2014</ref>). This study builds on these findings, demonstrating that uncertainty not only increases selfish behavior, but can even lead to anti-social behavior.</p><p>The studies allow elimination of several alternative explanations for the results. First, participants classified as anti-social were not indifferent with respect to the other person's outcomes-choices for others systematically differed from random choice both for choice situations with a risk-return trade-off and for the classification choices <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figures 2 and 4)</ref>. In addition, participants learned the values of the different sets, as they consistently selected for themselves the same high-EV decks that they denied to others. Moreover, excluding those who performed poorly in a task where participants had to distinguish decks by their variability in Experiment 2 did not change the results. Our conclusions, however, must be tempered by the observation that participants also exhibited increased levels of anti-social behavior in a single question under certainty, when asked directly to give a high or low amount to oneself and another participant. This task differed from the SVO tasks in that participants chose one outcome for themselves and one for the other person, whereas they chose distributions for both players at once in the SVO. The answers to this single choice suggest that, in addition to shifting to experience-based questions, other changes to the answer format might also trigger more anti-social behavior.</p><p>The observed increase in risk aversion for others in these experience-based decisions resembles behavior in some studies when decisions are based on summary descriptions (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Raynold, Joseph, &amp; Sherwood, 2009)</ref>, though other description-based studies have instead found more risk seeking for others (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Chakravarty et al., 2011)</ref>. Anti-social motives, as found here, might help provide an explanation as to why people sometimes choose more riskily and sometimes less so for others with described choices. When choosing between two options with different variances, if the higher variance option is more attractive to the decision maker, people may act more risk averse for others because they, anti-socially, choose this attractive high-variance option less often for others (as was the case with the risk-return trade-off trials in our experiments). If, however, the low-variance option is more attractive to the decision maker, people may, anti-socially, select the low-variance less often for others, producing more risk-seeking (as was the case in the classification trials in Exp. 2). Whether this line of reasoning about anti-social motives applies to description-based choices is an open question. At first glance, the explicit descriptions of probabilistic outcomes would seem to provide less mental wiggle room to justify a bad choice for another person <ref type="bibr">(Haisely &amp; Weber, 2010)</ref>. Nonetheless, wishful thinking about the unrealized outcomes is still possible, even when the odds and outcomes are fully described.</p><p>Our results have implications for other, related situations where people make decisions for others. For example, one design variation in the literature examines choices for a team including the decider, so that choices for self and other are not independent (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bolton &amp; Ockenfels, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Rohde &amp; Rohde, 2011)</ref>. It would be interesting to see in future studies whether a similar share of anti-social people would also be present when people who choose a bad option for the team would also suffer themselves. There is also some related research on how people predict the risk attitudes of others. People can be very inaccurate when predicting other people's risk preferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Faro &amp; Rottenstreich, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Hsee &amp; Weber, 1997)</ref>; this inaccuracy could be a further reason why they choose differently for others. It would be interesting to examine whether predictions about other people's preferences are more or less accurate after they experience the outcomes as opposed to encountering them in a described manner. Finally, choices for others can occur not only in the monetary realm, but also in the social domain, as in, for example, romantic relationships (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Beisswanger, Stone, Hupp, Allgaier, 2003)</ref>. In these instances, experience-based learning might have an even more pronounced effect on choices than in the monetary domain because non-monetary outcomes might be more memorable once experienced.</p><p>Social preferences differ significantly under risk or uncertainty and certainty (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bolton, Ockenfels, &amp; Stauf, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bradler, 2009)</ref>. Given the uncertainty in our daily interactions and in the economy more generally, measuring social preferences only under certainty (e.g., in a dictator game) likely underestimates the role that anti-social behavior plays in daily life. Our experiments suggest that the SVO Questionnaire underestimates the role of competitive behavior under uncertainty, but does capture some of the inter-individual differences (Exp. 2). Prosocial preferences thus do seem to generalize across certainty and uncertainty, but there are also considerable individual differences in how people deal with uncertainty that are not captured by social preferences under certainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Roch &amp; Samuelson, 1997)</ref>. People may, for example, differ in the degree they create and use the mental wiggle room which provides for plausible deniability in highly uncertain situations.</p><p>The high level of anti-social behavior in the current task is more congruent with the competitive motives observed in real-world studies of the links between happiness and income rank <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Clark &amp; Oswald, 1996)</ref> than is typically observed in laboratory studies of prosociality <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Engel, 2011)</ref>. Our results suggest that, in the real world, a key difference which enables the expression of such anti-social behavior is the level of uncertainty. In line with this idea, people use the risk in the outcome of a donation to a charity as an excuse not to give <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Exley, 2015)</ref>. Similarly, returning to the example from the introduction, making decisions that affect one's own career path or the career paths of peers is only indirectly connected to income levels, which are only known with uncertainty. Reducing the uncertainty of potential outcomes would thus seem to be one way to increase prosociality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplemental Online Material: Introduction</head><p>This supplemental material presents analyses of additional choice situations and sampling behavior in the two experiments. All presented analyses were pre-registered, but were omitted from the main manuscript due to space and clarity concerns. Analyses of inequity aversion and sample sizes are provided for both experiments, whereas social aspiration levels were only examined in the first experiment. The numbers for the choice situations refer to Tables 1 and 2 (for Experiments 1 and 2 respectively) in the main manuscript. The pre-registration documents for the two experiments can be found at https://osf.io/kn6dy/ and https://osf.io/nrfz3/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1: Supplemental Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Inequity Aversion</head><p>To examine first-order (disadvantageous) inequity aversion, as pre-registered, choices for the other participant were compared when the choice options were the same for both self and other <ref type="bibr">(Equal: 18,</ref><ref type="bibr">19,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; 5)</ref> against those when the other participant had a higher expected value (EV) option than the decision maker . Inequity aversion here would manifest as the decision maker choosing the higher EV option for the other participant more often when choice options were equal than when they were unequal. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1A</ref> shows that there was a slight trend toward such inequity aversion: participants chose the higher EV option for the other participant 4.6 ± 5.6% more often under equality compared to unequal choice situations, d = 0.21, t(57) = 1.60, p = .116 as pre-registered, but W(n=58) = 158.5, p = .049 with a Wilcoxon signed-rank tests as the choice proportions were not normally distributed. Using a logistic regression with subject random effects this effect was significant (β = -0.38, SE = 0.17, p = .025). In a follow-up exploratory analysis, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1B</ref> shows how this effect was driven by the prosocial participants. In a regression, the interaction between the prosocials and the choice sets was significant above the main effects (β = -1.11, SE = 0.43, p = .010).</p><p>To examine second-order (advantageous) inequity aversion, as pre-registered, we compared choices for oneself in situations with identical choice options <ref type="bibr">(Equal: 18,</ref><ref type="bibr">19,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; 5)</ref> against those made when the decision maker had a higher EV option for oneself compared to the choice options for the other participant . Here, we hypothesized that people would choose the higher EV option for themselves more often in equal than in unequal choice situations. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3C</ref> shows how people chose the higher EV option for themselves 4.4 ± 3.4% more often under equality than when the choice set was unequal, d = 0.33, t(57) = 2.55, p = .013, W(n=58) = 75, p = .018. These inferences were corroborated by a logistic regression with a significant group difference β = -0.52, SE = 0.21, p = .016. In a follow-up exploratory analysis, this effect also appeared larger for those classified as prosocials than those classified as competitive. This interaction between classification and choice set, however, was not significant (β = -0.81, SE = 0.49, p = .093). Finally, contrary to our initial hypothesis, the level of risk did not reliably influence either form of inequity aversion (Wilcoxon Test: W(n = 58) first.order = 152, r = 0.03, d = 0.06, p = .785; W(n = 58) second.order = 254, r = 0.15, d = 0.30, p = .236). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>: (A) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of higher EV choices for the other participant depending on the presence of equal <ref type="bibr">(5,</ref><ref type="bibr">(18)</ref><ref type="bibr">(19)</ref> or unequal (disadvantageous for decider) EV options <ref type="bibr">(12)</ref><ref type="bibr">(13)</ref><ref type="bibr">(14)</ref> for oneself and the other participant. (B) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of higher EV choices for the other participant based on classification as prosocial or competitive (see main manuscript). (C) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of higher EV choices for oneself depending on the presence of equal <ref type="bibr">(5,</ref><ref type="bibr">(18)</ref><ref type="bibr">(19)</ref> or unequal (advantageous for decider) EV options <ref type="bibr">(15)</ref><ref type="bibr">(16)</ref><ref type="bibr">(17)</ref> for oneself and the other participant. (D) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of higher EV choices for oneself split by classification. In all panels, grey points represent choice percentages for individual participants using horizontal jitter. * = p &lt; .05 in a logistic regression. A second pre-registered hypothesis was that the relative reward level of the second participant would set a social aspiration level for the decision-maker and thereby alter risk preference. To test this hypothesis, we compared situations where participants made risky choices for themselves, but where the other participant had the same options (1-3), worse options (6-8) or better options (9-11) in terms of EV. If participants used the higher EV options of the other participant as an aspiration level, they would choose the riskier option more often in cases where they choose from a lower EV choice set than when both participants have the same choice set. Yet, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref> shows how this pattern did not emerge either in choices for oneself, nor in choices for the other participant. In a logistic regression, neither the higher nor the lower EV choices for the other participant had a reliable effect on the tendency to choose the riskier option for oneself (β higher = -0.18, SE = 0.14, p = .189; β lower = -0.13, SE = 0.15, p = .391). The same held true when looking at choices for the other participant given higher EV options for the decision maker (β = 0.03, SE = 0.16, p = .828).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social Aspiration Level</head><p>Surprisingly, and against the preregistered hypothesis, there was a small but significant effect to choose the less risky option for the other participant, if the decision maker had a higher EV choice set (β = -0.33, SE = 0.15, p = .030). Overall, the EV of the options available for one person did not consistently influence risky choice for the other person. other with loss -higher EV options for oneself than for the other (9-11) and gain -higher EV options for the other than oneself <ref type="bibr">(6)</ref><ref type="bibr">(7)</ref><ref type="bibr">(8)</ref>. In all panels, grey points represent individual participants using horizontal jitter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sampling</head><p>The total sample size was fixed at 40 for each block, so we compared how those 120 samples were distributed between decks. As can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S3</ref>, there were no differences in sampling between different levels of variance for same EV decks (adjacent boxes; e.g., 4.5L vs. 4.5M). In contrast, the EV influenced sample size, as the high EV decks (6.5L &amp; 6.5M) were sampled more often than the others. This difference was confirmed by a regression of the logarithm of sample size on the decks' theoretical characteristics with subject random effects: the high-variance and low-variance decks did not reliably differ (β = 0.02, SE = 0.04, p = .900), but high-EV decks were sampled more often (β = 8.36, SE = 0.76, p &lt; .001) and low-EV decks less often (β = -1.83, SE = 0.75, p = .016) than the medium-EV decks. Finally, we hypothesized that participants took the target (self or other) of the decks into account, but there was no difference between the sample size for the medium-EV decks relevant only for the decision maker and the medium-EV decks relevant only to the other participant (for sample blocks 2 and 3 to allow for learning: β = 0.06, SE = 0.05, p = 0.24).</p><p>Moreover, this effect was not moderated by the classification results; there was no difference in sampling across participants classified as prosocial or anti-social (β = 0.09, SE = 0.08, p = .261) 1 . <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S3</ref>: Boxplot with median, quartiles and whiskers as first quartile minus 1.5 times the interquartile range and third quartile plus 1.5 times the interquartile range of sample size for each of the 8 decks. Sample size was aggregated across all three rounds of sampling. Dots are individual outliers below or above the whiskers. Deck Types are as described in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> of the main paper: The first number of each option is the EV and the letter symbolizes the ranges: L = ± 0.5, M = ± 2.0. The first two decks appeared only in choices for self and the last two decks only in choices for other.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2: Supplemental Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Inequity Aversion</head><p>As in Experiment 1, we examined first-and second-order inequity aversion (IA) by comparing situations where the decision maker and the other participant selected from the same choice set with situations where either the other (first-order) or the decision maker (second-order) had one high EV option. In terms of first-order IA, <ref type="figure">Figure S4A</ref> shows how people chose the higher EV option 9.1 ± 5.9% more often for the other participant when the deciders had the same options as compared to when they had worse options (W(n=67) = 243, p = .003; β = -0.67, SE = 0.15, p &lt; .001). In terms of second-order IA, <ref type="figure">Figure S4C</ref> shows how people chose the better option for themselves 5.8 ± 4.4% more often when the choice options were the same than when the other person had worse options available, (W(n=67) = 143, p = .014; β = -0.52, SE = 0.17, p = .003). Deck Type</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sample Size</head><p>Splitting up participants into those classified as prosocial and competitive, <ref type="figure">Figure S4B</ref> and S4D show that both types of inequity aversion were mainly expressed by the prosocial participants. Similar to the first study, the interaction between choice sets and classification was significant above the main effects for first-order (β = -1.10, SE = 0.46, p = .017), but not second-order inequity aversion (β = -0.22, SE = 0.54, p = .69). Hence, both first-and secondorder inequity aversion were observed in this task. As in the first experiment and in line with our classification interpretation, inequity aversion was mainly expressed by participants classified as prosocial in other choice situations. <ref type="figure">Figure S4</ref>: (A) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of higher EV choices for the other participant depending on the presence of equal <ref type="bibr">(16)</ref><ref type="bibr">(17)</ref><ref type="bibr">(18)</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sampling</head><p>The total sample sizes in Exp. 2 were set at 80 in the first sampling block and 30 in each of the second and third blocks. The relative distribution of samples was analysed together for all blocks. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure S5</ref> shows how the EV influenced sample size: High-EV decks (green) were sampled more often than the low-EV decks (blue). The different levels of variance (indicated by hue variation), however, did not affect sample size. This pattern was confirmed by a regression of log frequencies on mean and variance as well as random subject effects, where only the mean EV had a significant effect (β = 0.36, SE = 0.04, p &lt; .001). There were no obvious differences in the sampling pattern for participants classified as prosocial or antisocial. In sum, these results are in line with the first experiment and suggest that participants sampled more from high-EV options than from low-EV options. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure S5</ref>: Boxplot with median, quartiles and whiskers as first quartile minus 1.5 times the interquartile range and third quartile plus 1.5 times the interquartile range of sample size for each of the 8 decks. Sample size was aggregated across all three rounds of sampling. Dots are individual outliers below or above the whiskers. Deck details are as described in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> of the main paper: The first number of each option is the EV and the letter symbolizes variance levels: L = ± 0.5, M = ± 2.0, H = ± 4.0. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Screenshot from (A) the sampling block and (B) the choice block. Each square represents a deck of cards, and the symbols indicated the underlying distribution for a draw from that deck. The distributions could only be learned by sampling from each of the decks.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>B</head><label></label><figDesc>In the choice blocks, participants made 21 pairs of binary choices between the decks.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>(A) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of risky choices for all risk-attitude choice situations and then separately for those with the same expected value (1-3) and those with a risk-return trade-off (4-5). Grey dots are choice percentages for individual participants using horizontal jitter. (B) Mean percentage (± 95% CI) of risky choices for choice with a riskreturn trade-off (4-5), split by participant classification as prosocial or anti-social. (C) Percentage of risky choices for others in the risk-return trade-off choices (4-5) correlated with the percentage of dominant choice for other in classification trials</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>(A) Comparison of classification of prosocial behavior in the decision-fromexperience task (choices 20 &amp; 21) and the SVO Questionnaire (mini-dictator games). (B) Correlation between risky choice for others in the risk-return trade-off choices 4 &amp; 5 and the SVO Questionnaire. In both figures the colors signify classification based on the decisionfrom-experience task and vertical jitter was used to enable visibility of all datapoints.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Withthis alternate classification, 19 participants were classified as anti-social (of which one was not classified as anti-social originally and 8 previously classified as anti-social are absent) and 24 as prosocial (of which one was not classified as prosocial originally, and two previously A anti-social neither prosocial -</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>5, d = 0.28, p &gt; .250). A logistic regression confirmed a significant interaction between choosing for self and other and being classified anti-social or prosocial according to choices 18 and 19 in risk-return trade-off choices: β = 3.08, SE = 0.51, p &lt; .001. Furthermore, we checked for robustness of our analyses with respect to sampling errors. To do so, we compared the sampled mean and variance with the theoretical mean and variance of the respective choice options. After the first round of sampling, in none of the 348 relevant comparisons (risk-return trade-off choices 4 &amp; 5 and classification choices 20 &amp; 21)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>lower outcome for the other person. Thus, anti-social behavior was more pronounced here than in the SVO, where there were trade-offs between one's own and another person's outcome.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>(A) Comparison of the two methods for classification of prosocial individuals in Exp 2-choices with a dominant option for others in the mainDfE task (i.e., and the SVO Questionnaire (dictator games). (B) Correlation between choosing riskily for others in the risk-return trade-off choices (Choices 7-9 in the DfE task) and classification from the SVO Questionnaire. In both figures the colors signify classification based on the decision-from-experience task and vertical jitter was used. ** p &lt; .01RobustnessAbove, as pre-registered, we classified individuals on the basis of a subset of trials where there were dominant (higher mean; equal or smaller range) options for others </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>more often (W(n = 36) = 743, d = 0.37, p &gt; .250. A logistic regression confirmed this significant interaction between risk preference for self and other and being classified as antisocial or prosocial according to Choices 16-18: β = 3.53, SE = 0.53, p &lt; .001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>correct range answers was non-significant: r = -0.11, t(65) = -0.92, p &gt; .250. Similarly, a t-test (corrected for heterogeneous variances) for difference in number of correct range questions between anti-social and prosocial participants was non-significant (M Antisocial = 2.31 and M Prosocial = 2.03, t(18.99) = 0.80, p &gt; .25).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>S2: (A) Percentage (± 95% CI) of risky choices for different aspiration levels. Sameoptions for oneself and the other have same expected values(1-3). Loss -The other has higher EV options (6-8) and gain -oneself has higher EV options (9-11). (B) Choices for</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>shows the 21 choice situations, each consisting of a choice between 2 decks</cell></row><row><cell>for the decision maker and a choice between 2 decks for the other participant. Choices were</cell></row><row><cell>presented in a random order and presented once in each block. Each of the situations was</cell></row><row><cell>selected to test a particular hypothesis about how risk and inequity influence decision-making</cell></row><row><cell>in this social situation. The first 5 choices examined risk attitude for self and other, comparing</cell></row><row><cell>risk preference for identical choices, with a risk-return trade-off in choices 4 and 5. The next 6</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Choice situations in Experiment 1.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Choice</cell><cell>Self-A</cell><cell>Self-B</cell><cell cols="2">Other-A Other-B</cell><cell>Choose B</cell><cell>Choose B</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Self in %</cell><cell>Other in %</cell></row><row><cell>Risk Attitude</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>51</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>47</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>52</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>80</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>90</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Social Aspiration level</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>53</cell></row><row><cell>7</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>41</cell></row><row><cell>8</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>43</cell></row><row><cell>9</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>54</cell></row><row><cell>10</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>51</cell></row><row><cell>11</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>53</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Inequity Aversion</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>12</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>55</cell></row><row><cell>13</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>51</cell></row><row><cell>14</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>80</cell></row><row><cell>15</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>88</cell></row><row><cell>16</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>83</cell></row><row><cell>17</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>87</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Comparison -No Inequity Aversion</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>18</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>4.5L</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>91</cell></row><row><cell>19</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>4.5M</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>91</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Catch Trials &amp; Classification</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>20</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>2.5L</cell><cell>6.5L</cell><cell>96</cell></row><row><cell>21</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>2.5M</cell><cell>6.5M</cell><cell>94</cell></row><row><cell>Note.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">The pre-registration indicated that paired t-tests would be used, but the choice proportions were not normally distributed, so Wilcoxon tests were used instead. Sticking with the t-tests also yields the same qualitative conclusions.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">A full analysis as stated in the preregistration was not possible because deck target was nested within the different levels of EV.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measurements and effects of social-value orientation in social dilemmas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Au</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Kwong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Contemporary Psychological Research on Social Dilemmas</title>
		<editor>R. Suleiman, D. V. Budescu, I. Fisher, &amp; D. M. Messick</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fitting linear mixedeffects models using lme4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maechler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bolker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk taking in relationships: Differences in deciding for oneself versus for a friend</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Beisswanger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hupp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Allgaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ERC: A theory of equity, reciprocity, and competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ockenfels</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="166" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Betrayal aversion: Evidence from Brazil</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ockenfels</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comment. American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="628" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social responsibility promotes conservative risk behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ockenfels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stauf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="127" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social Preferences under Risk-An Experimental Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bradler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Jena Economic Research Papers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">22</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dictating the risk: Experimental evidence on giving in risky environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Brock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lange</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ozbay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does wage rank affect employees&apos; well-being?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Oswald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Industrial Relations: A Journal of Economy and Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of responsibility in strategic risktaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Charness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding social preferences with simple tests</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Charness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="817" to="869" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are you risk averse over other people&apos;s money?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chakravarty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Haruvy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rutström</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Southern Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="901" to="913" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Satisfaction and comparison income</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Oswald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="359" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dictator games: A meta study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="583" to="610" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Excusing selfishness in charitable giving: The role of risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Exley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Review of Economic Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="587" to="628" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting moral wiggle room: experiments demonstrating an illusory preference for fairness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Kuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economic Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="80" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affect, empathy, and regressive mispredictions of others&apos; preferences under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Faro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Rottenstreich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="541" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of fairness, competition, and cooperation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="817" to="868" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Slow to anger and fast to forgive: Cooperation in an uncertain world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fudenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dreber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="720" to="749" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The reversed descriptionexperience gap: Disentangling sources of presentation format effects in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hilbig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Henninger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fiedler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">145</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">486</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An experiment on risk taking and evaluation periods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Potters</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="631" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deterministic versus probabilistic consequences of trust and trustworthiness: An experimental investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Güth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Mugera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Musau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ploner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-serving interpretations of ambiguity in otherregarding behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Haisley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games and Economic Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="614" to="625" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions from experience and the effect of rare events in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Barron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="534" to="539" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk aversion and incentive effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Holt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Laury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1644</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fundamental prediction error: Self-others discrepancies in risk preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">126</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">45</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fairness as a constraint on profit seeking: Entitlements in the market</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Knetsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="728" to="741" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Give me a chance!&apos; An experiment in social decision under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Krawczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Le Lec</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="511" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How (in)variant are subjective representations of described and experienced risk and rewards?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pachur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">LmerTest package: Tests in linear mixed effects models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kuznetsova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Brockhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H B</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of social motives, communication and group size on behaviour in an N-person multi-stage mixed-motive game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Liebrand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="264" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Of black swans and tossed coins: is the descriptionexperience gap in risky choice limited to rare events?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20262</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extreme outcomes sway risky decisions from experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="156" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of memory in distinguishing risky decisions from experience and description</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2048" to="2059" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dishonesty of honest people: A theory of selfconcept maintenance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Amir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="633" to="644" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring social value orientation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ackermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Handgraaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="771" to="781" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PsychoPy -Psychophysics software in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Peirce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">162</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk taking by agents: The role of exante and ex-post accountability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pollmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Potters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Trautmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economics Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="390" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.R-project.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<pubPlace>Vienna, Austria</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">RStudio: Integrated Development for</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Studio Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">;</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rstudio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Inc</forename><surname>Boston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Url</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.rstudio.com/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Moral preferences, moral constraints, and self-serving biases. Economics Working Papers 95-241</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California at Berkeley</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risky shift versus cautious shift: determining differences in risk taking between private and public management decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sherwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business &amp; Economics Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of environmental uncertainty and social value orientation in resource dilemmas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Roch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Samuelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="235" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk attitudes in a social context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rohde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Rohde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Blame avoidance as motivating force in the first price sealed bid private value auction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Selten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Economics Essays</title>
		<editor>G. Debreu, W. Neuefeind, &amp; W. Trockel</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="344" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A social values analysis of self-other differences in decision making involving risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Allgaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relative income, happiness, and utility: An explanation for the Easterlin paradox and other puzzles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tideman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Frijters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Shields</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Literature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="144" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A meta-analytic review of two modes of learning and the description-experience gap</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Wulff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mergenthaler-Canseco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">144</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
