<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral and cognitive neuroscience findings regarding assumptions of the evidence accumulation model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yikang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanjing Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>210024</postCode>
									<settlement>Nanjing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hu</forename><surname>Chuan-Peng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanjing Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>210024</postCode>
									<settlement>Nanjing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral and cognitive neuroscience findings regarding assumptions of the evidence accumulation model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1360/TB-2023-1080</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:38+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Decision-making</term>
					<term>evidence accumulation</term>
					<term>cognitive modeling</term>
					<term>theoretical assumptions</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The evidence accumulation model is a widely used cognitive model of human decision-making, which assumes that decision-makers continuously gather and integrate information into evidence relevant to the decision and make a decision once the accumulated evidence reaches a predefined threshold. With the increasing popularity of evidence accumulation model, some researchers claim it has reached a theoretical plateau and can be considered as the standard model for analyzing response time and choices. However, the theoretical assumptions underlying these models lack rigorous testing. As an example, the drift-diffusion model (DDM) is an instantiation of evidence accumulation and has five underlying assumptions: (1) the universality of evidence accumulation; (2) the selectivity of evidence accumulation; (3) linear integration of evidence with noise; (4) a constant decision criterion; and (5) decision-making is independent of motor execution. DDM has been widely used in cognitive tasks, such as value-based decision-making, and social decision-making, probably due to the availability of user-friendly software for parameter estimation. However, only a few studies systematically examined to what extent these five assumptions of DDM were supported by empirical studies. To fill the gap, we reviewed studies that tested these five assumptions. For the first assumption of DDM, the universality of evidence accumulation, we only found direct evidence from studies that employed perceptual decision-making tasks. For other studies that used DDM for modeling, such as value-based decision-making or social decision-making, we found few studies that directly tested the existence of evidence accumulation. The second assumption, the selectivity of evidence accumulation, suggested that only information related to the goal would contribute to evidence accumulation. We did not find empirical data supporting this assumption except for O&apos;Connell et al. (2012). However, evidence from conflict tasks (e.g., flanker task) suggested that information irrelevant to the goal may also be incorporated into the evidence accumulation. Data from conflict tasks inspired new models related to evidence accumulation model and called for further investigation into the mechanism behind the selectivity of evidence. The third and fourth assumptions constitute the core assumptions of DDM, i.e., &quot;evidence accumulate-to-bound&quot;. Regarding the third assumption, which posits that evidence with noise is accumulated linearly, supporting data were found from animal studies and human EEG studies that employed perceptual decision-making. However, human EEG data from value-based decision-making tasks has challenged the validity of this Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Decision-making, which refers to the process of choosing between different options, is an integral part of people's lives and is the participant of interdisciplinary research <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> . Researchers have proposed a large number of theoretical models to explain human decision-making behavior, such as Rational Model in economics <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[2]</ref> and Prospect Theory in behavioral economics <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[3]</ref> . In cognitive science, researchers pay more attention to the cognitive process of decision making. For example, based on information processing theory, decision-making is regarded as the process of processing and integrating information <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">5]</ref> ; or based on computational theory, decision-making is regarded as the process of calculating the probability of choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[6]</ref> . These theoretical models can help us better understand the nature of decision-making and the process by which the brain makes decisions.</p><p>Evidence accumulation model (EAM) is a type of theoretical model used to explain the decisionmaking process in cognitive science, which assumes that human decision-making process follows the mechanism of evidence accumulation, i.e., the decision maker collects information from multiple sources from the external environment or internal memory to form evidence. As evidence accumulates, the decision maker approaches a threshold required to make a decision, and once that threshold is reached, the decision maker stops accumulating evidence and makes a decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref> . Due to its manner of accumulating evidence by sampling from the external environment or internal memory based on the current information available at each time point, it is alternatively referred to as a Sequential Sampling Model (SSM). Both terms are interchangeably used by researchers, and in the following text, it will be consistently referred to as EAM. EAM provides researchers with a theoretical framework for explaining human decision-making behavior and mathematically translates it into a concrete computational model, which provides the researcher with an important tool for understanding empirical data. For example, researchers have proposed the Drift Diffusion Model (DDM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">11]</ref> under the framework of EAM to explain the decision maker's fast decision making behavior, which has been applied not only to explain the results of simple binomial forced-choice tasks, but also to perceptual decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[17]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref> , value-based decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">20]</ref> , and social cognitive tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref> , and it is one of the important models in current computational psychiatry <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref> .</p><p>It is due to the widespread use of EAM that some researchers have pointed out that the development of EAM has reached a "Plateau" <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[25]</ref> . Based on this judgment, Evans and Wagenmakers <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[25]</ref> Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL.</p><p>Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 EAM assumes that there are two basic mechanisms in the decision-making process of human decision makers: the evidence accumulation process and the decision-making mechanism <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref> . The evidence accumulation mechanism explains how decision-related evidence accumulates, and it usually assumes that there exists a Decision Variable (DV), which is continuously updated over time, i.e., the process of accumulating decision-related evidence. The decision mechanism explains when a decision maker makes a decision, and it usually assumes that there is a decision boundary or decision-making criteria, which is quantified as the amount of accumulated evidence needed to make a decision, and the decision maker makes a decision when the amount of accumulated evidence reaches or exceeds this threshold.</p><p>In empirical studies, researchers need to specify the two mechanisms of EAM to construct different computational models for computational modeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref> . Therefore, there are several specific computational models under the EAM framework, the most widely used of which is the Drift diffusion model (DDM). DDM takes only the outcome of a time-pressured two-item forced-choice task (response time and choice) as modeling objects, and further specifies the above two mechanisms on the basis of EAM: (1) there exists only one decision variable in the decision process, which accumulates evidence linearly; (2) the two options correspond to different decision-making processes which are fixed and do not change over time in the same decision task. When the amount of accumulated evidence reaches the decision boundary, the decision maker makes response <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">11]</ref> . However, including only these two mechanisms still does not provide a complete explanation of the results about the two forced-choice tasks. The reason is that from the time the decision maker receives an external stimulus to the time he or she makes a choice, the whole process, in addition to the evidence accumulation, also includes stimulus encoding and response execution <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8]</ref> . In the stage of stimulus encoding, the brain needs to receive physical stimuli from various external sensory modalities to form sensory information, and select the task-related sensory information to be integrated as evidence for decision making. In the evidence accumulation stage, the brain accumulates the integrated evidence to form decision variables and sets fixed decision boundaries to determine decision-making criteria. Finally, in the response execution stage, the signals formed by the decision are transmitted to the brain regions responsible for motor execution to make the corresponding response action. Thus, when modeling data from behavioral tasks using DDM, five specific model assumptions are actually involved: evidence accumulation is universal; evidence accumulation is selective; evidence accumulates is linear with</p><p>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 noise; decision-making criteria is constant; and the decision-making process is independent of response execution (see the first three columns of <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>).</p><p>Firstly, Evidence accumulation is universal. The assumption is that decision evidence can come from a variety of information (sensory, memory, economic or social value) relevant to the decision, whether it is sensory information from different sensory modalities (sound, light, or smell) or from more abstract information (option-based values or information extracted from memory). This information is encoded and transformed so that it can be converted into abstract decision evidence for accumulation. Although the proponents of the DDM, such as Ratcliff et al., explicitly stated that the DDM is applicable to faster two-choice tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref> , researchers from different fields still widely apply the DDM to various decision tasks and interpret the estimated parameters of the DDM based on their significance in perceptual decision-making (e.g., Hu et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[28]</ref> ). Therefore, from this perspective, researchers from different research domains implicitly assume that the evidence accumulation process in the DDM can generally apply to the cognitive processes of multiple tasks.</p><p>Secondly, the evidence accumulation is selective. In the decision-making process, the decisionmaker receives a large amount of information, but not all information is relevant to the task goal, and the decision-making evidence includes only the information relevant to the decision-making goal.</p><p>Therefore, in the process of transforming sensory or other forms of information into decision-making evidence, only information relevant to the goal will be transformed into decision-making evidence.</p><p>Thirdly, the evidence is accumulated linearly with noise, assuming that decision-makers integrate the sampled information from the external environment or memory linearly. The overall process of evidence integration is conducted linearly, but it exists noise, which follows a normal distribution. It is precisely the existence of noise that introduces random variability in the decision-making process. By linearly integrating the sampled information, the noise at different time points cancels out, resulting in a linear accumulation of decision evidence over time.</p><p>Fourthly, decision-making criteria is constant. This assumption proposes that the criteria for forming the final decision are fixed in individual decisions. Once the accumulated evidence meets this criterion, the decision maker makes a decision. According to this assumption, the criteria for decision making in a single decision do not change over time, and the amount of evidence required to form a decision is constant regardless of when the decision is formed. Together with the third assumption, this hypothesis forms the "accumulate-to-bound" pattern.</p><p>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080</p><p>Fifthly, Decision-making is independent of reaction execution. This assumption distinguishes between two processes in decision making: decision formation and response execution. Further, the drift-diffusion model assumes that these two processes occur sequentially and are independent of each other. When a decision is formed, a response needs to be executed through a response execution process, such as keypress, eye movements, or verbal reports, whereas the response execution process will only begin after the decision is formed and will not have an impact on the decision-making process. Just as statistical assumptions need to be satisfied to perform t-tests, the five assumptions mentioned above also constrain the algorithmic implementation of DDM. There is also a need to ensure Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 that these assumptions hold true when applying DDM, otherwise its parameters need to be interpreted with caution. However, these assumptions are seldom expressed in a systematic and clear manner, which may have led researchers to ignore the importance of these assumptions and test them less rigorously. Also, due to the lack of clear expression of these assumptions, researchers are less likely to question the plausibility of these model assumptions, i.e., whether each of them has been tested in empirical studies. By critically scrutinizing and empirically testing these five assumptions, this paper finds that the models still need more empirical data to be examined, rather than being able to be used directly as a standard model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Empirical tests of DDM assumptions</head><p>Studies that validate DDM model assumptions can be categorized into two types. Observations for these studies may be single-cell recordings of animal nerve cells, which have high temporal resolution and can be accurately localized to specific brain structures, or non-invasive recorded electroencephalogram (EEG) or magnetoencephalography (MEG) data of human decisionmaking processes. It is worth pointing out that since human decision-making is a process that takes place over time, these techniques provide observations of the decision-making process with a high temporal resolution, which is more useful for validating model assumptions.</p><p>Overall, these techniques need to be combined with a specific experimental design to provide a more robust test. Through precise experimental design and the use of neural recording techniques with high temporal resolution, researchers can better validate the assumptions of DDM models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Evidence accumulation is universal</head><p>Currently, DDM is widely used in perceptual decision making, value-based decision making, and social decision making. Implicit in all these applications is the common assumption that there is a process of evidence accumulation in decision-making tasks, where evidence can be various information In perceptual decision making, O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> directly tested this assumption, supporting the assumption that decision evidence is stable across modalities. They used both visual and auditory experimental materials to verify the existence of decision evidence across modalities. The visual stimulus was a circle that flicked at a fixed frequency, and the auditory stimulus was a continuous tone.</p><p>During the task, the contrast/volume of the two stimuli gradually decreased, and participants were required to judge whether the contrast/volume had decreased or not. The results of the study showed that during perceptual decision-making with both stimuli, the researchers observed the Centro-Parietal Positivity (CPP), an EEG indicator of evidence accumulation.</p><p>Apart from O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> who directly compared the process of evidence accumulation in perceptual decision making across modal stimuli, research on whether the evidence accumulation process is stable across modalities is more limited. However, there are a number of findings that provide indirect evidence for this assumption. In these studies, researchers did not specifically design experiments to validate the existence of the evidence accumulation process. However, they employed paradigms that are commonly used in classical perceptual decision-making tasks. Firstly, in the visual modality, researchers asked participants to judge the orientation of gratings <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[49]</ref> , the direction of random dot motion <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[42,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">50,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">51]</ref> , or the similarity of faces <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[52]</ref> . They found neural activity in participants consistent with evidence accumulation. Secondly, in studies using auditory stimuli alone, researchers asked participants to discriminate sounds, and they also observed neural activity consistent with evidence accumulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[53,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">54]</ref> . Additionally, when stimuli were presented simultaneously from both the visual and auditory modalities, researchers observed the neural correlate of evidence accumulation, known as the CPP <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[53]</ref> . However, there is relatively little evidence for perceptual decision-making tasks from modalities other than visual/auditory stimuli alone or audiovisual integrated stimuli.</p><p>In addition, there is a relative lack of validation studies on the existence of evidence accumulation processes in other decision-making tasks in non-perceptual decision-making. In memory extraction studies, some researchers have argued that the process of evidence accumulation also exists in memory</p><p>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 retrieval <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7]</ref> , whereas it is still controversial whether evidence accumulation exists in value-based decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[55]</ref> . Frömer et al. point out that value-based decision making is a process in which goal-directed and automated processing work together, and not just the process of evidence accumulation. They argue that if there exists evidence accumulation for value-based decision making, then researchers would be able to observe CPP signals, an EEG marker characterizing evidence accumulation, in EEG recordings. However, using the deconvolution technique, the researchers found that the EEG data could be decomposed primarily into an emotion-related component and a valuerelated component, and neither component showed a pattern of evidence accumulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref> . However, this study does not rule out methodological limitations as the absence of CPP may not indicate the nonexistence of CPP but rather the failure of the deconvolution method to extract CPP components.</p><p>Therefore, this conclusion still requires further validation.</p><p>In conclusion, the generalizability of "evidence" in DDM is an assumption for the wide application of DDM to perceptual decision-making, value/social decision-making, and memory research. However, validation studies on the existence of evidence accumulation in decision-making processes have mainly focused on simple perceptual decision-making tasks, whereas in other decisionmaking tasks (e.g., value-based decision-making), direct evidence on the process of evidence accumulation is still scarce, and even questionable <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[41]</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Evidence accumulation is selective</head><p>In the assumptions of DDM model, external stimuli are encoded and transformed into evidence for decision making, but not all stimuli are encoded as evidence. From the point of view that the evidence accumulation serves for decision-making, the evidence accumulation should be selective, i.e., only external stimuli that are relevant to the decision-making goal will be accumulated.</p><p>O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> tested this assumption experimentally. Similar to the experimental manipulation described above, participants were required to determine whether the contrast of the circles had changed. In this task, the contrast of the circles was correlated with the decision goal, and participants were able to observe not only the Steady-State Visual-Evoked Potential (SSVEP) associated with the sensory input to the stimulus, but also the CPP, the EEG signal for the evidence accumulation. In another task, however, participants saw the same frequency of flicked circles, but the task was to note whether the square at the central gaze point had changed. In this task, the contrast of the circles was no longer correlated with the decision goal (the size of the background square), and the Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 researcher did not observe the CPP, but was still able to observe the SSVEP reflecting sensory information input. Similarly, Loughnane et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref> using a variant of the random-dot motion paradigm also found that the CPP can be observed when participants were asked to determine the direction-n of the random-dot motion; however, when the participants' task was to detect a color change between random dot movement intervals, random dot movement did not trigger the CPP. It is evident that only stimuli relevant to the experimental task are able to form evidence.</p><p>In addition, based on the characteristics of limited human attentional resources, the researchers proposed that stimuli receiving human attention would be encoded as evidence more efficiently, while stimuli not receiving human attention would be encoded as evidence less efficiently. Based on this view, they established aDDM (Attentional Drift Diffusion Model) <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[32]</ref> . The aDDM assumes that attention influences the evidence accumulation in decision-making, thereby impacting the final choice.</p><p>This assumption suggests that decision-makers pay more attention to options they consider relevant to the ultimate decision goal, and options that receive more attention are more likely to be chosen. When they attend to a particular option, they continuously accumulate evidence related to that option while disregarding the evidence of unattended options. The aDDM utilizes eye-tracking data as an external indicator of attention and has successfully explained a range of value-based decision phenomena <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[56,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">57]</ref> for instance, Sheng et al. used the aDDM to successfully explain the endowment effect in economics <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[58]</ref> , which provides evidence that evidence accumulation is selective.</p><p>However, in the two studies mentioned above, the mutual interference between the task target and the stimuli was weak. For example, in the experiment by O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> changes in contrast were much less pronounced than changes in the size of the gaze point. Thus, when participants were asked to attend to changes in the gaze point, contrast changes did not interfere. However, in many other cognitive tasks, stimuli unrelated to the task goal may be so obvious that it is difficult for participants to ignore their presence. In classic cognitive conflict tasks (Stroop task, Flanker task, Simon task), taskirrelevant information has a strong effect on decision making. Under these contexts, outside information has a significant effect on evidence accumulation. Under the EAM framework, researchers are trying to build corresponding computational models based on the characteristics of conflict tasks instead of directly using the standard DDM <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[59]</ref> .</p><p>However, the study by Tump et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[21]</ref> in the context of social decision-making may raise questions about this assumption. The researchers asked participants to complete a social decision task</p><p>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080</p><p>where the relevant information for the decision was the quantity of target stimuli (sharks) on the screen.</p><p>According to this assumption, irrelevant information would not be transformed into evidence and would not impact the decision outcome. However, when participants observed the decisions of others in the group, the decisions of others also influenced the participants' choices. These findings suggest that the selectivity of evidence transformation is not solely dependent on the relevance of information to the task goal. Tump et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[21]</ref> also found that these results could not be explained using the standard DDM model but instead required a modification of the DDM, using a Social DDM model that incorporates social information to better explain the results.</p><p>Therefore, the assumption that "evidence accumulation is selective" in DDM may have some boundaries of applicability, and is mainly applicable to standard perceptual decision-making tasks, while it may not be satisfied for cognitive tasks involving cognitive conflicts or other decision tasks where factors can influence the task outcome. This implies that researchers need to adopt more appropriate models, but empirical studies are needed to validate this idea.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Evidence accumulation is linear with noise</head><p>One of the core assumptions of DDM is that external stimuli are encoded and then integrated into the decision variables at a specific rate, thus enabling the accumulation of the amount of evidence over time. This process may be somewhat random and exists noise, but overall it is linearly accumulative and the amount of evidence accumulates without leakage or forgetting.</p><p>The study by Stine et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[33]</ref> altered the design of a random- Okazawa et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[34]</ref> then tested this assumption by manipulating the intensity of sensory stimulus evidence accumulation. The results of Okazawa et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[34]</ref> suggest that a linear evidence accumulation model is more in line with the true performance of the participants.</p><p>A study by Roitman and Shadlen <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[28]</ref> provided neurophysiological data to support the linear accumulation of decision variables. They found that firing rate of neurons in the lateral intraparietal area (LIP) during perceptual decision making in monkeys were similar to the way evidence for decision making accumulates. According to the third assumption of DDM, there should be specific representations in neural activity that are used to indicate that evidence for a decision accumulates at a specific rate. Specifically, there is a difference in the brain between the firing rate of neurons that characterize one option and those that characterize another option, a difference that can indicate current evidence for a decision, and that this evidence accumulates over time, resulting in a gradual increase in the firing rate of specific brain regions. The researchers asked trained monkeys to judge the direction of motion of random dots on a screen, and they found that when the random dots began to move in the direction of the target, the firing rate of neurons in the LIP brain region gradually increased at a specific rate, and when the firing rate reached a peak, the monkeys responded, which was consistent with the dynamics of firing rate under the assumption that the evidence was accumulated at a specific rate.</p><p>Moreover, according to the above assumptions, if participants face a relatively simple decisionmaking task and they can make a decision easily, the firing rate in support of one option will be higher than that in support of the other, the greater the evidence for decision-making under the same moment, and the faster the firing rate of neurons in the corresponding brain region will increase. In contrast, when participants were faced with a more difficult decision-making task, they had difficulty making a decision, the difference between the firing rate supporting one option and the other was not large, the smaller the evidence for decision-making at the same moment was, and the firing rate in the corresponding brain regions increased more slowly. The researchers observed that when the monkeys completed the task, the easier the task and the shorter the response time, the faster the firing rate of LIP neurons increased, whereas the more difficult the task and the longer the response time, the slower the firing rate of LIP neurons increased. These observations similarly support the assumption that neurons in LIP regions accumulate sensory evidence over time. They also provide support at the neural level for DDM assumption that decision variables accumulate evidence at a specific rate.</p><p>Similarly, O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> observed patterns of EEG activity consistent with the process of evidence accumulation in humans making perceptual decisions. In that experiment, participants were</p><p>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 required to judge whether the contrast of a stimulus had decreased and to perform a key press response.</p><p>O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> observed that the EEG component CPP exhibited a pattern consistent with the process of increased firing rate of LIP neurons in animal studies, whereas this component did not encode visual information (unlike SSVEP) and did not reflect the action preparation processes (unlike Left Hemisphere Beta, LHB). The signal of evidence accumulation in human EEG has been validated in other studies, for example, Philiastides et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[35]</ref> used machine learning techniques to isolate the component of neural activity that predicts coherence condition, and the distribution of the weights of this component on the human scalp was consistent with the topography of the CPP. Behavioral data at each level of coherence were modeled using DDM model, which showed that higher levels of coherence corresponded to faster drift rates <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[35]</ref> . These findings further support the existence of linear evidence accumulation in human perceptual decision making. suggested that this may be an artifact due to the overlap of different components of EEG activity <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref> .</p><p>Thus, the observed CPP does not directly provide evidence for the third assumption of DDM.</p><p>However, further empirical studies are still needed to verify whether the third assumption of DDM remains true in value-based decision making.</p><p>In conclusion, behavioral experiments in perceptual decision making with high temporal resolution of neural data recording give strong supporting evidence for the third assumption of DDM, but it remains questionable whether this assumption is true in value-based decision making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Decision-making criteria is constant</head><p>The first three assumptions of DDM focus on the process of generating and accumulating evidence for decision making, while the fourth assumption is that the decision maker's decision-making criteria is fixed. Decision boundaries are also known as decision thresholds, a concept derived from signal detection theory. In signal detection theory, the decision boundary divides possible observations into two categories, "signal" and "noise". In DDM, the decision boundary represents the amount of Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 evidence required to form a decision. It is worth noting that within the EAM framework, researchers have made different assumptions about the form of the decision boundary; DDM assumes that the decision boundary remains constant throughout the decision-making process <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8]</ref> , but other variations of the EAM, such as the collapsing boundary model, assume that the decision criterion gets lower and lower over time, i.e., that less evidence is required to reach the boundary <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">60]</ref> . Here, we will focus only on DDM model's assumptions about constant decision boundaries.</p><p>Hawkins et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[36]</ref> and Voss et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[37]</ref> compared models for a large number of data, and the results are more supportive of the idea that decision boundaries do not change over time. Hawkins et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[36]</ref> analyzed nine different datasets, including human and primate decision data under different paradigms,</p><p>including the random-dot motion paradigm, the brightness discrimination paradigm, and the dot with collapsed boundaries, which further supports the assumption that decision boundaries remain fixed. Voss et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[37]</ref> also provide evidence for this assumption by the method of model comparison.</p><p>Their experiment consisted of two tasks, a single-stimulus task in which participants were required to identify whether the presented stimulus was a number or a letter, and a multi-stimulus task in which participants were required to determine whether the presented stimulus were letters or numbers. The results of the model fit similarly supported the assumption that decision boundaries do not change over time.</p><p>The study by Stine et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[38]</ref> validates the assumption that decision boundaries remain fixed during decision making directly at the level of neural activity. terminating decisions is temporarily weakened, and more amount of evidence is needed to form a decision, which leads to a longer time of accumulating evidence in the LIP brain region, and at the same time, the longer response time means that more noise in the process of accumulating evidence is counteracted, which biases responses toward particular options. The experimental results support this view. Crucially, there was little difference in the peak of SC firing rate corresponding to different reaction durations, providing evidence for the assumption of a fixed decision boundary. In addition,</p><p>Purcell et al. found that firing rate of neurons in the frontal eye fields (FEF) region were similar to those in the LIP region <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[39]</ref> , and that the firing rate of neurons in this region of the brain ramped during decision making until they reached a fixation threshold at the time of the response, which also provides evidence for the assumption that the decision boundary remains fixed during the decision making process.</p><p>The assumption that the decision boundary is fixed is also supported in human EEG recordings by a permutation test of the amplitude in a time window before the CPP signal peaks by O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> . The potential of the CPP signal ramps from stimulus onset until it reaches threshold and begins to fall. If the threshold is fixed, which means that the threshold of the CPP does not vary much regardless of the participants' response time, then the amplitude within a window of time before the response time does not vary much between trials. However, if there is no fixed threshold for the CPP, then there will Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 be a significant difference in amplitude between trials that cannot be distinguished from the randomized level. To verify that the peak CPP at the time the participant made the response was fixed, the researchers verified it using a permutation test. They formed a random distribution by disrupting the correspondence between response time and CPP by randomly redistributing the response time from one trial to the other. This distribution reflected the variation in CPP amplitude during a specific time window before the reaction. The experimental results showed that the likelihood of the variation in amplitude measured before the response in each trial appearing in the randomized distribution was very small (less than 5%). This provides evidence that evidence accumulates up to a fixed threshold in the decision-making process.</p><p>However, Churchland et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[40]</ref> found evidence that was inconsistent with previous assumptions.</p><p>They found that without presenting participants with any information, firing rate in LIP brain regions still grow and participants respond randomly. And according to DDM's assumptions, in the absence of any evidence for decision-making, participants should have no evidence to accumulate and thus have difficulty making decisions. But the researchers found results that differed from this by asking trained rats to judge the direction of movement of dots on a screen, during which time the firing rate of the LIP brain region was recorded. It turned out that neurons in the LIP region fired even when the coherence of the stimulus was zero, i.e., when the dot on the screen was moving in a random direction, at which point the participants' rate of accuracy approached a random level. This implies that firing rate of neurons in the LIP brain region is not a process that reflects the evidence accumulation for decision making. Therefore, the researchers explain that the firing rate of neurons in the LIP brain region when there is no valid information input reflects the information that prompts the decision maker to respond,</p><p>i.e., the signal of time urgency. This signal of time urgency prompts participants to make a decision, but it is independent of the process of evidence accumulation, which together influence decision making and lead to the descend of the decision criterion over time. This explanation is consistent with the mechanism by which decision boundaries collapse over time and supports the idea that decision boundaries change over time.</p><p>Steinemann et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[41]</ref> and Kelly et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[42]</ref> also found evidence in human EEG recordings that questioned this assumption. As a neural marker in the EEG that indicates the evidence accumulation, the amplitude of the CPP reflects the amount of accumulated evidence, whereas the amplitude of the CPP at the time of response reflects the amount of evidence required to make a decision, i.e., the Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 decision boundary. If the decision boundary does not change over time, then the amplitude of the CPP at the time of the response is consistent regardless of the participants' response time. However, if the decision boundary collapses over time and the amount of evidence required becomes less and less, then the longer the response time, the lower the peak amplitude of the CPP. The findings suggest that the peak amplitude of the CPP decreases with response time. These findings do not support the assumption that decision boundaries do not change over time.</p><p>It is worth noting that in tasks where the decision boundary changes, there is usually a time constraint on the task that participants complete, requiring a decision to be made within a specified time. Thus, time constraints may be a condition under which this assumption cannot hold, an idea that still requires further research and testing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Decision-making is independent of response execution</head><p>The last implicit assumption of DDM is the distinction between the decision-making process and the response execution process, which is independent of each other and do not affect each other. Under this assumption, participants begin to perform a response action only after the decision has been formed. However, validation of this assumption faces great difficulties due to the fact that, when performing task with response, human participants are usually asked to perform a reaction by pressing a key, which makes it difficult to distinguish between the process of evidence accumulation and the process of response execution. If participants are asked not to response, no behavioral indicators of the participants' behavior can be observed. Therefore, to validate this assumption, data sources except behavior are needed.</p><p>O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> observed evidence in support of this assumption using EEG techniques. In EEG, CPP is closely associated with the process of evidence accumulation and may be a neuromarker of evidence accumulation, whereas the LHB is an EEG component that appears in the left hemisphere during response execution. The dynamics of the CPP and LHB are highly similar when participants perform action based on a specific decision outcome, and they both peak when a decision is made.</p><p>However, if the participant does not execute a specific action response while making a decision, a separation of CPP and LHB potentials may be observed. Since there is no action response, the LHB will not appear, but the participant still needs to make an implicit perceptual decision, and therefore the CPP, an EEG indicator of evidence accumulation, will still appear. Following this reason, O' Connell et al. asked participants in a task to determine whether a change in circular contrast had occurred to</p><p>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 count the total number in a set of trials in which the contrast had changed. It occurred as a perceptual decision (detecting a change in contrast) and without the need to make a keypress response. In this case, the researcher still observed CPP but not LHB. This result suggests that in human perceptual decision making, evidence accumulation is independent of motor preparation.</p><p>However, no evidence supporting this assumption has been found in animal studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">44]</ref> . If the movement process is independent of the evidence accumulation process, then intervening on the movement execution process alone should not have an effect on the decision outcome without changing the information presented to the participant. When monkeys were asked to judge the direction of movement of random dots, the researcher interrupted eye movements at a random time by interrupting the random-dot motion stimulus and applying a brief electric current to the FEF area; the intervention triggered a bias in the participants' movements, and this induced influence biased the monkeys toward choosing the direction of the current eye movement more favorably. The results showed that the motion bias indeed influenced the final choice outcome of the monkey, while the trajectories of the decision variables fitted to the behavioral data were consistent with the trajectories of the monkeys' eye movements after being subjected to the electric current. This experiment suggests that the movement process and the decision-making process are not independent of each other when monkeys make decisions, and that the movement process affects the monkey's decision-making process.</p><p>Voss et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[45]</ref> have also questioned the assumption that the decision process is independent of the motor process. According to this assumption, if the decision process is independent of the motor process, previous decision outcomes should not impact non-decision time, regardless of the chosen option. However, if the decision process does influence the motor process, there would be differences in non-decision time associated with different options. They incorporated these differences in nondecision time between options as a new parameter into the standard DDM. If this parameter is nonzero, it suggests that the decision process does impact the motor execution process. Empirically, Starns</p><p>and Ma <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[46]</ref> validated this viewpoint. They found that when a specific mapping was established between options and responses, the response time was faster compared to situations where there was no mapping <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[46]</ref> . The fitting of the data using the modified DDM model by Voss et al. indicated that the parameter representing differences in non-decision time between options was non-zero in the former case. This result challenges the fifth assumption of the DDM at the behavioral level.</p><p>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080</p><p>Weindel et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[47]</ref>  In terms of available empirical studies, researchers have only recently begun to pay attention to the assumption that decision-making is independent of the motor execution process, and the small number of empirical studies currently available remain highly controversial. At the same time, these studies themselves may be deficient; for example, perceptual decision-making task without motor execution conducted by the O' Connell et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> has not been found to be subsequently replicated, so further validation is urgently needed; and while the intervention on movement in the animal studies did affect final response choice, it is still unclear whether this manipulation merely altered behavior (the animal had to choose A, the current did not change its choice, but the execution chose B), or whether it changed the decision (the animal was going to choose B, but the current changed its choice to option A, and the motor execution chose A as well); and it may also be controversial as to whether EMG is a good measure of motor execution in the study by Weindel et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[25]</ref> . These studies and their shortcomings suggest that this assumption of DDM still needs further direct experimental evidence to confirm or deny it.</p><p>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. into evidence, a process that requires greater consideration of neuron-to-loop modeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">[61]</ref> .</p><p>Second, negative results play an important role in cognitive modeling. Positive evidence for model assumptions will provide support for the model, while negative evidence for model assumptions Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 will qualify the scope of the original model, as well as bring about model updating and advance the theory. From the evidence reviewed so far, except for the second assumption of DDM, which lacks empirical studies, evidence questioning the remaining four assumptions of DDM has emerged.</p><p>Contrary to the conclusions of Evans et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[25]</ref> , evidence questioning the assumptions of DDM model suggests that DDM is not a common applicable model and that its ability to serve as a standard model for the analysis of response time data deserved to further debate. For example, in value-based decision making, researchers have found that decision evidence may not accumulate linearly <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref> . Therefore, for scenarios that have not yet been tested in empirical studies, researchers need to be cautious about the conclusions drawn from the use of DDM. Of greater significance is that questioning and supplementing the assumptions of a model lead to its updates. For instance, the Leaky Competing Accumulator model (LCA) supplements and updates the fundamental assumptions of the DDM and its variants. It introduces two additional principles, assuming the existence of leakage and decay in the accumulation of information and the presence of lateral inhibition between accumulations of different options <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[62]</ref> . On the other hand, the Linear Ballistic Accumulator model simplifies the basic assumptions of the LCA by reducing the noise in the evidence accumulation process to a completely linear process <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">[63]</ref> . These Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL. Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080</p><p>Finally, in the current environment of rapid development of artificial intelligence, researchers can combine artificial neural networks and large-scale data to conduct data-driven research. Compared with traditional cognitive modeling, data-driven research can better analyze complex cognitive tasks and make up for the shortcomings of traditional methods in dealing with complex tasks. However, traditional cognitive modeling has advantages in terms of the interpretability of model parameters, and thus more and more studies are trying to combine traditional cognitive modeling with current emerging technologies such as artificial neural networks to advance the understanding of human cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[64]</ref> .</p><p>These studies combine the advantages of cognitive models, which offer good interpretability, with the fitting capabilities of artificial neural networks to explain the cognitive mechanisms of decisionmaking. This approach overcomes the limitations of cognitive models in terms of reliance on researchers' subjective experiences and difficulties in explaining internal states of neural networks. The key lies in validating and refining traditional cognitive models themselves. For example, Rafiei et al.</p><p>constructed and trained a neural network called RTNet based on the evidence accumulation principles of perceptual decision-making, and its performance in decision tasks closely approximated human performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[65]</ref> . Chen et al. combined the characteristics of DDM, which enhances the accuracy of human perceptual decision-making, with deep neural networks to improve the performance of neural networks in classification tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[66]</ref> . Additionally, Masí s et al. employed recurrent neural networks to simulate human decision tasks and demonstrated dynamics consistent with DDM <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[67]</ref> . In the future, in the field of DDM, artificial neural networks can be constructed based on the mechanisms proposed by DDM to perform decision tasks and compare their performance with that of human subjects, thus providing supporting or negating evidence for the assumptions of DDM. In addition, EAM are beginning to be applied in real world <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[68]</ref> , and correctly understanding and improving the evidence accumulation model itself is fundamental to making it useful in real-world applications. Clearly articulated model assumptions can help to more transparently and logically link theory and empirical data, enhance the interpretability of the model, and promote a virtuous circle between theory, model, and empirical data, rather than a "decoupling" between theory and data <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[27]</ref> .</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>input over time. If sensory information is consistently integrated into decision evidence linearly, then the strength of the sensory information over time also affects the rate of evidence accumulation: when the strength of the sensory information is greater, the amount of evidence accumulates faster (i.e., there is a larger incremental increase from the amount of evidence at the current moment to the amount of evidence at the next moment); conversely, if the strength of the current sensory information is less strong, then the rate of evidence accumulation is slower. Based on this logic, the researcher adjusted the spatial and temporal characteristics of faces to manipulate the intensity of input from sensory stimuli. Participants were required to perform an identity and expression categorization task for faces, in which the eyes, nose, and mouth of the face were associated with decision-making goals, and changes in these features resulted in changes in the identity and expression of the face. In the experiment, the stimulus intensity of each feature of the face changes over time when presented. Since changes in the intensity of sensory information about the features of faces can be accurately calculatedat each time point, if the process of transforming sensory information into decision variables (the amount of evidence) is linearly accumulative, then the amount of evidence at each time point is a weighted sum of the intensity of the stimuli presented before that point in time; conversely, if the process of transforming sensory information into decision variables (the amount of evidence) is not linearly accumulative, for example, in the Leakage Competition model, where evidence leaks, the amount of evidence at each time point cannot be obtained simply by a weighted summation of the intensities of previously presented stimuli. The accumulation of decision variables can be fitted to behavioral data by DDM, thus validating and comparing different theoretical assumptions about the Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL.Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The discussion about the manner of evidence accumulation is predicated on the actual existence of evidence accumulation. The first assumption suggests that the majority of evidence supporting the existence of evidence accumulation is derived from the domain of perceptual decision-making, while the question of whether evidence accumulation occurs in other decision tasks remains a matter of debate. Although EEG activity like CPP has been observed in studies in different sensory modalities, some researchers have questioned the CPP signals observed in value-based decision making and have</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>separation paradigm. They employed models with fixed boundaries and collapsing boundaries to fit the data and compared the goodness of fit of these models using Bayesian Information Criterion (BIC), Akaike Information Criterion (AIC), and Likelihood Ratio Tests (LRT). Due to the similarity in the results obtained from the comparison of the three models, the researchers reported only the BIC.A lower BIC indicates a better fit. Models with fixed boundaries had lower BICs compared to models</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>utilized electromyogram (EMG) studies to similarly find evidence questioning this assumption. According to the fifth assumption of DDM, the onset of response execution is the time when the evidence accumulation is complete. According to this assumption, a participant's response time can be divided into three stages: stimulus encoding time, decision time, and response execution time, where the sum of the first two is called premotor time. With known response time, the stimulus encoding time should remain constant under different response requirements, so the premotor time under different response requirements can be separated, and the difference between the premotor time and the response time is the response execution time. The researcher fitted the response time with a DDM model, and according to the preset, there should be no difference in other parameters except for the non-decision time. When a participant is ready to execute an action response, the muscle generates an action potential. By measuring the duration of the EMG signal, this can be considered as the time of response execution. The researchers obtained the response execution time from EMG measurements and isolated the premotor time from it. They found that there were differences in decision thresholds in addition to non-decision times. This suggests that the appearance time of EMG is not equivalent to the end time of evidence accumulation, and that there is an overlap between the time course of evidence accumulation and the actual course of response execution, which are not independent of each other.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>4</head><label></label><figDesc>Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 Summary and outlook EAM, one of the main current frameworks for modeling response times and choices together, are widely used, but studies that test the intrinsic assumptions of each computational model under this framework are relatively rare. We analyze the DDM, which is the most representative model used in EAM, to clearly articulate its five modeling assumptions, and based on this, we review empirical studies that have tested these assumptions. These reviews may provide the following insights for subsequent research:First, the researcher needs a clear articulation of the basic assumptions of DDM in order to test these assumptions more systematically and rigorously. After a clear formulation of the basic assumptions of DDM, it can be seen that there are assumptions that are of great concern to the researcher, as well as some important assumptions that have been overlooked by the researcher. In DDM, the third (evidence accumulation is linear) and fourth assumptions (decision-making criteria is constant) have received much attention from researchers as explicitly stated assumptions, and a large number of researchers have attempted to test their plausibility (or to disprove their plausibility) with empirical studies, while the other three assumptions are implicitly ignored by researchers in the formulation of the model, and fewer empirical studies have directly verified their plausibility.However, all five assumptions of DDM are critical. For example, the generalizability of evidence accumulation is an assumption for researchers to apply DDM to different tasks, and the independence of decision-making and motor execution processes is a theoretical assumption for the independence of non-decision time from other parameters in DDM parameter estimation. Therefore, subsequent cognitive modeling requires a clear brief description or formalization of the model's assumptions so that they can be systematically and rigorously tested. Specifically for DDM model, subsequent research may need to continue to empirically test the assumptions of university of evidence accumulation, selectivity of evidence accumulation, and independence of decision making from motor execution. In particular, researchers may need to consider more carefully what constitutes "evidence" in the decisionmaking tasks of interest to them, and how sensory or memory-extracted information can be converted</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>models have updated the EAM based on questioning the basic assumptions of DDM, advancing the understanding of human decision-making mechanisms. Negative results are therefore essential to advance the development and improvement of cognitive modeling. Third, in future empirical studies, researchers will have to aggregate evidence from multiple perspectives to provide more solid evidence for the basic assumptions of DDM. The human decisionmaking process has not only behavioral outcomes but also its physiological basis, and different research instruments can provide different levels of evidence. Behavioral experiments can provide behavioral performance indicators to test different theoretical models, EEG can provide high temporal resolution to test the time course of decision-making mechanisms, and single-cell recordings of neurons can provide high spatial resolution while providing high temporal resolution to explore the origin of decision-making mechanisms. The use of multiple levels of evidence to test the same assumption can bring more convincing evidence from different perspectives, and these aggregated evidences provide strong support for the rationality of this assumption, and also provide a reference for testing other assumptions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Basic assumptions and performance of DDM</figDesc><table><row><cell>Cognitive</cell><cell>Underlying</cell><cell>Manifestations</cell><cell>Supporting evidence</cell><cell>Challenging</cell></row><row><cell>stage</cell><cell>hypothesis</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>evidence</cell></row><row><cell>Stimulus</cell><cell>Evidence</cell><cell>Different information</cell><cell>[29]</cell><cell>[30]</cell></row><row><cell>encoding</cell><cell>accumulation</cell><cell>can be transformed</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>is universal</cell><cell>into abstract</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>"evidence".</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Evidence</cell><cell>Only information</cell><cell>[29,31,32]</cell><cell>[21]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>accumulation</cell><cell>relevant to the</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>is selective</cell><cell>experimental task is</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>converted into</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>"evidence".</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Evidence</cell><cell>Evidence</cell><cell>Decision makers</cell><cell>[28,29,33,34,35]</cell><cell>[30]</cell></row><row><cell>accumulation</cell><cell>accumulation</cell><cell>accumulate evidence</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>is linear</cell><cell>at a fixed rate during</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>the decision-making</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>process.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Decision-</cell><cell>The amount of</cell><cell>[29,36,37,38,39]</cell><cell>[40,41,42]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>making</cell><cell>evidence needed to</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>criteria is</cell><cell>make a decision is</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>constant</cell><cell>constant throughout</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>the decision-making</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>process</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Response</cell><cell>Decision-</cell><cell>Only when a decision</cell><cell>[29]</cell><cell>[43,44,45,46,47]</cell></row><row><cell>execution</cell><cell>making is</cell><cell>is formed does the</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>independent</cell><cell>decision maker</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>of response</cell><cell>generate a movement</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>execution</cell><cell>response</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>In perceptual decision making, the information inputs come from different sensory modalities; in value-based decision making, the information inputs are the values of the options, which are encoded as evidence. A direct test of this assumption can be made by observing whether the process of evidence accumulation is similar under different decision-making tasks or under conditions of the same task but with different stimulus inputs.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL.</cell></row><row><cell>Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080</cell></row><row><cell>inputs about different options.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>dot motion task to test whether sensory signals in perceptual decision-making influence decisions in an integrated manner. They hypothesized that in perceptual decision making, sensory information is input via sequential sampling, but that there are three ways in which a decision maker may utilize this information: integrating and accumulating evidence (the integration hypothesis), detecting whether currently used evidence exceeds the decision criterion (the extremum detection hypothesis), or randomly selecting evidence (the snapshot hypothesis), where the integration hypothesis is precisely what is assumed by DDM. Under different experimental manipulations, the three ways of utilizing sensory information yield different results.Under different experimental manipulations, the three ways of utilizing sensory information yield This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL.Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 because noise is eliminated by averaging during integration, whereas the other modalities utilizing the evidence are unable to eliminate the effects of noise, and therefore are less accurate. When changing the response time window, the accuracy under the integration hypothesis will also increase if the width of the response time window is increased, because the integration hypothesis is more capable of eliminating the effect of noise through averaging, while the accuracy under the other hypotheses is not affected by the width of the response time window. The results of the experiment show that the evidence integration model fits most of the participants' behavioral data better, whereas the other model predictions differ from the participants' behavioral data. Thus, the experiment provides support for the assumption of evidence integration in DDM model.</figDesc><table /><note>different results. When varying the signal-to-noise ratio of the sensory input, there may not be much difference between the three hypothesis under high signal-to-noise condition, but under low signal-to- noise condition, the evidence accumulation under the integration hypothesis will perform the best Note:</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The decision-making process involves a number of brain regions, and in addition to the LIP brain region, which is responsible for the evidence accumulation, there exists the superior colliculus (SC) brain region, which specializes in the termination of decisions. Since both brain regions are responsible for functions related to decision This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL.Published Chinese article https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080 according to the third assumption of DDM, the decision variable accumulates evidence at a specific rate, and therefore the firing rate of the LIP brain region will ramp at a specific rate. Whereas the SC brain region is responsible for terminating decisions, the SC brain region will be less activated when the amount of evidence does not reach the decision threshold, but when the amount of evidence reaches a fixed threshold, the SC brain region will activate in order to control the LIP brain region to stop the evidence accumulation. The researchers conducted an experiment in which rats were trained to complete a random-dot motion task and activities of neurons were recorded in both the LIP brain region and the SC brain region. The results showed that firing rate of neurons in the LIP brain region ramped with stimulus presentation and peaked when the participants responded, whereas the SC brain</figDesc><table /><note>making, there is a certain similarity between the firing rate activity of neurons in the SC and LIP brain regions, with both firing rate starting to ramp at the onset of a stimulus and reaching a threshold at the time of the response. However, since the LIP brain region is responsible for evidence accumulation, Note:region exhibited a burst dynamic, in which firing rate in the SC brain region suddenly ramped to a peak just before a response occurs. In order to further test this deduction, the researchers decided to use drugs to inhibit the SC brain region. If the SC brain region does have the function of terminating decisions, then after the SC brain region is inhibited, the function that was originally responsible for</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision Making as a Window on Cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="791" to="806" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1360/TB-2023-1080</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Published Chinese article</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Behavioral Model of Rational Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Q J Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">99</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Prospect Theory: An Analysis of Decision Under Risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collicular involvement in a saccadic colour discrimination task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F P</forename><surname>Ottes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J A M</forename><surname>Van Gisbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Eggermont</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Exp Brain Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="465" to="478" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R D. Response</forename><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Times</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Games and Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R D</forename><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Raiffa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Teichmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Today</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision Making and Sequential Sampling from Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="927" to="939" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Diffusion Decision Model: Theory and Data for Two-Choice Decision Tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="873" to="922" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion Decision Model: Current Issues and History</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sequential Sampling Models in Cognitive Neuroscience: Advantages, Applications, and Extensions</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="666" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Category salience and racial bias in weapon identification: A diffusion modeling approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A R</forename><surname>Todd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lassetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Pers Soc Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="672" to="693" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Analyzing facial expression decision times: Reaction time distribution matters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tipples</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">2022</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rapid temporal accumulation in spider fear: Evidence from hierarchical drift diffusion modelling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tipples</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="742" to="751" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A diffusion model analysis of the effects of aging on letter discrimination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Thapar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A diffusion model analysis of the effects of aging on brightness discrimination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Thapar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Percept Psychophys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="523" to="535" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural Representation of Task Difficulty and Decision Making during Perceptual Categorization: A Timing Diagram</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Philiastides</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8965" to="8975" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of stimulus strength on the speed and accuracy of a perceptual decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A C</forename><surname>Huk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Vis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Attentional Drift-Diffusion Model Extends to Simple Purchasing Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of evidence accumulation during value-based decisions revealed via simultaneous EEG-fMRI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M A</forename><surname>Pisauro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fouragnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Retzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15808</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wise or mad crowds? The cognitive mechanisms underlying information cascades</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A N</forename><surname>Tump</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T J</forename><surname>Pleskac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R H J M</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2020</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">266</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social Sampling Explains Apparent Biases in Judgments of Social Environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Galesic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Olsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1515" to="1523" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biased sequential sampling underlies the effects of time pressure and delay in social decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3557</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational psychiatry as a bridge from neuroscience to clinical applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q J M</forename><surname>Huys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T V</forename><surname>Maia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="404" to="413" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evidence Accumulation Models: Current Limitations and Future Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1360/TB-2023-1080</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Published Chinese article</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Directions. Quant Method Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2020</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bridging Neural and Computational Viewpoints on Perceptual Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>O'connell R G</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wong-Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="838" to="852" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Addressing the theory crisis in psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychon Bull Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1596" to="1618" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response of Neurons in the Lateral Intraparietal Area during a Combined Visual Discrimination Reaction Time Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J D</forename><surname>Roitman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9475" to="9489" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A supramodal accumulation-to-bound signal that determines perceptual decisions in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P M</forename><surname>O'connell R G, Dockree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1729" to="1735" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Common neural choice signals emerge artifactually amidst multiple distinct value signals. bioRxiv</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Frömer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M R</forename><surname>Nassar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B V</forename><surname>Ehinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Target Selection Signals Influence Perceptual Decisions by Modulating the Onset and Rate of Evidence Accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G M</forename><surname>Loughnane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D P</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M A</forename><surname>Bellgrove</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="496" to="502" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual fixations and the computation and comparison of value in simple choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1298" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Differentiating between integration and nonintegration strategies in perceptual decision making. eLife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G M</forename><surname>Stine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zylberberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ditterich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">55365</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linear Integration of Sensory Evidence over Space and Time Underlies Face Categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Okazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Sha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7876" to="7893" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human Scalp Potentials Reflect a Mixture of Decision-Related Signals during Perceptual Choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M G</forename><surname>Philiastides</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H R</forename><surname>Heekeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sajda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16877" to="16889" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting the Evidence for Collapsing Boundaries and Urgency Signals in Perceptual Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2476" to="2484" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential sampling models with variable boundaries and non-normal noise: A comparison of six models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lerche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Mertens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychon Bull Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="832" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A neural mechanism for terminating decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G M</forename><surname>Stine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E M</forename><surname>Trautmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jeurissen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">0896627323004002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Salience to Saccades: Multiple-Alternative Gated Stochastic Accumulator Model of Visual Search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B A</forename><surname>Purcell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J D</forename><surname>Schall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G D</forename><surname>Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3433" to="3446" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-making with multiple alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A K</forename><surname>Churchland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="693" to="702" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions are expedited through multiple neural adjustments spanning the sensorimotor hierarchy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N A</forename><surname>Steinemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>'connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R G</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3627</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neurocomputational mechanisms of prior-informed perceptual decision-making in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S P</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E A</forename><surname>Corbett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Hum Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2021</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="481" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Influence of Behavioral Context on the Representation of a Perceptual Decision in Developing Oculomotor Commands</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="632" to="651" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representation of a perceptual decision in developing oculomotor commands</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">404</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6776</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="390" to="394" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Separating response-execution bias from decision bias: Arguments for an additional parameter in Ratcliff&apos;s diffusion model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Klauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br J Math Stat Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="539" to="555" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1360/TB-2023-1080</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Published Chinese article</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response biases in simple decision making: Faster decision making, faster response execution, or both?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J J</forename><surname>Starns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychon Bull Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1535" to="1541" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Decisive Role of Non-Decision Time for Interpreting the Parameters of Decision Making Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Weindel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Burle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<publisher>PsyArXiv</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Good Me Bad Me: Prioritization of the Good-Self During Perceptual Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C-P</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C N</forename><surname>Macrae</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Collabra Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2020</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The role of premature evidence accumulation in making difficult perceptual decisions under temporal uncertainty. eLife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C A</forename><surname>Devine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gaffney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G M</forename><surname>Loughnane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">48526</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internal and External Influences on the Rate of Sensory Evidence Accumulation in the Human Brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S P</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19434" to="19441" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visuospatial Asymmetries Arise from Differences in the Onset Time of Perceptual Evidence Accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D P</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G M</forename><surname>Loughnane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S P</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3378" to="3385" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Behavioural and neural signatures of perceptual decision-making are modulated by pupil-linked arousal. eLife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Van Kempen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G M</forename><surname>Loughnane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D P</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">42541</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The interplay between multisensory integration and perceptual decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M R</forename><surname>Mercier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cappe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">222</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">116970</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Behavioral and neural measures of confidence using a novel auditory pitch identification task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Samaha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<publisher>PsyArXiv</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Filling the gaps: Cognitive control as a critical lens for understanding mechanisms of value-based decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Frömer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurosci Biobehav Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">104483</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaze bias differences capture individual choice behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A W</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Molter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Hum Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="635" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Uncovering the computational mechanisms underlying many-alternative choice. eLife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A W</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Molter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">57012</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The art of the deal: Deciphering the endowment effect from traders&apos; eyes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2023</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2115</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model-based approach to disentangling facilitation and interference effects in conflict tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Servant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2022</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1183" to="1209" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal Integration of Olfactory Perceptual Evidence in Human Orbitofrontal Cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N E</forename><surname>Bowman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K P</forename><surname>Kording</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gottfried</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="916" to="927" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamics and Computation of Continuous Attractors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hamaguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Amari</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="994" to="1025" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The time course of perceptual choice: The leaky, competing accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="550" to="592" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The simplest complete model of choice response time: Linear ballistic accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cogn Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatic Discovery of Cognitive Strategies with Tiny Recurrent Neural Networks. bioRxiv</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ji-An</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M K</forename><surname>Benna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mattar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">RTNet: A neural network that exhibits the signatures of human perceptual decision making. bioRxiv</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rafiei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rahnev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">DDDM: a Brain-Inspired Framework for Robust Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Strategically managing learning during perceptual decision Note: This article is a translation of the original Chinese text, generated by DeepL</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Masí S</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J Y</forename><surname>Rhee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1360/TB-2023-1080</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1360/TB-2023-1080" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Published Chinese article</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence accumulation modelling in the wild: understanding safety-critical decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R J</forename><surname>Boag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Strickland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends Cogn Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2022</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1364661322002947</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
