<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">ADOLESCENCE AGE GROUP</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2024-11-10">November 10, 2024</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nada</forename><surname>Mansour</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Clinical Mental Health</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Houston Clear Lake</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dana</forename><surname>Al Sagheer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Clinical Mental Health</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Houston Clear Lake</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">ADOLESCENCE AGE GROUP</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2024-11-10">November 10, 2024</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:44+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Adolescence is a transformative stage of development marked by significant changes across physical, cognitive, and emotional domains. This period involves rapid brain growth, which enhances reasoning, decision-making, and emotional regulation. Simultaneously, physical maturation brings notable changes, including increased strength, organ development, and the onset of sexual maturity. However, these transformations often lead to challenges in navigating relationships and conflicts with authority figures as adolescents strive for independence and identity formation. Psychological and social factors, such as peer influences, family dynamics, and societal pressures, are critical in shaping their experiences and can exacerbate stress and communication difficulties. Supporting adolescents effectively requires open and empathetic communication, clear boundaries, and encouragement of autonomy within a secure framework. Drawing from key developmental theories, including those addressing cultural identity, this stage emphasizes the importance of fostering resilience through social-emotional learning, proactively addressing mental health needs, and promoting meaningful engagement. Role models who exemplify empathy and integrity further enrich this developmental process. Recognizing the complex interplay of biological, social, and cultural factors is essential for crafting strategies that balance guidance with respect for adolescents&apos; emerging autonomy, enabling their growth into confident and capable individuals. Adolescence is a pivotal phase of human development characterized by significant physical, emotional, cognitive, and social transformations. This stage is crucial in shaping an individual&apos;s identity and laying the foundation for future well-being, social engagement, and overall success. Research underscores the multifaceted nature of adolescent development, highlighting the dynamic interplay between individual traits, social environments, and cultural contexts [1, 2]. Various theoretical perspectives, such as ecological systems theory and self-determination theory, provide valuable insights into adolescents&apos; processes as they tackle identity formation, moral reasoning, motivation, and risk-taking behaviors [3, 4]. Key influences on adolescent growth include family dynamics, peer interactions, and socioeconomic factors, all of which profoundly shape developmental trajectories [5, 6]. By exploring these factors, the literature paints a detailed picture of adolescence as a time filled with opportunities for growth and vulnerabilities to challenges. This comprehensive</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>understanding emphasizes the diverse elements that contribute to the development of young individuals and their journey toward adulthood <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref>.</p><p>It was 2003, my first year as a teacher. I started working at a girls' middle school. I introduced myself to the 6th graders. I was young, nervous, and excited. I was in my twenties. They started commenting on my clothes, how I talked to them, and the accessories I wore. We started to build up a good relationship. There was trust and transparency, and I was a very active listener. They enjoyed sharing so many things with me. These kids were very energetic, active, happy, and moody. Those kids were brilliant. For me, they were easy to motivate, while for other teachers, they were not. That was my turning point to learn more about adolescents, their interests, way of thinking, social skills, feelings, and emotions. So I started to teach myself more about adolescence.</p><p>We will highlight adolescents from different aspects through the key developmental theories, cultural identity development, resilience, and critical psychological and social factors. The conclusion will be through the counselor's influence and approach. Before all of that, we know that there are multiple biological changes that lead to all that change.</p><p>Let us check what impacts adolescents' bodies and hormones, and how puberty takes action in girls and boys.</p><p>2 Adolescence Development</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Unseen Development</head><p>Adolescence typically begins during late childhood and involves profound changes across various domains of development, starting with unseen shifts within the body. Hormonal changes are central to this process, as hormones regulate vital functions such as hunger, sleep, mood, stress responses, sexual development, and reproduction. The onset of puberty is triggered by the activation of multiple glands, including the adrenal glands, sex glands, and gonads. In females, estrogen is the primary sex hormone, while in males, testosterone plays the key role. These hormones contribute to physiological transformations, emotional changes, and cognitive restructuring. For girls, the first signs of puberty include nipple growth, the appearance of pubic hair, and the onset of menstruation. Boys typically experience the growth of testes, pubic hair, penile development, initial ejaculation, the appearance of facial hair, and a deeper voice. Generally, puberty begins between ages 8 and 14, with visible changes becoming apparent between ages 9 and 14.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Brain Development</head><p>During adolescence, pubertal hormones significantly influence brain development, particularly targeting the amygdala, a key part of the limbic system. This results in heightened emotional and instinctual responses. These changes often precede the maturation of the brain's reflective and analytical regions. Teenagers also experience notable changes in sleep and appetite patterns, often feeling energized late at night but struggling with energy and appetite in the mornings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Physical Growth</head><p>The body undergoes rapid growth during adolescence, with changes often beginning at the extremities before progressing to the core. For example, fingers and toes grow before hands, arms, feet, and legs. Adolescents may notice frequent changes in shoe sizes as their feet grow rapidly. Weight gain, increased muscle mass, and height changes are also common during this period.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Organ Development</head><p>Internally, significant growth and development occur in vital organs. The lungs triple in weight, allowing for deeper and slower breathing. The heart, being a muscle, doubles in size, improving circulatory efficiency. Red blood cell production increases to support enhanced oxygen transport during physical activity. Boys also experience deepened voices as the larynx grows. Conversely, the lymphoid system, including tonsils and adenoids, shrinks in size, enhancing immune efficiency. Adolescents also often deal with oilier skin, increased sweating, and acne due to hormonal shifts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Body Image</head><p>Adolescents frequently struggle with body image issues, influenced by societal standards, media portrayals, and peer comparisons. Challenges such as body shaming, poor dietary habits, and unrealistic ideals further exacerbate these struggles.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">Sexual Maturation</head><p>The physical maturation of primary sex characteristics, such as the ovaries in females and the testes and penis in males, prepares adolescents for reproduction. These developments also contribute to the ongoing cognitive and emotional growth seen during this stage. As the brain grew up physically that would develop the adolescents' cognition. Accordingly. This great storm is going all over the adolescent body, brain, body image, emotions, and many more developments. Their ways of cognition will be different sometimes will be intelligence, egocentrism, rumination, or fables. Let us have a quick look at each one of them: Adolescent Egocentrism when adolescence focuses on themselves and what others think of them. They start to analyze and judge people's behavior because their emotions are not grounded in reality. Since egocentrism is focusing a lot on themselves, the result should lead to Rumination where they are questioning themselves by assuming questions like what they said, and why they do that. Excessive rumination could lead to depression. Adolescents have very impulsive actions. They have a high rate of suicide. Adolescents believe that they are on the spot where others are watching them and all eyes are following them. They imagine that people are watching them. Their imaginary audience is another teen, not a parent or a teacher. In personal fables, where they come up with egocentrism, they believe that they might become rich or become movie stars, or maybe they will die soon or so. Now, it is time to discuss the impact of these changes on mental health and behaviors. Several key developmental theories discuss adolescents' thoughts. We would like to stop at each one to discuss how adolescents' cognition and identity improve. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">James Marcia's Identity Development Theory</head><p>James Marcia expanded upon Erikson's psychosocial framework, focusing on how adolescents address identity formation. Adolescents face significant stress as they make important personal and social decisions during a time when their sense of self is still forming. They must not only answer the question, "Who am I?" but also determine "What do I want to become?" Marcia (1966) introduced four identity statuses to describe how adolescents manage this process:</p><p>• Identity Diffusion: A lack of exploration or commitment, often leading to uncertainty.</p><p>• Identity Foreclosure: Commitment made without exploration, typically influenced by external pressures.</p><p>• Identity Moratorium: Active exploration without commitment, representing a transitional phase.</p><p>• Identity Achievement: A stable sense of self, achieved through both exploration and commitment.</p><p>These statuses reflect the diverse paths adolescents take in navigating their identity development. An insightful diagram by Sarah Blackford, featured on her bioscience career blog in the article "I'm a Scientist! [Don't] Get Me Out of Here!", vividly illustrates the exploration crisis central to Marcia's theory. This crisis underscores the active period of self-discovery that defines adolescent identity formation. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> illustrates the relationship between commitment and crisis in this developmental process. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Cultural Identity Development</head><p>Cultural influences play a vital role in shaping adolescents' identities, both through internal processes like personal exploration and external influences such as family and peer dynamics (Phinney, 1990). My personal experience with my children highlights how cultural shifts can impact identity development. When our family relocated to the United States, my children faced the challenge of balancing our cultural traditions with American norms. For example, in our culture, familism emphasizes respect for family authority and adherence to rules, such as parents inquiring about their children's plans-where they are going, who they are with, and how long they will be out. My son, however, expressed frustration, noting that many American parents appeared more relaxed in their approach. Another cultural difference arose in school lunchtime practices. In our culture, lunch is typically a family-centered meal, whereas in American schools, students often bring hearty lunches like chicken or fish, which initially surprised my children. Additionally, our cultural norms dictate that children usually live with their parents until marriage, contrasting sharply with American customs that encourage young adults to move out at 18. Although these differences initially created confusion, they ultimately provided my teenagers with opportunities to adapt, reflect, and grow while staying connected to their cultural roots.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">The Power of Peers</head><p>Adolescence is a time when young people begin to expand their social networks beyond their family. This period of self-discovery often leads to the formation of new friendships, which play a crucial role in development. Adolescents start to explore what it means to have meaningful relationships, discerning between positive and negative influences. However, navigating these social dynamics can be challenging due to the powerful influence of peer pressure, which can significantly shape their behaviors and choices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6">Resilience in Adolescence</head><p>Resilience refers to the capacity to cope with challenges and positively recover from setbacks. It allows adolescents to navigate life's ups and downs with strength and adaptability. Building resilience requires support from family, friends, teachers, and mentors, as well as a healthy lifestyle. Regular physical activity, nutritious meals, adequate sleep, and constructive stress-management strategies all contribute to fostering resilience in teenagers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.7">Critical Psychological and Social Factors</head><p>Psychological and social factors are crucial in determining how adolescents respond to stress and engage in relationships. Key psychological components include self-esteem and emotional regulation-the ability to identify, manage, and express emotions appropriately. These skills help adolescents face challenges, maintain healthy relationships, and build a foundation for mental well-being.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.8">Behavioral Types in Adolescence</head><p>Adolescents exhibit a variety of behavioral patterns influenced by their personality, environment, and stage of development. Understanding these behaviors can guide caregivers and educators in providing effective support.</p><p>• Acceptant Adolescents: These individuals are generally well-adjusted, cooperative, and thrive in structured environments. They are open to guidance and maintain positive relationships with peers and authority figures, which supports their emotional and social growth.</p><p>• Aggressive Adolescents: Aggression in this group often manifests as hostility or confrontational behavior, potentially stemming from trauma or difficulty regulating emotions. Interventions like counseling and conflict resolution training can help channel their energy into constructive outlets.</p><p>• Withdrawn Adolescents These individuals may struggle with social interaction and self-expression due to factors such as anxiety, bullying, or other mental health challenges. Gradual social engagement, a supportive environment, and efforts to boost self-esteem can help them build confidence and integrate better into their social networks.</p><p>By understanding these behavioral tendencies and the factors influencing them, caregivers and educators can create tailored approaches that support adolescents during this pivotal developmental stage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Parenting Challenges and Mistakes</head><p>Parenting teenagers comes with unique challenges, and certain common mistakes can strain the parent-child relationship. Overly controlling or micromanaging a teen's life may cause them to feel suffocated and push back against authority. On the other hand, dismissing their emotions with phrases like "You're overreacting" can make them feel invalidated and reluctant to open up. Criticism and comparisons to others can erode a teen's self-confidence, while inconsistent rules or poor role modeling may create confusion and instability. Overprotective behaviors, while well-intentioned, can hinder teens' ability to learn independence and resilience. Ignoring signs of mental health struggles or failing to dedicate quality time sends a message that their well-being isn't a priority. Instead, parents can strengthen relationships by showing empathy, listening without judgment, and respecting their independence. Creating a balance between providing guidance and allowing autonomy can help teenagers grow into confident and capable adults.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Islamic Perspectives on Character Development</head><p>In Islam, character education is central to personal development. It emphasizes aligning actions with knowledge, balancing spiritual and worldly pursuits, and fostering emotional, spiritual, and moral growth. Adolescents who lack strong character are seen as lacking dignity and self-worth. While some believe character traits are innate, Islamic teachings stress that character can be cultivated through proper education and upbringing. The role of parents is particularly significant in shaping a child's character. The Prophet Muhammad (peace and blessings be upon him) said: "Every child is born upon the natural disposition, but it is the parents who make them Jewish, Christian, or Magian" (Sahih Bukhari). This highlights the profound influence of family in shaping moral and ethical development.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Motivating Adolescents</head><p>Motivating teenagers begins with focusing on their efforts rather than outcomes. Recognize and celebrate their hard work, even if their results aren't perfect, and reassure them that they are valued for who they are, not just for their achievements. Giving teens the freedom to make mistakes allows them to learn and grow. Respecting their opinions and listening without judgment fosters a sense of validation and trust. Avoid comparisons, as every adolescent is unique. Highlighting their strengths can help them feel confident and motivated to continue growing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Counseling Considerations for Adolescents</head><p>Counselors working with adolescents must understand their developmental and environmental contexts. Adolescents are at a critical phase of identity exploration, and counselors can play a significant role by providing a safe, nonjudgmental space where teens feel heard and respected. Counselors should address safety concerns and be vigilant for signs of self-harm or other mental health challenges. Encouraging adolescents to explore their interests and align them with potential future paths can help build a sense of purpose. These considerations are vital in creating strategies that support adolescents during this transformative period.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>Adolescence is a unique and dynamic stage of life marked by significant physical, emotional, and social changes. While these challenges can be overwhelming when viewed individually, they are part of a broader process of growth and development. Adolescents are like young trees-nurtured carefully during their early years but requiring pruning and guidance during their teenage years to grow stronger and more specialized. This stage involves refining their abilities and focusing their development. Reflecting on my own experience as a teenager, I recall struggling with self-doubt and complex emotions. I often felt lost and overwhelmed. These memories drive my passion for helping adolescents navigate this challenging time. By explaining the changes they are experiencing, I hope to ease their stress and help them better understand themselves.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Crisis and Exploration Matrix: The relationship between Commitment and Crisis.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>3</head><label></label><figDesc>Key Developmental theories 3.1 Piaget's Stage Number (4): Theory of Formal Operational Thought This developmental stage begins around age 12 and continues into adulthood. According to Piaget (1972), adolescents acquire abstract and deductive reasoning capacities. Abstract thinking lets them grasp complex ideas, including love, hate, success, failure, and freedom. Deductive reasoning, on the other hand, enables them to apply general principles to specific situations to conclude. Adolescents in this stage demonstrate enhanced logical thinking, the ability to anticipate outcomes, and strong problem-solving skills.3.2 Erikson's Theory of Identity vs. Role ConfusionErikson's psychosocial development theory emphasizes the critical role of social relationships in fostering personal growth. He suggested that individuals progress through a series of stages, each marked by a unique conflict that must be resolved to develop a core</figDesc><table /><note>virtue (Erikson, 1968). During the fifth stage, Identity vs. Role Confusion, adolescents between the ages of 12 and 18 focus on gaining a deeper understanding of themselves and their independence. Successfully resolving this stage results in a well-defined sense of identity.</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Social Factors and Adolescent DevelopmentSocial factors play a crucial role in shaping adolescent development, often relying on the support systems provided by family, friends, and the community. These support networks offer emotional and practical help during challenging times. Socioeconomic status, for example, influences access to critical resources such as education, healthcare, and safe housing, all of which directly impact psychological well-being. Cultural identity also plays a significant role, as adolescents often take pride in aspects of their culture that they can share with their peers. This sense of pride can boost self-esteem and provide a sense of belonging. Adolescents' behaviors and traits are shaped by their environments, personalities, and life experiences, which can either promote positive growth or lead to challenges that conflict with societal and moral norms.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An interactionist perspective on the socioeconomic context of human development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Conger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Donnellan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="199" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The cultural nature of human development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rogoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adolescent development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Steinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-determination theory and the facilitation of intrinsic motivation, social development, and well-being</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Deci</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stage-environment fit during adolescence: Trajectories of family relations and adolescent outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gutman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Eccles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="522" to="537" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adolescents&apos; preparation for the future</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mortimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="209" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The path to purpose: How young people find their calling in life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Damon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Free Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk behavior in adolescence: A psychosocial framework for understanding and action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jessor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="374" to="390" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Identity: Youth and crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Erikson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
			<pubPlace>Norton</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
