<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Effects of personal force and physical contact on moral decision-making: A replication</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trent</forename><surname>Lynds</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mackinnon</surname></persName>
							<email>mackinnon.sean@dal.ca</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology and Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalhousie University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology and Neuroscience Dalhousie University</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">EMAIL</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1355 Oxford Street</addrLine>
									<postBox>PO BOX 15000</postBox>
									<postCode>B3H 4R2</postCode>
									<settlement>Halifax</settlement>
									<region>NS</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Dalhousie University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Effects of personal force and physical contact on moral decision-making: A replication</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-022-01319)</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:51+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>moral dilemmas</term>
					<term>moral acceptability</term>
					<term>personal force</term>
					<term>physical contact</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>on which both Sean and Trent are co-authors. We did this so Trent could have original data to analyze for his honours thesis timeline. Given that the Psychological Accelerator project tests the same hypothesis more rigorously, we decided to abandon formal publication through the peer review process because the study lacks novelty. Nonetheless, since it is a competent preregistered replication study with open data, it is worth archiving for posterity; hence, this paper has been archived online, but has not been peer reviewed nor has it been published in an academic journal.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Moral dilemmas portray moral principles: consequential (utilitarian) and deontological reasoning. Consequentialists believe actions by moral decision makers should result in the best consequences for the greatest number of individuals <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Greene, 2008)</ref>. Deontological reasoning revolves around moral rules such as rights and duties <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Greene, 2008)</ref>. That is, performing an action may be wrong, even if the decision yields the greatest consequences <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Manfrinati et al, 2013)</ref>. We replicate findings of experiments 1a and 1b of <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al (2009)</ref>, to verify prior research on consequential vs. deontological responses to hypothetical moral dilemmas. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">experiments 1a and 1b)</ref> investigated the influence of physical contact, personal force, and spatial proximity on moral acceptability ratings for hypothetical moral dilemmas. Personal force is the use of one's own muscles to impact the victim, such as pushing the victim with their hands or an object. Physical contact is when the agent makes physical contact with the victim, such as pushing the victim with their hands (physical contact entails personal force). Lastly, spatial proximity is when the agent is close to the victim. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref> compared moral acceptability ratings in response to three versions of the footbridge dilemma: standard footbridge, footbridge pole, and footbridge switch. In Standard footbridge a trolley is set to collide with five workmen, resulting in their deaths. Joe is standing next to a workman on a footbridge that stands over the trolley tracks. Joe can avoid the deaths by pushing the workman off the footbridge; the workman would die but he would be heavy enough to stop the trolley. The footbridge pole dilemma is like standard footbridge, except the agent uses a sixfoot pole to push the workman, thus eliminating physical contact. Footbridge switch eliminates physical contact and personal force because Joe hits a switch causing the workman to fall through a trap door. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref> found the test comparing standard footbridge vs. footbridge pole was nonsignificant. However, there was a significant effect of personal force when comparing footbridge switch vs footbridge pole (d = .40). These findings highlight the importance of personal force in moral decision-making. <ref type="bibr">Greene and colleagues (2009)</ref> also examined speedboat dilemmas to test generalizability to different contexts. In standard speedboat John is driving a speedboat when he spots five drowning swimmers. To save them in time, John must lighten the load of the speedboat. John must decide whether to push a passenger off his boat with his hands, resulting in the passenger's death, to make it to the five drowning swimmers in time. Speedboat oar is like standard speedboat, except John uses an oar to push the passenger. In speedboat accelerate John accelerates the boat quickly, causing the passenger to fall off the boat. Much like the footbridge dilemmas, the test comparing moral acceptability ratings of standard speedboat vs. speedboat oar was nonsignificant. There was a significant effect of personal force when comparing speedboat oar vs speedboat accelerate (d = 0.69). Awad and colleagues (2020) found similar results comparing responses to footbridge vs. switch dilemmas in their large crosscultural study. The 70,000 participants were more likely to sacrifice an individual in the switch scenario (mean country-level average: 81%) compared to the footbridge scenario (mean countrylevel average: 51%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Replication Target</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rationale</head><p>Although the generalizability of moral dilemmas to real-life phenomena, such as selfdriving cars <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cunneen et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Himmelreich, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Keeling, 2020)</ref> has been debated, it remains a simple and ethical way to determine when one would elicit a consequentialist or deontological response. The present study is a direct replication of experiments 1a and 1b of <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref> in a Canadian sample of undergraduates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hypotheses</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H1:</head><p>The mean moral acceptability ratings will be higher in the footbridge switch condition when compared to the footbridge pole condition.</p><p>H2: The mean moral acceptability ratings will be higher in the speedboat accelerate condition when compared to the speedboat oar condition.</p><p>Greene and colleagues found nonsignificant effects of physical contact (standard footbridge vs. footbridge pole; standard speedboat vs. speedboat oar). Since we predict these findings as well, but it is not possible to endorse the null hypothesis in a traditional null hypothesis test, we predict that these tests assessing physical contact will not be statistically significant (i.e., inconclusive).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Power Analysis</head><p>We required a minimum of 64 participants per condition (192 participants total) to detect an effect size of d = .50, assuming a two-tailed alpha of .05 and 80% power. The effect size averages the effect of personal force from study 1a (d = .40) and study 1b (d = 0.69) in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref>. Data were collected as part of an honors thesis, with a short window for data collection (Sept 2019 -Feb 2020). Our stopping rule required a minimum of 192 participants but allowed for as many participants as could be collected prior to February 23, 2020.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Participants (N = 268) were required to be undergraduate students at Dalhousie University. Participants were recruited via the online psychology participant pool and posters displayed around campus. After exclusions (see analysis plan), most (27%) had an annual income between $5001 and $10000, $10001 and $15000 (23%), and $15001 and $25000 (16%).</p><p>Most lived in urban areas (78%). Lastly, most participants reported as having no religious background (21%), being agnostic (17%), atheist (15%), Christian (14%), or Catholic specific Christian (14%). This study was reviewed by the Social Sciences and Humanities Research Ethics Board at Dalhousie university (#2019-4940).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>Moral dilemmas. Participants were randomized to one of three footbridge dilemmas (standard footbridge, footbridge pole, and footbridge switch) and the corresponding one of three speedboat dilemmas (standard speedboat, speedboat oar, and speedboat accelerate). The wording of the footbridge and speedboat dilemmas was identical to Greene and colleagues' (2009) study. Full materials (including participant instructions) can be accessed at https://osf.io/47msh/.</p><p>Moral acceptability ratings. To determine the extent to which the action by the agent is morally acceptable, participants provided moral acceptability ratings between 1 (completely unacceptable) and 9 (completely acceptable).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Confusion.</head><p>To assess for confusion, participants indicated whether they were: not confused, confused at first but understood the material enough by the end, or confused enough to believe their answers to the questions were not reasonable.</p><p>Realism. To assess whether participants believed the dilemmas were realistic, participants indicated whether they found the dilemmas: to be realistic, did not find it realistic but responded under the assumption that it was accurate, or did not find it realistic which resulted in inability to take the description seriously.</p><p>Additional questions. Additional questionnaires were administered, but these questions had no pre-registered hypotheses and are not analyzed in this report. All measures are presented here: https://osf.io/47msh/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>The study's survey was provided to participants through the online survey tool Opinio (Object Planet; Version 7.8). Participants were first provided the consent form and instructions.</p><p>Participants were then randomized to one of the three conditions and a counterbalanced order (i.e., footbridge first vs. speedboat first). The study design is outlined in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. Sample sizes are unequal due to limitations of the randomization feature in Opinio. After reading each dilemma, participants supplied moral acceptability ratings, answered follow-up questions, and completed the additional questionnaires, in that order. After study completion, researchers awarded 0.5 bonus credits to eligible students, and entered participants into a $50 gift card raffle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis Plan</head><p>We conducted four Welch independent t-tests; two to test the effect of personal force (footbridge switch vs. footbridge pole, speedboat accelerate vs. speedboat oar) and two to test the effect of physical contact (footbridge pole vs. standard footbridge, speedboat oar vs. standard speedboat). Mean differences and 95% confidence intervals, and cohen's d were reported. Consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref>, we excluded those who were confused (N = 7) or lacked realism (N = 11) from analyses. All statistical analyses were conducted using R and jamovi software (Version 1.2), with syntax uploaded to our OSF page: https://osf.io/47msh/. Preregistration of confirmatory tests is located here https://osf.io/uxe4h.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methodological Differences Between the Current Replication and the Replication Target</head><p>There are differences between this study and <ref type="bibr">Greene and colleagues' (2009)</ref>. Firstly, Greene and colleagues conducted their study via pen and paper, whereas we used an online survey program completed at home.</p><p>One notable difference between this study and Greene et al. is that each participant in our study responded to one footbridge dilemma and one speedboat dilemma with counterbalancing, creating a within-subject component. In Greene and colleagues' study, Experiment 1a (footbridge) and Experiment 1b (speedboat) were conducted with separate participants. Our within-subjects approach to conducting Experiment 1a and 1b simultaneously maximized the data collected in a shorter timeframe. We also omitted the remote footbridge dilemma. The remote footbridge dilemma is similar to footbridge switch, except the agent is at a distance from the workman, eliminating spatial proximity. The planned contrast in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref> that involved the remote footbridge dilemma (i.e., remote footbridge vs. footbridge switch to test the effect of physical proximity) was non-significant in the original study. Given the tight timeframe of data collection, we chose to omit this condition in this replication to maximize data collected for other conditions. Lastly, both studies screened for 'suspended belief' or 'unconscious realism' (when participants unconsciously replace unrealistic assumptions, portrayed by a moral dilemma, with more realistic ones). Both studies did this by asking participants whether they thought the action by the agent would result in the desired outcome. Participants provided an estimate (0-100%) as to whether the outcome would turn out as planned, turn out as worse, and turn out as better. Greene and colleagues used these estimates as covariates, while this study did not. Again, these covariates were all reported as nonsignificant in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref>, suggesting that they were unnecessary to add in the model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Disclosure Statement</head><p>Above, we report how we determined our sample size, data exclusions, all manipulations, and link to all measures in the study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Results are depicted in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> &amp; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures 1 &amp; 2</ref>. T-tests revealed an effect of personal force for the footbridge dilemmas (footbridge switch vs. footbridge pole; p = .02, d = -.37).</p><p>Results were similar for the speedboat dilemmas (speedboat accelerate vs. speedboat oar; p &lt; .001, d = -.54). T-tests examining physical contact were inconclusive, for both the footbridge dilemmas (footbridge pole vs. standard footbridge; p = .88, d = .02) and speedboat dilemmas (speedboat oar vs. standard speedboat; p = .69, d = -.06).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Participants were randomized to one of three conditions: physical contact and personal force, personal force only, and no physical contact or personal force. We found that personal force influences a person's decision in footbridge and speedboat dilemmas, such that a person is more likely to present a deontological response if the action entails personal force, supporting H1 and H2. These results partially replicate <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implications</head><p>To our knowledge, this is one of only a handful of studies to investigate moral reasoning in Canadians (c.f., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Cushman et al., 2006)</ref>. Thus, this study provides insight on the prevalence of deontological and consequential reasoning in Canadian students, at least in response to these moral dilemmas. Results may be useful in the implementation of moral decision-making in technology such as autonomous vehicles (AVs) in Canada. Using human responses to train AVs may be the only ethical way to determine how AVs should make moral decisions. However, footbridge and speedboat dilemmas differ from dilemmas that AVs would face. Therefore, future research might implement AV dilemmas, to more closely depict the real-world situations AVs would face.</p><p>There are parallels between this study <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">and Milgram's (1963)</ref> obedience to authority studies. Milgram tested if 'psychological' proximity or 'immediacy' with a victim influences the likelihood of a subject obeying the experimenter <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Milgram, 1965)</ref>. Milgram tested this theory via four conditions and found that participants were less and less likely to shock the victim as physical proximity to the victim increased. The more 'removed' (i.e., lack of personal force) someone feels from the situation, the more likely they will harm someone for the 'greater good'.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations</head><p>We did not fully replicate all 4 studies in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref>, so the reproducibility of all their findings is unknown. Due to time pressures inherent in honors thesis research (and the sudden impact of COVID-19 on university operations; our data collection ceased February 23, 2020, mere weeks before our institution locked down), the final sample size is unable to detect small effect sizes, though we reached our minimum pre-registered requirements. Participants were provided with equivalent footbridge and speedboat dilemmas using a within-subjects component. If participants realized that their second dilemma entailed the same factors (e.g., physical contact and/or personal force) as the first dilemma, this may have primed their responses to the second dilemma; nonetheless, counterbalancing should distribute this error equally between conditions. Results from this study may be somewhat unrealistic, thus lacking ecological validity. Reaction time and various social or psychological factors may influence their decisions in a real-world setting. Lastly, the sample consists entirely of psychology undergraduates, limiting generalizability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>The moral dilemmas tested involve rating the moral acceptability of sacrificing one person to save five. Consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Greene et al. (2009)</ref>, we found that people rate this sacrifice as less morally acceptable when personal force is applied (i.e., a deontological response). We failed to find an effect of physical contactif physical contact influences moral acceptability, the effect size is likely small. Future research should investigate the cross-cultural applicability of these findings. The Psychological Accelerator is currently collecting data with over 150 laboratories across the world to further replicate an extend this effect. 1 It is hoped that this collaborative effort will confirm the results of this replication, and that it will provide insights into the magnitude of the effect and its generalizability across cultures.</p><p>1 The Psychological Accelerator study <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bago et al., 2022)</ref> has since been published, and found similar results to what was in the present paper. The paper you are reading was written before the <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bago et al. (2022)</ref> paper was completed (excepting, of course this footnote that was added in 2024 when we decided to archive the paper). Note. Pc and Pf are abbreviations of physical contact and personal force, respectively. Conditions 1-3 are between-subjects manipulations. Each participant was presented with both the footbridge and speedboat variation of that condition in a counterbalanced order.   </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A stacked dot plot, means, and 95% CIs comparing moral acceptability responses in the footbridge dilemmas.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>A stacked dot plot, means, and 95% CIs comparing moral acceptability responses in the speedboat dilemmas.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Study Design.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>N</cell><cell>Measure 1</cell><cell>Measure 2</cell></row><row><cell>Condition 1</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>Standard Footbridge</cell><cell>Standard Speedboat</cell></row><row><cell>Pc + Pf (N = 90)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>45</cell><cell>Standard Speedboat</cell><cell>Standard Footbridge</cell></row><row><cell>Condition 2</cell><cell>39</cell><cell>Footbridge Pole</cell><cell>Speedboat Oar</cell></row><row><cell>Pf only (N = 74)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>35</cell><cell>Speedboat Oar</cell><cell>Footbridge Pole</cell></row><row><cell>Condition 3</cell><cell>41</cell><cell>Footbridge Switch</cell><cell>Speedboat Accelerate</cell></row><row><cell>No Pc nor Pf (N = 86)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>45</cell><cell cols="2">Speedboat Accelerate Footbridge Switch</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Welch Independent T-tests Comparing Mean Moral Acceptability Ratings.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Dilemma</cell><cell>n</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>df</cell><cell>p</cell><cell>Lower</cell><cell>Upper</cell><cell>d</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(SD)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>95% CI</cell><cell>95% CI</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Footbridge Pole</cell><cell>74</cell><cell cols="3">3.80 (1.78) 0.15 154</cell><cell>.88</cell><cell>-0.50</cell><cell>0.59</cell><cell>0.02</cell></row><row><cell>Standard Footbridge</cell><cell>90</cell><cell>3.76 (1.73)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Footbridge Pole</cell><cell>74</cell><cell cols="3">3.80 (1.78) -2.34 158</cell><cell>.02</cell><cell>-1.34</cell><cell>-0.11</cell><cell>-0.37</cell></row><row><cell>Footbridge Switch</cell><cell>86</cell><cell>4.52 (2.15)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Speedboat Oar</cell><cell>74</cell><cell cols="3">3.53 (1.76) -0.40 151</cell><cell>.69</cell><cell>-0.64</cell><cell>0.42</cell><cell>-0.06</cell></row><row><cell>Standard Speedboat</cell><cell>90</cell><cell>3.63 (1.65)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Speedboat Oar</cell><cell>74</cell><cell cols="4">3.53 (1.76) -3.45 158 &lt; .001</cell><cell>-1.60</cell><cell>-0.44</cell><cell>-0.54</cell></row><row><cell>Speedboat Accelerate</cell><cell>86</cell><cell>4.55 (1.97)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Universals and variations in moral decisions made in 42 countries by 70,000 participants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Awad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dsouza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shariff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rahwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J-F</forename><surname>Bonnefon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1911517117</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1911517117" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<publisher>PNAS</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2332" to="2337" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bago</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kovacs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Protzko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nagy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Kekecs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Palfi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Matibag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Situational factors shape moral judgements in the trolley dilemma in Eastern, Southern and Western countries in a culturally diverse sample</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-022-01319</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-022-01319" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="880" to="895" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Artificial driving intelligence and moral agency: Examining the decision ontology of unavoidable road traffic accidents through the prism of the trolley dilemma</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cunneen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mullins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gaines</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/08839514.2018.1560124</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/08839514.2018.1560124" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="293" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of conscious reasoning and intuition in moral judgment: Testing three principles of harm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-9280.2006.01834.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9280.2006.01834.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1082" to="1089" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neuroscience of morality: Emotion, brain disorders, and development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Moral psychology</title>
		<editor>W. Sinnott-Armstrong</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston Review</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="80" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The secret joke of Kant&apos;s soul</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pushing moral buttons: The interaction between personal force and intention in moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lowenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nystrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="364" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2009.02.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2009.02.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Never mind the trolley: The ethics of autonomous vehicles in mundane situations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Himmelreich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ethical Theory and Moral Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="669" to="684" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10677-018-9896-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10677-018-9896-4" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why trolley problems matter for the ethics of automated vehicles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Keeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11948-019-00096-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11948-019-00096-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science and Engineering Ethics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="307" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral dilemmas and moral principles: When emotion and cognition unite</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Manfrinati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lotto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sarlo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Palomba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Rumiati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02699931.2013.785388</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/02699931.2013.785388" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition &amp; Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1276" to="1291" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral study of obedience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Milgram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/h0040525</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0040525" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="378" />
			<date type="published" when="1963" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some conditions of obedience and disobedience to authority</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Milgram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/001872676501800105</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/001872676501800105" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Relations</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Opinio (Version 7.8) [Online Survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Objectplanet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.objectplanet.com/opinio/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The jamovi project (2020). jamovi (Version 1.2) [Computer Software</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.jamovi.org" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R: A language and environment for statistical computing</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
