<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Information Acquisition and Evaluation in Decision Making: A General Computational Framework</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2023-08-09">August 9, 2023</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Wall</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lisheng He</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sudeep</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
							<email>bhatiasu@sas.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Information Acquisition and Evaluation in Decision Making: A General Computational Framework</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2023-08-09">August 9, 2023</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:51+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Decision making</term>
					<term>Process tracing</term>
					<term>Computational modeling</term>
					<term>Attention</term>
					<term>Search</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>How do people acquire and aggregate information when making decisions? This question has been widely studied; however existing theories have not been comprehensively compared on data. We present a general computational framework that allows us to jointly model several different types of attentional and decision processes. We use our framework to test 63 distinct decision models, which apply assumptions from classical decision theories (e.g., the weighted additive rule, the tallying heuristic), contemporary dynamic theories (e.g. decision field theory, the attentional drift diffusion model), as well as several variants of these theories. We combine these decision models with a general attentional model that predicts the dynamics of information acquisition, and fit our models to eye-movement and choice data from three core decision making domains: risk, time, and effort allocation. Our tests identify the set of modeling assumptions necessary to best describe search and choice behavior. In doing so, they reveal the cognitive mechanisms at play in choice, resolve recent theoretical debates on the interplay of attention and choice, and provide new insights on how to generate choice environments aligned with people&apos;s goals.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Understanding the cognitive processes underlying information acquisition and decision making is key to a complete theory of choice. While the role of attention in decision making is widely studied (for reviews see <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hutchinson et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Mormann et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Orquin &amp; Wedel, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Russo, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">Weber &amp; Johnson, 2009)</ref>, few attempts have been made to quantitatively compare the large set of feasible attentional and decision processes at play in standard choice settings. In the absence of such a comparison, there are several unresolved debates about the relationship between attention and choice.</p><p>Some researchers propose that attention has a causal effect on choice, with higher attention to an option increasing people's preference for that option <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Fisher, 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Fisher, , 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Yang &amp; Krajbich, 2022)</ref>. Others argue that the causal effect can also be in the opposite direction, with high-valued options and attributes being attended to more frequently <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Anderson et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Fiedler &amp; Glöckner, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Glöckner &amp; Betsch, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Gluth et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Jekel et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Mormann &amp; Russo, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Orquin &amp; Loose, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Shimojo et al., 2003)</ref>. Another recent debate involves time at which people start aggregating acquired information. Dynamic models of decision making, which are currently dominant in psychology and neuroscience, propose that information aggregation starts with the first information sample <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Busemeyer et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>, however, other researchers have argued that evaluative processes only begin after most or all pieces of information have been obtained <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Edmunds et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Russo &amp; Leclerc, 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Shi et al., 2013)</ref>. Finally, there is the question of whether or not people simplify the weighting and aggregation of attributes, as proposed by models of heuristic decision making. Although there is a long history of research on these models <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Gigerenzer et al., 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Payne et al., 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Shah &amp; Oppenheimer, 2008)</ref>, they are seldom integrated with or tested alongside dynamic theories of information aggregation (but see <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bhatia, 2017</ref> for one such attempt).</p><p>These debates have implications that extend beyond behavioral and cognitive theories of choice.</p><p>The measurement of consumer preferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Green &amp; Srinivasan, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Li et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Meißner et al., 2016)</ref>, the use of information manipulations to influence choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hutchinson et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Mormann et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Orquin &amp; Wedel, 2020)</ref>, and the design of choice environments aligned with consumer or firm goals <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">(Thaler &amp; Sunstein, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Zhao, Coady et al., 2022)</ref>, all depend critically on the underlying relationship between attention and choice. Accordingly, a better understanding of attention and choice processes can improve managerial decision making, and generate new insights on how to influence and improve consumer choice.</p><p>Unfortunately, attention and decision processes are highly complex. Information acquisition data (e.g. eye or mouse-movement data) is dynamic, and at any given time, decision makers can attend to one of several different pieces of available information. The aggregation of this information and the construction of preference also happens dynamically, and after each information sample decision makers can choose to make a decision or to keep sampling more information. Attentional dynamics guide and constrain decisions, and both attention and decision processes are sensitive to several nuanced cognitive factors. This complexity has made it difficult to jointly model, and comprehensively test, the large set of mechanisms that could be at play in choice.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a general computational framework for solving this problem. We use our framework to test 63 decision models on five eye-tracking datasets, spanning risky, intertemporal, and effort allocation domains. Our models include classic heuristic decision rules, leading dynamic choice models, and several variants that combine insights from different modeling traditions and theoretical positions. We also propose and test a generalized model of attentional dynamics, which allows us to formalize distinct attentional dispositions, including the tendency to search within options or within attributes, the tendency to search for novel pieces of information, and the tendency to look at options with high-valued pieces of information. This combined framework allows us to predict the information that people acquire, the time at which they stop acquiring information, and the option they eventually choose.</p><p>In this way, our framework provides a comprehensive computational account of decision processes that can be used to resolve theoretical debates, describe human behavior with quantitative precision, and improve managerial and consumer decision making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Theoretical Overview</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Decision Problem</head><p>When faced with a choice between options, the decision maker must search their environment for information about the options and aggregate that information to decide whether to continue searching or to stop searching and choose an option. We model the entire process from initial sample to ultimate choice using data from five studies spanning three types of choice scenarios: intertemporal choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Amasino et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b86">Zhou et al., 2021)</ref>, risky choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Glickman et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Stewart et al., 2016)</ref>, and effort allocation <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(Westbrook et al., 2020)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1A</ref> illustrates each of these scenarios. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1B</ref> presents a schematic of the data used by our models and the predictions they make in the context of an effort allocation choice between two monetary payouts earned from exerting different amounts of effort (in the form of an N-back task 1 ). In the top row of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1B</ref>, the decision maker starts by fixating on the top left piece of information (1€), then the top right (3€), the bottom right (a 3-back working memory task), the bottom left (a 1-back task), then back at the top right and bottom right pieces of information, and finally, after the sixth sample, makes a decision to stop sampling and choose the option on the right (getting 3€ to complete a 3-back task). The data from other domains have a similar structure: in risky choice individuals sequentially attend to probabilities and payoffs when choosing between two gambles, whereas in intertemporal choice individuals sequentially attend to time delays and payoffs when choosing between two monetary sequences.</p><p>We model the observed data as involving distinct attentional and decision processes. Models of decision processes use the information participants have sampled to predict their decision to continue sampling and if they decide not to continue sampling, the option that they choose. Models of attention processes use the information participants have sampled to predict which piece of information people will sample next (if they choose to continue sampling). The middle and bottom rows of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1B</ref> present a schematic of decision and attention model predictions over the course of the deliberation process. In the middle panel, the decision model predicts a high probability of continuing to sample for the first five time periods, and then predicts a moderate probability of choosing option 2 in the sixth time period, followed by a high probability of choosing option 2 in the seventh time period. In the bottom panel, the attention model attaches a sampling probability to each of the four pieces of information at each time period (e.g. in the first time period, it predicts that the top left information will be the most likely to be sampled). Note that we assume that time units in our attention and decision models correspond to individual fixations (i.e. individual information samples), so that a trial in which the decision maker makes six fixations before selecting an option (as in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1B</ref>) takes seven units of time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decision Models</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Existing Approaches</head><p>Understanding the processes underlying decision making has, for several decades, been an important research area in multiple fields. While this research has increased our understanding of core decision making principles, it has also led to a proliferation of quantitative decision models (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Bhatia et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">He et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">He et al., 2022</ref>, for a discussion of this issue). Even for relatively simple choices between two options with two attributes, existing models make various assumptions about the underlying decision processes.</p><p>For simplicity, decision models can be seen as being either static or dynamic . Static decision models take the information within a choice, e.g., receiving 1€ for completing an easy 1-back task, or receiving 3€ for completing a more difficult 3-back task, and combine it, typically into a continuous measure of "utility", to predict which option the participant will choose. For instance, a weighted additive (WAD) model determines the utility of an option by weighing all attributes and summing them <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Keeney &amp; Raiffa, 1993)</ref>. Other static models propose a simplification of attribute weighting and comparison rules <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Huber, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Russo &amp; Dosher, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">Tversky, 1969)</ref>. Dynamic models, by contrast, explicitly specify how utilities change over time as information is sampled. In general, dynamic models assume that people accumulate utilities for options as they sample information, and once the accumulated utility reaches a threshold, a choice is made <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bhatia, 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bhatia, , 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Dai &amp; Busemeyer, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Fisher, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Frydman &amp; Nave, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kellen et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Roe et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Trueblood et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Tsetsos et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Yang &amp; Krajbich, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">Zhao, Richie, et al., 2022</ref>; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Busemeyer et al., 2019 and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Ratcliff et al., 2016</ref> for an overview).</p><p>Our modeling framework is fundamentally dynamic, as it attempts to predict both the eventual choice, as well as the attentional samples that culminate in the choice. However, we preserve the insights of static models by combining their assumptions about attribute weighting and comparison rules, with assumptions about how utility accumulates (see also Bhatia, 2017 for a cognitively plausible implementation of these assumptions). We divide these assumptions into three broad categories: utility formation, utility accumulation, and the timing of utility accumulation, and summarize these assumptions in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Core Assumptions</head><p>Utility Formation. A fundamental component of decision models involves the transformation of attribute information into utility. Attribute values can be differentially weighted, as in the WAD model, or be given equal weights, as in the equal weights (EW) model <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Dawes, 1979)</ref>. Additionally, attribute values may be aggregated as continuous numbers, as in the WAD and EW models, or as binary numbers with a 1 for the option that has the highest value on the attribute and a 0 for all other options, as with the weighted pros (WP) and the tallying (TAL) heuristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Huber, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Russo &amp; Dosher, 1983</ref>; see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Noguchi &amp; Stewart, 2018)</ref>. It is also possible for the decision maker to use only a single attribute to make their decision, as with the lexicographic (LEX) <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Fishburn, 1974)</ref> and the LEX semiorder <ref type="bibr" target="#b78">(Tversky, 1969)</ref> heuristics. It is important to note that different utility formation assumptions lead to different predictions about information acquisition data. For instance, to implement the WAD utility function, a decision maker needs to attend to each available piece of information; however, the LEX model only requires attention to a single attribute value across options.</p><p>Utility Accumulation. Dynamic decision models propose that decision makers represent utilities in dynamically evolving accumulator variables. Different dynamic models make different assumptions about the number of accumulators. For example, in diffusion models, the difference in utility of the two options is accumulated in a single dynamic accumulator (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>, and when this accumulator reaches a threshold (intuitively when the relative utility for one option over the other gets high enough), a decision is made. In race models, each option's utility is stored in its own accumulator (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Brown &amp; Heathcote, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Roe et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001)</ref>, and when one of the accumulators crosses a threshold (intuitively when the absolute utility for an option gets high enough), a decision is made. A related assumption involves the decay in accumulation. In models that assume decay, previously sampled information is given a smaller weight than more recently sampled information (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Roe et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001)</ref>. Models with decay also sometimes make assumptions about inhibition. In such models the accumulated utility of an option can reduce or suppress the utility of the other options.</p><p>A key assumption of many accumulator models is that utility accumulation is a function of attention <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bhatia, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Fisher, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Roe et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Yang &amp; Krajbich, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Usher &amp; McClelland, 2004)</ref>. Specifically, the attention-to-utility assumption states that the fixated piece of information factors more heavily in utility accumulation than other pieces of information. For this reason, the attention-to-utility assumption predicts that options that receive more attention or options with attributes that receive more attention, are also more likely to be chosen. The attentional assumption can take on many forms: some models assume that non-fixated pieces of information still enter into utility accumulation, but at a reduced rate; others assume that non-fixated pieces of information do not enter into utility accumulation at all. One could also assume that utility decay is independent of attention, i.e., utility decays regardless of which option is being fixated on; however, it may also be the case that utility decays only for the fixated option (as the utility for that option is updated).</p><p>Timing. Nearly all dynamic models assume that utility starts accumulating immediately after the first piece of information is sampled. However, some have questioned this initial-accumulation assumption in dynamic models <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Edmunds et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Russo &amp; Leclerc, 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr">She et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">)</ref>. In fact, many static models assume that people need to sample all or most choice information before making a decision. Thus utility accumulation may not begin until multiple or all pieces of information have been sampled.</p><p>Dynamic models generally assume that utility accumulation continues until the last fixation. In this way these models make an accumulation-termination assumption, which states that people continue accumulating utility until they indicate their choice. Other work, however, suggests that utility accumulation may terminate before people physically indicate their choice (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Mormann &amp; Russo, 2021)</ref>. Specifically, people may make up their minds after sampling all unique pieces of information, but nonetheless continue resampling information to verify their decision before indicating it with a motor response. These late fixations may not alter accumulated utility. This account is again consistent with static decision models: people may generate utilities all at once after observing all necessary information, and these utilities stay fixed even if some information is reacquired.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Summary.</head><p>The above assumptions can be combined with each other in many different ways, which can sometimes yield new models that have not been tested previously. In the Appendix, we provide a detailed account of the 63 distinct dynamic decision models that emerge from this combinatorial analysis. Despite their diverging properties, each of these models give us, at each point in time (i.e., after each fixation), a predicted probability of continuing sampling, choosing option 1, or choosing option 2. These predictions can be used to fit the models to eye-movement and choice data and to determine the combination of assumptions that are necessary for best describing the decision process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attention Model</head><p>Most decision models make assumptions about how information sampling determines utility and choice, however these models seldom predict actual attention probabilities for each piece of information at each point in time. Quantitatively specifying these attentional processes is necessary for a complete understanding the role of attention in choice. For instance, there is an ongoing debate about whether preferences drive attention, attention drives preferences, or attention and preferences both influence each other. Such debates can be resolved by jointly modeling both the types of decision processes outlined above, as well as the attentional processes that determine the information that is sampled. Our general attention model uses eight variables to predict the probability of fixating on a piece of information at a given point in time, contingent on the information that was sampled earlier in the trial.</p><p>We break these eight variables into four categories, corresponding to four general attentional tendencies.</p><p>These categories are summarized in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Baseline attentional variables capture people's overall tendencies to fixate on certain pieces of information (e.g., people may have an overall attentional bias towards the monetary amount of the high-effort-high-reward option). These baseline variables can be thought of as information-specific intercepts or attentional fixed effects. Transition variables capture people's tendencies to make different types of switches between information states <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Payne et al., 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Reeck, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Russo &amp; Rosen, 1975)</ref>. One transition variable involves transitions to information states within a given option (e.g., from the monetary amount of the high-effort-high-reward option to the difficulty of effort for this option); another variable involves transitions to information states within a given attribute (e.g., from the monetary amount of the high-effort-high-reward option to the monetary amount of the low-effort-low-reward option); and a third variable involves transitions back to the currently sampled piece of information (e.g., refixating on the monetary amount of the high-effort-highreward option). The novelty variable captures the tendency to look at never-before-sampled information.</p><p>Finally, the previous-value variable captures how the attribute value revealed in a fixation influences people's subsequent propensity to fixate on options. This variable allows attention to be driven towards high-valued options, a behavioral pattern known as the "attraction search effect" <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Jekel et al., 2018</ref>; see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Anderson et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Fiedler &amp; Glöckner, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Glöckner &amp; Betsch, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Gluth et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Mormann &amp; Russo, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Orquin &amp; Loose, 2013)</ref>. We model the effect of these variables on attention using a linear function passed through a softmax transformation. This function has eight flexible parameters (or coefficients), one for each of the variables, and gives us, at each point in time, the predicted probability of attending to each piece of information. We fit these predictions to attention data in order to determine the variables that are necessary for characterizing the attention process. 2</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview of Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Datasets</head><p>We use data from five eye-tracking studies of two-alternative, two-attribute choices to test the above attention and decision models. Two of the datasets involve intertemporal choices between a smaller amount of money received sooner and a larger amount of money received later <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Amasino et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b86">Zhou et al., 2021)</ref>. Two of the datasets involve risky choices between a smaller amount of money received with a higher probability and a larger amount of money received with a lower probability <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Glickman et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Stewart et al., 2016)</ref>. One dataset involves effort allocation choices between exerting low effort and receiving a low reward and exerting higher effort and receiving a higher reward <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(Westbrook et al., 2020)</ref>. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1A</ref> for an illustration, <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> for a summary, and the Appendix for a detailed overview. To ensure consistency across and within datasets, we code the data such that option 1 2 Note that our attention model is closely related to the hierarchical hidden Markov model proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Shi et al. (2013)</ref>. Unlike Shi et al., however, we do not flexibly infer underlying attention sampling strategies from data, but rather specify the influences of a select set of variables using a linear function (with weights inferred from dat a). We do this for two reasons. Firstly, our approach allows us to quantitatively test which of several previously proposed attentional tendencies are observed in our data (for example, using the weight on the previous-value variable, we can determine whether or not attention is biased towards high-value options). Secondly, our approach requires less data to estimate, as it allows for only a small number of flexible parameters. This makes it possible to fit our model on existing datasets. The limitation of this is that we are unable to flexibly specify different types of possible attentional strategies or model how the use of these strategies shifts over time (though note that we find that most underlying attentional tendencies remain stable over timesee Results section).</p><p>is always the smaller-sooner, low-risk-low-reward, or low-effort-low-reward option. We also normalize all attribute values based on the range of the values of that attribute in the corresponding dataset (see Appendix for details).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Modeling Problem</head><p>Our goal is to use our modeling framework to describe information acquisition (eye-movement) patterns and decisions in these five datasets. For this purpose, we jointly fit the 63 decision models and general attentional model outlined in the sections above. Our attentional model specifies which pieces of information are sampled whereas our decision models aggregate sampled information over time to make a choice. To simply this modeling problem, and to separate the attentional and decision mechanisms into two separate components, we rely on the concept of context introduced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">Zhao, Richie, et al. (2022)</ref>. Context is used to generate a model's predicted probability for each action taken. For example, after sampling the first piece of information, the probability of continuing sampling more information is (KeepSamp| 1 ). If the decision maker continues sampling, then the probability of fixating on the top right piece of information is (FixTopRight| 1 ). We can define the predicted probabilities for the entire sequence of observed attention states using this method. We can also describe the probability of stopping sampling and choosing option 2 after the sixth sample as (ChooseOpt2| 6 ).</p><p>Using context in this manner allows us to write a model's predicted probability of the entire sequence of observed actions (i.e., observed attention samples and eventual choice) in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1B</ref> as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(KeepSamp | 0 ) * (FixTopLeft| 0 ) * (KeepSamp | 1 ) * (FixTopRight| 1 ) … (KeepSamp| 5 ) * (FixBotRight| 5 ) * (ChooseOpt2| 6 )</formula><p>The above equation can be written as two products of probabilities:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">1) (KeepSamp| 0 ) * (KeepSamp| 1 ) * … * (ChooseOpt2| 6 ) 2) (FixTopLeft| 0 ) * (FixTopRight| 1 ) * … * (FixBotRight| 5 )</formula><p>The first product defines the modeling problem for decision modelsat each point in time, these models generate probabilities for choosing each of the options or to keep sampling, contingent on the context at that time (as in the middle panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1B</ref>). Good models are those that attach high probabilities to the observed sampling and choice data. The second product defines the modeling problem for our attention modelsat each point in time, these models generate attention sampling probabilities for each of the possible attentional states contingent on the context at that time (as in the bottom panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1B</ref>). Good models are those that attach high probabilities to observed information samples . Note that there is an important assumption underlying the split into the two products: We need to assume that attention and decision processes are conditionally independent on context, i.e. if we know the context at time , the probabilities generated by the attention model provide no information about the probabilities generated by the associated decision model, and vice versa (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">Zhao, Richie, et al., 2022</ref> for a detailed description of this assumption).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exemplar Models</head><p>As discussed above, we have a single attentional model that linearly combines the eight attentional variables. We fit this attentional model to eye-movement data, and infer the role of each of the attentional variables using best fit weights and fit comparisons with constrained variants of the model.</p><p>The assumptions underlying our decision models, by contrast, cannot be combined in this way, as many of the assumptions are mutually exclusive. Overall, these assumptions give rise to a total of 63 distinct decision models, each of which must be fit separately to decision data (the description of the full set of models and their fits is presented in the Appendix). We describe a representative subset of seven exemplar decision models in this section. The first four of these decision models are illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure   2</ref>, which shows how utility in these models evolves as information is sampled in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 1B</ref>.</p><p>The Attentional Accumulator model, has a single accumulator that keeps track of the relative utilities of each option. Accumulation begins with the first fixation and continues until the choice is made.</p><p>This accumulator also updates after each information sample, based on the weighted attribute value revealed in the sample. This is why the accumulated utility for this model in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2</ref> fluctuates heavily as the decision maker shifts focus. The Attentional Accumulator shares key assumptions with the models presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Yang and Krajbich (2022)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Fisher (2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Fisher ( , 2021</ref>, however, there are also three key differences. First, our Attentional Accumulator model assumes that only the fixated piece of information enters into utility. We make this assumption because, assuming that all pieces of information are accumulated implies that people know all pieces of information before fixating on them (a criticism put forth by <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Edmunds et al., 2020)</ref>. Second, for tractability, our Attentional Accumulator model assumes that utility accumulation is a function of fixations and not of fixation time, i.e. that the changes in utility are not dependent on the duration of each fixation. Third, our Attentional Accumulator model assumes that previously accumulated utility can decay over time.</p><p>The Dynamic LEX model is an implementation of the traditional LEX model. Specifically, it assumes that utility is calculated immediately after a within-attribute transition, and depends only on the difference between the attribute values that are sampled. This is why the accumulated utility for this model (i.e. the utility for the low-effort-low-reward option relative to the utility for the high-effort-highreward option) in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2</ref> is negative after sampling the effort attributes successively, positive after sampling the reward attributes successively, and zero at all other points in time.</p><p>The Dynamic WAD model assumes that the utility for an option is its weighted additive utility,</p><p>where each attribute has its own weight. Further, it assumes that people can only know the utility of both options once every piece of information has been sampled, and, after all unique pieces of information have been sampled, additional fixations yield no changes to utility. This is why the utility variable for this model in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2</ref> is 0 until after the fourth fixation, at which point it takes on a stable negative value (corresponding to the WAD utility difference between option 1 and 2).</p><p>The WAD Attentional Accumulator model combines insights of the Attentional Accumulator and Dynamic WAD models. As with Dynamic WAD, the WAD Attentional Accumulator assumes that each attribute has its own weight and that the decision maker calculates utility only after every piece of information has been sampled. As with the Attentional Accumulator, utility continues accumulating after all pieces of information have been sampled, based on the decision maker's attention: for every postcomplete-sampling fixation, utility is accumulated based on weighted additive utility of the option that is being attended to. The WAD Accumulator model also allows utility to decay over time. This is why the accumulator for this model in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2</ref> is at 0 until the fourth fixation, after which it evolves in a concave trajectory, with a rate proportional to the WAD utility of the item that is being fixated on (option 2).</p><p>In addition to the above four models, shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2</ref>, we also consider three additional exemplar models. The first of these, the WAD Accumulator, makes similar assumptions as the WAD Attentional Accumulator model. However, the utility accumulated for each post-complete-sampling fixation does not depend on which option was fixated on, i.e. for every post-complete-sampling fixation utility is accumulated based on the (fixed) weighted additive utility difference, independent of attention.</p><p>This is thus a model that allows for WAD utility to accumulate, but not in way that is biased by attention.</p><p>The EW Attentional Dual Accumulator differs from the WAD Attentional Accumulator in two ways. First, it assumes that in the formation of utility, continuous attributes values are given equal weights (in this way it is a dynamic implementation of the equal weights (EW) heuristic). Second, it assumes that there are option-specific accumulators. Combined with the dual accumulator assumption, it also assumes that the accumulators affect each other, i.e., there is inhibition between accumulators. The WP Attentional Dual Accumulator model shifts only the utility formation assumption of the EW Attentional Dual Accumulator model. Specifically, instead of assuming utility is calculated via continuous attributes with equal weights, this model assumes that utility is calculated via a binary comparison of attributes with unequal weights, in line with the weighted pros (WP) heuristic.</p><p>The above models embed their dynamic utility formation assumptions in a stochastic decision rule, that, after each fixation, determines whether decision makers continue sampling or whether they terminate choice and select one of the options. For the Attentional Accumulator this involves combining accumulated utility with normally distributed noise and testing if the resulting variable crosses a threshold. This is done at each point in time during deliberation. The remaining models also use a noiseplus-threshold mechanism but do so only after all pieces of information have been sampled. For the WAD Attentional Accumulator, WAD Accumulator, EW Attentional Dual Accumulator and WP Attentional Dual Accumulator the thresholds can be non-zero, reflecting the intuition that some utility needs to accumulate before choice is made. For models without explicit accumulation, like Dynamic LEX and Dynamic WAD, the threshold is fixed at zero, implying that the option with the higher utility-plus-noise is chosen. Note that these six models can make a choice even before sampling all necessary information, as they are equipped with a premature choice termination mechanism that attaches a low but positive probability to erroneous termination. Dynamic LEX and Dynamic WAD also allow for a low but positive probability of continuing sampling even after all necessary information is acquired. These and the remaining 56 models are fit to individual-level eye-movement and choice data, which allows us to infer participant-specific parameters (e.g. attribute weights, choice thresholds, error probability etc.) and compare the performance of the best-fitting implementations of each model. Again, we provide more details in the Appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Qualitative Patterns</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Utility Formation</head><p>The exemplar decision models discussed above make various assumptions about underlying decision processes (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> for a summary). We begin by examining the patterns predicted by the utility formation assumptions, which pertain to how attributes are weighted and aggregated during deliberation. For the Dynamic WAD, WAD Accumulator, EW Attentional Dual Accumulator, and WAD Attentional Accumulator models, accumulated utility is a linear function of the difference in the options'</p><p>utilities. Since we can rearrange the formula for utility differences to be a function of attribute differences, these models predict that the higher the value of an option on an attribute, relative to its competitor, the more likely the option is to be chosen. Similarly, the Attentional Accumulator model assumes that an option's utility is a (weighted) sum of the attribute values that have been fixated on. Thus, controlling for attention, this model also predicts that the higher the value of an option on an attribute, relative to its competitor, the more likely the option is to be chosen. The Dynamic WAD, WAD Accumulator, WAD Attentional Accumulator, Attentional Accumulator models further assume that attributes can have different weights. This implies that the slopes of the relationship between attribute value difference and choice can vary by attribute. By contrast, the EW Attentional Dual Accumulator model predicts that these slopes are equivalent across attributes. Finally, the Dynamic LEX and WP Attentional Dual Accumulator models, are sensitive to attribute differences, though they rely only on the sign of these differences. Thus, they predict that the slope of the relationship between attribute value difference and choice should be flat.</p><p>As seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Utility Accumulation</head><p>Although there are four distinct types of utility accumulation assumptions in our framework, the only type that makes clear qualitative predictions is attention-to-utility. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> To test this assumption, we relate the relative number of fixations on option 1 to the observed proportion of option 1 choices. Recall that the Attentional Accumulator, WAD Attentional Accumulator, EW Attentional Dual Accumulator, and WP Attentional Dual Accumulator all predict that the more a participant fixates on option 1 compared to option 2, the more likely it is that they choose option 1. On the other hand, the Dynamic WAD, WAD Accumulator, and Dynamic LEX models predict that there should be no relationship between relative attention and choice.</p><p>As seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref>, for most datasets, the more participants fixated on option 1 relative to option 2, the more likely they were to choose option 1 (Spearman's correlations are included in the figure). <ref type="bibr">6</ref> These results suggest that the amount of attention directed towards an option affects utility accumulation. This is why the Attentional Accumulator and WAD Attentional Accumulator models, fit to individuallevel data, are able to reproduce the patterns in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref>. Interestingly, the EW Attentional Dual Accumulator and WP Attentional Dual Accumulator have difficulty capturing this pattern all datasets <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Here, and elsewhere in the qualitative patterns section, we present the predictions of our best -fit models. These predictions are obtained by fitting each model to each participant's data, calculating its prediction, and averaging predictions over participants. The details of the model fits and associated parameters are provided in the subsequent section and the Appendix.</p><p>5 Assumptions about the number of accumulators and decay and inhibition between accumulators influence quantitative fits, but are hard to test using qualitative trends. But see <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ashby et al. (2016)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Mullett &amp; Stewart (2016)</ref> for some previous attempts.</p><p>despite assuming that attention biases choice ---this may be because these models do not assume that attributes are weighted and aggregated continuously, which may be necessary for capturing the link between attention and choice. Also note that the Attentional Accumulator generates the steepest relationship between relative attention and choice, and for all datasets it predicts a steeper slope than the empirical slope.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Timing</head><p>To qualitatively assess accumulation timing assumptions, namely initial-accumulation and accumulation-termination, we examine the probability of continuing to sample as a function of the and WP Attentional Dual Accumulator models, which continue to accumulate utility until a threshold has been passed. Finally, the Dynamic LEX model assumes that utility is accumulated and choice is made after a within-attribute transition, and that people should terminate search after the first such transition.</p><p>As seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5</ref>, for all datasets, there is a negative empirical relationship between the number of samples made and the probability of continuing to sample (Spearman's correlations are included in the figure). Additionally, people often sample four or more pieces of information. For the Glickman and</p><p>Westbrook data, there is a precipitous drop in the probability of continuing to sample after four pieces of information have been sampled 7 . For the Stewart, Amasino, and Zhou datasets there is an initial moderate decline in the probability of continuing to sample that flattens out. Altogether these results are inconsistent with Dynamic LEX which predicts early search termination. The strong drop after the fourth sample also appears to be contradictory to the predictions of the Attentional Accumulator model, which predicts that accumulation begins after the first sample and continues till a threshold has been crossed.</p><p>Lastly, the fact that sampling rates remain moderately high after the fourth sample is inconsistent with Dynamic WAD, which predicts that decision makers are likely to terminate choice after sampling all unique pieces of information. For these reasons, the Attentional Accumulator, Dynamic LEX and Dynamic WAD models, fit to individual-level data, do a poor job of predicting the decision to continue sample regardless of the number of samples made. The remaining models, which assume that accumulation starts after all information has been sampled, and that it continues till a choice is made, all make similarly accurate predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attention</head><p>The variables in our attention model predict which piece of information will be sampled given what has been sampled previously. As summarized in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, we break these variables into four categories. Here, we begin by examining qualitative attentional patterns corresponding to our model's assumptions about transitions between pieces of information (for space reasons we do not examine baseline variables in the main text). There are 16 possible transitions between boxes in our two-attributetwo-alternative datasets. Each piece of information has four possible transitions, one where the participant resamples the piece of information they were just sampling, and three transitions to the other pieces of <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Note that sampling four pieces of information is not equivalent to a sampling each unique piece of information; however, these two values are similar as people's first four fixations are generally on each unique piece of information, as seen in the results of our attention model. For the Glickman data a small percentage of choices, 4%, in which not all pieces of information were sampled, were removed in the dataset post ed by the original authors. This biased the results towards the complete sampling models.</p><p>information. Our attention model allows some transitions to be more prevalent than others. As seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 6</ref>, there is variance in the prevalence of transitions: within-option and within-attribute transitions are more common than transitions that switch both the option and attribute people were looking at.</p><p>Additionally, item resampling is very rare. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 7</ref> we plot the probability of within-option and within-attribute transitions as a function of sample number. This figure shows that the tendency to make within-option and within-attribute transitions remain relatively steady throughout the course of the trial. 8</p><p>Both these patterns are easily captured by our attention model, fit to individual-level sampling data.</p><p>Another assumption is that novel information may be more likely to be fixated on. As seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 7</ref>, the first four fixations people make tend to be on a novel piece of information after which there are no novel pieces of information and the percentage of fixations on novel information declines precipitously. In three studies, Stewart, Westbrook, and Glickman, the degree of the drop is larger than the other two studies, Amasino and Zhou. This slight difference may be due to domain (both the Amasino and Zhou data involve intertemporal choices), study design (the Amasino data only varied two pieces of information) or cultural context (the Zhou data was collected in China whereas other datasets were collected in Western cultures). Regardless of these differences, the attention model, fit to individual-level data, provides a good account of novelty seeking behavior in the studies.</p><p>Our attentional model also allows for the most recently sampled piece of information to influence the subsequent sample. We operationalize this using a previous-value variable for each option such that a high previous-value for the option means that the participant just sampled a high attribute value in that option or a low attribute value in the competing option (attribute values are scaled such that the largest value of that attribute in the dataset is given a 1 and the smallest value is given a 0). For example, if someone just looked at $10 (the highest dollar amount in the Amasino dataset) in the larger-later option the previous-value equals 1 for the larger-later option and 0 for the smaller-sooner option. <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref> displays the association between the mean number of fixations on an option and the previous-value variable for that option, at each point in time. Here we see that all datasets contain a clear positive association between the previous-value and fixations, implying that observing a high (low) value attribute in an option makes it more (less) likely to fixate on that option in the next time period. 9 Our attention model, fit to individual-level data, easily captures the positive relationship between previousvalue and fixations and closely mimics observed empirical patterns.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Summary</head><p>Overall, we find that decision makers separately weigh and aggregate continuous attribute values, that increased attention to a choice option leads to a higher choice probability for that option, and that decision makers sample all pieces of information and often continue accumulating utility after all information has been sampled. Out of the seven exemplar decision models considered in this paper, only the WAD Attentional Accumulator captures all qualitative patterns. This indicates that the WAD Attentional Accumulator may also be able to provide a good quantitative account of choice data.</p><p>On the attention side we find that decision makers are more likely to transition within-options and within-attributes, more likely to sample novel pieces of information, and more likely to sample an option if the sample preceding that option revealed a high-valued attribute in that option or a low-valued attribute in the competing option. Our attention model allows for all of these tendencies to guide attention, implying that it may be able to also provide a good quantitative account of information sampling behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Quantitative Fits</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decision Models</head><p>Aggregate Data. The ability of the exemplar models to reproduce observed empirical patterns provides evidence for several decision model assumptions. To rigorously test which assumptions best capture decision processes, we compare the quantitative model fits of all 63 decision models summarized in the Appendix. We measure the quality of fit using the AIC of best-fitting individual-level models. Accumulator models are typically outperformed by the WAD Attentional Accumulator model: this is the best performing exemplar model in three datasets and the second best in two datasets.</p><p>In the Appendix <ref type="table">Table A1</ref>, we present the mean AICs for all 63 decision models. Here we can see that the best performing model (as determined by the rank of the average AIC value across datasets) is nearly identical to the WAD Attentional Accumulator model, except that it assumes that decay affects the utility calculation of only the fixated option. The second-best model is nearly identical to the first but, instead of assuming utility is combined into a single accumulator, it assumes separate accumulators for each of the options. The third-best model is the WAD Accumulator model.</p><p>Heterogeneity across Individuals and Domains. While the results using mean AICs provide evidence for the assumptions of the WAD Attentional Accumulator, averaging over participants may obscure individual-level model performance. In the Appendix <ref type="table">Table A2</ref>, we present the proportion of participants whose data was best fit by each of the 63 decision models. These results are generally consistent with the Mean AIC results, except that the best performing model is the WAD Accumulator, which best describes an average of 12.4% of participants across the datasets. The second best model is the WAD Attentional Accumulator model, but where only the fixated option's utility decays. This model best describes an average of 7.4% of participants across the datasets. The improved performance of the WAD Accumulator when examining the proportion of participants best-fit by a given model is due to the fact that we consider 32 variants of the WAD Attentional Accumulator (e.g. variants with one or two accumulators, variants with or without decay and with different decay assumptions, variants with and without inhibition, and variants with different ways of implementing the attention-to-utility assumption)</p><p>but only 20 variants of the WAD Accumulator. This means that there are many nearly identical models that compete directly with the WAD Attentional Accumulator when measuring the proportion of participants best-fit by a given model (this is not an issue when using mean AIC). Overall, an average of 36% of participants across the five datasets are best described by the WAD Accumulator or one of its variants, whereas 52% of participants are best described by the WAD Attention Accumulator or one of its variants.</p><p>To get a sense of how different the proportion best-fit results were from the mean AIC results, we correlate the mean model rankings for both metrics (such that higher ranks corresponded to better model fits). The relationship between these metrics is positive and significant (Spearman's r = .68, p &lt; .001). These results suggest that, in general, aggregated AICs tell a similar story as the individual-level best fitting models. To assess the consistency of model fits across datasets, we compare the rankings of the mean AIC for all 63 models. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> presents the Spearman correlation between fits for each dataset, which was uniformly high (&gt;.8). This result suggests that our best-fitting models capture important domain general decision processes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decision Model Assumptions.</head><p>To assess which decision model assumptions are necessary for describing the data, we present a comparison of models that differ on a single assumption (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Turner et al., 2018</ref> for previous analysis using this method). For instance, to assess the importance of utility decay, we compare the fit of a model that assumes utility decays to an equivalent model that assumes that utility does not decay. To assess the performance of equivalent models, we compare decision model AICs at the individual-level and calculate the proportion of participants for whom the AIC of one model is lower (better) than the other model.</p><p>We first investigate models that differ on utility formation assumptions. Consistent with the patterns in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3</ref>, <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows that decision models that assume attribute-specific weights outperform equivalent models that assume equal weights. By contrast, models that assume the accumulation of continuous attribute values perform similarly to those that assume binary attribute values.</p><p>This appears to contradict the patterns shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3</ref>, which display a strong effect of the magnitude of attribute-value differences on choice probability. However, note that attribute values could have a continuous effect on choice by altering information sampling probabilities, as implemented in the pervious-value assumption of our attention model. In particular, it could be that high attribute values increase the probability that the decision maker resamples the option, thereby increasing the choice probability of the option. This could yield the patterns shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3</ref> even if the accumulation process is itself based on binary attribute information.</p><p>Next, we compare models that differ on utility accumulation assumptions. As seen in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>, single accumulator models perform roughly equivalently to dual accumulator models. Additionally, models with decay almost always outperform their equivalent no decay models. Conversely, models with inhibition are almost always outperformed by their equivalent no-inhibition models. Finally, and perhaps most importantly, models equipped with an attentional bias typically do better than models without such a bias. This is consistent with the patterns shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref>.</p><p>Finally, we compare equivalent models that differ in accumulation timing assumptions. As seen in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>, models that assume accumulation does not start until all pieces of information have been sampled outperform those that assume utility accumulation begins with the first fixation. Additionally, models that assume utility accumulation terminates as soon as all unique pieces of information have been sampled are outperformed by models that assume that decision makers continue accumulating utility until they make a decision. This is consistent with the patterns shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attention Models</head><p>To rigorously test which assumptions are necessary for describing information sampling processes, we fit our attention model to individual-level data. <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> summarizes these fits for the three transition variables (which capture the tendency to transition within-options, within-attributes, and to avoid resampling the same piece of information), the novelty variable, and the previous-value variable (for expositional convenience we do not present the baseline parameters). Here we can see that the median coefficients on these variables are all positive, and that a large proportion of participant have positive coefficients for these variables. This corresponds to the patterns in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figures 6, 7</ref> and 8. <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> also shows the proportion of participants for whom the best-fit coefficients are significantly positive (p &lt; 0.05) as assessed by a likelihood ratio test between the full attention model and a restricted model with the coefficient on the associated variable constrained to zero. Here we see that every variable, except for the previous-value variable, provides a significant improvement over the corresponding restricted model for the majority of participants. The previous-value parameter shows high between-study variability and only crosses the threshold of significance for 45% of participants in the full dataset.</p><p>To get a sense of dataset level heterogeneity in parameter values, <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> presents the correlation between the median parameter values for the 5 datasets. The correlations shown here are moderate to strong, indicating that attentional tendencies are largely consistent across domains.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Summary</head><p>Overall, the results in this section provide further evidence about underlying decision processes.</p><p>Consistent with the qualitative analysis, they suggest that attributes are given different weights and that utility accumulation is sensitive to attention. Additionally, accumulation generally starts late (after all unique pieces of information have been fixated on) and continues until participants choose an option.</p><p>Moreover, accumulation decays, though there is little or no inhibition. Assumptions about the accumulation of continuous vs. binary attribute values and assumptions about the number of accumulators do not greatly alter model fit. On the attention side, we find that most decision makers sample withinoptions and within-attributes, that they tend to avoid resampling the same piece of information successively, that they seek out novel information, and that the value revealed in a given sample influences the next sample (with high-valued attributes increasing sampling probabilities for their associated options). These results are largely consistent across individuals and domains.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>What are the core mechanisms at play in the sampling and accumulation of information? We have provided a comprehensive investigation of this question by modeling several distinct attention and decision processes across five eye-movement and choice datasets. Our flexible attentional models have permitted four different types of dynamic attentional sampling tendencies, whereas our 63 distinct decision models have made varying assumptions about how utility is formed, as well as how and when utility is accumulated. We have fit these models to eye-movement and choice data from each of the 376 individuals in our datasets, and evaluated the models both using quantitative fit statistics as well as their ability reproduce key behavioral patterns. Overall, we have found that the best attentional models allow for biases for within-option and within-attribute search, a predilection for sampling novel information, as well as a tendency to sample options that that are known to have high-valued attributes. The best decision models accumulate the information revealed by attentional samples using flexible decision weights, but importantly they do so only after all unique pieces of information have been obtained. Furthermore, this accumulation process involves decay, is sensitive to the amount of attention towards a choice option, and continues till a choice is made.</p><p>These results help resolve some recent debates about the interplay of attention and decision making. Firstly, we have shown that attention affects the rate of accumulation (as argued by <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Fisher, 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Fisher, , 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Yang &amp; Krajbich, 2022)</ref>. Importantly, however, this does not happen throughout the deliberation process. Rather, the frequency with which people sample information from a given option influences the rate of utility accumulation only after all unique pieces of information have been sampled. Additionally, we have shown that decision makers are more likely to attend to desirable choice options. In particular, decision makers tend to resample an option if they observe a high attribute value in that option, and are more likely to sample the alternate option if they observe a low attribute value in an option <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Fiedler &amp; Glöckner, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Jekel et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">also Anderson et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Gluth et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Jekel et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Mormann &amp; Russo, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Orquin &amp; Loose, 2013)</ref>. These results indicate that the relationship between attention and preference is bidirectional <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bhatia, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Glöckner &amp; Betsch, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Roe et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Shimojo et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Simon et al., 2004)</ref> and that both sides of the debate have merit.</p><p>These results also open new questions about the role of attention in choice: Is the type of bidirectional effect documented in our paper adaptive <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Gigerenzer et al., 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Payne et al., 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Shah &amp; Oppenheimer, 2008)</ref>, that is, does it help people make faster and more accurate choices (see <ref type="bibr">Glöckner &amp;</ref> Betsch, 2008 for a discussion)? Relatedly, does it persist across different types of choice sets, or do people modify information acquisition and aggregation strategies based on the environment they are in <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Payne et al., 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Russo &amp; Rosen, 1975)</ref>. Also, does this type of bidirectionality persist when attention is explicitly manipulated <ref type="bibr">(Armel et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Newell &amp; Le Pelley, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Towal et al., 2013)</ref>, that is when one attribute or option is made more salient to the decision maker? Resolving these questions can provide further theoretical insights about underlying choice processes, while also improving our ability to influence and improve choice in real-world settings.</p><p>Our results also show that utility accumulation begins after all unique pieces of information have been sampled. In essence, people first observe all attributes, then calculate utility, and then continuously aggregate utility (in a manner that is sensitive to attention) until a threshold is crossed. By contrast, models that allow for utility to fluctuate from the very start of the decision perform relatively poorly.</p><p>These models generate high threshold crossing probabilities (and thus high search termination probabilities) early on during choice, contradicting observed behavioral patterns. Similarly, models that assume that utility stops accumulating after all unique attributes have been sampled also perform poorlythese models cannot account for the fact that people often resample information, and that they have an increasing tendency to terminate choice after each additional information sample. Our results suggest that the standard approach to modeling preference accumulation in multiattribute choice may be flawed; rather a two-stage accumulation process, with only search in the first stage and both search and accumulation in the second stage may provide a better account of behavior (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Edmunds et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Russo &amp; Leclerc, 1994</ref> for an extended discussion). However, it is important to note that there are more complex modeling assumptions that allow for utility accumulation from the very start of deliberation, without generating early stopping. For example, we could assume that decision makers have very high threshold at the start of the decision, and that this threshold gradually collapses over time (e.g. <ref type="bibr">Ditterich, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Cisek et al., 2009)</ref>. In this way, utility can fluctuate with early information samples without prematurely hitting a threshold. It is not clear whether such a model makes unique predictions or if it could be tested using only eye-movement and choice data. Examining this problem is an important topic for future work.</p><p>We believe that our paper is notable for illustrating a new approach to decision modeling. Until recently, researchers have studied choice by proposing and testing individual models. They have seldom considered the large set of previously proposed decision models and have not examined the different combinations of assumptions that underlie these models. This research approach has led to an explosion of models, with little consensus about the right theory for describing choice (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Bhatia et al., 2021</ref> for an extended discussion). By contrast we have distilled previous decision models into their core mechanistic assumptions, and paired these assumptions with each other to generate several unique models, which we have comprehensively tested on eye-movement and choice data (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">He et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">He et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Turner et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zhao, Richie et al., 2002)</ref>. Our approach can not only help resolve theoretical disagreements; it can also be used to identify the most effective ways to influence and improve choice.</p><p>Our attention model, for example, describes how a given information sample determines the probability of the subsequent information sample. Our decision models likewise describe how attentional samples are aggregated into preferences. Since our framework makes quantitative predictions, researchers can use it to test the down-stream effects of attentional manipulations and thus identify the best interventions for a given policy or marketing goal <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hutchinson et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Mormann et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Orquin &amp; Wedel, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Zhao, Coady et al., 2022)</ref>. Similarly, our modeling framework flexibly recovers attribute weights from data, and can be used to determine the attributes that are most important to a decision maker. Unlike previous approaches to measuring preferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Green &amp; Srinivasan, 1978</ref>), we explicitly model information acquisition and aggregation dynamics. For this reason, our approach controls for the biasing role of attention and response time, and likely generates more accurate attribute weight estimates. We are excited about the possibility of using our framework to improve people's decisions, and look forward to future work that attempts to describe and influence choice with theoretical rigor and quantitative precision.   Option 1 is coded to be smaller on attribute 1-money-and, by design, larger on attribute 2-probability, delay (reverse-scored so sooner is higher), and effort (reverse-scored so lower effort is higher). Therefore, attribute 1 differences are less than 0 and attribute 2 differences are greater than 0. Lines indicate attribute-specific linear regressions where attribute differences are regressed on p(Choose 1). For the empirical data, p(Choose 1) is the empirical proportion of option 1 choices; for the decision models, p(Choose 1) is the best-fitting model's predicted probability of choosing option 1. Points indicate the average empirical choice probability of option 1 for the associated attribute difference. The size of empirical points corresponds to proportion of the dataset with that value. For legibility, attribute differences in the Zhou and Westbrook datasets are binned in .1 increments. r values indicate the Spearman's rho correlation between the empirical proportion of option 1 choices and attribute values differences (correlations were split by attribute and weighted based on the number of empirical observations).  . The decision to continue sampling for each study. The x-axis indicates the sample number and the y-axis denotes the probability of continuing to sample after the corresponding sample number. For the empirical data, this is the observed probability that participants continued sampling, and, for the decision models, it is the best-fit model's predicted probability of continuing to sample. The model lines correspond to the average (prediction or observation) over all participants. For empirical data, the size of the points corresponds to the proportion of the dataset with that number of samples. r values indicate the Spearman's correlation between sample number and the probability of continuing to sample.   <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>. Probability of making a fixation to an option given the previous-value. A high previous-value means that the participant just sampled a high attribute value in that option or a low attribute value in the competing option. For the Amasino, Zhou, and Westbrook datasets, we rounded previous-values to the nearest tenth for interpretability. Lines indicate linear regression fits where the previous-value parameter is regressed on the probability of fixating on an option which is either the empirical fixation probability or the best-fit attentional model predicted fixation probability. The size of empirical points corresponds to the proportion of the dataset with that value. Correlations indicate the Spearman's rho between the previous-value variable and fixation probability weighted by sample size. Since mean AICs varied widely across studies, we allowed the scale of the x-axis vary by study. Additionally, since exemplar models clustered around low mean AICs, we used a base-10 logarithmic transformation on the x-axis. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Categories of assumptions of decision models (utility formation, utility accumulation, and accumulation timing) and attention models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assumption Description</head><p>Utility Formation Attribute weighting and comparison rules used to combine attribute values into utilities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Utility Accumulation</head><p>Number of Accumulators The number of accumulators in which utility information is stored.</p><p>Decay Down-weighting of initially sampled utility compared to recently sampled utility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Inhibition</head><p>Suppression or reduction of accumulated utility in other options' accumulators.</p><p>Attention-to-utility The positive effect of attention towards an option on the option's utility accumulation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Accumulation Timing</head><p>Initial-accumulation The fixation where utility begins to accumulate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Accumulation-termination</head><p>The fixation where utility stops accumulating.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attention</head><p>Baseline Absolute tendency to fixate on certain pieces of information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Transition</head><p>Tendency to transition within options, within attributes, or within the same item.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Novelty</head><p>Tendency to fixate on never-before-seen pieces of information.</p><p>Previous-value Tendency to fixate on an option in which a previous fixation revealed a large attribute value. models, but instead of the option specific 's being subtracted to get a single measure of utility difference, each option's utility is given its own chance to reach a threshold. Specifically, these models calculate the probability that option 1's utility is over the threshold with 1 − Φ 1 , ( ), and the probability that option 2's utility is over the threshold with 1 − Φ 2 , ( ). These over-threshold probabilities are then converted to probabilities for the three decision outcomes: the probability of choosing option 1 is the probability that only option 1's utility is over the threshold plus half the probability that both accumulators are over the threshold; the probability of choosing option 2 is defined similarly; the probability of continuing to sample is the probability that neither of the two utilities are over the threshold. Intuitively, the decision maker chooses an option if its utility crosses the threshold. If both utilities cross the threshold, then each option is chosen with an equal probability. If neither cross the threshold, search continues. Again, we allow to be flexible, and set = 1.</p><p>We consider variants of the Dual Attentional Accumulator with and without decay. For models with decay, we assume the same decay parameter for both accumulators. We also allow for variants of the decay model with and without inhibition. In models with inhibition, the utility from one accumulator suppresses the utility in the other. Specifically,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">1 = • −1 1 − • −1 2 + 1</formula><p>where is an inhibition parameter that determines the amount of this suppression.</p><p>There are a total of two Single Attentional Accumulator variants (one with decay and one without decay) and a total of three Dual Attentional Accumulator variants (one with decay and inhibition, one with only decay, and one with neither decay nor inhibition).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dynamic Additive Utility</head><p>The Dynamic Additive Utility variants assume that people can only know the utility of both options once every piece of information has been sampled. However, these variants can differ in their underlying utility functions. The Dynamic WAD model assumes that utility for an option is the weighted additive utility i.e., = 1 • 1 + 2 • 2 . The Dynamic EW model is similar except that it assumes that both attributes receive the same weight, e.g., 1 = 2 . The Dynamic WP model assumes that the attribute values are compared and binarized (e.g. if option 1 has a higher value on attribute 1 than option 2, then 1 1 = 1 and 1 2 = 0). The Dynamic TAL model assumes that both attributes receive the same weight with the same attribute comparison process as the Dynamic WP model.</p><p>The Dynamic Additive Utility variants further assume that utility is calculated after all pieces of information have been sampled. If t* is the time at which this happens, then these models generate = 0 for all t &lt; t*, and = 1 − 2 for all t ≥ t*. We also add an error parameter, , to allow for premature choice termination before all information has been acquired as well as the continuation of sampling after all information has been acquired. Thus, for t &lt; t*, the probability of choosing each option is . 5 • and the probability of continuing sampling is 1 − . For t ≥ t*, the probability of choosing option 1 is</p><p>(1 − ) • Φ , (0), where Φ is the cumulative normal distribution with mean and a standard deviation of , evaluated at a threshold of zero. Likewise, the probability of choosing option 2 is</p><p>(1 − ) • Φ − , (0); and the probability of continuing to sample is . We allow for flexible . Intuitively, these models propose that choice is made immediately after all pieces of information have been sampled, and that this choice depends on utilities plus noise being greater or less than zero. With some error, the decision maker terminates choice without sampling all information, in which case they choose randomly (uniformly) between the options. There is also some chance that the decision maker erroneously continues sampling after all pieces of information has been sampled. There are a total of four Additive Utility variants, corresponding to variants of the WAD, EW, WP and TAL heuristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dynamic Lexicographic Choice</head><p>Our Dynamic LEX model assumes that utility is based on the values of a single attributes. If the most recent transition was within an attribute, then is the attribute value for option 1 minus the attribute value for option 2. The probability of choosing option 1 is (1 − ) • (1 − Φ , (0)); the probability of choosing option 2 is (1 − ) • (1 − Φ − , (0)); the probability of continuing to sample is . If the most recent transition was not with an attribute, then = 0. the probability of choosing each option is . 5 • and the probability of continuing sampling is 1 − . Intuitively, Dynamic LEX assumes that choice is made immediately after a within-attribute sample, and that this choice depends on attribute values plus noise being greater or less than zero. With some error, the decision maker terminates choice after a betweenattribute sample, in which case they choose randomly (uniformly) between the options. There is also some chance that the decision maker erroneously continues sampling after making a within-attribute transition.</p><p>The Dynamic Lexicographic Semiorder model adapts the Dynamic Lexicographic model by adding two additional threshold parameters, one for each attribute. If the most recent transition was within attribute 1, then the probability of choosing option 1 is (1 − ) • (1 − Φ , ( 1 )), where 1 is the attribute 1 threshold parameter and is the difference in attribute 1 values. The probability of choosing option 2 is the same as above, but with substituted with − . The probability of continuing to sample is . If the most recent transition was within attribute 2, the probability of choosing option 1 is (1 − ) •</p><p>(1 − Φ , ( 2 )), where 2 is the attribute 2 threshold parameter and is the difference in attribute 2 values. The probability of choosing option 2 once again reverses the sign of , and the probability of continuing to sample is . If the most recent transition was not with an attribute, the probability of choosing each option is . 5 • and the probability of continuing sampling is 1 − .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additive Utility Accumulators</head><p>Additive Utility Single Accumulator variants combine the assumptions of the Additive Utility variants and the Single Attentional Accumulator variants. Specifically, they assume that information is converted to utility via a weighted additive rule: e.g., = 1 1 + 2 2 in the case of the WAD Single Accumulator models or a simplification of this rule in the case of the EW, TAL or WP models .</p><p>These models further assume that accumulation continues after all four pieces of information have been sampled. That is, for each subsequent fixation both 1 and 2 are incremented by their respective 1 and 2 respectively. Note that this structure does not make the attentional assumption: utility accumulation is the same no matter where attention is placed. As with the Additive Utility variants, the Additive Utility Single Accumulator variants assume that before fixating on all four pieces of information, search termination probabilities are given by the error probability , and that if search terminates prematurely, the decision maker chooses each option with a 50% probability. After all four pieces of information have been sampled, the models make similar assumptions about choice as the Single Attentional Accumulators:</p><p>e.g., the probability of choosing option 1 is 1 − Φ , ( ), with σ = 1. There are a total of 8 distinct </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attention Model</head><p>The attention model determines the probability that each piece of information is sampled, based on the items that were sampled previously. Formally, this is done by calculating an activation value for each piece of information, and passing that activation value through a soft-max function. Thus, at time t, the probability that a piece of information, , will be fixated on is: information. If item i has not been sampled previously in the trial we have Nt = 1. Otherwise we have Nt = 0. Finally, βPV captures the effect of the previously sampled attribute value. If the participant just sampled from the same option as i, then PVt is the value of the attribute that was sampled; otherwise PVt is one minus the value of the attribute that was sampled (recall that attribute values are scaled such that the largest value of an attribute in the dataset is given a 1 and the smallest value is given a 0).</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">, = exp( , ) ∑ exp( , )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Fitting Procedure</head><p>To fit our models to individual-level data we use the optimize-minimize function from the scipy Python library to minimize the Negative Log Likelihood of the model using the Nelder-Mead algorithm.</p><p>We fit the models 200 times with different, randomly drawn starting parameters. All models converge, e.g., multiple model fits find a practically equivalent minima with practically equivalent parameter values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Details of Datasets</head><p>In the Amasino dataset, 190 participants made 141 intertemporal choices between a smaller amount of money-ranging from $0.25 to $10 in increments of $0.25-available that day and $10 available 1, 7, 15, 30, 90, 180 or 365 days later. We combined data from the main study-where the choice options were displayed on the left and right sides of the screen, the amount at the top and time at the bottom-and the replication study, which systematically varied the position of choice information. A</p><p>keyboard press recorded choices. Responses longer than 10s were removed. The choices were incentivecompatible: people received the money from their chosen option for one trial at the specified delay.</p><p>In the Zhou dataset, 60 participants made 100 intertemporal choices with monetary amounts ranging between 120-990 Yuan and delayed between 11 and 99 days. There were 50 pairs of options, and each participant made two choices on each pair. Participants also completed a bidding task that measured participants' valuation of select intertemporal options; we do not analyze this task. The task order, bid or choice, and placement of amount and time were counterbalanced across participants. The choices were incentive-compatible: people received the money from their chosen option for one trial at a delay.</p><p>In the Stewart dataset, 48 participants made 71 choices between a low -risk-low-reward option and a high-risk-high-reward option. The probabilities of the options varied between 10% and 100%, and the payouts ranged from 100 Pounds to 500 Pounds. The location of probability and amount-top or bottom-and the alignment of options-horizontal or vertical-were counterbalanced across participants.</p><p>In the Glickman dataset, 31 participants made 94 choices between a low -risk-low-reward option and a high-risk-high-reward option. The amounts varied between 3 and 30 Israeli Shekels, and the probabilities varied between 10% and 100%. Probabilities were presented as the lower sectors of pie charts; monetary amounts were presented as divided bar graphs. The location of probability and amount-top or bottom-and the alignment of options-horizontal or vertical-were counterbalanced across participants.</p><p>In the Westbrook dataset, as part of a more extensive neuroimaging study, 47 participants made choices between exerting differing amounts of effort, e.g., varying difficulty N-back tasks, for varying amounts of money. The offers were tailored to everyone's indifference point for exerting effort and were designed to have varying degrees of difficulty. Participants made these choices after receiving a placebo and a stimulant; we only use placebo trials. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> in the main text describes the data for the five studies. For the intertemporal choice studies-Amasino and Zhou-we present the percentage of Smaller-sooner choices; for the risky choice studies-Stewart and Glickman-we present the percentage of low-risk-low-reward choices; for the effort allocation study-Westbrook-we present the percentage of low-effort-low-reward choices.</p><p>Participants chose both options equally often for the risky choice studies and the effort allocation study.</p><p>In the Amasino data, however, participants were far more likely to choose the larger-later option, likely because the stimuli included stimuli that would require extreme discounting to choose the smaller-sooner: e.g., 50 cents today versus $10 in 1 day.</p><p>Participants spent, on average, between 1.11 and 3.02 seconds fixating and made between 6.62 and 13.46 fixations per trial. Note that the Zhou data has more fixations per trial than the other datasets.</p><p>This pattern may be due to different cultural contexts. The datasets were collected in various cultures:  <ref type="table">Table A2</ref>. Proportion of participants best fit by a given model in each dataset. Rank indicates the rank of the average proportion across datasets (lower ranks are better). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Formally</head><label></label><figDesc>, we define context, , as the information already sampled by a participant at time, , where takes on discrete values starting at 0 and incrementing each time the participant fixates on a piece of information. In the example from Figure 1B, C evolves as follows: 0 = [ ], 1 = [TopLeft = 1€], 2 = [TopLeft = 1€,TopRight = 3€], … , 6 = [TopLeft = 1€,TopRight = 3€,… BotRight = 3back].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, the magnitude of the difference on attributes has a positive empirical relationship with choice probability. 3 This is consistent with the Dynamic WAD, WAD Accumulator, EW Attentional Dual Accumulator, WAD Attentional Accumulator, and Attentional Accumulator models, and inconsistent with the Dynamic Lex and WP Attentional Dual Accumulator models (Spearman's Rho's are presented for each attribute in Figure 3). The slope of the attribute differences also varies across attributes. This is inconsistent with the EW Attentional Dual Accumulator. For these reasons, the Dynamic WAD, WAD Accumulator, WAD Attentional Accumulator, and Attentional Accumulator models, fit to individual-level data 4 , are generally able to reproduce the empirical patterns in Figure 3, whereas the Dynamic Lex, WP Attentional Dual Accumulator and EW Attentional Dual Accumulator cannot.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 9</head><label>9</label><figDesc>presents a histogram plot of the mean participant-level AICs for all 63 decision models; the exemplar decision models are shown with vertical lines. As can be seen in this figure, the exemplar models perform consistently across datasets. The Dynamic LEX and Dynamic WAD models are always either the worst or second worst fitting exemplar models. The Attentional Accumulator and the EW Dual Attentional Accumulator models are, respectively, always the third and fourth worst fitting exemplar models. Of the three best fitting exemplar models, the WAD Accumulator and WP Dual Attentional</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A) Example stimuli from the five studies. The smaller-sooner/low-risk-low-reward/and loweffort-low-reward choices are on the left, and monetary rewards are on the top. For the Glickman stimuli, the light bars indicate the number of Shekels, with 30 being the entire bar. The light portion of the pie chart indicates the probability of receiving the corresponding number of Shekels. For the Westbrook stimuli, the bottom row indicates the task's difficulty measured by N-back load (higher loads require more cognitive effort to complete). B) Example of an effort allocation trial involving six fixations and a choice for a high-effort-high-reward option. The top row of panels displays the empirical data we observe: the darkened piece of information is what the participant sampled, the circle in the final panel indicates the chosen option. The second row of panels displays the predictions of the decision model: darker colors indicate a higher prediction for an action: KeepSamp = keep sampling; Opt1 = Choice of Option 1 (Left side); Opt2 = Choice of Option 2. The third row of panels displays the predictions of the attention model: darker colors indicate a higher predicted likelihood for fixating on that piece of information, and the position of the boxes corresponds to the position of the information in the top panel.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Schematic of utility accumulation for four exemplar decision models. The x-axis represents the number of samples and the y-axis represents the accumulated utility for option 1 relative to option 2 after the sample at each point in time. The sequence of fixations underlying utility accumulation is taken fromFigure 1B(top panel).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Relationship between choice and differences in attribute values. Option 1 is the low-risk-lowreward option in the Stewart and Glickman data, the smaller-sooner option in theAmasino and Zhou  data, and the low-effort-low-reward option in the Westbrook data.  </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Relationship between choice and the relative attention towards option 1, measured as the number of fixations on option 1 minus the number of fixations on option 2, binned into equally sized deciles on the fixation level. Option 1 is the low-risk-low-reward option in the Stewart and Glickman data, the smaller-sooner option in the Amasino and Zhou data, and the low-effort-low-reward option in the Westbrook data. Lines indicate linear regressions where attention decile is regressed on p(Choose 1).For the empirical data, p(Choose 1) is the empirical proportion of option 1 choices; for the decision models, p(Choose 1) is the best-fit model's predicted probability of choosing option 1. Points indicate the empirical probability of choosing option 1 at each decile of relative attention. (Note: The empirical points are the same size as each decile has the same number of observations). r values indicate the Spearman's correlation between attention decile and the probability of choosing option 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5. The decision to continue sampling for each study. The x-axis indicates the sample number and the y-axis denotes the probability of continuing to sample after the corresponding sample number. For the empirical data, this is the observed probability that participants continued sampling, and, for the decision models, it is the best-fit model's predicted probability of continuing to sample. The model lines correspond to the average (prediction or observation) over all participants. For empirical data, the size of the points corresponds to the proportion of the dataset with that number of samples. r values indicate the Spearman's correlation between sample number and the probability of continuing to sample.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Heatmap of empirical and predicted transition probabilities from the piece of information on the y-axis to the piece of information on the x-axis. Cells are labeled ij with i indexing the option number and j indexing the attribute number, e.g., the top row indicates the number of transitions from the option 1 attribute 1 piece of information back to itself, to option 1 attribute 2, to option 2 attribute 1, and option 2 attribute 2. Option 1 is the low-risk-low-reward, smaller-sooner or low-effort-low-reward option. Attribute 1 is money, and attribute 2 is probability, delay or effort.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Probability of transitioning to a novel piece of information, a within-attribute piece of information, and a within-option piece of information for empirical data and as predicted by the attention model. Solid lines are empirical data, and dotted lines are model predictions; black lines capture the proportion of transitions to novel information, orange to within-attribute information, and blue to withinoption information. Point size for the empirical sample corresponds to the proportion of dataset at each sample.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Histogram of the mean of participant-level AICs for each of the 63 decision models. The mean AICs of the exemplar decision models are represented by colored vertical lines.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>number of samples made. The Attentional Accumulator model assumes that utility is accumulated immediately after the first fixation, and thus predicts that people can terminate search before all pieces of information have been sampled. By contrast, the Dynamic WAD, WAD Accumulator, WAD Attentional Accumulator, EW Attentional Dual Accumulator, WP Attentional Dual Accumulator models assume that utility accumulation begins only after all pieces of information have been sampled, and thus predict that people should be unlikely to terminate search before sampling all pieces of information. As for accumulation-termination, the Dynamic WAD model predicts that people should be highly likely to stop sampling as soon as all pieces of information have been sampled. This is sooner than what is typically predicted by the WAD Accumulator, WAD Attentional Accumulator, EW Attentional Dual Accumulator,</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 :Table 3 .</head><label>23</label><figDesc>Descriptive statistics for the five eye-tracking studies. # Fixations indicates the average number of fixations per trial, with standard errors in parentheses. The % Choice row indicates the percentage oflow-risk-low-reward, smaller-sooner, or low-effort-low-reward choices. Spearman correlations of model performance across datasets. For decision models, we examine correlations of mean AIC ranks for N = 63 models for each pair of datasets. For the attention model, we examine correlations of N = 8 median participant-level parameter values for each pair of datasets.Table 4. Comparison of models that differ only on a single assumption. Numbers represent the proportion of individual-level models with the assumption on the left that outperformed (according to AIC) equivalent models with the assumption on the right. For example, the top left cell, which shows a value of 0.9, indicates that decision models with flexible weights outperformed equivalent models with equal weights for 90% of participants in the Stewart data. The final column shows the average value across datasets.Table 5. Summary of attention model fits. Positive parameter values indicate a tendency to make withinoption and within-attribute transitions, a tendency not to resample an item immediately after attending to it, a tendency to search for novel information, and a tendency to sample from options that have previously revealed high attribute values. is simply one minus the summed probability of choosing option 1 and option 2. We allow for to be a flexible parameter and set = 1.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Stewart</cell><cell>Glickman</cell><cell>Amasino</cell><cell>Zhou</cell><cell>Westbrook</cell></row><row><cell>Domain</cell><cell>Risk</cell><cell>Risk</cell><cell>Intertemporal</cell><cell>Intertemporal</cell><cell>Effort</cell></row><row><cell># Subj.</cell><cell>48</cell><cell>31</cell><cell>190</cell><cell>60</cell><cell>47</cell></row><row><cell># Trials</cell><cell>70</cell><cell>94</cell><cell>141</cell><cell>99</cell><cell>168</cell></row><row><cell># Fixations</cell><cell>7.17 (0.06)</cell><cell>9.06 (0.07)</cell><cell>6.62 (0.02)</cell><cell>13.46 (0.12)</cell><cell>6.28 (0.27)</cell></row><row><cell>% Choice</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>78</cell><cell>44</cell></row></table><note>Dual Attentional Accumulator models similar assumptions as Single Attentional Accumulator</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Additive Utility Single Accumulator variants ({WAD, EW, WP, TAL}x{decay, no decay}). In the main text, the WAD Accumulator model is an Additive Utility Accumulator variant that assumes a weighted additive utility function with decay.The Additive Utility Dual Accumulator variants make similar assumptions as the Additive Utility Accumulator variants, except that utilities are coded in separate accumulators. There are a total of 12 distinct Additive Utility Dual Accumulator variants ({WAD, EW, WP, TAL}x{decay and inhibition, decay without inhibition, no decay and no inhibition}).The Additive Utility Attentional Accumulators are identical to the Additive Utility Accumulators, except that for fixations after all four pieces of information have been accumulated, utility is only accumulated for the fixated option, e.g., if someone fixates on option 1 then 1 is incremented by 1 but Attentional Accumulators into two families based on their assumptions about utility decay. The dual decay variants assume that decay happens for both 's; that is, if someone fixates on option 1 then 1 = Additive Utility Dual Attentional Accumulator variants ({WAD, EW, WP, TAL}x{decay and inhibition, decay without inhibition}) with single decay, 8 distinct Additive Utility Dual Attentional Accumulator variants with dual decay, and 4 distinct Additive Utility Dual Attentional Accumulator without decay. In the main text, the WAD Attentional Accumulator model is an Additive Utility Single Attentional Accumulator variant that assumes a weighted additive utility function, a single accumulator, and that utility decays for both options. The WP Dual Attentional Accumulator model is an Additive Utility Dual Attentional Accumulator variant that assumes a weighted pros utility function, dual accumulators with inhibition, and that utility decays for both options. The EW Dual Attentional Accumulator model is an Additive Utility Dual Attentional Accumulator variant that assumes an equal weighting utility function, dual accumulators with inhibition, and that utility decays for both options.</figDesc><table><row><cell>• −1 1</cell><cell cols="2">+ 1 and 2 = • −1 2 . The single decay variants assume that decay only happens for the</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">fixated option; that is, if someone fixates on option 1 then 1 = • −1 1</cell><cell>+ 1 but 2 = −1 2 .</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Again, we allow for versions of these models with single and dual accumulators. Thus, there are a</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">total of 4 distinct Additive Utility Single Attentional Accumulator variants with single decay (variants with</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">the WAD, EW, WP, TAL utility functions); 4 distinct Additive Utility Single Attentional Accumulator</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">variants with dual decay, 4 distinct Additive Utility Single Attentional Accumulator variants with no</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">decay; 8 distinct</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Additive Utility Attentional Accumulators</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Here Ij are indicator variables indexing each unique piece of information, so that we have Ij = 1 if j = i, and zero otherwise. αj subsequently capture baseline biases (i.e. fixed effects) for each of the four pieces of information. βWO captures the tendency to make within-option transitions. If the information sample at t -1 was from the same option as i¸ we have WOt = 1. Otherwise, we have WOt = 0. βWA captures the tendency to make within-attribute transitions. If the prior information sample was from the same attribute as i¸ we have WAt = 1. Otherwise, we have WAt = 0. βWI captures the tendency not to transition back to the item that was sampled previously. If the prior information sample was the same as i¸ we have WIt = 0. Otherwise, we have WIt = 1. βN captures the tendency to sample novel pieces of</figDesc><table /><note>with, = α1•I1 + α2•I2 + α3•I3 + α4•I4 + βWO •WOt + βWA•WAt + βWI•WIt + βN•Nt + βPV•PVt</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Zhou in China, Glickman in Israel, Stewart in the UK, Amasino in the US, and Westbrook in the Netherlands. This divergent cultural context means that the default reading order may differ across datasets making information location-top left, bottom left, top right, bottom right-an incomparable proxy for attention across datasets.</figDesc><table><row><cell>WP Dual Decay</cell><cell>478</cell><cell>550</cell><cell>766</cell><cell>696</cell><cell>913</cell><cell>680</cell><cell>16</cell></row><row><cell>WP No Decay</cell><cell>526</cell><cell>610</cell><cell>879</cell><cell>1303</cell><cell>953</cell><cell>854</cell><cell>45</cell></row><row><cell>EW Single Decay</cell><cell>476</cell><cell>541</cell><cell>772</cell><cell>705</cell><cell>987</cell><cell>696</cell><cell>24</cell></row><row><cell>EW Dual Decay</cell><cell>578</cell><cell>629</cell><cell>842</cell><cell>853</cell><cell>1012</cell><cell>783</cell><cell>42</cell></row><row><cell>EW No Decay</cell><cell>1047</cell><cell>930</cell><cell>1755</cell><cell>2366</cell><cell>1486</cell><cell>1517</cell><cell>60</cell></row><row><cell>T al Single Decay</cell><cell>458</cell><cell>565</cell><cell>808</cell><cell>748</cell><cell>941</cell><cell>704</cell><cell>31</cell></row><row><cell>T al Dual Decay</cell><cell>606</cell><cell>598</cell><cell>938</cell><cell>852</cell><cell>1109</cell><cell>821</cell><cell>43</cell></row><row><cell>T al No Decay</cell><cell>792</cell><cell>905</cell><cell>1234</cell><cell>2298</cell><cell>1193</cell><cell>1285</cell><cell>50</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Additive Utility Dual Attentional Accumulator</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>WAD Single Decay and Inhib.</cell><cell>434</cell><cell>522</cell><cell>761</cell><cell>684</cell><cell>909</cell><cell>662</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>WAD Single Decay and No Inhib.</cell><cell>437</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">In the N-back task, participants are presented with a sequence of numbers and are asked to list the N th previous number. Higher Ns require increased cognitive effort, as participants must keep track of a larger set of numbers (see<ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Jaeggi et al., 2010</ref> for an overview).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">The notable exceptions are the attribute 1 values for the Stewart data. This may be because there were only three possible attribute 1 differences in the data. Additionally, there was a high correlation between a choice's attribute 1 and attribute 2 values (Pearson's r = -.81, p &lt; .001).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">The notable exception to this trend is the Stewart data: while the correlation between attention and choice is high, the slope of the relationship is shallow.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">Other work has shown that the prevalence of within-option and within-attribute transitions changes over time<ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Shi et al., 2013)</ref>. This discrepancy may be due to differences in choice complexity: our stimuli had two attributes, Shi and colleague's stimuli had 12.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">The within-study correlations inFigure 8are equivalent because the previous-value for one option is one minus the previous-value of the other option, and, intuitively, the proportion of fixations on one option is one minus the number of fixations on the other option.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">is not incremented at all. In this way, utility depends on attention. We split the Additive Utility</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decision Models</head><p>In what follows, we formally specify all 63 decision models as well as the general attentional model. Note that in order to make fits comparable across attributes and datasets, we normalize all attribute values based on the maximum and minimum values for the attribute in the corresponding dataset. In particular, the attribute value for attribute j in option i, , used in our analysis, is obtained using the following equation:</p><p>. Here is the raw value of attribute j in option i, and maxj and minj are the maximum and minimum values of attribute j in the full dataset. In this way all attribute values range from 0 (for the worst in the dataset) to 1 (for the best). We reversed code negative attributes (delay and effort) so that higher values on all attributes are more desirable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attentional Accumulators</head><p>We begin with the Single Attentional Accumulator No Decay model. In this model, the accumulated utility for option at time t, , is the sum of the previously accumulated utility, −1 , and the utility acquired for option at time , , that is, = −1 + . is equal to the weighted value of the fixated attribute if the fixation was in option and 0 otherwise. For attribute j in option i, this weighted value is • , where is the weight placed on attribute j and is the normalized value of attribute j for option (attribute weights are constrained so that 2 = 1 − 1 ). This model assumes that the utility difference between the two options is stored in a single accumulator. At time t, the value of this accumulator variable is = 1 − 2 . At t = 0, we have = 0 1 = 0 2 = 0. The accumulated difference in utility is transformed into probabilities via the cumulative standard normal distribution.</p><p>Specifically, the probability of choosing option 1 at time, , is given by 1 − Φ , ( ), where Φ is the cumulative normal distribution with mean and a standard deviation of , evaluated at a threshold, .</p><p>Intuitively, this is the probability that plus noise, crosses the threshold . In the same way, the probability of choosing option 2 is given by 1 − Φ , (− ) = 1 − − , ( ). The probability of </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Amount and time exert independent influences on intertemporal choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Amasino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kranton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Huettel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-019-0537-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0537-2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value-driven attentional capture</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Laurent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yantis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10367" to="10371" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding the right fit: A comparison of process assumptions underlying popular drift-diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J S</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jekel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dickert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1982" to="1993" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Associations and the Accumulation of Preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0032457</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0032457" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="522" to="543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequential sampling and paradoxes of risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-014-0650-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-014-0650-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1095" to="1111" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Choice rules and accumulator networks. Decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dec0000038</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/dec0000038" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="170" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The simplest complete model of choice response time: Linear ballistic accumulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive and Neural Bases of Multi-Attribute, Multi-Alternative, Value-based Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2018.12.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2018.12.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision Field Theory: A Dynamic -Cognitive Approach to Decision Making in an Uncertain Environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PSYCHOLOGICAL REVIEW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fixation patterns in simple choice reflect optimal information sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Callaway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1008863</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1008863" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions in changingconditions: The urgency-gating model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cisek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Puskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>El-Murr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11560" to="11571" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A probabilistic, dynamic, and attribute-wise model of intertemporal choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">143</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1489" to="1514" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0035976</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0035976" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The robust beauty of improper linear models in decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dawes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0003-066X.34.7.571</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.34.7.571" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="571" to="582" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for time-variant decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ditterich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">EuropeanJournal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3628" to="3641" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Accumulation is late and brief in preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E R</forename><surname>Edmunds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mullett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Psyarxiv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/sa4zr</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/sa4zr" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Dynamics of Decision Making in Risky Choice: An Eye-Tracking Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fiedler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00335</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00335" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexicographic Orders, Utilities and Decision Rules: A Survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Fishburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.20.11.1442</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.20.11.1442" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1442" to="1471" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An attentional drift diffusion model over binary-attribute choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2017.06.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2017.06.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">168</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Multiattribute Attentional Drift Diffusion Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">165</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="182" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Time Discounting and Preference: A Critical Time Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Frederick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Donoghue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E D O</forename><surname>Donoghue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="401" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extrapolative Beliefs in Perceptual and Economic Decisions: Evidence of a Common Mechanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Frydman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nave</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2340" to="2352" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.2016.2453</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2016.2453" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Simple heuristics that make us smart</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Todd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Abc Research</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Group</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The formation of preference in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Sharoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Niebur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Stuphorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007201</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007201" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling option and strategy choices with connectionist networks: Towards an integrative model of automatic and deliberate decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Betsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="228" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value-based attention but not divisive normalization influences decisions with multiple alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kortmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Vitali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-020-0822-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-0822-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="634" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conjoint analysis in consumer research: issues and outlook</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Wisdom of Model Crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Analytis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.2021.4090</idno>
		<idno>mnsc.2021.4090</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2021.4090" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An ontology of decision models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000231</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000231" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bidirectional reasoning in decision making by constraint satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holyoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0096-3445.128.1.3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0096-3445.128.1.3" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nontransitive multidimensional preferences: Theoretical analysis of a model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF00126336</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00126336" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theory and Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="165" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual attention in consumer settings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hutchinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Weingarten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Routledge International Handbook of Consumer Psychology</title>
		<editor>C. V. Jansson-Boyd &amp; M. J. Zawisza</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge/Taylor&amp;Francis Group. Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The concurrent validity of the N -back task as a working memory measure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Jaeggi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Buschkuehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Perrig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="394" to="412" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/09658211003702171</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/09658211003702171" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new and unique predic tion for cue-search in a parallelconstraint satisfaction network model: The attraction search effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jekel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bröder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000107</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000107" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="744" to="768" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Keeney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Raiffa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Decisions with Multiple Objectives: Preferences and Value Tradeoffs</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Revised edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling choice paradoxes under risk: From prospect theories to sampling-based accounts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Steiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Davis-Stober</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Pappas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2019.101258</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2019.101258" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual fixations and the computation and comparison of value in simple choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.2635</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2635" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1298" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative drift-diffusion model predicts the relationship between visual fixations and choice in value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1101328108</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1101328108" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13852" to="13857" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The More You Ask, the Less You Get: When Additional Questions Hurt External Validity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Krefeld-Schwalb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Wall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Toubia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bartels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/00222437211073581</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/00222437211073581" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye-Tracking Reveals Processes that Enable Conjoint Choices to Become Increasingly Efficient with Practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Meißner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Musalem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>Forthcoming</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time to pay attention to attention: Using attention-based process traces to better understand consumer decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mormann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Janiszewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aribarg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J S</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bagchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kovacheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Meissner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mrkva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11002-020-09520-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11002-020-09520-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does Attention Increase the Value of Choice Alternatives?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mormann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2021.01.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2021.01.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implications of visual attention phenomena for models of preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mullett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dec0000049</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/dec0000049" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="253" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceptual but not complex moral judgments can be biased by exploiting the dynamics of eye-gaze</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Le Pelley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xge0000386</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0000386" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="417" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative decision by sampling: A model of decision making constrained by process data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Noguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="512" to="544" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000102</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000102" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention and choice: A review on eye movements in decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Orquin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Loose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.actpsy.2013.06.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2013.06.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">144</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="190" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contributions to attention based marketing: Foundations, insights, and challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Orquin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jbusres.2020.02.012</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbusres.2020.02.012" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive Strategy Selection in Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bettman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="534" to="552" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0278-7393.14.3.534</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-7393.14.3.534" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Comparison of Sequential Sampling Models for Two-Choice Reaction Time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.111.2.333</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.111.2.333" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="367" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion Decision Model: Current Issues and History</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2016.01.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2016.01.007" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Search predicts and changes patience in intertemporal choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Reeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11890" to="11895" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative decision field theory: A dynamic connectionst model of decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Roe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="370" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037//0033-295X.108.2.370</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//0033-295X.108.2.370" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye fixations as a process trace</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A handbook of process tracing methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategies for multiattribute binary choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Dosher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">676</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Eye-Fixation Analysis of Choice Processes for Consumer Nondurables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Leclerc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1086/209397</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1086/209397" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An eye fixation analysis of multialternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Russo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rosen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="276" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Visual attention modulates the integration of goal-relevant evidence and not value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sepulveda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Benson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ortoleva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Martino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.60705</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.60705" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<pubPlace>ELife, 9</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heuristics Made Easy: An Effort-Reduction Framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Oppenheimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-2909.134.2.207</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.134.2.207" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="222" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information Acquisition During Online Decision Making: A Model-Based Exploration Using Eye-Tracking Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">G M</forename><surname>Pieters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.1120.1625</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.1120.1625" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1009" to="1026" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Rik</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaze bias both reflects and influences preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shimojo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Simion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shimojo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Scheier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1317" to="1322" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Construction of preferences by constraint satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Krawczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holyoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="331" to="336" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye Movements in Risky Choice: Eye Movements in Risky Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hermens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.1854</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.1854" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simultaneous modeling of visual saliency and value computation improves predictions of economic choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Towal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mormann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1304429110</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1304429110" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3858" to="3867" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nudge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The multiattribute linear ballistic accumulator model of context effects in multialternative choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0036137</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0036137" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="205" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Salience driven value integration explains decision biases and preference reversal</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1119569109</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1119569109" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9659" to="9664" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competing theories of multialternative, multiattribute preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Schley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="362" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000089</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000089" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intransitivity of preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0026750</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0026750" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The time course of perceptual choice: The leaky, competing accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.108.3.550</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.108.3.550" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="550" to="592" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loss Aversion and Inhibition in Dynamical Models of Multialternative Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.111.3.757</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.111.3.757" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="757" to="769" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mindful judgment and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev.psych.60.110707.163633</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.60.110707.163633" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dopamine promotes cognitive effort by biasing the benefits versus costs of cognitive work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Westbrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Van Den Bosch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Määttä</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hofmans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Papadopetraki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cools</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.aaz5891</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaz5891" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6484</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1362" to="1366" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic computational model of gaze and choice in multi-attribute decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000350</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000350" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational mechanisms for context-based behavioral interventions: A large-scale analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Coady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2114914119</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2114914119" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Process and content in decisions from memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Richie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000318</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000318" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual attention and time preference reversals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y.-B</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H. -Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">29</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">EW No Decay and No Inhib</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1043" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">919</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">No</forename><surname>Decay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">No</forename><surname>Inhib</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">779</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="945" to="1445" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
