<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">More than two intuitions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Grüning</surname></persName>
							<email>david.gruening@psychologie.uni-heidelberg.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Psychology Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Survey Design and Methodology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Heidelberg University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">GESIS -Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences Joachim I. Krueger Cognitive, Linguistic &amp; Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Brown University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Psychology Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Heidelberg University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Hauptstraße 47</addrLine>
									<postCode>69117</postCode>
									<settlement>Heidelberg</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">More than two intuitions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X2200142X</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:55+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We consider an underdeveloped feature of De Neys&apos;s model. Decisions with multiple intuitions per option are neither trivial to explain nor rare. These decision scenarios are crucial for an assessment of the model&apos;s generalizability and adequacy. Besides monitoring absolute differences in intuition strength, the mind might add the strengths of intuitions per choice option, leading to competing and testable hypotheses.!</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The first stage of De Neys's model, the processing of intuitions, requires elaboration. We here respond to two of the author's key assumptions. The first assumption is that "the uncertainty parameter might focus on the absolute difference" (p. 44) between the strongest competing intuitions. The second assumption is that decision-making scenarios with more than two intuitions are "a-typical cases" (p. 45). As to the former assumption, we show, by example, that there are several different ways in which decision-makers might process more than two competing intuitions.</p><p>As to the latter assumption, we argue that having multiple intuitions can be considered the norm rather than an anomaly. For simplicity, we will only consider decisions with two choice options. Extending the author's (p. 31) example, suppose John has to choose between a cupcake and an apple for dessert. While John's first intuition (I1) favors the cupcake for its sweet taste, two other intuitions come to mind. The second intuition (I2) is the realization that an apple is tasty too, and the third intuition (I3) is that the apple is healthier than the cupcake. Like De Neys, we assume that these intuitions differ in strength.</p><p>Although the cupcake is tastier (with a weight of .80) than the apple (.60), the apple's healthiness is also noteworthy (.50). We can now imagine two pathways for the intuitive response. In one pathway, the strongest intuition, I1 wins, and John decides to eat the cupcake. This is the outcome De Neys's model predicts from the monitoring of the absolute difference between the strongest competing intuitions. In the other pathway, the combined strengths of intuitions I2 and I3 override the strength of I1; John eats the apple because its acceptable tastiness and evident health benefit together trump the allure of the cupcake's sweetness <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Anderson, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Juslin et al., 2008)</ref>.</p><p>Limited comparisons between the strengths of the strongest intuitions become less compelling as the number of intuitions favoring consumption of the apple grows, even if each additional intuition is weak. De Neys's process assumption neglects the possibility that separate but weak intuitions may amount to a strong incentive for choice. Here, the absolute difference between the two strongest intuitions has not changed as medium tastiness remains the primary intuition favoring the apple. By contrast, it is even conceivable that the absolute difference between cupcake and apple increases because the average intuition strength in favor of the apple decreases with each weak additional intuition in favor of it. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows both possibilities of absolute difference and also the simple additive processing. We recognize De Neys's call for research on cases with more than two competing intuitions, but we disagree with his emphasis. Research on cue utilization and information integration (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Candolin, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr">Cooksey, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gunes et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Grüning et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Plessner et al., 2009)</ref> shows that multiple intuitions are the norm in decision-making. Whereas novel situations may end in deliberation because intuitions are missing, familiar situations offer a rich range of different cues (e.g., color, availability, smell, and nutrition value) supporting the rise of multiple intuitions in the decision-maker's mind. Accordingly, we regard the question of how decision-makers process multiple competing intuitions to be pressing, especially for cases where individuals have learned new features of choice objects (e.g., that an apple also provides more energy than a cupcake and it requires less energy to be produced). Naturally, many familiar decision-making situations will be dominated by a few very strong intuitions per option. However, for these situations, too, our example above necessitates thinking about how more than two competing intuitions are consolidated. At the limit, we argue, the presence of many weak intuitions in favor of option B can overcome a single strong intuition favoring the alternative option A.</p><p>Conceptualizing decision-makers' multiple-intuitions processing as an act of adding instead of monitoring absolute difference changes the predictions about whether thoughtful reflection will occur. The view that individuals compare their strongest intuitions by assessing the absolute difference yields a clear prediction regarding the onset of deliberation: If the two strongest competing intuitions are close enough, the resulting feeling of indifference triggers the need for deliberate thinking. Adding a large number of weak intuitions to one option (i.e., the apple) should not change the outcome. Assuming additive processing, however, decision-makers with added weak intuitions in favor of the apple should come to a point of indifference about choosing the apple or the cupcake; exactly when the strong intuition about the cupcake's tastiness is matched by the composite of the apple's lower tastiness and the additional intuitions favoring it. Again, our main argument is not that addition is the more probable basic element behind intuition processing. This has to be tested. We suggest that thinking about how multiple intuitions are processed is central to predicting not only which intuitive decisions are made but also when deliberation occurs. How decision-makers process their multiple intuitions is the fundamental predictive mechanism of De Neys's model and understanding it is a key challenge for his theory.</p><p>In conclusion, we welcome De Neys presenting an intriguing and novel model of decision-making.</p><p>Nevertheless, we think that one central aspect of the model, namely how decision-makers process multiple intuitions, requires more attention. Theoretical and empirical advancements in understanding this process are possible and would move De Neys's model closer to a general theory of decision-making.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Different processing styles of multiple intuitions in competing optionsThis multiple-intuitions example is one of many non-trivial cases where individuals process multiple intuitions for competing options. At this early stage of model-building, purely theoretical exploration and thought experiments are a productive beginning. Yet, experiments and empirical research are needed to determine the conditions allowing the rise of multiple intuitions and to understand how people process them. A first step could be to test competing hypotheses about how decision-makers consolidate multiple intuitions (e.g., absolute difference vs. addition) by presenting</figDesc><table><row><cell>Intuitions</cell><cell>Cupcake</cell><cell>Apple</cell></row><row><cell>Intuition 1</cell><cell>.80</cell><cell>.60</cell></row><row><cell>Intuition 2</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>.50</cell></row><row><cell>Intuition 3</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>.10</cell></row><row><cell>Intuition 4</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>.10</cell></row><row><cell>Intuition 5</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>.10</cell></row><row><cell>Difference between strongest competing intuitions</cell><cell>.80</cell><cell>.60</cell></row><row><cell>Difference between means of competing groups of intuitions</cell><cell>.80</cell><cell>.28</cell></row><row><cell>Simple addition of intuitions</cell><cell>.80</cell><cell>1.40</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing interest statement</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Funding statement</head><p>This research received no specific grant from any funding agency, commercial or not-for-profit sectors.!</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Foundations of information integration theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The use of multiple cues in mate choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Candolin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1464793103006158</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1464793103006158" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="595" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advancing theorizing about fast-and-slow thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>De Neys</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>forthcoming)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reversing the cumulative redundancy bias to demonstrate metacognitive flexibility in cue utilization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Grüning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Alves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">O P</forename><surname>Mata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Fiedler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/6gbca</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/6gbca" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From the lab to the real world: Affect recognition using multiple cues and modalities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gunes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Piccardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pantic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Affective Computing. IntechOpen</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information integration in multiple cue judgment: A division of labor hypothesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Juslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Karlsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Olsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2007.02.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2007.02.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="298" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multiple-cue learning approach as the basis for understanding and improving soccer referees&apos; decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Plessner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Schweizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Brand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0079-6123(09)01313-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0079-6123(09)01313-2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Progress in Brain Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">174</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="158" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
