<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Measure Reinforcement: Emergent Causality From Quantum Interactions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2025-04">April 2025</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><forename type="middle">Mahdi</forename><surname>Mirrashid</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Measure Reinforcement: Emergent Causality From Quantum Interactions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2025-04">April 2025</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T12:58+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We introduce Measure Reinforcement (MR), a computational framework for modeling quantum cognition and inference in a unified quantum mechanical framework. This framework bridges quantum cognition and emergent causality, modeling neural learning (STDP) within the relational interpretation of quantum mechanics where causality emerges from interactions. We model quantum cognition as a learning process where asymmetric entanglement-driven updates lead to the emergence of causal asymmetric neural patterns of activities. These updates are valid under quantum mechanics and resemble Hebbian learning. Classical causal graphs arise only when interpreted from the perspective of an observer enforcing a measurement basis.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Causality in a quantum mechanical view of reality challenges classical notions due to non-locality and entanglement, and is possibly violated <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>.</p><p>This work proposes a quantum-mechanically valid framework for emergent cognition and causal structure, grounded in relational quantum mechanics and inspired by asymmetric neural learning rules. It introduces a unified perspective on measurement, learning, and inference in quantum systems. We draw on the relational interpretation of quantum mechanics (RQM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref>, where quantum states are defined through interactions, and causality emerges from the network of correlations these interactions establish.</p><p>Our approach is further informed by quantum Darwinism, which posits that classical information about a quantum system becomes redundantly encoded in the environment, allowing multiple observers to agree on a shared reality <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>. This supports MR's framework, as the emergent causal graph reflects a classical observer's neural consensus on relational interactions. Additionally, we draw on applied phenomenology to interpret quantum measurements as observer-dependent phenomena, consistent with RQM's relational ontology, where causality arises from the observer's interaction with the system.</p><p>We propose Measure Reinforcement (MR), a computational framework for to model how classical causality from the point of view of a classical observer can emerge in quantum systems, where quantum subsystems (qubits, neurons) represent variables, and their interactions are quantified as directed information flows. MR captures two processes: the quantum mechanical evolution of a closed fully quantum system, which may exhibit indefinite causal orders and violate Bell inequalities, and a conscious observer's inference of a causal graph from these interactions. The relational framework extends observer-dependent collapse <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Pothos, 2013)</ref>, positioning causality as an emergent property of quantum interactions.</p><p>Notably, MR demonstrates that the Born rule emerges naturally when the observer enforces a measurement basis, linking quantum measurement to emergent causality. This perspective is particularly relevant for applications in quantum cognition, where causal relationships could explain decision-making processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>, and quantum computation, where causal structures can inform circuit design for simulating quantum systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. Our work also adapts to quantum gravity where relational causality may model spacetime emergence <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>, a connection not explored in this work.</p><p>Our contributions are as follows:</p><p>• a computational framework for modeling biological learning through quantum interactions.</p><p>This framework bridges quantum cognition and emergent causality, modeling neural learning (STDP) within the relational interpretation of quantum mechanics where causality emerges from interactions, and unlike classical causal inference, recovers a causal structure even in quantum systems violating Bell's inequalities. MR quantifies how subsystem entanglement entropies evolve under interactions, allowing a classical observer to interpret these changes as causal structure. The Born rule arises only if the observer enforces a measurement basis.</p><p>• We theoretically show that the MR algorithm converges to a stable graph and that its updates reinforce the correct causal paths. We also show that the discovered edges are faithful and sound in the case that a true predefined causal graph exists.</p><p>• We experimentally validate that MR updates exhibit spiking neural network dynamics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>MR builds on relational quantum mechanics <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19]</ref>, where causality emerges from interactions, and aligns with bundle-theoretic interpretations, where properties of the system arise from vanishing distinguishability of indescernible particles <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. The topic of causality in quantum systems has increasingly gained attention, as quantum systems can exhibit non-local correlations only explainable with hidden variables <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5]</ref>. Similar to the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, we model a dynamic quantum network where all subsystems have quantum properties. Their work is of close interest to us. Motivations include quantum computation, quantum gravity, and modeling cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>Information theoretic methods for causal discovery such as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">21]</ref> [10] have increasingly gained attention. MR leverages the information theoretic notion of transfer entropy <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25]</ref> to discover causal structures in quantum systems, and can be seen as an online algorithm which converges to the true causal graph when such graph exists. We adapt the notion of transfer entropy for the quantum Von Neumann entropy in our work.</p><p>While MR is developed for quantum systems, its asymmetric updates mirror hebbian learning and STDP models in neural systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12]</ref>. This mirrors spike-timing-dependent plasticity in neural systems, suggesting a unified model of emergent causality and highlights broader applicability.</p><p>Causal emergence has recently gained attention as a paradigm for modeling systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6]</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> quantifies emergent causality in classical systems. Our work can be seen as following this direction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Framework: Measure Reinforcement</head><p>Let the global quantum system be partitioned into subsystems x, y, z, with state ρ ∈ H x ⊗ H y ⊗ H z , modeling the system's dynamics, reflecting the state evolution postulate of quantum mechanics. Here, system y is a quantum observer of the states x and z, and can be seen as the "environment" of the two neural regions firing. The global state of the closed system evolves as ρ t = U (ρ t−1 )U † , introducing entanglement and correlation between the subsystems. This evolution is followed by a measurement process on the system, with the observer Z providing a relational reference frame. The measurement of the observer then gives a noisy estimate of the system's state ρ xy . The observer y's measurements are classically modeled as probabilistic sampling of pairs X and Y, where each pair is sampled with p(x, y) ∝ I(x; y) exp(−S(ρ x ||ρ y )), and I(x; y) is the quantum mutual information. The exponential bias term prioritizes interactions between more entangled states, reflecting RQM's relational nature <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>We have so far assumed that the state of the system can reliably be estimated, which is a reasonable assumption using techniques such as quantum state tomography <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. However, our work relies on Petz recovery maps <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref> to quantify how reliably the directionality of the updates emerges.</p><p>at each evolution of the state, the measures are upated as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">µ t (x) = γµ t−1 (x) + ϕ(T x→z|y ), µ t (z) = γµ t−1 (z) + ϕ(T z→x|y )</formula><p>where ϕ(m) &lt; 1 is a monotone function with a lipschitz constant less than 1. T y→x|z is defined as the quantum version of transfer entropy</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">T y→x|z = S(X|Z) − S(X|Y, Z)</formula><p>. The asymmetric update rules are inspired by hebbian learning, and model the current understanding of neural learning. Here, subsystem y serves as a relational quantum reference frame, with conditioning on y capturing the timing's dependence on Z's relational history. Subsystem Z keeps a memory of previous interactions because of long-term potentiation.</p><p>MR's Z interactions stochastically reinforce causal links where entanglement predicts collapse outcomes. The term γ &lt; 1 is a parameter, controlling the balance between the past and the new information. We note that γ helps record causal history in case of non-invertible maps such as noisy channels.</p><p>The gamma factor mirrors STDP dynamics, suggesting that such process could govern cognitive processes. The asymmetric updates mirror spike-timing-dependent plasticity, with Z's decoherence playing the role of neural firing activity. This gives a process for explaining how with no-fine-tuning and no hidden variables, STDP and causality can emerge from entanglement and decoherence alone.</p><p>Most importantly to our work, the entanglement entropy updates align with standard quantum information theory, preserving the Data Processing Inequality: the transfer entropy T y→x|z reflects the processed information, ensuring that the observer's inference of causal influence adheres to quantum constraints.</p><p>MR process stops when for all directions, T x→y|z &lt; ϵ. The µ updates quantify the causal influence relative to the global state z, consistent with RQM's relational ontology. This follows from Petz' recovery maps <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>, which ensures existence of a recovery map with small relative entropy of the recovered state and the true state, which is when the subsystems form a markov chain, which happens when the inferred causal link is through the decoherence of the observer subsystem. As the upate rules are contractive and bounded, the process reaches a fixed point Taking a more mathematical approach, MR is a fundamental limit to the observer's perception of causal structures in quantum systems. The conditional mutual information I(X; Y |Z) is bounded below by the relative entropy of Petz recovery maps <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. This suggests that the observer's perception of causality is limited by the reliability of state reconstruction via Petz recovery maps <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. Such process shows that for separable subsystems (e.g. observer Z and subsystem Y), a unique universal Petz recovery map exists, and the conditional mutual information I(X; Y |Z) equals the relative entropy between the true and the recovered joint state ρ xyz .</p><p>Importantly, causal direction emerges through internal system interactions, defined relative to the rest of the subsystems, aligning with RQM's relational causality. The measures µ(t) evolve continuously to reflect causal influence. A discrete causal graph can be obtained by creating directed edges with a robustness estimate. The Born rule emerges naturally when the observer enforces a measurement basis, with the probability density of X's states determined by the entanglement entropy S(x), consistent with RQM's relational framework.</p><p>On a philosophical note, MR quantifies how subsystem entanglement entropies evolve under interactions, allowing a classical observer to interpret these changes as causal structure. An important distinction of our framework with classical causal discovery such as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> is that causal structures emerge through asymmetric probabilistic updates informed by the evolution of the state of the quantum system. Quantum systems can exhibit indefinite causal orders (non-separable causal processes) due to non-locality and entanglement effects, even violating temporal order of events. In MR, the measure µ(x) quantifies a subsystem's causal influence purely relationally, via quantum transfer entropy computed from the global state ρ xyz . MR's causal graph is invariant to global temporal order, as updates depend only on relational transfer entropy. For the quantum observer y, 'past' and 'future' refer to states before and after the interaction. Our framework respects the quantum mechanical setup and recovers the causal direction of influence in the closed system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>To validate MR, we propose a simulation of a quantum system with 3 qubits ⟨A, B, C⟩ with a known causal structure A → B → C. B asks a yes or no question about direction of causality, through a number of noisy observations of states A → C and C → A. B acts as an observer making noisy measurements with a depolarization channel Φ dep (ρ) = (1 − p)ρ + p I d where p ∈ [0, 1] is the depolarization probability. In such scenario, the measure of influence of each subsystem, as encoded in the brain of the conscious observer, will grow in correlation with its entanglement entropy with the observerd states, reflecting the relational influence of interactions.</p><p>Comparison with classical causal discovery methods: classical causal discovery methods can fail to recover a causal graph even with perfect measurements, as processes such as quantum switches <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref> means that no causally separable process explains the system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion on Connection to STDP and Applications to Quantum Machine Learning</head><p>MR's asymmetric updates mirror spike-timing-dependent plasticity (STDP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>: The causal direction is reinforced by larger updates, through long-term potentiation, where a post-synaptic neuron strengthens its connection when activated after a pre-synaptic neuron. Our model can be seen as a quantum mechanical view of asymmetric Hebbaian learning, and models emergent directional neural activity. Measure Reinforcement suggests that decision-making processes can be modeled as emergent causal structures, mirroring STDP in neural systems. This aligns with Pothos' quantum Markov <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref> models by introducing asymmetry in causal updates. This in neural-inspired quantum systems such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>. Thus, our work provides a unified framework for: 1. quantum cognition, 2. hebbian learning as a quantum mechanical process governed by entanglement gradients, and 3. a model for how a quantum mechanical conscious observer can make perceive time and causality through neural strenthening. Specifically, the neurons with a larger measure of influence as described by the MR updates, encode memories associated with the "past". This happens only through neural wirings, a process without a predefined notion of time or causality. In applications to quantum machine learning, our model can use cross-correlations models of neural activity, typical in neuroscience literature, to update the influence measures, and provide a quantum mechanical view of cognitive activity and the brain. For example, MR could model a quantum Hopfield neural network <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref> by updating synaptic weights based on quantum transfer entropy, simulating emergent causality in decision-making processes. This means that such update rules can in principle be estimated via quantum circuits efficiently, as the Kitaev theorem <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> ensures that any quantum circuit, which can be the quantum circuit describing the relations above, can efficiently be estimated by finite circuit gates with small error bounds from noisy measurements and efficient number of samples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Future Work and Conclusion</head><p>MR provides a novel framework for causal discovery in quantum systems, with theoretical guarantees of convergence and faithfulness. The emergent causal graph reflects RQM's relational causality, where causal influence is defined relative to other subsystems. MR's measure updates resemble STDP, suggesting a quantum basis for emergent causality in neural networks. An intriguing direction is to explore MR as a model for universal quantum computation, where the emergent causal graph and measure updates could inform the design of quantum circuits, enhancing applications in quantum computation and machine learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>.</p><p>A key insight of MR is the natural emergence of the Born rule for activation of neural regions, suggesting that fundamental quantum principles can arise from relational interactions, opening new avenues for quantum computation, and cognition.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Theorem 3 . 1 .</head><label>31</label><figDesc>For any quantum system with finite-dimensional subsystems, MR's updates converge to a stable causal graph.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pablo</forename><surname>Arrighi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amélia</forename><surname>Durbec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Quantum networks theory. Quantum</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024-10" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1508</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mu-Ming</forename><surname>Guo-Qiang Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Poo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Synaptic Modifications in Cultured Hippocampal Neurons: Dependence on Spike Timing, Synaptic Strength, and Postsynaptic Cell Type</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10464" to="10472" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum machine learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Biamonte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Wittek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Pancotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Rebentrost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seth</forename><surname>Lloyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">549</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7671</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="202" />
			<date type="published" when="2017-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Christandl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maris</forename><surname>Ozols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Walter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Freek</forename><surname>Witteveen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Quantum Information Theory</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A quantum causal discovery algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Giarmatzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabio</forename><surname>Costa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Causal emergence 2.0: Quantifying emergent complexity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Hoel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting many properties of a quantum system from very few measurements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hsin-Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Kueng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Preskill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1050" to="1057" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Entropic Causal Inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Murat</forename><surname>Kocaoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandros</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Dimakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sriram</forename><surname>Vishwanath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Babak</forename><surname>Hassibi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A new interpretation of quantum theory, based on a bundle-theoretic view of objective idealism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Korth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2208.10964</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multivariate information-theoretic measures reveal directed information structure and task relevant changes in fMRI connectivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Lizier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jakob</forename><surname>Heinzle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annette</forename><surname>Horstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John-Dylan</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mikhail</forename><surname>Prokopenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Computational Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="107" />
			<date type="published" when="2011-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Selection of Intrinsic Horizontal Connections in the Visual Cortex by Correlated Neuronal Activity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Siegrid</forename><surname>Löwel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wolf</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">255</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="212" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Autonomous emergence of connectivity assemblies via spike triplet interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisandro</forename><surname>Montangie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Miehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julijana</forename><surname>Gjorgjieva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1007835</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Nielsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Quantum Computation and Quantum Information: 10th Anniversary Edition</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>10 edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum correlations with no causal order</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ognyan</forename><surname>Oreshkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabio</forename><surname>Costa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caslav</forename><surname>Brukner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1092</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A graph-separation theorem for quantum causal models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacques</forename><surname>Pienaar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Brukner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New Journal of Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">73020</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emmanuel</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerome</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Busemeyer. Quantum Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="749" to="778" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can quantum probability provide a new direction for cognitive modeling?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Emmanuel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerome</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and brain sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="274" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum hopfield neural network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Rebentrost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Bromley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seth</forename><surname>Weedbrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lloyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physical Review A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">42308</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Carlo Rovelli. Relational Quantum Mechanics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1637" to="1678" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Relational Interpretation of Quantum Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlo</forename><surname>Rovelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Information Transfer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Schreiber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physical Review Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="464" />
			<date type="published" when="2000-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universal recovery map for approximate Markov chains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Sutter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Omar</forename><surname>Fawzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Renato</forename><surname>Renner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">472</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20150623</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum circuits with classical versus quantum control of causal order</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Wechs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hippolyte</forename><surname>Dourdent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alastair</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Abbott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cyril</forename><surname>Branciard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">30335</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Emergence and Causality in Complex Systems: A Survey of Causal Emergence and Related Quantitative Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiang</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aobo</forename><surname>Lyu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiayun</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhipeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingzhe</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaiwei</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muyun</forename><surname>Mou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peng</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">108</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Causality detection with matrix-based transfer entropy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wanqi</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shujian</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Badong</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">613</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="375" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum darwinism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wojciech</forename><surname>Hubert Zurek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
