<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">AI AND WORKER COMPENSATION</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
							<email>jin.kim1@northeastern.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shane</forename><surname>Schweitzer</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>De Cremer</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">'</forename><surname>Amore</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">D&apos;Amore-McKim School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Northeastern University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Author Note Jin Kim https://orcid.org</addrLine>
									<postCode>0000-0002-5013-3958, 0000-0002-4548-0410, 0000-0002-3807-6364</postCode>
									<settlement>Shane Schweitzer https://orcid.org/, Christoph Riedl https://orcid.org/, David De Cremer</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">McKim School of Business</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>360 Huntington Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>02115</postCode>
									<settlement>Boston</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">U.S.A</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">AI AND WORKER COMPENSATION</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:00+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>AI in the workplace</term>
					<term>compensation</term>
					<term>employment</term>
					<term>public attitudes</term>
					<term>judgment and decision making</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We investigate whether and why people might reduce compensation for workers who use AI tools. Across 10 studies (N = 3,346), participants consistently lowered compensation for workers who used AI tools. This &quot;AI Penalization&quot; effect was robust across (1) different types of work and worker statuses and worker statuses (e.g., full-time, part-time, or freelance), (2) different forms of compensation (e.g., required payments or optional bonuses) and their timing, (3) various methods of eliciting compensation (e.g., slider scale, multiple choice, and numeric entry), and (4) conditions where workers&apos; output quality was held constant, subject to varying inferences, or controlled for. Moreover, the effect emerged not only in hypothetical compensation scenarios (Studies 1-5) but also with real gig workers and real monetary compensation (Study 6). People reduced compensation for workers using AI tools because they believed these workers deserved less credit than those who did not use AI (Studies 3 and 4). This effect weakened when it is less permissible to reduce worker compensation, such as when employment contracts provide stricter constraints (Study 4). Our findings suggest that adoption of AI tools in the workplace may exacerbate inequality among workers, as those protected by structured contracts face less vulnerability to compensation reductions, while those without such protections risk greater financial penalties for using AI.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>People Reduce Workers' Compensation for Using Artificial Intelligence</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Artificial Intelligence (AI)-computers acting, deciding and advising in ways that seem intelligent-is expected to improve workers' productivity and transform the way they work across industries <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Maslej et al., 2024)</ref>. For example, AI helped software engineers at Google write code faster <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Paradis et al., 2024)</ref>, enabled taxi drivers to find customers more efficiently <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Kanazawa et al., 2022)</ref>, and allowed artists to produce more artworks as well as receive more favorable evaluations over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Zhou &amp; Lee, 2024)</ref>. Not surprisingly, then, workers are increasingly using AI for their work. For example, McKinsey &amp; Company found that 39% of 1,363 workers they surveyed in 2024 reported using generative AI tools regularly for work, which was a notable increase from 22% in 2023 <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Singla et al., 2024)</ref>.</p><p>While AI is likely to boost productivity of workers and improve efficiency within organizations, it also has the potential to negatively impact the perceived value of work outputs <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Longoni et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Magni et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Ragot et al., 2020)</ref>. Specifically, we develop the argument that the use of AI by workers may influence how their outputs are evaluated by others, potentially creating perceptions that AI-assisted workers deserve less credit and therefore lower compensations than workers unassisted by AI. We postulate this idea partly based on recent surveys showing that employees are hesitant to admit to their managers that they used AI for common workplace tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Microsoft, 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Slack, 2024)</ref>, suggesting that observers and organizations may view AI use negatively-a perception that, we argue, could lead to financial penalties for these workers. Given such possibilities, our research examines whether people reduce compensation for workers who use AI and explores the psychological mechanism underlying the possible reduction in worker compensation.</p><p>Previous research offers both indirect and conflicting clues to the question of whether people will reduce workers' compensation for using AI. In their theoretical framework concerning AI and work, Acemoglu and Restrepo identify countervailing forces that may reduce or boost worker compensation following the use of AI <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Acemoglu &amp; Restrepo, 2018)</ref>. Notable among these forces are (1) the displacement effect, where AI replaces humans in tasks, which reduces labor demand and worker compensation; (2) the productivity effect, where AI lowers task costs, spurring economic growth, which boosts labor demand and worker compensation; and</p><p>(3) the reinstatement effect, where AI creates new tasks favoring human skills, which boosts labor demand and worker compensation.</p><p>In line with the countervailing forces in Acemoglu and Restrepo's theoretical framework, empirical research also shows mixed results regarding AI's impact on worker compensation. On the one hand, findings from recent research suggest that the use of AI may boost compensation for workers. For example, increased exposure to AI was associated with an increase in workers' wages in Germany between 2010 and 2017 <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Engberg et al., 2023)</ref>. Likewise, researchers find a strong positive correlation between exposure to AI and wages in analyses at the occupation level <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Felten et al., 2023)</ref>, and occupational exposure to AI was associated with a positive wage growth <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Fossen et al., 2022)</ref>. Moreover, analyses of Indian job ads show that job positions that require AI use offered higher wages <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Copestake et al., 2024)</ref>.</p><p>On the other hand, however, research also finds that AI use may reduce compensation for workers. For example, freelancers on Upwork who worked in areas impacted by generative AI (e.g., writing and copyediting impacted by ChatGPT, as well as design-or image-based services impacted by DALL-E 2 and Midjourney) experienced an estimated decrease of 5.2% in monthly compensation relative to freelancers in other areas, following the release of respective generative AI models <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Hui et al., 2024)</ref>. Notably, the negative impact of AI was observed both for the number of jobs and income-and even when the analyses focused only on workers who actually managed to secure work. Similarly, other researchers find that earnings for freelancing translators dropped by 30% following the release of ChatGPT <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Qiao et al., 2023)</ref>. Together, the findings highlighted in the preceding paragraph and this paragraph suggest that AI's impact on worker compensation may be complex in nature (e.g., positive or negative depending on various factors). Moreover, they also suggest that the AI may disparately negatively impact workers with fewer protections, thereby exacerbating workplace inequalities.</p><p>While observational studies suggest that AI use can influence worker compensation through economic mechanisms (e.g., the displacement or productivity effects), experimental research that directly manipulates AI use to examine its impact on worker compensation is notably absent, to our knowledge. This lack of experimental evidence leaves an important gap in understanding how psychological factors-rather than broader economic forces-may affect individuals' decisions to compensate workers who use AI. Thus, our experimental research specifically examining individuals' decisions to compensate AI-assisted workers will deepen our understanding of AI's impact on worker compensation.</p><p>We conducted 10 experiments (N = 3,346 individual participants in total; four expriments preregistered) to investigate how the use of AI affects people's decisions regarding worker compensation. We find robust evidence that people consistently reduce compensation for workers who use AI tools, a phenomenon we term the "AI Penalization effect." This effect is observed across a range of scenarios (abstract or concrete) featuring different types of work (e.g., graphic design and web design) and various worker statuses (e.g., full-time, part-time, and freelancers). The reduction in compensation holds regardless of the form of payment (required payments or optional bonuses) or timing of payment (e.g., before or after a task is completed), and even when the quality of the output is held constant (e.g., to be "good," "satisfy[actory]", or "impressive"), possibly differently inferred, or statistically controlled.</p><p>What mechanism may explain this effect? We investigated whether workers' use of AI makes people think that those workers deserve less credit (compared to workers not using AI), which in turn leads people to reduce compensation for those workers. We predicted that workers using AI would be perceived as deserving less credit because some of the credit for their output would be attributed to AI. Indeed, our speculation was in line with a recent study showing that people attributed less credit to a human content creator when they used AI for creating a blog post than when they did not use AI <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Earp et al., 2024)</ref>. Similarly, other researchers find that people thought a worker should take less credit for creating a social media campaign proposal when the worker relied on AI more (vs. less) <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Wei et al., 2024)</ref>. Likewise, recent research also finds that observers perceived AI-assisted workers to be less responsible <ref type="bibr">(vs. unassisted workers)</ref> for various task outputs (e.g., haikus, arguments, and summaries), just as the AI-assisted workers themselves thought they were less responsible for their outputs . In a similar vein, previous research documents people assigning responsibility to AI systems, for example, for a hypothetical medical error <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Orr &amp; Davis, 2020)</ref> or people holding AI agents causally responsible and blaming them similarly to human agents in bail decision-making scenarios <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Lima et al., 2021)</ref>. Together, these findings support our hypothesis that people will think workers deserve less credit for their outputs when they use AI. Consequently, all else equal, people would likely reduce compensation for AI-assisted workers <ref type="bibr">(vs. unassisted workers)</ref> because they will perceive the former as deserving less credit for their outputs. Indeed, our studies demonstrate that people reduce compensation because they think AI-assisted workers deserve less credit for their output than unassisted workers (Studies 3-4).</p><p>We also tested an additional hypothesis that the negative effect of AI use on worker compensation through credit deservingness would be weakened when reducing compensation is seen as less permissible. Previous research shows that reducing workers' compensation may be seen as more or less permissible (or acceptable) depending on context. For example, people found it acceptable for an employer to reduce workers' wages when the employer transitioned into a new business venture with the same workers, but they also deemed the same wage reduction unacceptable when it was in response to changes in the business environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Kahneman et al., 1986)</ref>. Furthermore, research also shows that workers responded less negatively to a wage reduction when the reduction was more reasonable or justifiable <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Chen &amp; Horton, 2016)</ref>. So, not only does the permissibility of reducing workers' compensation vary, but workers also react differently to the same compensation reduction depending on how permissible it is perceived to be. Accordingly, this permissibility can also influence employers' reduction of workers' compensation based on credit deservingness. We test this moderated mediation hypothesis in Study 4.</p><p>Our findings offer valuable insights into how the use of AI systems can affect worker compensation. By demonstrating that AI use reduces the extent to which workers deserve credit for their work outputs, we contribute to the literature on the psychological effects of AI in the workplace and labor market. Moreover, our results highlight possible ways that inequality among workers may be exacerbated through the introduction of AI use, as compensation is more likely to be reduced for workers for whom reduced compensation is considered more permissible (whose baseline compensation is likely to be low to begin with). In the remainder of the paper, we present the procedure and results of our experiments, interpret the results, and discuss the limitations and implications of our findings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Transparency Statement</head><p>This research was approved by the Institutional Review Board at [redacted for peer review] (IRB #: 23-12-14). Funding was provided by [redacted for peer review]. We have no conflicts of interest to disclose. All participants, recruited from Prolific, were adults who provided informed consent. We did not exclude any participants who completed the study from our analyses. Four of the 10 studies were preregistered (Studies 1, S1, 3, and 6). All preregistrations, data, and analyses code are available on the project's Open Science Framework page: https://osf.io/awhbg/?view_only=b30a909b3cf54185aa7d0f9b8c05e301.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>Study 1 tested whether people would reduce hypothetical compensation for workers for using an AI system to complete a task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>We recruited 303 workers from Prolific and randomly assigned them to one of two conditions: AI versus No AI. In both conditions, participants read and imagined a scenario in which they were running a small business. Participants imagined that they have hired different graphic designers to create social media ads throughout the year and that they have paid the designers "between $40 and $60 for about an hour's work." They further imagined that they had found a new graphic designer who agreed to create a new ad for them. In the AI condition, the scenario continued with the sentence: "The graphic designer asked if they <ref type="bibr">[could]</ref> work with an AI system for creating the ad, to which you agreed." This sentence was absent in the No AI condition. Then, in both conditions, participants read that the graphic designer estimated it would take about an hour to create the ad. We then asked participants, "How much payment would you offer them?" Participants determined their hypothetical compensation for the graphic designer on a 101-point slider scale from $0 to $100 with $1 increments (and the slider button initially anchored at $0). After answering this dependent measure, participants provided demographic information (age and gender) to complete the study. The materials of this and all other studies are presented in the Supporting Information (hereafter, SI). For Study 1 materials, see SI, Section 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>As predicted (https://aspredicted.org/qzyv-46kk.pdf), participants offered a smaller payment for the graphic designer in the AI condition (M = $33, SD = $14) than in the No AI condition (M = $47, SD = $8.5), t(301) = -10.70, p &lt; .001, d = -1.23; see the left panel of <ref type="figure">Figure   1</ref>. These results provide the initial evidence that people reduce compensation for workers using</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>AI.</head><p>We conducted a nearly direct replication of Study 1 in Study S1 (see SI, Sections 2 and 11 for more details). The only notable differences in Study S1 was that (1) its participants entered the study immediately after completing another study for an unrelated project; (2) it recruited a slightly larger sample of participants (N = 359); and (3) it featured a minor difference in wording of the scenario. As predicted (https://aspredicted.org/swb2-j6d3.pdf), Study S1 replicated the findings of Study 1: Participants offered a smaller payment for the graphic designer in the AI condition (M = $35, SD = $14) than in the No AI condition (M = $47, SD = $9.4), t(357) = -9.74, p &lt; .001, d = -1.03; see the right panel of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Both the mean payments and effect sizes were comparable to those of Study 1. Together, Studies 1 and S1 show that people reduce compensation for workers when they use AI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>Results From Study 1 and Study S1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2A</head><p>Study 2A tested the robustness of findings from Studies 1 and S1 by featuring four main differences. First, Study 2A investigated whether people might compensate temporary and permanent workers differently. That is, whereas Studies 1 and S1 examined people's decisions to compensate only the workers who were hired temporarily (i.e., graphic designers who were hired for a one-off task of creating a social media ad), Study 2A directly manipulated the type of workers (temporary or permanent workers) to test whether compensation might differ between the different types of workers. Second, Study 2A tested whether the reduction observed in one kind of compensation (i.e., a "payment" that implies a required, agreed-upon price to pay for service rendered) might also be observed for a different kind of compensation (i.e., a "bonus" which is an optional, additional payment for a service). Third, Study 2A tested whether reduction in compensation would occur after the task is completed rather than before the task is completed.</p><p>Lastly, Study 2A tested whether reduction in compensation would occur even when the quality of the workers' outputs is held constant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Study 2A used a scenario similar to that of Study 1, but it employed a 2 (Temporary vs. Permanent Worker) × 2 <ref type="bibr">(AI vs. No AI)</ref> between-subjects design. As in Study 1, participants across the four conditions (N = 400) read and imagined a scenario in which they were running a small business. In the Temporary Worker condition, participants imagined that they "hired a graphic designer from an online freelancing platform to create a social media ad for <ref type="bibr">[their]</ref> business," whereas in the Permanent Worker condition, participants imagined that they "assigned a task to [their] salaried graphic designer to create a social media ad for [their] business." Participants in all four conditions further read that they "received the ad they created… and</p><p>[were] satisfied with it. The quality of the ad matche[d] that of other ads [they] have recently used for [their] business." This scenario detail ensured that all participants, regardless of their condition, perceived the worker's output to be of uniformly high quality. Participants then read about a reference range of a bonus to give to the worker ("You typically consider offering a bonus between $0 and $50 for such work"). At this point in the scenario, we manipulated the worker's use of AI: In the AI condition, participants read that "From your earlier conversation with the designer, you know that they used an AI system to create the ad," whereas this sentence was absent in the No AI condition. Participants then answered the dependent measure of the study: "What amount would you give the designer as a bonus?" (followed by a 51-point slider scale from $0 to $50 in $1 increments with the slider button anchored at $0). Afterwards, participants answered exploratory measures and provided demographic information (age and gender) to complete the study. See SI, Section 3, for Study 2A materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>A 2-way ANOVA revealed only the main effect of the AI condition to be significant, F(1, 396) = 112.86, p &lt; .001; see <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Neither the interaction between the AI condition and Worker Type condition, F(1, 396) = 0.69, p = .41, nor the main effect of Worker Type, F(1, 396) = 3.59, p = .059, were significant at α = .05 level.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results of Study 2A</head><p>A simple effects analysis showed that, in the Temporary Worker condition, participants gave a smaller hypothetical bonus when the worker used an AI system (M = $15, SD = $12) than when the worker did not use an AI system (M = $27, SD = $13); simple effects analysis b = 6.07, SE = 0.88, t(396) = 6.91, p &lt; .001. Likewise, in the Permanent Worker condition, participants gave a smaller hypothetical bonus when the worker used an AI system (M = $16, SD = $13) than when the worker did not use an AI system (M = $31, SD = $13); simple effects analysis b = 7.10, SE = 0.87, t(396) = 8.12, p &lt; .001.</p><p>In sum, both for temporary workers and permanent workers, people reduced hypothetical compensation when the worker in question used an AI system to complete a task, even when the quality of the output was held constant.</p><p>One limitation of this study is worth noting. Based on the scenario we used in this study, one could argue that the ad for which the worker used AI could actually be worse in some ways if the quality of the ad matched the quality of the other recent ads. That is, participants might expect certain aspects of the ad to improve if the worker used an AI tool. So, the fact that the focal ad's (overall) quality matched that of the other recent ads might imply that certain other aspects of the ad actually worsened. If the AI and No AI conditions induced such a difference in the inferences about workers' output quality, then it could explain the difference in worker compensation between the AI and No AI conditions. We therefore address the concern for such different inferences by including a more specific description of workers' output quality (e.g., Study 2B) and by directly estimating and statistically controlling for differences in workers' actual output quality (Study 6).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2B</head><p>Study 2B tested the same hypotheses with the same design as in Study 2A but featured some changes in the scenario. Study 2B again tested (1) whether people would reduce compensation for workers using AI and (2) whether such a reduction in compensation would occur for both temporary and permanent workers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>As in Study 2A, Study 2B employed a 2 (Temporary vs. Permanent Worker) × 2 <ref type="bibr">(AI vs.</ref> No AI) between-subjects design. As in previous studies, participants across the four conditions (N = 398) imagined a scenario in which they were running a small business. Unlike in previous studies, however, participants imagined "launch[ing] a new product" and working with a web designer to "create a dedicated landing page for it" (rather than creating a social media ad with a graphic designer; see SI, Section 4, for Study 2B materials). The descriptions for worker type were changed as well: Instead of a "salaried" graphic designer and a graphic designer "from an online freelancing platform," the workers were respectively described as "full-time" and "freelance" web designers to maintain parallelism in wording. The quality of the workers' outputs was controlled with a more specific description: "[Y]ou reviewed the landing page they designed, and you are impressed with the result. The page is visually appealing and functional."</p><p>We manipulated the use of AI by including or excluding the sentence, "During your earlier discussion, [the worker] mentioned that they used an AI tool to assist with the design." Finally, participants chose a bonus for the worker on a different scale ($50 to $150, rather than $0 to $50). Aside from these differences, all other aspects of Study 2B mirrored those of Study 2A.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>A 2-way ANOVA revealed that only the main effect of the AI condition was significant, F(1, 394) = 68.93, p &lt; .001. Neither the interaction between the AI condition and Worker Type condition, F(1, 394) = 1.42, p = .24, nor the main effect of Worker Type, F(1, 394) = 0.20, p = .66, were significant.</p><p>A simple effects analysis showed that, in the Temporary Worker condition, participants gave a smaller hypothetical bonus when the worker used an AI system (M = $76.10, SD = $27.48) than when the worker did not use an AI system (M = $95.71, SD = $27.31); simple effects analysis b = 9.80, SE = 1.95, t(394) = 5.03, p &lt; .001. Similarly, in the Permanent Worker condition, participants gave a smaller hypothetical bonus when the worker used an AI system (M = $74.04, SD = $25.71) than when the worker did not use an AI system (M = $100.21, SD = $29.36); simple effects analysis b = 13.08, SE = 1.95, t(394) = 6.71, p &lt; .001.</p><p>Replicating the findings of Study 2A, participants in Study 2B reduced compensation for the worker who used AI compared to the worker who did not use AI-regardless of whether the worker was hired temporarily (as a "freelancer") or permanently (as a "full-time" employee).</p><p>Study 2B addresses a notable limitation of Study 2A. Specifically, Study 2A participants might have made different inferences about the quality of workers' outputs in the AI and No AI conditions, due to our weak scenario detail employed to hold the quality constant ("The quality of the ad matche[d] that of other ads…recently used for business"). Unlike in Study 2A, however, Study 2B not only held the quality constant with more details ("The page is visually appealing and functional"), but it also described the workers' output as "impress[ive]" in both the AI and No AI conditions. Such descriptions make it less likely that participants in the AI and No AI condition would make different inferences about the quality of workers' outputs. Study 2B thus provides evidence against the alternative explanation for the AI Penalization effect. In other words, people reducing compensation for workers using AI is unlikely to be a result of the perception that the AI-assisted output is of lower quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2C</head><p>Studies 2A and 2B show that worker status (i.e., whether a worker is hired temporarily or permanently) does not moderate people's tendency to reduce compensation when workers use AI. In Study 2C, we tested whether having a prior history with the worker might attenuate such reduction in compensation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>We randomly assigned 200 participants to one of four conditions in a 2 (No History vs. Long History) × 2 <ref type="bibr">(AI vs. No AI)</ref> between-subjects design. As in previous studies, participants imagined that they ran a small business, and the scenario details matched those of Study S1. In the No History condition, participants imagined hiring a new graphic designer with whom they had no prior history of working together ("Over the course of the year, you have hired different graphic designers… Today you found another graphic designer who agreed to create a new ad").</p><p>In the Long History condition, participants imagined working with one designer for a long time ("Over the course of the past 4 years, you have been working with a graphic designer… Today you and the designer discussed creating a new ad"). The worker's use of AI was manipulated the same way as in Study S1, by including or excluding the sentence, "The graphic designer asked if they [could] work with an AI system for creating the ad, to which you agreed." The study's dependent measure asked participants to choose the amount of payment for the worker on a slider scale from $0 to $100. After choosing the payment amount, participants provided demographic information to complete the study (as Study 2C included no exploratory measures). See SI, Section 5, for Study 2C materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>A 2-way ANOVA revealed a nonsignificant interaction between the History condition and AI condition, F(1, 196) = 0.03, p = .86. However, the main effect of the History condition was significant, F(1, 196) = 9.07, p = .003, as was the main effect of the AI condition, F <ref type="bibr">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr">196)</ref> = 74.97, p &lt; .001.</p><p>A simple effects analysis showed that, in the No History condition, participants made a smaller hypothetical payment to the worker who used an AI system (M = $35.65, SD = $11.83) than to the worker who did not use an AI system (M = $48.24, SD = $7.56); simple effects analysis b = 6.29, SE = 1.04, t(196) = 6.06, p &lt; .001. Similarly, in the Long History condition, participants made a smaller hypothetical payment to the worker who used an AI system (M = $39.86, SD = $13.97) than to the worker who did not use an AI system (M = $52.96, SD = $6.98); simple effects analysis b = 6.55, SE = 1.06, t(196) = 6.18, p &lt; .001.</p><p>Participants again reduced compensation for the worker who used AI compared to the worker who did not use AI-regardless of whether the worker was newly hired or had worked with them for the past four years. Thus, prior history of collaborating with workers does not seem to attenuate people's tendency to reduce compensation for workers using AI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2D</head><p>Study 2D further tested the robustness of the AI Penalization effect by making changes in five main aspects. First, we used an alternative method to measure the dependent variable, replacing a slider scale with a ternary choice measure. Second, we examined AI Penalization effect in the context of productivity growth by emphasizing that workers' productivity increased (with or without the use of AI)-a realistic workplace outcome not explored in previous studies.</p><p>Third, we investigated a different category of workers, namely, part-time workers (rather than freelancers). Fourth, we modified the scenario to involve multiple workers rather than a single worker, which better reflects more common real-world business contexts. Lastly, we made the scenario more abstract by removing details on payment structures, specific tasks, and industry context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>We randomly assigned 401 participants to one of four conditions in a 2 (Temporary vs. Permanent Worker) × 2 (AI vs. No AI) between-subjects design. In all conditions, participants imagined that they ran a small business with five employees, but these employees were described either as "part-time employees" in the Temporary Worker condition or "full-time employees" in the Permanent Worker condition. More importantly, the scenario in this study described a growth in productivity: "At the end of the year, you notice that the productivity of your [full-time / parttime] employees has slightly increased compared to the previous year." This productivity growth was attributed to the use of AI in the AI condition ("This increase in productivity was mainly due to the new AI tools you provided them earlier in the year"), or no such attribution was made in the No AI condition.</p><p>Aside from the information about productivity growth, the scenario did not feature any concrete details like those featured in previous studies (e.g., specific tasks like creating a social media ad or a landing page, or industry contexts like graphic or web design). Based on the abstract information alone, then, participants answered the dependent measure with three choices: "Assuming that the current level of productivity [driven by the AI tools (this phrase was added only in the AI condition)] can be sustained next year, would you adjust the compensation for the [full-time / part-time] employees? That is, would you increase or decrease the compensation, or keep it the same? (Decrease the compensation / Keep the compensation the same / Increase the compensation)." After answering this question, participants explained their answer in a free-response format ("Please briefly explain why you would decrease the compensation / increase the compensation / keep the compensation the same") and provided demographic information to complete the study. See SI, Section 6, for Study 2D materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>Unlike the previous studies where there was no mention of productivity growth, Study 2D specifically described an increase in workers' productivity, either because of AI tools or unspecified reasons. Likely due to this productivity growth, most participants showed the intent to increase compensation for the workers. Specifically, the percentage indicating the intent to increase compensation ranged from 50% in the AI &amp; Temporary Worker condition to 83% in the No AI &amp; Temporary Worker condition; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. More importantly, however, we still find that the use of AI tools had a negative effect on compensation. As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>, the percentage of participants increasing the compensation for part-time workers in the No AI condition was 83%, but this percentage significantly decreased to 50% in the AI condition, χ 2 (1) = 23.81, p &lt; .001. Similarly, the percentage of participants increasing the compensation for full-time workers in the No AI condition was 75%, but it significantly decreased to 55% in the AI condition, χ 2 (1) = 7.83, p = .005. Regressing the binary variable of choosing to increase the compensation versus not (1 = "Increase the compensation" vs. 0 = "Decrease the compensation" or "Keep the compensation the same") on the two condition variables and their interaction in a logistic regression revealed that the interaction was not significant, b = 0.68, SE = 0.45, z = 1.52, p = .13. Thus, it seems that the use of AI had a negative effect on workers' compensation-regardless of whether the workers were part-time or full-time employees.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3</head><p>Results From Study 2D</p><p>Study 2D presents results that clarify the nature of the AI Penalization effect. As hypothetical small business owners, most participants chose to increase the compensation for workers even when AI was used. In other words, even in cases of AI use, participants did not directly cut or trim worker compensation. Rather, AI use led participants to reduce worker compensation relative to the increased compensation they would have offered in the absence (or nonsalience) of AI use. The AI Penalization effect in Study 2D, then, manifested as a dampened increase in worker compensation for AI use following a productivity growth. Hence, the AI Penalization effect is more nuanced than "people simply slashing or trimming compensation as a result of AI use"; instead, it describes a negative impact on worker compensation as a result of AI use that can take on various forms, such as a dampened increase in compensation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>Having found that people tend to reduce workers' compensation for using AI (Studies 1</p><p>and S1) and having tested the robustness of this tendency (Studies 2A -2D), we conducted Study 3 to examine whether this tendency might be explained by a perceived reduction in credit deservingness associated with the use of AI. To this end, we employed the design of Study 1 and measured the extent to which people thought workers deserved credit for their work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>The design of Study 3 was the same as that of Study 1, except for the addition of three items measuring the extent to which participants thought workers deserved credit for their work (hereafter, credit deservingness). We recruited 303 workers from Prolific and randomly assigned them to either the AI or No AI condition. As in Study 1, participants imagined hiring a graphic designer who created a social media ad for them either using an AI system or not (i.e., no mention of an AI system). After participants answered the dependent measure-their choice of the hypothetical payment amount for the designer-they answered three questions measuring the extent to which they thought the designer deserved credit for their work (credit deservingness):</p><p>(1) "How much credit do you think the graphic designer deserves for creating the ad? (1 = No credit at all, 7 = All the credit)"; (2) "How responsible do you think the graphic designer was for creating the ad? (1 = Not at all responsible, 7 = Completely responsible)"; (3) "How important do you think the graphic designer's role was in creating the ad? (1 = Not at all important, 7 = Extremely important)." Participants then reported demographic information (age and gender) to complete the study. See SI, Section 7, for Study 3 materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>As predicted (https://aspredicted.org/3nfn-p23y.pdf), we replicated the findings of Studies 1 and S1. Specifically, participants offered a smaller payment for the graphic designer in the AI condition (M = $37, SD = $14) than in the No AI condition (M = $48, SD = $11), t(286.1) = -7.47, p &lt; .001, d = -0.86.</p><p>Our next set of analyses involved the three items measuring perceived credit deservingness. First, a parallel analysis of participants' ratings on the three items indicated that only one factor should be retained, as only the first eigenvalue exceeded the 95th percentile of random eigenvalues (see SI, Section 12 and <ref type="figure">Figure S1</ref>). Next, a factor analysis (i.e., a principal component analysis extracting one factor <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Field et al., 2012)</ref>) revealed that each item contributed strongly to the underlying factor (all factor loadings ≥ 0.93) and that the extracted factor captured 90% of the total variance among the items (see SI, Section 12 and <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table S1</ref>). This high proportion of explained variance indicated that the single factor was sufficient to represent the shared variance across the items. We thus averaged each participant's ratings on the three items to create a composite index of credit deservingness.</p><p>Now that we had a measure of credit deservingness, we estimated a mediation model in which the use of AI (or not) affected the compensation for the designer indirectly through credit deservingness (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>). Consistent with our preregistration, the estimated indirect effect was significant, a × b = -6.33, SE = 1.22, 95% CI = <ref type="bibr">[-8.81, -4</ref>.05], p &lt; .001. That is, when participants were told about the designer's use of an AI system (vs. when they were not told anything about their use of an AI system), they perceived that the designer deserved less credit for their work output (i.e., the social media ad), which in turn led the participants to give a smaller hypothetical payment to the designer. In addition, we find that the indirect effect accounted for 60% of the total effect (95% CI = [38%, 88%]) that the independent variable (use of AI) had on the dependent variable (worker compensation).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4</head><p>Mediation Model Estimated in Study 3</p><p>Study 3 provides the initial evidence for a mechanism underlying the AI Penalization effect. Specifically, we find that people reduce compensation for workers using AI, likely because they perceive that such workers deserve less credit for their work output. This explanation was supported by the highly significant indirect effect through credit deservingness estimated in the simple mediation model. In the next study, we test this simple mediation model again and investigate whether this indirect effect may be moderated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 4</head><p>We conducted Study 4 with two goals in mind: to test again the simple mediation model from Study 3 and to explore whether the mediation might be moderated by the extent to which the act of reducing worker compensation was permissible. We hypothesized that when it is less permissible to reduce worker compensation-for example, because their compensation is protected by an employment contract-then the AI Penalization effect through credit deservingness might weaken. We thus adapted the scenario from Study 2B not only to manipulate whether a worker used AI, but also to create two different situations where reducing worker compensation was more or less permissible.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>We randomly assigned 281 participants to one of four conditions in a 2 (AI vs. No AI) × 2 (More vs. Less Permissible [to Reduce Worker Compensation]) between-subjects design. All participants imagined that they ran "a small company that sells consumer products" and that they "decided to launch a new product and wanted to create a dedicated landing page for it." Unlike in Study 2B, Study 4 scenario described working with an in-house web designer and did not explicitly describe them as "full-time" or "freelance." Moreover, the scenario explicitly described the task as an extra task (outside of their regular tasks) voluntarily accepted by the worker based on mutual agreement with the participant: "You asked your web designer whether they would be interested in creating the landing page. They agreed to do so as an extra task, in addition to their regular tasks." As in Study 2B, Study 4 scenario controlled the quality of the work output to be high but explicitly mentioned a realistic amount of time taken to complete the task: "Within just three days of taking on the task, the designer delivered a landing page that was visually appealing and functioned exactly as you envisioned."</p><p>At this point, we manipulated the use of AI with a more realistic detail that was not included in Study 2B. In the AI condition, participants read: "During your conversation about the task, the designer mentioned that they used AI tools (ChatGPT and Midjourney) to create the page." In the No AI condition, this sentence was omitted. Finally, participants imagined choosing the amount of bonus for the designer ("You are considering offering a bonus for this good work").</p><p>At this point in the scenario, we manipulated the extent to which it was permissible to reduce the worker's compensation. Specifically, in the Less Permissible condition, participants read "Your company writes into employment contracts to give bonus payments of $100 for extra tasks such as this," whereas in the More Permissible condition, they read, "Your company has in the past consistently given bonus payments of $100 for extra tasks such as this." Thus, we presented the same reference bonus amount of $100 in all conditions, but this amount reflected either a strict term in the employment contracts (in the Less Permissible condition) or the company's past behavior (in the More Permissible condition). By explicitly telling participants that the amount was written in the employment contract, we sought to convey that reducing the bonus amount would not be permissible, or at least be less permissible than simply deviating from the past behavior. After reading this last sentence of the scenario, participants chose the bonus amount for the designer on a 201-point slider scale from $0 to $200. Participants then answered the three mediator items measuring credit deservingness (the same items as in Study 3) and reported demographic information to complete the study. See SI, Section 8, for Study 4 materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>We first estimated the same simple mediation model as in Study 3. Replicating the finding of Study 3, the estimated indirect effect through credit deservingness was significant, a × b = -22.67, SE = 3.23, 95% CI = <ref type="bibr">[-29.31, -16</ref>.55], p &lt; .001. In other words, when participants learned that the designer used an AI system for their work (vs. when they did not learn anything about an AI system), they perceived that the designer deserved less credit for their work output, which in turn translated to a smaller hypothetical payment to the designer. The indirect effect through credit deservingness accounted for 85% of the total effect (95% CI = [62%, 117%]) that the independent variable (use of AI) had on the dependent variable (worker compensation).</p><p>Although this simple mediation model represents what some researchers call a "complete" or "full" mediation, we refrain from making claims about partial or complete mediation regarding our mediation models, concurring with the opinion of Hayes <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Hayes, 2018)</ref>. Nevertheless, these results suggest that the reduction in worker compensation caused by AI use is explained in large part by people's judgment that the worker deserves less credit for the output aided by AI.</p><p>Next, we tested our moderated mediation model. Specifically, we tested whether the mediation through credit deservingness mentioned in the previous paragraph might be moderated by our manipulation of permissibility of reducing worker compensation. Using Hayes's PROCESS Model 15 <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Hayes, 2018)</ref>, we estimated the moderated mediation model depicted in  <ref type="bibr">-35.25, -19.21]</ref>. Put differently, participants paid a smaller hypothetical bonus to the worker using AI (than to the worker supposedly not using AI), likely because they thought the AI-assisted worker deserved less credit for their work output, but the extent to which participants reduced the bonus for this reason was attenuated when participants learned that the bonus amount was specified in employment contracts (as compared to when the bonus amount reflected the company's past behavior). Study 4 thus demonstrates that the permissibility of reducing worker compensation sets a boundary condition for our finding that AI use can reduce worker compensation through credit deservingness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 5</head><p>The Moderated Mediation Model Estimated in Study 4</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 5</head><p>Studies 1-4 show that people penalize workers when the workers receive help from AIbut is this effect unique to AI? In other words, do people penalize workers for receiving help from AI specifically or for receiving help from any entity at all? Study 5 was conducted to explore these questions. We used the same scenario as in Studies 1 and S1 and included the same No AI and AI conditions (respectively labeled "No Help" and "Help From AI" conditions). More importantly, however, we added a third condition (labeled "Help from Human" condition) whose scenario described a worker receiving help from another human. We reasoned that if people penalize workers for receiving help from any entity, we should observe a reduction in compensation in both the Help From AI and Help From Human conditions. However, if people penalize workers for receiving help specifically from AI, then we should observe a reduction in compensation only in the Help From AI condition and not in the Help From Human condition.</p><p>Therefore, Study 5 allowed us to test whether our effect is indeed an "AI Penalization" effect, rather than an "Assistance Penalization" effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>We randomly assigned 471 participants to one of three conditions (No Help vs. Help From AI vs. Help From Human) in a between-subjects design. As in Study S1, all participants entered Study 5 immediately after completing another study for an unrelated project. The No Help and Help From AI conditions were respectively identical to the No AI and AI conditions from Study S1. Participants in all conditions imagined running a small business and hiring a graphic designer to create a social media ad. In the Help From AI condition, participants learned that the designer received help from an AI system to create the ad ("The graphic designer asked if they can work with an AI system for creating the ad, to which you agreed"), whereas in the Help From Human condition, participants learned that the designer received help from another human to create the ad ("The graphic designer asked if they can work with another graphic designer for creating the ad, to which you agreed"). In the No Help condition, the sentence about the designer receiving help (from either AI or another human) was omitted. In all conditions, participants chose the payment for the designer (i.e., answered the question, "How much payment would you offer them?" on a 101-point slider scale from $0 to $100). Participants then reported demographic information to complete the study. See SI, Section 9, for Study 5 materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>A one-way ANOVA revealed a significant difference in payment for the graphic designer across the three conditions, F(2, 468) = 61.57, p &lt; .001. Replicating the findings from Study S1, From Human condition, we observed an increase in compensation. These results suggest that people reducing compensation for workers assisted by AI is indeed an "AI Penalization" effect rather than a mere "Assistance Penalization" effect, as such reduction seems unique to assistance from AI and does not seem to extend to assistance from other entities like another human.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 6</head><p>So far, we have used scenarios to investigate whether and why people might reduce compensation for workers using AI. In Study 6, we examined whether this reduction in compensation extends to real payments made to real workers. To do so, we first recruited participants to work on a task either using AI or not. We then recruited a second group of participants to take on the role of manager that allocates real monetary bonuses among some of the previous workers with the knowledge of which workers had used AI. We thus tested whether our main finding could be replicated with real monetary compensation to real workers.</p><p>In addition, by recruiting different participants to work on the same task, Study 6 allowed the quality of workers' outputs to vary naturally. Study 6 then examined the effect of AI use on worker compensation while statistically controlling for this natural variation in workers' output quality. In some of the previous studies, we artificially held workers' output quality constant through scenario details (e.g., by telling participants that the outputs of the workers who used AI and those who did not use AI were both "impress[ive]," "good," or "appealing" as in Studies 2B and 4). In other studies, we allowed participants to make different inferences about workers'</p><p>(future) output quality in the AI and No AI conditions by not providing such details in the scenario (e.g., Study 1 and 2C). However, the scenarios used in these studies may have resulted in a perceived difference in workers' output quality between the AI and No AI conditions. For example, a "good work" done with AI and a "good work" done without AI may not be of the same quality in participants' minds. So, it is possible that such a difference in perceived quality of workers' outputs between the AI and No AI condition could drive the difference in worker compensation. Study 6 thus addressed this concern by allowing a natural variation in workers' output quality and statistically controlling for this variation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Study 6 was conducted in two stages. In the first stage, we recruited from Prolific 60 participants (hereafter, the workers) to work on a task as gig workers. The workers were first thanked for participating in the study and were informed that they would "write a short social media post to promote a fictional product." They were further told that a judge or judges would evaluate the social media posts in terms of "how likely they [were] to encourage readers to learn more about the product," and that if their post ranked among the top 50% of all the posts, they would receive a bonus payment of $0.30. We then asked the workers, "Are you motivated to write a social media post that earns a bonus? [Yes, I am motivated / No, I am not really motivated]." We used this item to screen out submissions from unmotivated workers when presenting their work to managers.</p><p>The workers then received the instructions for the task. Specifically, they were asked to imagine that they were a social media manager for a product and to "write a 2-4 sentence social media post that grabs attention and encourages readers to learn more about the product." They then received information on the product name ("Beannovation") and product description ("Beannovation is a cutting-edge coffee maker… Brew a rich, barista-quality cup in just 3 minutes…"). The workers received more detailed instructions for writing the social media post ("Highlight the key benefit(s)… End with a call to action") and saw an example of a social media post. The exact materials presented to the workers are included in SI, Section 10, "Part 1."</p><p>At this point, we manipulated the workers' use of AI. Below the aforementioned example of a social media post, a randomly selected half of the workers were presented with the instructions to use an AI tool for the task: "For this task, please use our ChatGPT interface by clicking the button below." Below these instructions was a button that the workers could click, and once they clicked the button, a new browser tab opened and presented the workers with an interface that allowed them to directly interact with ChatGPT to receive assistance for the task . After the workers used ChatGPT to draft or refine their social media post, they returned to the original study page and entered their social media post in a text box. For the other half of the workers, no AI tool was provided, and these workers wrote a social media post on their own. (In this No AI condition, submissions from workers who later reported using AI were excluded for managers' evaluation.) After writing their social media posts, all workers answered exploratory questions which asked whether and how they used an AI tool for the task (either within or outside the study) and provided demographic information to complete the study; see SI, Section 10, "Part 1," for all measures used in the study.</p><p>In the second stage, we recruited from Prolific 140 participants (hereafter, the managers)</p><p>who would take on the role of managers overseeing the workers from the first stage. The managers were first thanked for participating in the study and were informed that they would "make decisions as a manager overseeing four gig workers who participated in our previous study on Prolific." They were informed that the workers had previously written social media posts for a product and were presented with the same information on product name and description that had been presented to the workers.</p><p>Prior to the second stage, we selected four of the 60 social media posts submitted in the first stage. Specifically, we selected four social media posts that were of similar length and quality (as judged by the first author), two of which were produced by workers using AI and the other two produced by workers not using AI. Each of the 140 managers were asked to "review the submissions from four workers and allocate a total bonus of $1.00 among them." The managers were further informed that the bonus amount they assign to each worker would "serve as input to determine the actual bonus payments" that the workers receive. Before reviewing the social media posts, the managers received a note in red font which stated that "[s]ome workers were provided with an AI tool to assist in creating their social media posts" and that whether a given worker used AI would be indicated for each post.</p><p>Next, each of the 140 managers reviewed the same four social media posts. Importantly, these posts came with labels that indicated whether the workers used AI; see SI, Section 10, "Part 2." For example, above the first social media post was the label "Submission by Worker 1 (who used an AI tool)" with the parenthetical remark in red font. We randomized the order of the four social media posts, as well as which two of the posts would be labeled as assisted by AI ("who used an AI tool") and which two would be labeled as unassisted by AI ("who did not use an AI tool"). Thus, the labels indicating whether the worker used AI or not were affixed to the posts independently of whether the workers actually used AI or not. After reviewing the four social media posts by four workers, each manager decided the amount of bonus to give to each worker by entering a number between 0 and 100 (representing $1.00 or 100 cents) in each of four text boxes ("Bonus for Worker 1: ___; Bonus for Worker 2: ___; [and so on]"). The managers then provided demographic information to complete the study. See SI, Section 10, for Study 6 materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dependent t-Test</head><p>Following the preregistration (https://aspredicted.org/9tsh-78jy.pdf), for each manager, we summed their bonus amounts for two workers who purportedly used AI and their bonus amounts for two workers who purportedly did not use AI. We then compared the total bonus for workers using AI and the total bonus for workers not using AI across all managers by conducting a dependent t-test. As predicted, managers gave smaller bonuses to workers who used AI (M = $0.35, SD = $0.21) than to workers who did not use AI (M = $0.65, SD = $0.21), t(139) = -8.74, p &lt; .001.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Multilevel Modeling and Regression Analyses Accounting for Workers' Performance</head><p>In previous studies, we estimated the effect of AI use on worker compensation while holding constant workers' performance through scenario details. However, Study 6 enabled us to estimate the effect of AI use on worker compensation while statistically controlling for workers' performance, because we could now directly measure workers' performance by having third-party judges evaluate their outputs. For this analysis, we recruited from Prolific yet another separate sample of 30 participants (hereafter, the judges). We presented these judges with each of the same four social media posts presented to the managers and asked them to rate the likelihood that the social media post would "encourage readers to learn more about the product" on a 7point scale (1 = Not likely at all, 7 = Extremely likely); see SI, Section 10, "Part 3." We then computed the mean of the likelihood ratings for each of the four social media posts so that each mean value would represent the level of performance by the worker who produced the given social media post.</p><p>Next, we estimated a multilevel model in which the bonus amounts allocated by managers were predicted by (1) the within-subjects binary variable of whether workers purportedly used AI (Purported Use of AI by Worker) and <ref type="formula">2</ref>  The results from both (1) the dependent t-test and (2) multilevel and regression models replicate the findings from our scenario studies with real monetary compensation for real workers. That is, the managers who oversaw a group of gig workers gave smaller bonuses for workers who used AI, as compared with workers who did not use AI. Thus, even when paying real workers with real money, people penalized workers for using AI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Summary of the Findings</head><p>Across 10 studies (N = 3,346), we consistently find robust evidence for the AI Penalization effect-people's tendency to reduce compensation for workers who use AI compared to those who do not. Most importantly, this effect was observed both with real monetary compensation for real gig workers (Study 6) and hypothetical compensation in scenarios (Studies 1-5). The effect was also unique to instances where workers received assistance from AI, rather than from another entity, such as another human (Study 5). Moreover, the AI Penalization effect was observed when the output quality of AI-assisted and unassisted workers was described as matching a reference (Study 2A), equivalently framed as impressive <ref type="bibr">(Study 2B)</ref>, left open to interpretation (Study 1), or statistically controlled (Study 6). Notably, the effect also persisted in the context of productivity growth, manifesting as smaller increases in compensation for AI-assisted workers compared to their unassisted counterparts.</p><p>Building upon these findings, we investigated a mechanism underlying the AI Penalization effect (Studies 3 and 4). The results from our simple mediation analyses revealed that workers' use of AI led people to view them as deserving less credit for their work outputs and subsequently reduce their compensation for AI use. Additionally, we find that this indirect effect of AI use on compensation reduction through credit deservingness weakened when reducing compensation was less permissible, such as when an employment contract fixed the compensation amount.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implications of the Findings</head><p>Results of Study 4 have important implications for both workers and policymakers. Study 4 shows that the AI Penalization effect through credit deservingness weakened when it was less permissible to adjust worker compensation-such as when reducing compensation would violate a term of an employment contract. This finding suggests that workers whose compensation is protected by rigid employment contracts may be less likely to experience compensation reduction due to diminished credit deservingness. Conversely, however, workers without explicit contractual protections may face a higher risk of compensation reductions driven by the same mechanism. For example, independent contractors and freelancers who operate under general agreements regarding project scopes or hourly rates rather than fixed compensation terms may be particularly vulnerable to such outcomes when using AI. Similarly, workers under implied or informal contracts, those under flexible compensation schemes (e.g., based on performance), those whose compensation is adjustable during probationary periods, or even those who work in startups or tech companies (where employment agreements might emphasize equity, stock options, or future profits rather than fixed compensations), may also be especially vulnerable to the AI Penalization effect. Thus, our findings suggest that workers negotiating employment contracts and expecting to use AI in their work may want to be especially mindful of how their compensation will be determined and how they could be vulnerable to the AI Penalization effect.</p><p>For policymakers, our findings highlight the need to prevent a possible exacerbation of compensation inequality among workers. As AI use becomes more widespread at work, workers in flexible arrangements (e.g., those without fixed compensation) may face disproportionate risks of compensation reduction. As flexible arrangements tend to be more common in lower-wages jobs than in higher-wage jobs <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Adams-Prassl et al., 2020)</ref>, workers in lower-wage jobs may be more likely to experience compensation reduction due to AI use lowering credit deservingness than workers in higher-wage jobs. This in turn could widen the wage gap between workers in lower-and higher-wage jobs and possibly exacerbate compensation inequality among workers.</p><p>To address or prevent this outcome, policymakers may consider offering greater protection for workers in flexible arrangements or incentivizing employers to increase transparency in how AI use influences compensation decisions.</p><p>Our findings also suggest that there may be something unique about AI that affects people's judgments differently than other tools. In Study 5, participants penalized workers for being assisted by AI but not for being assisted by another human. performance and reduce their effort <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Edelman et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Noy &amp; Zhang, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Peng et al., 2023)</ref>, but because our study designs held such differences in performance and effort constant, they may not adequately reflect certain real-life work situations.</p><p>Notably, our Study 6 did measure variations in performance between the AI and No AI conditions and controlled for their effects on compensation, but future research can do more to address concerns about other factors of work not explicitly examined in this paper (e.g., effort).</p><p>For example, future research may examine what would happen to workers' compensation when AI use simultaneously reduces their effort and responsibility but boosts their performance. This is an important empirical question not answered by this paper, and the answer may depend on the relative importance or magnitude of changes on such possible determinants of worker compensation. Recent work addresses similar questions , and we encourage further exploration in this area to deepen our understanding of AI's multifaceted impact on worker compensation.</p><p>Another limitation of our research is that most-though not all-of our studies were scenario-based, which may limit the generalizability of our findings. However, Study 6 did examine real monetary compensation for real gig workers (despite the use of a hypothetical work task) and found a large reduction in compensation for workers using AI. Future research can further test or expand on our findings by examining more real-world compensation decisions across diverse workplace settings to better assess the generalizability of the AI Penalization effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Our research shows that people consistently reduce compensation for workers who use AI tools compared to those who do not-a phenomenon we term the "AI Penalization" effect.</p><p>This effect was observed both for real monetary compensation and hypothetical compensation, and it was robust across various work types, worker statuses, forms and timing of compensation, and methods of eliciting compensation decisions (among other factors tested). People reduce compensation for AI-assisted workers (vs. unassisted workers) likely because they think those workers deserve less credit for their work outputs. However, the AI Penalization effect through credit deservingness diminished when reducing compensation was less permissible, such as under rigid terms of employment contracts. Our findings highlight the potential of AI use exacerbating inequality in worker compensation, as workers without contractual protections may be more vulnerable to the AI Penalization effect. As AI reshapes our work and the labor market, it will become increasingly critical to consider and address its potential negative impacts on workers and shared expectations of economic equity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Section 1. Study 1 Materials</head><p>[Prolific ID Entry and Consent Form]</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">[Page Break]</formula><p>Thank you for participating in our study!</p><p>In this study, we will ask you to imagine a scenario and answer a question.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>Imagine that you run a small business.</p><p>Throughout the year, you have hired different graphic designers to create social media ads, paying each one between $40 and $60 for about an hour's work.</p><p>Today, you found a new graphic designer who has agreed to create a new ad for you.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>[AI vs. No AI manipulation:</head><p>The designer asked if they could use an AI system to assist in creating the ad, and you agreed. (AI condition only)]</p><p>They estimated it would take about one hour to create the ad.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>How much payment would you offer them?</head><p>[ Today, you received the ad they created, and you are satisfied with it. The quality of the ad matches that of other ads you have recently used for your business.</p><p>You typically consider offering a bonus between $0 and $50 for such work.</p><p>[AI vs. No AI manipulation: From your earlier conversation with the designer, you know that they used an AI system to create the ad. (AI condition only)]</p><p>What amount would you give the designer as a bonus?</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>[The exploratory items below measured the extent to which participants viewed their imagined relationship with the graphic designer as a relationship characterized by communal sharing and/or market pricing, which are two of the four relational models identified by previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Fiske, 1992)</ref>. The items were selected and adapted from a scale used in previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Haslam &amp; Fiske, 1999)</ref>.]</p><p>In this part of the study, we are interested in your thoughts about the relationship between you and the graphic designer in the imagined scenario.</p><p>Please read each of the statements below and rate how true it would be of the relationship between you and the designer in the scenario.</p><p>[Participants answered each of the questions below on a 6-point scale (1 = Not at all true of the relationship, 6 = Very true of the relationship). The order of the questions was randomized.]</p><p> If either of you needs something, the other would give it without expecting anything in return.  You and the designer would make decisions together by consensus.  The two of you would tend to develop very similar attitudes and values.  You feel that you would have something unique in common that makes you two essentially the same.  The two of you would be a unit: you would belong together.  What you get from the designer would be directly proportional to how much you give them.  You and the designer would divide things up according to how much each of you has paid or contributed.  You would pay the designer in proportion to how long they worked or how much they did.  The designer would have a right (they would be entitled) to a fair rate of return for what they put into the interaction.  The designer would expect to get the same rate of return on their effort and investment that other people get.</p><p>[ Imagine that you run a small business.</p><p>You recently decided to launch a new product and wanted to create a dedicated landing page for it.</p><p>[Worker type manipulation: You hired a freelance web designer to take on this task. (Temporary Worker condition) / You assigned this task to your full-time web designer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(Permanent Worker condition)]</head><p>Today, you reviewed the landing page they designed, and you are impressed with the result. The page is visually appealing and functional.</p><p>You typically consider offering a bonus between $50 and $150 for exceptional work like this.</p><p>[AI vs. No AI manipulation: During your earlier discussion, the designer mentioned that they used an AI tool to assist with the design. (AI condition only)]</p><p>What amount would you give the web designer as a bonus?</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>[The exploratory items below measured the extent to which participants viewed their imagined relationship with the graphic designer as a relationship characterized by communal sharing and/or market pricing, which are two of the four relational models identified by previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Fiske, 1992)</ref>. The items were selected and adapted from a scale used in previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Haslam &amp; Fiske, 1999)</ref>.]</p><p>In this part of the study, we are interested in your thoughts about the relationship between you and the graphic designer in the imagined scenario.</p><p>Please read each of the statements below and rate how true it would be of the relationship between you and the designer in the scenario.</p><p>[Participants answered each of the questions below on a 6-point scale (1 = Not at all true of the relationship, 6 = Very true of the relationship). The order of the questions was randomized.]</p><p> If either of you needs something, the other would give it without expecting anything in return.  The two of you would tend to develop very similar attitudes and values.  You feel that you would have something unique in common that makes you two essentially the same.  The two of you would be a unit: you would belong together.  What you get from the designer would be directly proportional to how much you give them.  You would pay the designer in proportion to how long they worked or how much they did.  The designer would have a right (they would be entitled) to a fair rate of return for what they put into the interaction.  The designer would expect to get the same rate of return on their effort and investment that other people get.</p><p>[ Thank you for participating in our study!</p><p>In this study, we will ask you to imagine a scenario and answer some questions.</p><p>[ At the end of the year, you notice that the productivity of your full-time employees has slightly increased compared to the previous year.</p><p>[AI vs. No AI manipulation: This increase in productivity was mainly due to the new AI tools you provided them earlier in the year. (AI condition only)]</p><p>Assuming that the current level of productivity, driven by the AI tools, can be sustained next year, would you adjust the compensation for the full-time employees?</p><p>That is, would you decrease or increase the compensation, or keep it the same?</p><p>Decrease the compensation / Keep the compensation the same / Increase the compensation Thank you for participating in our study!</p><p>In this study, we will ask you to imagine a scenario and answer some questions.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>Imagine that you run a small business.</p><p>Throughout the year, you have hired different graphic designers to create social media ads, paying each one between $40 and $60 for about an hour's work.</p><p>Today, you found a new graphic designer who agreed to create a new ad for you.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>[AI vs. No AI manipulation:</head><p>The designer asked if they could use an AI system to assist in creating the ad, and you agreed. (AI condition only)]</p><p>They estimated that it would take about one hour to create the ad. Thank you for participating in our study!</p><p>In this study, we will ask you to imagine a scenario and answer some questions.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>Imagine that you run a small company that sells consumer products.</p><p>You recently decided to launch a new product and wanted to create a dedicated landing page for it. You asked your web designer whether they would be interested in creating the landing page. They agreed to do so as an extra task, in addition to their regular tasks.</p><p>Within just three days of taking on the task, the designer delivered a landing page that was visually appealing and functioned exactly as you envisioned.</p><p>[AI vs. No AI manipulation: During your conversation about the task, the designer mentioned that they used AI tools <ref type="formula">(</ref> In this part of the study, we are interested in your thoughts regarding the scenario.</p><p> How much credit do you think the graphic designer deserves for creating the ad? (1 = No credit at all, 7 = All the credit)  How responsible do you think the graphic designer was for creating the ad? (1 = Not at all responsible, 7 = Completely responsible)  How important do you think the graphic designer's role was in creating the ad? (1 = Not at all important, 7 = Extremely important) In this study, we will ask you to write a short social media post to promote a fictional product.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>[A question to screen out unmotivated workers]</p><p>On the next page, you will learn about a product and write a social media post for it.</p><p>At the end of this study, a judge or judges will read the social media posts you and other participants submit. They will then evaluate the posts in terms of how likely they are to encourage readers to learn more about the product.</p><p>If your post ranks among the top 50% of all the posts based on this evaluation, we will send you a bonus payment of $0.30 through Prolific.</p><p>Are you motivated to write a post that earns a bonus? (Please answer honestly, as either answer is perfectly acceptable.)</p><p>Yes, I am motivated. / No, I am not really motivated.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>Imagine that you are a social media manager for the product described below.</p><p>Your task is to write a 2-4 sentence social media post that grabs attention and encourages readers to learn more about the product. For this task, please use our ChatGPT interface by clicking the button below.</p><p>[Clicking the button above opens a new browser tab like the one below.]</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>[Both AI and No AI conditions]</head><p>Please write your social media post for the product in the text box below.</p><p>[Text box]</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">[Page Break]</formula><p>We are curious about how you approached this task.</p><p>Please note that your answers to any of the subsequent questions will not affect your base payment or bonus payment in any way.</p><p>[The question below was shown to participants in the AI condition only.]</p><p>Did you consult an AI tool to write your social media post?  Yes, I consulted the ChatGPT interface provided in this study.  Yes, I consulted an AI tool other than the one provided in this study. In this study, you will make decisions as a manager overseeing four gig workers who participated in our previous study on Prolific.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>In our previous study, we asked Prolific workers to craft a social media post promoting the fictional product described below. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with the product.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Product Name:</head><p>"Beannovation"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Product Description:</head><p>Beannovation is a cutting-edge portable coffee maker designed to elevate your coffee experience wherever life takes you. Brew a rich, barista-quality cup in just 3 minutes, ensuring fresh and flavorful coffee every time. Compact and lightweight, Beannovation is perfect for busy commuters, adventure-seekers, and anyone on the go. Its eco-friendly design features a reusable filter, helping reduce waste and saving you money on disposables. Available in a range of stylish colors, Beannovation is as sleek as it is functional. With its USB-rechargeable battery, you can enjoy your coffee anytime-even off the grid. Whether you're exploring the outdoors, at your desk, or relaxing at home, Beannovation ensures your perfect cup is always within reach.</p><p>Based on the information presented above, the workers were tasked with creating a social media post that encourages readers to learn more about the product.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>In this study, you will take on the role of a manager overseeing four workers.</p><p>Please review the submissions from the four workers below and allocate a total bonus of $1.00 among them.</p><p>The bonus amount you assign to each worker will serve as input to determine the actual bonus payment they receive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Note:</head><p>Some workers were provided with an AI tool to assist in creating their social media posts. For each worker below, we have indicated in red font whether the worker used an AI tool.</p><p>[AI vs. No AI manipulation: Below, we randomly chose two of the four submissions to have the note "(who used an AI tool) and the other two submissions to have the note "(who did not use an AI tool).]</p><p>[The four submissions below were shuffled for each participant. For example, the first submission below ("Bring the coffee shop with you…") could have shown up as Submission by Worker 1, 2, 3, or 4 as a result of this shuffling.]</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------</formula><p>Submission by Worker 1 (who used an AI tool) / (who did not use an AI tool):</p><p>"Bring the coffee shop with you everywhere you go with Beannovation! Our portable coffee maker is lightweight, compact, and USB-rechargeable. Make an eco-friendly, barista-quality drink anywhere in just 3 minutes! Check out Beannovation and give a whole new meaning to your daily grind."</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------</formula><p>Submission by Worker 2 (who used an AI tool) / (who did not use an AI tool):</p><p>"Start your morning by skipping the line and bringing our 3-minute barista into your kitchen! USB functionality allows this sleekly designed device to travel to all of your favorite places, letting you sip in luxury! Charge and recharge with us today!" --  In this study, you will evaluate social media posts promoting a fictional product.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>In our previous study, we asked Prolific workers to craft a social media post promoting the fictional product described below. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with the product.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Product Name:</head><p>"Beannovation"</p><p>Product Description:</p><p>Beannovation is a cutting-edge portable coffee maker designed to elevate your coffee experience wherever life takes you. Brew a rich, barista-quality cup in just 3 minutes, ensuring fresh and flavorful coffee every time. Compact and lightweight, Beannovation is perfect for busy commuters, adventure-seekers, and anyone on the go. Its eco-friendly design features a reusable filter, helping reduce waste and saving you money on disposables. Available in a range of stylish colors, Beannovation is as sleek as it is functional. With its USB-rechargeable battery, you can enjoy your coffee anytime-even off the grid. Whether you're exploring the outdoors, at your desk, or relaxing at home, Beannovation ensures your perfect cup is always within reach.</p><p>Starting on the next page, you will review 4 social media posts promoting the product. Please rate each post based on how likely it is to encourage readers to learn more about the product.</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>[The order of the four submissions below was randomized for each judge.]</p><p>"Bring the coffee shop with you everywhere you go with Beannovation! Our portable coffee maker is lightweight, compact, and USB-rechargeable. Make an eco-friendly, barista-quality drink anywhere in just 3 minutes! Check out Beannovation and give a whole new meaning to your daily grind."</p><p>How likely is this post to encourage readers to learn more about the product? (1 = Not likely at all, 7 = Extremely likely)</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>"Start your morning by skipping the line and bringing our 3-minute barista into your kitchen! USB functionality allows this sleekly designed device to travel to all of your favorite places, letting you sip in luxury! Charge and recharge with us today!"</p><p>How likely is this post to encourage readers to learn more about the product? (1 = Not likely at all, 7 = Extremely likely)</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>"Elevate your coffee game with Beannovation! This portable coffee maker brews rich, baristaquality coffee in just 3 minutes, wherever you are. Perfect for commuters, adventurers, and busy lifestyles, its eco-friendly design features a reusable filter and USB-rechargeable battery. Try it today!"</p><p>How likely is this post to encourage readers to learn more about the product? (1 = Not likely at all, 7 = Extremely likely)</p><p>[Page Break]</p><p>"Meet Beannovation, the coffee maker that transforms mornings with cafe-quality brews at the touch of a button! Its sleek design and user-friendly interface make it a kitchen must-have, while eco-friendly features let you enjoy guilt-free sips. Ready for delightful mornings? Get yours today!"</p><p>How likely is this post to encourage readers to learn more about the product? (1 = Not likely at all, 7 = Extremely likely) </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview</head><p>Study S1 was a nearly direct replication of Study 1. The only notable difference was that Study S1 participants entered the study immediately after completing another study for an unrelated project. That is, Study S1 participants were recruited for two studies (one unrelated study for another project and Study S1), whereas Study 1 participants were recruited only for Study 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>The design of Study S1 was identical to that of Study 1, randomly assigning participants to either the AI or No AI condition. Study S1 recruited a slightly larger sample of participants (N = 359), but all other aspects of the study were the same as in Study 1, except for very minor differences (e.g., having a preamble before the scenario for a smoother transition from the unrelated study ["We have one last unrelated question"] or changes in wording such as "Over the course of the year, you have hired different graphic designers…" vs. "Throughout the year, you have hired different graphic designers…").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>As predicted (https://aspredicted.org/swb2-j6d3.pdf) and replicating the results of Study 1, participants offered a smaller payment for the graphic designer in the AI condition (M = $35, SD = $14) than in the No AI condition (M = $47, SD = $9.4), t(357) = -9.74, p &lt; .001, d = -1.03.</p><p>Both the mean payments and effect sizes were comparable to those of Study 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Section 12. Factor Analysis for the Items Measuring Credit Deservingness</head><p>To confirm that the three items measuring credit deservingness, we first conducted a parallel analysis using the R package 'kim' which relies on the R package 'paran' <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Dinno, 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Kim, 2024)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure S1</head><p>Parallel Analysis of the Items Measuring Credit Deservingness</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure S1</ref>, only the first component's eigenvalue exceeded the eigenvalues derived from random data at the 95 th percentile, while second and third components' eigenvalues did not. Thus, the parallel analysis suggests only one factor accounts for variance beyond what would be expected by chance, supporting the retention of a single factor for further analysis.</p><p>We followed up the parallel analysis by conducting a confirmatory factor analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Field et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Revelle, 2024)</ref>. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table S1</ref>, the factor analysis results indicated that a single component accounted for 90% of the total variance in the mediator items, with high factor loadings observed across all items, λs &gt; 0.94. These high loadings suggest that each item strongly reflects the latent construct of credit deservingness.</p><p>The communalities were also high across all the items (h 2 s &gt; 0.89), indicating that the factor of credit deservingness explained a substantial proportion of the variance in each item.</p><p>In addition, a reliability analysis showed high reliability for the three items (α = 0.94, average inter-item correlation = 0.85), suggesting that the mediator items were highly consistent in measuring the construct of credit deservingness. Note. % of variance explained = 90%. α = 0.94. Average inter-item correlation = 0.85.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>The results showed that the indirect effect through credit deservingness was moderated by the binary variable representing our More or Less Permissible condition, the index of moderated mediation = 10.06, SE = 5.09, 95% CI = [0.37, 20.49]. Consistent with our speculation, the indirect effect through credit deservingness was weaker in the Less Permissible condition, a × b = -16.76, SE = 4.13, 95% CI = [-25.41, -9.13], than in the More Permissible condition, a × b = -26.82, SE = 4.07, 95% CI = [</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>participants offered lower hypothetical payments to the designer assisted by AI (M = $35.3, SD = $16.6) than to the designer who received no assistance (M = $48.6, SD = $11.2), t(312) = -8.29, Holm-adjusted p &lt; .001, d = -0.94. More importantly, however, participants offered significantly higher hypothetical payments to the designer assisted by another human (M = $53.6, SD = $16.8) than to the designer who received no assistance (M = $48.6, SD = $11.2), t(312) = 3.13, Holmadjusted p = .002, d = 0.35. That is, instead of observing a reduction in compensation in the Help</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The AI Penalization effect was evident across various types of work, including social media content creation (Study 6), graphic design (Study 1), web design (Study 2B), and work described in general terms (Study 2D). It applied consistently to workers of different statuses, such as salaried (Study 2A), full-time (Study 2B), part-time (Study 2D), and freelance workers (Study 2A). The effect persisted regardless of collaboration history, appearing both for a newly hired worker and a worker with four years of prior collaboration (Study 2C), and was observed whether compensation decisions involved a single worker (Study 1) or multiple workers (Study 2D).The effect also emerged across different forms of compensation, such as a required payment (Study 1), an optional bonus (Study 2A), and a fixed bonus pool distributed among multiple workers (Study 6). It was unaffected by the timing of payment, occurring both before (Study 1) and after task completion (Study 2A), and was robust to various methods used to elicit compensation decisions, including a slider scale (Study 1), a multiple-choice question(Study   2D), and numeric entry (Study 6).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Page Break] Suppose you operate a small business with five [Worker type manipulation: part-time (Temporary Worker condition) / full-time (Permanent Worker condition)] employees.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>ChatGPT and Midjourney) to create the page. (AI condition only)] You are considering offering a bonus for this good work. [Permissibility manipulation: Your company writes into employment contracts to give bonus payments of $100 for extra tasks such as this. (Less Permissible condition) / Your company has in the past consistently given bonus payments of $100 for extra tasks such as this. (More Permissible condition)] How much bonus would you pay them?</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Participants' Choice on Compensation by Condition After a Productivity Growth</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">% of Response Within Each Condition each condition's sample size</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Part-Time Employees 205</cell><cell cols="2">Full-Time Employees 196</cell></row><row><cell>Response</cell><cell>No AI 104</cell><cell>AI 101</cell><cell>No AI 99</cell><cell>AI 97</cell></row><row><cell>Increase the compensation</cell><cell>83%</cell><cell>50%</cell><cell>75%</cell><cell>55%</cell></row><row><cell>Keep the compensation the same</cell><cell>16%</cell><cell>50%</cell><cell>24%</cell><cell>44%</cell></row><row><cell>Decrease the compensation</cell><cell>1%</cell><cell>0%</cell><cell>1%</cell><cell>1%</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Purported use of AI by workers significantly reduced the bonuses allocated by managers.</figDesc><table><row><cell>46, t(418) = -10.61, p</cell></row><row><cell>&lt; .001, even when the model controlled for the effects of workers' different levels of</cell></row><row><cell>performance. Although workers' performance positively predicted the bonus allocated to them (b</cell></row><row><cell>= 2.20, SE = 2.29), this relationship was not statistically significant, t(418) = 0.96, p = .34. When</cell></row><row><cell>we estimate a multiple regression model that does not control for the fixed effects of different</cell></row><row><cell>managers (Model 2 in Table 2) to address possible overfitting in the previous multilevel model</cell></row><row><cell>(implied by the negative adjusted R 2 value of -.05 in Model 1), we essentially obtain the same</cell></row><row><cell>results:</cell></row></table><note>workers' performance, while controlling for the fixed effects of different managers; see Model 1 in Table 2. Consistent with the results from the dependent t-test, we find that the purported use of AI by workers led the managers to significantly reduce their compensation, b = -15.45, SE = 1.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Multilevel Modeling and Regression Analyses Accounting for Workers' Performance</figDesc><table><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>Fixed Effects of Managers Added?</cell><cell>Variable</cell><cell>b</cell><cell>SE</cell><cell>p</cell></row><row><cell>1 R 2 = .21 Adj. R 2 = -.05</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell cols="4">Purported Use of AI by Worker -15.45 1.46 &lt; .001 Worker's Performance 2.20 2.29 .34</cell></row><row><cell>2 R 2 = .21 Adj. R 2 = .21</cell><cell>No</cell><cell cols="4">(Intercept) Purported Use of AI by Worker -15.45 1.26 &lt; .001 22.06 9.65 .023 Worker's Performance 2.20 1.99 .27</cell></row></table><note>Note. Dependent Variable: Bonus in number of cents (Allocated by Manager to Worker).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>and Other Directions for Future Research While</head><label></label><figDesc>This result is interesting because what separate AI from other tools is arguably the human-likeness of AI. Accordingly, one might think that assistance from AI and assistance from another human might lead to similar reductions in compensation (at least to the extent that AI is like a human). But this is not what we find. If there is indeed something unique about AI (apart from its human-likeness) that drove the AI Penalization effect, it underscores the need for further research to understand exactly what it is about AI that produces phenomena like the AI Penalization effect. our approach of controlling for natural outcomes of workers' AI use (e.g., performance boost or effort reduction) enhances the internal validity of our findings, it may limit their ecological validity. To investigate the effect of AI use in isolation, we ensured in almost all our studies that the only difference between the AI and No AI conditions was the disclosure of the workers' use of AI. In other words, apart from the information on whether workers used AI or not, we eliminated all other sources of variation, such as differences in workers' effort or performance. Although this careful manipulation ensured that any effect on worker compensation would be exclusively attributed to AI use (and any resulting inferences), it may have had an unintentional negative impact on the ecological validity of our findings. In real work settings, AI use can impact various factors of work that can affect decisions on worker compensation. For example, recent research shows that AI use can improve workers'</figDesc><table><row><cell>Limitations</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Today, you found another graphic designer who agreed to create a new ad for you in an hour.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Section 5. Study 2C Materials Section 6. Study 2D Materials</cell></row><row><cell>[Prolific ID Entry and Consent Form] [Prolific ID Entry and Consent Form]</cell></row><row><cell>[Page Break] [Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>Thank you for participating in our study!</cell></row><row><cell>[Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>Imagine that you run a small business.</cell></row><row><cell>[Collaboration history manipulation: Over the course of the year, you have hired different</cell></row><row><cell>graphic designers to create social media ads for your business, paying each designer between $40</cell></row><row><cell>and $60 for about an hour's work. (No History condition) / Over the course of the past 4 years,</cell></row><row><cell>you have been working with a graphic designer to create social media ads for your business,</cell></row><row><cell>paying the designer between $40 and $60 for about an hour's work. (Long History condition)]</cell></row><row><cell>How much payment would you offer them?</cell></row><row><cell>Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>Demographics Form [Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>How old are you? Demographics Form</cell></row><row><cell>_____ How old are you?</cell></row><row><cell>What is your gender? _____</cell></row><row><cell>Man / Woman / Other ________ What is your gender?</cell></row><row><cell>Man / Woman / Other ________</cell></row></table><note>[AI vs. No AI manipulation: The graphic designer asked if they can work with an AI system for creating the ad, to which you agreed. (AI condition only)]</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>decrease the compensation / keep the compensation the same / increase the compensation.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Section 7. Study 3 Materials</cell></row><row><cell>[Prolific ID Entry and Consent Form]</cell></row><row><cell>[Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>[Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>[Exploratory Item]</cell></row><row><cell>Please briefly explain why you would [Text box]</cell></row><row><cell>[Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>Demographics Form</cell></row><row><cell>How old are you?</cell></row><row><cell>_____</cell></row><row><cell>What is your gender?</cell></row><row><cell>Man / Woman / Other ________</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>In this part of the study, we are interested in your thoughts regarding the scenario.</figDesc><table><row><cell>[Mediator: Credit Deservingness] Section 8. Study 4 Materials</cell></row><row><cell>[Prolific ID Entry and Consent Form]</cell></row><row><cell> How much credit do you think the graphic designer deserves for creating the ad? (1 = No [Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>credit at all, 7 = All the credit)  How responsible do you think the graphic designer was for creating the ad? (1 = Not at</cell></row><row><cell>all responsible, 7 = Completely responsible)  How important do you think the graphic designer's role was in creating the ad? (1 = Not</cell></row><row><cell>at all important, 7 = Extremely important)</cell></row><row><cell>[Page Break]</cell></row><row><cell>Demographics Form</cell></row><row><cell>How old are you?</cell></row><row><cell>_____</cell></row><row><cell>What is your gender?</cell></row><row><cell>Man / Woman / Other ________</cell></row><row><cell>How much payment would you offer them?</cell></row><row><cell>[Page Break]</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Beannovation is a cutting-edge portable coffee maker designed to elevate your coffee experience wherever life takes you. Brew a rich, barista-quality cup in just 3 minutes, ensuring fresh and flavorful coffee every time. Compact and lightweight, Beannovation is perfect for busy commuters, adventure-seekers, and anyone on the go. Its eco-friendly design features a reusable filter, helping reduce waste and saving you money on disposables. Available in a range of stylish colors, Beannovation is as sleek as it is functional. With its USB-rechargeable battery, you can enjoy your coffee anytime-even off the grid. Whether you're exploring the outdoors, at your desk, or relaxing at home, Beannovation ensures your perfect cup is always within reach.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Your post should:</cell></row><row><cell>1. Highlight the key benefit(s) of Beannovation.</cell></row><row><cell>2. Use an engaging and friendly tone.</cell></row><row><cell>3. End with a call to action (for example, "Get yours today").</cell></row><row><cell>Example (Do NOT Copy):</cell></row><row><cell>"Meet Beannovation, your new coffee companion! Brew a perfect cup in just 3 minutes,</cell></row><row><cell>anytime, anywhere. Get yours today and elevate your coffee game!"</cell></row><row><cell>Product Name:</cell></row><row><cell>"Beannovation"</cell></row><row><cell>Product Description:</cell></row></table><note>[AI vs. No AI manipulation: AI condition only]</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>The question below was shown to participants who answered "Yes…" to either of the two questions above.]</head><label></label><figDesc>No, I did not consult any AI tool. Did you consult an AI tool to write your social media post?  Yes, I consulted an AI tool (like ChatGPT, Gemini, etc.)  No, I did not consult any AI tool. How did you use the AI tool's response(s)?  I submitted what the AI tool gave me (without editing it).  I edited what the AI tool gave me a little bit before submitting it.  I edited what the AI tool gave me a lot before submitting it.  I only used what the AI tool gave me for inspiration or copyediting. I essentially wrote what I submitted.  I did not use what the AI tool gave me at all.  I used what the AI tool gave me in some other way (please specify): __________ [Page Break]</figDesc><table><row><cell>[Part 2 recruiting managers]</cell></row><row><cell>[Page Break] How old are you? _____ What is your gender? -Man / Woman / Other ________ What is your race or ethnicity? -White / Hispanic, Latino, or Spanish / Black or African American / Asian / American Indian or Alaska Native / Middle Eastern or North African / Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander / Some other race or ethnicity What is the highest level of education you have completed? -Did not complete high school / High school graduate / Some college, no degree / Associate's degree / Bachelor's degree / Master's, Professional, or Doctorate degree Approximately, how much is your annual household income? -[21 Choices] Less than $10,000 / $10,000 -$19,999 / … / $190,000 -$199,999 / $200,000 or more [Prolific ID Entry and Consent Form] [Page Break] [Demographics Form Thank you for participating!</cell></row></table><note>[The question below was shown to participants in the No AI condition only.]</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14"><head>Table S1</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Factor Analysis of the Items Measuring Credit Deservingness</figDesc><table><row><cell>#</cell><cell>Item</cell><cell>Factor Loading</cell><cell>Commu-nality</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">1 How much credit do you think the graphic designer deserves for creating the ad? (1 = No credit at all, 7 = All the credit)</cell><cell>.95</cell><cell>.90</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">2 How responsible do you think the graphic designer was for creating the ad? (1 = Not at all responsible, 7 = Completely responsible)</cell><cell>.95</cell><cell>.91</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">3 How important do you think the graphic designer's role was in creating the ad? (1 = Not at all important, 7 = Extremely important)</cell><cell>.94</cell><cell>.89</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supporting Information for</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>People Reduce Workers' Compensation for Using Artificial Intelligence</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">-Submission by Worker 3 (who used an AI tool) / (who did not use an AI tool): &quot;Elevate your coffee game with Beannovation! This portable coffee maker brews rich, baristaquality coffee in just 3 minutes, wherever you are. Perfect for commuters, adventurers, and busy lifestyles, its eco-friendly design features a reusable filter and USB-rechargeable battery</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Ready for delightful mornings? Get yours today!</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>-Submission by Worker 4 (who used an AI tool) / (who did not use an AI tool): &quot;Meet Beannovation, the coffee maker that transforms mornings with cafe-quality brews at the touch of a button! Its sleek design and user-friendly interface make it a kitchen must-have, while eco-friendly features let you enjoy guilt-free sips</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Artificial intelligence, automation, and work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Acemoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Restrepo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The economics of artificial intelligence: An agenda</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>University of Chicago Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="197" to="236" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Flexible work arrangements in low wage jobs: Evidence from job vacancy data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Adams-Prassl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Balgova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IZA Discussion Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Research note-Are online labor markets spot markets for tasks? A field experiment on the behavioral response to wage cuts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Horton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Systems Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="423" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Copestake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marczinek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pople</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Stapleton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://copestake.info/workingpaper/akai/AKAI.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AI and Services-Led Growth: Evidence from Indian Job Adverts</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">paran: Horn&apos;s Test of Principal Components/Factors. The Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dinno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.32614/CRAN.package.paran</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.32614/CRAN.package.paran" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Credit and blame for AI-generated content: Effects of personalization in four countries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Earp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Porsdam Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Hannikainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Khan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Savulescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Measuring the impact of AI on information worker productivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Edelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ngwe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Available at SSRN 4648686</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Artificial intelligence, tasks, skills and wages: Worker-level evidence from Germany</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Engberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lodefalk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schroeder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Felten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Raj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Seamans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2303.01157</idno>
		<title level="m">How will language modelers like chatgpt affect occupations and industries</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv Preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Field</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Miles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Field</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Discovering Statistics Using R</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>SAGE Publications</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">778</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">760</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The four elementary forms of sociality: Framework for a unified theory of social relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="689" to="723" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How are patented AI, software and robot technologies related to wage changes in the United States?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fossen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Samaan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sorgner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">869282</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relational models theory: A confirmatory factor analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Haslam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personal Relationships</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="250" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to mediation, moderation, and conditional process analysis: A regression-based approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The short-term effects of generative artificial intelligence on employment: Evidence from an online labor market</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Reshef</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organization Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fairness as a constraint on profit seeking: Entitlements in the market</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Knetsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="728" to="741" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ai, skill, and productivity: The case of taxi drivers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kanazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kawaguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Shigeoka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">National Bureau of Economic Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.32614/CRAN.package.kim</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.32614/CRAN.package.kim" />
		<title level="m">A Toolkit for Behavioral Scientists. The Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">AI and Entitlement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cusimano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Unpublished Manuscript</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">G4R: GPT Interface for Researchers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cusimano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cremer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://g4r.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human perceptions on moral responsibility of AI: A case study in AI-assisted bail decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Grgić-Hlača</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">News from generative artificial intelligence is believed less</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Longoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fradkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2022 ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency</title>
		<meeting>the 2022 ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="106" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Humans as creativity gatekeepers: Are we biased against AI creativity?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Magni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business and Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="656" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Maslej</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fattorini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Perrault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Parli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Reuel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Brynjolfsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Etchemendy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ligett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lyons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Manyika</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Niebles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shoham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.19522" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Artificial Intelligence Index Report</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Microsoft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
			<biblScope unit="page">7</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">2024 Work Trend Index Annual Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experimental evidence on the productivity effects of generative artificial intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Noy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">381</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6654</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="192" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Attributions of ethical responsibility by Artificial Intelligence practitioners. Information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Orr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<publisher>Communication &amp; Society</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="719" to="735" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How much does AI impact development speed? An enterprise-based randomized controlled trial</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Paradis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Grey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Madison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Macvean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Meimand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ferrari-Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2410.12944</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv Preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kalliamvakou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cihon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Demirer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2302.06590</idno>
		<title level="m">The impact of ai on developer productivity: Evidence from github copilot</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv Preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Qiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Rui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Xiong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2312.04180</idno>
		<title level="m">AI and Jobs: Has the Inflection Point Arrived? Evidence from an Online Labor Platform</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv Preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ai-generated vs. Human artworks. A perception bias towards artificial intelligence?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ragot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cojean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Extended Abstracts of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Revelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">psych: Procedures for Psychological, Psychometric, and Personality Research. The Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.32614/CRAN.package.psych</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.32614/CRAN.package.psych" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The state of AI in early 2024: Gen AI adoption spikes and starts to generate value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Singla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sukharevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Yee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Workforce Index</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Slack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Who Gets the Credit? Selfother differences in evaluating workplace collaboration with generative AI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ibrahim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rudd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024-06-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Behavioral Decision Research in Management (BDRM) Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Chicago</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generative artificial intelligence, human creativity, and art</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PNAS Nexus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">52</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
