<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The illusion of information adequacy: A corollary to naïve realism</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hunter</forename><surname>Gehlbach</surname></persName>
							<email>gehlbach@jhu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carly</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
							<email>carly_robinson@stanford.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angus</forename><surname>Fletcher</surname></persName>
							<email>fletcher.300@osu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The illusion of information adequacy: A corollary to naïve realism</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:02+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Treatment 1a</term>
					<term>Survey Group Information adequacy Decision-making competence Key details Lingering questions Curious Demographic items Treatment 2a</term>
					<term>Survey Group Information adequacy Decision-making competence Key details Lingering questions Curious Demographic items</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Read pro-separation article Measures completed: Decision to merge False consensus Confidence in recommendation Read pro-merge article Measures completed: Decision to merge False consensus Confidence in recommendation Read balanced article Measures completed: Information adequacy Decision-making competence Decision to merge False consensus Confidence in recommendation Key details Lingering questions Curious Demographic items Treatment 2b: Additional Article Group (N = 252) Read 2 nd article (pro-merge arguments) Measures completed: Decision to merge False consensus Confidence in recommendation Information comparison Key details Lingering questions Demographic items Treatment 1b: Additional Article Group (N = 252) Read 2 nd article (pro-separation arguments) Measures completed: Decision to merge False consensus Confidence in recommendation Information comparison Key details Lingering questions Demographic items</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Abstract</head><p>The theory of naïve realism suggests that many disagreements occur because different parties construe the same situation differently. The present study proposes a corollary: the illusion of information adequacy. Specifically, we argue that in addition divergent construals of the same situation, naïve realism is precipitated by people who are exposed to different information assuming that their information is sufficient to adequately understand the situation.</p><p>Participants in our preregistered studies (Ns = 218 and 1261, respectively) responded to a hypothetical scenario in which control participants received full information and treatment participants received approximately half of that same information. Across both studies, we found that treatment participants assumed that they had comparably adequate information and that they were just as competent in making a thoughtful decision based on that information. Participants' decisions were heavily influenced by which cross-section of information they received. Finally, in line with the false consensus effect, participants believed that most other people would make a similar decision to the one they made. We discuss the implications of this corollary to naïve realism within the context of interpersonal conflict resolution strategies.</p><p>You don't know what you don't know.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>--Socrates</head><p>There are known knowns. These are things we know that we know. There are known unknowns. That is to say, there are things that we know we don't know. But there are also unknown unknowns. There are things we don't know we don't know.</p><p>--Donald Rumsfeld Naïve realism <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Robinson et al., 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Ross &amp; Ward, 1996)</ref> causes a host of relationship problems from the interpersonal to the international. As naïve realists, individuals believe they accurately perceive objective reality. They assume that rational others will agree with their reactions, behaviors, and opinions. When others disagree, it must be because these people (a) have been exposed to different information, (b) are unwilling or unable to logically proceed from objective evidence to reasonable conclusion, or (c) are biased <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Ross &amp; Ward, 1996)</ref>.</p><p>For those interested in resolving conflicts, this theory raises the important question: What lies upstream from naïve realism? According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Robinson et al. (1995)</ref>, people hold divergent perceptions of reality primarily because they construe the situation in different ways. We propose that an equally important tributary feeding the river of misunderstanding that sets the stage for naïve realism is the illusion of information adequacy. Differences in construal may be particularly helpful in understanding how naïve realism affects people's thinking about major conflicts (e.g., political disagreements, international discord, etc.) where knowledge about both sides is readily available. However, at the interpersonal level, many misunderstandings arise over minutiae where information may not be readily accessible to each party. In these cases, perceivers' tacit assumption that the quantity and caliber of the information that they know provides them with an adequate, objective understanding of the situation may be especially helpful in explaining what precipitates naïve realism. Given the havoc that these minor misunderstandings can inflict over time, documenting and understanding this phenomenon could have immense value for improving our interpersonal relationships.</p><p>From Socrates to Rumsfeld, people have realized that there is much that they do not know, including a meta-awareness that there are some things that they are unaware of that they also do not know. However, we hypothesize that people frequently lose track of this fact and navigate their social worlds while confidently assuming that they have adequate information. They form opinions, reify values, and behave in ways that suggest that they have sufficient information to make rational decisions even when they have minimal understanding of how much they do not know.</p><p>This illusion of adequate information creates strong enabling conditions for a second pathway to naïve realism. Imagine two individuals who were exposed to half the information required for a clear understanding of a situation. Each party thinks that they understand the full picture but actually holds a sense of reality that is impoverished by 50%. In this hypothesized case, both parties would maintain robust confidence that they see the situation as it truly is-i.e., close enough to 100% for a clear, actionable understanding.</p><p>If, by coincidence, two parties gain exposure to the exact same sample of half the information, then naïve realism would only occur through different construals of that information. However, in many situations we contend that, perceivers will frequently be privy to distinct cross-sections of the information. Their assumptions that they perceive objective reality will rest upon completely different samples of that reality. Our theory of information adequacy anticipates that each individual will nevertheless retain a robust level of confidence (i.e., that they know more than 50%) in their perception of the situation. Thus, we posit that the illusion of information adequacy represents an additional, critical contributor to naïve realism and the conflicts that it amplifies. This article describes two preregistered experiments that demonstrate this phenomenon of the illusion of information adequacy. Our preliminary study (preregistered at https://osf.io/2h9kj) focused on adolescents on the premise that they might be particularly susceptible to the illusion of information adequacy, given the still-developing stage of their abstract and counterfactual thinking <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Elkind, 1974;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Inhelder &amp; Piaget, 1958;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Lapsley et al., 1986)</ref>. Our second study (preregistered at https://osf.io/wqksj) replicates the first on a broader sample of adults, improves the research design, and presents additional exploratory analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Naïve Realism in Context</head><p>In their original formulation of naïve realism, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Robinson et al. (1995)</ref> describe how people construing the same situation in distinct ways catalyzes naïve realism. How can community members look at the same wind farm proposal and be convinced that either (a) these eyesores will jeopardize their property values and destroy the economic prosperity of their town or (b) pave the way towards a clean energy future that will ensure the health and well-being of future generations? The theory suggests that these distinct perceptions of the same proposal will arise because people attach different levels of importance to different characteristics of the situation (e.g., upfront economic costs versus long-term health risks). Moreover, perceivers on both sides underestimate the subjectiveness of their read of the situation by assuming their perception to be more objective than it really is (e.g., presuming one's opinion about the aesthetic value of a wind turbine to be a consensus view). Furthermore, perceivers struggle to accept that someone else could construe the information or draw conclusions in a different, yet still reasonable, way. This assumption that others are being unreasonable sets the stage for the misunderstanding, frustration, and distrust of naïve realism, thereby exacerbating many conflicts.</p><p>A scan of the naïve realism literature reveals that many studies establish and explore the phenomenon focus in the context of prominent public issues-issues which encompass lots of relevant, well-known information and arguments. Past scholars have investigated the abortion debate <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Robinson et al., 1995)</ref>, affirmative action <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Sherman et al., 2003)</ref>, the Israeli-Palestinian conflict <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Maoz et al., 2002)</ref>, and other well-known current events of the time <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Liberman et al., 2011)</ref>. In these illustrations or the aforementioned wind farm example, construal almost certainly matters lot. While Republicans and Democrats, Israelis and Palestinians, or Real Madrid and Barcelona fans may have deep, overlapping knowledge bases, thanks to differences in construal, they draw very different conclusions.</p><p>Yet, for many of the disagreements of daily life-the routine and interpersonal rather than the dramatic and international-we may lack strong prior opinions and/or exposure to substantial proportions of the relevant information. For example, many people have disagreed with (otherwise sensible, rational) work colleagues, only to find out later that critical information from an email landed in a spam filter and was not read. Even during the days of writing this paper, the lead author fell prey to the illusion when he pulled up behind another car at a stop sign. When the other car did not proceed in timely fashion, the author "knew" that the other driver lost concentration and so used his horn to provide a firm call to attention… only to realize that the missing information, obscured from view, was a mother about to push her stroller across the intersection.</p><p>In conflicts like these, we argue that the first possibility of naïve realism-that the parties were exposed to different information-is not what triggers the assumption of perceiving objective reality. Rather, perceivers think that they perceive objective reality (and the other party is deficient) because they tacitly assume that they have sufficient information to make competent inferences, conclusions, and decisions. In other words, if people navigated their social worlds while humbly appreciating that they may lack relevant information, the exposure to different samples of information would not lead to the naïve realist's assumption that they see objective reality.</p><p>The original theory notes that exposure to distinct sources of information may cause distinct perceptions and suggests optimistically that "provided that the other party is reasonable and open minded, the sharing or pooling of information should lead us to reach agreement" <ref type="bibr">(Ross &amp; Ward, 1996, p. 111)</ref>. However, we argue that because people will assume that their particular (incomplete) slice of information is adequate, they will not only assume that they are seeing objective reality, but they will also fail to entertain the question of what additional puzzle pieces they may be missing. Because of their tacit assumption that they possess sufficient information, perceivers will then: presume that they are competent to make decisions based on that information, make decisions that are biased by their particular cross-section of information, and assume that others would draw the same conclusions as they have drawn-i.e., the false consensus effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Ross, Greene, et al., 1977)</ref>.</p><p>Though ostensibly lower stakes, these daily disagreements and misunderstandings can play an outsized role in our relationships (see for example <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gottman &amp; Gottman, 2017)</ref>. We offer the present studies to provide evidence for the illusion of information adequacy in the context of more routine differences of opinion that require the processing of new information. We see this corollary to the theory as complementing naïve realism's frequent focus on prominent public issues in which information on both sides may already be well-known.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1 Hypotheses</head><p>We hypothesize that the illusion of adequate information catalyzes four specific phenomenon in situations where parties are exposed to different amounts and types of information relevant to understanding a situation. First, regardless of the quantity of information individuals learn about a situation (e.g., half or all the information), parties will think that they have similarly adequate amounts. Second, irrespective of whether they are privy to full or only partial information, people will deem themselves equally competent to make decisions based on that information. Third, the type of information people learn will impact their beliefs, attitudes, opinions, etc. In other words, in our hypothetical dilemma where a school board must decide whether to merge schools or keep them separate, exposure to arguments that suggest merging schools is a good idea would lead people to advocate for the merging the schools; and vice-versa for keeping the schools separate. Fourth, in line with the false consensus effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Ross, Greene, et al., 1977)</ref>, people will reinforce their sense that they perceive the situation in an objectively correct way by assuming that most others would make the same decision that they did.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>We conducted our first study in collaboration with the Character Lab Research Network (CLRN). CLRN cultivates and maintains partnerships with middle and high schools across the United States who are interested in participating in research studies. For participating schools, CLRN distributed the different versions of an article and corresponding survey to the students in participating classrooms, oversaw the data collection, and returned an anonymized data set to us for analysis. In turn, students at these participating schools were randomly assigned to read a version of this article (ostensibly from the Prairie View school newspaper about the school board's decision whether or not to merge their school with another in its district), selected a recommended course of action, and completed survey questions related to the vignette and their recommendation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Although we requested 600 participants and assumed a typical distribution of male and female students, CLRN ultimately secured 237 participants (19 of whom did not answer any questions). In addition, the sample was 99% female sample, with 2 students selecting "Other" or "Prefer not to say". Thus, our final sample (N = 218) was substantially smaller and more homogeneous than anticipated. Attrition from our 237 initial participants to our final sample of 218 did not differ by condition (ncontrol = 72, npro-merging = 75, npro-separation = 71). The sample was 80% white, 10% Asian, and 8% Black, with 7% identifying as Hispanic and consisted entirely of high school students (Mgrade level = 10.54, sd = 1.11; Mage = 15.98, sd = 1.28).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures</head><p>Our primary outcomes of interest included students' perceptions of the adequacy of the information that they read, their confidence in making a competent decision based on that information, which decision they recommended, and the percentage of individuals they expected would make the same recommendation.</p><p>The information adequacy scale ( = .74) consisted of five self-report items with fullylabeled verbal response options designed to assess the extent to which students felt as though the information they read in the article was sufficient, credible, and comprehensive enough to give them a reasonably complete sense of the overall situation. "In making your decision, how much of what you needed to know about the two schools did the article provide?" was a representative item.</p><p>The decision-making competence scale ( = .37) also consisted of five self-report items with fully-labeled verbal response options. This measure assessed students' perceptions that they could make a competent recommendation regarding the fate of the school based on the article that they read, e.g., "How thoughtfully did you weigh all the information in the article?" This scale included one reverse-scored item.</p><p>The decision outcome was a binary choice, "What decision would you recommend that the school board make." Response options were "Merge Prairie View into Landon" or "Keep the schools separate."</p><p>Our consensus outcome was a single item designed to assess the false-consensus effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Ross, Greene, et al., 1977)</ref> using a 0-to-100 slider that asked, "About what percentage of people do you think would make the same decision as you did?"</p><p>The comprehensive list of the measures used in this study are posted publicly at https://osf.io/f5ngd. For ease of interpretation across the different outcomes, all scores were mathematically transformed to scores ranging from 0 to 1 prior to analyzing our prespecified hypotheses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Upon entering the survey, students were randomly assigned to one of three groups that differed by the content of the article that they were assigned to read. Each participant read a school newspaper article, entitled Our School Water is Disappearing. The piece described a school located in a region where the local aquifer was drying up. Consequently, the school faced a decision to risk staying put (and hope for more rain in the future) or to merge with another school (a decision that entailed other risks). The control group's version of the article presented seven facts about the situation: three facts described benefits of merging, three identified benefits of remaining separate, and one neutral piece of information. The pro-merge treatment participants' article presented the three facts describing the benefits of merging and the neutral piece of information; the pro-separate participants' article presented the three facts about the benefits of remaining separate and the neutral information. The text for the articles can be found on the Intervention tab of our codebook: https://osf.io/f5ngd. After reading their respective articles, all participants recommended that the schools either merge or remain separate. The students then completed the other survey measures as described above and as presented in our codebook (https://osf.io/f5ngd). Finally, the two treatment groups read the information that had been previously excluded from their initial articles and filled out two exploratory measures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preliminary analyses</head><p>The descriptive statistics and correlations presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> provide context for our primary variables of interest. For instance, overall the students favored the decision to merge with the other school by a little more than a 2:1 ratio. In general, participants' scores for information adequacy and decision-making competence reflect responses between the "somewhat" and "quite" (relevant, believable, trustworthy, etc.) options; for consensus, participants thought 57% of other people would make the same decision they did. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Prespecified hypotheses</head><p>First, we wanted to document the extent to which an illusion of information adequacy existed. Specifically, in our study, we tested whether the participants who received half of the information felt as though had comparably adequate information to those in the control condition, who were exposed to twice as much information. Specifically, we hypothesized that the combined treatment groups would not differ significantly from the control group on our information adequacy scale. To test this prespecified hypothesis, we fit an ordinary least squares (OLS) regression model. Because our randomization produced approximately equivalent groups by condition, we did not include any addition covariates for this or any of the other analyses in Study 1. Our model supported this hypothesis Pooled = 0.006, 95% CI [-0.031, 0.043], adjusted R 2 = -0.004. As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, none of the groups differ in any meaningful way. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean ra ngs of adequacy of informa on by condi on and 95% CIs</head><p>From the correlations in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>, it is clear that participants' perceptions of information adequacy are associated with the ability to make a good decision. Our second hypothesis tests whether the pooled treatment groups would perceive their decision-making competence to be as high as the control group, despite being provided with half as much information. Our OLS model supported this prespecified hypothesis Pooled = 0.01, 95% CI [-0.024, 0.037], adjusted R 2 = -0.004. See <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean ra ngs of confidence in decision-making by condi on and 95% CIs</head><p>Given that participants perceived that they had adequate information and thought they could make competent decisions based on that information, we then tested whether they made different decisions based on this information. Congruent with our hypothesis, our OLS model indicated that 91% of the "pro-merge" treatment participants recommended that the schools merge Pro-merge = .12, 95% CI [-0.015, 0.245]; correspondingly the "pro-separation" participants were more likely to recommend that the schools remain separate Pro-separate = -.44, 95% CI [-0.571, -0.308], as compared to the control group adjusted R 2 = .26. <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> shows the mean proportions for each group. Although the directionality of the results matched expectations, the distribution of responses was less balanced than we had anticipated-a strong majority in the control group favored merging the schools. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean propor ons of par cipants from each condi on recommending merging and 95% CIs</head><p>Finally, we examined whether each group would predict that a majority of people would make the same recommendation that they had made-i.e., display the false consensus effect. To evaluate this hypothesis, we conducted three one-sample t-tests to see whether each mean was significantly higher than 50%. As <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean ra ngs of consensus of recommenda on by condi on and 95% CIs</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>This study provides evidence that people tend to assume that they have adequate information about a situation even when they may lack critically informative perspectives. Furthermore, they assume a moderately high level of competence to make a reasonable decision using this information. The information they are exposed to strongly influences their recommendations. Finally, in line with the second tenet of naïve realism <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Ross &amp; Ward, 1996)</ref> and the false consensus effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Ross, Greene, et al., 1977)</ref>, they assume that most other (reasonable) people would come to the same recommendation that they did. On the one hand, our data provide strong support for our hypothesis that people may operate under an illusion of adequate information, even when they lack important data or perspectives. On the other hand, a number of quirks-ranging from the female sample, to the lack of reliability on the decision-making competence scale, to the smaller than anticipated sample size-may undermine readers' confidence in the results and/or in the generalizability of the findings. To try and address these and other shortcomings, we conducted a second study with several improvements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2 Methods</head><p>In addition to testing the replicability of Study 1, the primary goals of Study 2 were to (a) improve the decision-making competence measure, (b) revise the article that participants read so as to get a more even distribution of recommendations to the school board, (c) to buttress our key outcome measures with convergent assessments, (d) test the extent to which treatment participants stuck to their original recommendation after exposure to the remaining information (i.e., the three facts that were omitted from their original article), (e) improve the experimental design to ensure that our survey questions did not bias treatment participants' reading of the additional facts, and (f) obtain a more representative sample with respect to gender. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> depicts the survey flow for different participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited an initial group of 1501 participants within the United States using the online platform, Prolific. We excluded those who failed an attention check question prior to entering the study (n = 240). Our final sample (N = 1261) had 252 participants in the control group, 503 in the pro-merge condition, and 506 in the pro-separate condition. The two treatment groups were randomly divided a second time so that, after making an initial recommendation regarding the merging of the schools, approximately 50% of each treatment group was routed into a set of survey questions asking them to evaluate the information they received in the article, while the other 50% read a second article containing the additional facts they had not previous received before responding to questions that allowed them to revise their initial recommendation.</p><p>The majority male sample (59%) was predominantly White (71%); others identified as Asian/ Pacific Islander (9%), Black (11%), or Other (3%), and 8% identified as Hispanic. Participants' mean age was 39.8 years (sd = 13.6), with a median education level of 3 years of college. Politically, 651 participants identified as liberals, 254 as moderates, and 356 as conservatives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures</head><p>Study 2 also relied upon information adequacy ( = .79), decision-making competence scale ( = .76), decision to merge (M = .55), and consensus (M = .65, sd = 0.16) as key outcome measures. In addition to updating the article, we revised the decision-making competence scale in an effort to improve the scale's reliability; the other three measures remained identical to those used in Study 1.</p><p>For the purposes of exploratory analyses, several other measures were added. On 0-100 slider bar scales, all participants were asked to rate their confidence in their decision using a single item, "How confident are you that this is the smartest action for the school board to take?" Next, treatment groups 1a, 2a, and the control group responded to the following three items on 0-100 slider bars:</p><p> "To what extent do you feel that you understand enough of the key details of the situation to make a good decision?"  "To what extent do you feel as though you still have questions about important details of Prairie View's situation?" and  "How curious would you be to read a second article to learn more about this school's dilemma?"</p><p>For treatment participants who were instead routed to read a second article with the arguments they had not previously read (i.e., groups 1b and 2b), we reassessed their recommendations using our decision to merge, consensus, and confidence measures. These participants then completed an information comparison scale (.88) which asked participants to compare the information between the first and second articles on criteria like relevance, trustworthiness, and importance. Finally, we reassessed these treatment participants' perceptions with the key details and questions items described above.</p><p>The full codebook can be accessed here: https://osf.io/pgezc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>One motive for the design of this second experiment was to ensure that the questions regarding information adequacy and decision-making competence did not inadvertently suggest to participants that they perhaps did not have sufficient information to make a fully informed recommendation. To that end, after randomly assigning participants to either of the two treatment conditions or the control condition, we sub-divided each treatment group to either: (a) respond to survey questions (regarding information adequacy, decision-making competence, consensus, and other exploratory measures) or (b) to read a second article that exposed them to the remaining arguments to merge or maintain separation of the two schools (so that we could reassess their recommendations). Beyond that alteration to the research design, the procedures of Study 1 mirrored Study 2. See <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preliminary analyses</head><p>In line with our preregistration, we conducted a multinomial logistic regression to test whether participant demographics predicted condition assignment. We find no evidence to that effect, LR (14) = 11.26, p = .665, pseudo R 2 = 0.005. Thus, we do not employ any covariates in any of the models we report (i.e., we had no need to correct for imbalances in condition assignment).</p><p>As before, we present the descriptive statistics and correlations for our primary variables of interest in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pre-specified Hypotheses</head><p>First, we wanted to see whether participants in this sample perceived themselves as having adequate information about the situation even though the treatment groups had only half of the information of the control group. Specifically, we tested whether the combined treatment groups 1a and 2a (who were routed directly to survey questions after making their initial recommendations) would perceive the caliber of the information that they received as comparable to the control group. Our OLS model supported this prespecified hypothesis Pooled = 0.00, 95% CI [-0.021, 0.022], adjusted R 2 = -.001. To help contextualize these numbers, the raw mean responses were closer to the "quite" (relevant, believable, trustworthy, etc.) than the "somewhat" response option for all three groups. See <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean ra ngs of adequacy of informa on by condi on in Study 2 and 95% CIs</head><p>Next, we tested whether the pooled treatment groups 1a and 2a would perceive their ability to make a competent decision based on the information they read to be as high as the control group's perceived ability. Our OLS model supported this prespecified hypothesis also Pooled = 0.00, 95% CI [-0.018, 0.019], adjusted R 2 = -.001. In addition to the consistency of the means between the groups, it is worth noting the relatively high overall means-on average, participants responses were modestly higher than qualitative values corresponding to being "quite" objective, careful, fair, etc. in evaluating the information and making a decision. See <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean ra ngs of confidence in decision-making by condi on in Study 2 and 95% CIs</head><p>For our third prespecified hypothesis, we fit an OLS regression model to test for differences in the initial recommended decisions of our different groups. Congruent with our hypothesis, we found that "pro-merge" treatment participants (groups 1a and 1b) were significantly more likely to recommend that the schools merge Pro-merge = 0.33, 95% CI [0.27, 0.40]; and the "pro-separation" participants (treatment groups 2a and 2b) were significantly more likely to recommend that the schools remain separate Pro-separate = -0.32, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-0.38, -0.26]</ref>, as compared to the control group adjusted R 2 = .34. See <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>. This time, the distribution of responses was more balanced than in the first study-e.g., 55% of the control group favored merging the schools (as opposed to 79% in Study 1). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean propor ons of par cipants from each condi on recommending merging in Study 2 and 95% CIs</head><p>Then we examined whether each group would predict that a majority of people would make the same recommendation that they had made-i.e., display the false consensus effect. To evaluate this hypothesis we conducted three single-sample t-tests (for the control group, the pooled treatment group of 1a and 1b, and the pooled treatment group of 2a and 2b) to see whether each mean was significantly higher than 50%. We found that participants in each condition believed that the majority of other people would reach the same recommendation that they did; Mcontrol  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mean ra ngs of consensus of recommenda on by condi on and 95% CIs</head><p>Finally, we predicted that treatment groups 2a and 2b (who, after making their initial recommendations, read a second article providing the other half of the information that the control group received) would endorse their initial recommendation in significantly higher proportions than the control group (55% of whom recommended merging). In other words, we anticipated that the original information these treatment groups received-despite its partial nature-would help them form opinions that would be hard to undo, even in the face of learning compelling information to the contrary. Our data did not support this hypothesis. The majority of the participants in these two conditions did adhere to their original recommendation (MPro-merge = .64, t(235) = 1600, 95% CI [0.574, 0.697]; MPro-separate = .68, t(229) = 1600, 95% CI [0.617, 0.739]) after learning the additional information from the second article. However, they endorsed the recommendation to merge the two schools at comparable rates to the control group. See <ref type="figure">Figure  10</ref>. Treatment groups' 2a and 2b mean endorsement of merging recommenda on before (T1) and a er (T2) reading addi onal informa on in Study 2 and 95% CIs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory findings</head><p>To further illuminate our understanding of the illusion of asymmetry and the robustness of our prespecified findings, we included a series of additional measures for exploratory purposes. As one example, each group also reported how confident they were about the recommendation that they provided. If people frequently fail to consider what they do not know about a situation, we anticipated that participants' confidence about their decision would be largely unaffected by the amount of information they possessed.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref>, despite having half as much information, treatment groups 1a, 1b, 2a, and 2b all report greater mean levels of confidence in their initial recommendations than the control group. Pooling the means of all the treatment groups (MPooledTreatment = .71, sd = .21) reveals that these participants reported significantly greater confidence than their control counterparts (MControl = .65, sd = 0.21; t(1181) = 4.22, p &lt; .001, d = -0.30, 95% CI <ref type="bibr">[-0.45, -0.16]</ref>. Participants in treatment groups 1b and 2b rated their confidence twice, allowing for a withinsubjects test of their confidence. A paired-sample t-test revealed that these participants became significantly less confident from their initial ratings (MInitialPooled = .71, sd = 0.22) to their final ratings (MFinalPooled = .67, sd = .21); t(459) = 5.031, p &lt; . <ref type="bibr">001,</ref><ref type="bibr">d = 0.17,</ref><ref type="bibr">95% CI [0.06,</ref><ref type="bibr">0.28]</ref>. In other words, across two different analyses we found that those with less information manifested greater confidence. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ini al Confidence in Decision by Condi on and 95% CIs</head><p>A second set of exploratory analyses was designed to further assess how participants' perceptions of whether they had adequate information to make a decision changed after learning exposure to new information. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 12</ref> shows the mean ratings across all five branches of the study for participants thinking that they understood enough key details to make a decision (Panel A) and whether they still had questions (Panel B). These results provide additional, descriptive support for our core hypothesis that individuals assume they have adequate information to make recommendations even when some of them (the control group and treatment groups 1b and 2b) received twice as much information as others (treatment groups 1a and 2a). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Anecdotally, naïve realism feels like a greater problem than ever. Divergent perceptions of realities have clashed across the globe around vaccines, the right to abortions, which countries hold the legitimate claims to which lands, whether climate change exists, and so forth. However, misunderstandings frequently occur at the interpersonal level too, inflicting similar harm on relationships, albeit at a less global scale. Although it is hard to assess how much social media and the global pandemic have exacerbated people's tendencies towards naïve realism, it seems especially important now to ascertain what engenders such discrepant perceptions of "objective reality."</p><p>In the original formulation of naïve realism, differences in construal-how different parties perceive the situation differently-represents the crux of the challenge <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Robinson et al., 1995)</ref>. We augment this theory by proposing that a second major contributor to naïve realism is the illusion of adequate information. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Ross and Ward (1996)</ref> point out that a reason for naïve realism to potentially occur is that parties have been exposed to different information. Building off this part of the theory, we test a critical nuance in the context of an issue participants are learning about for the first time: that people generally assume that the information they possess is adequate.</p><p>Our two preregistered studies provide convergent evidence across two populations that people indeed make this assumption even when they may be lacking critically informative pieces of information. Furthermore, they assume a moderately high level of competence to make a fair, unbiased, careful evaluation of the information in reaching their decisions. In turn, the crosssection of information that they are exposed to strongly influences their recommendations. Finally, in line with the second tenet of naïve realism <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Ross &amp; Ward, 1996)</ref> and the false consensus effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Ross, Greene, et al., 1977)</ref>, they assume that most other (reasonable) people would make the same recommendation that they did. Somewhat to our surprise, we found that although the majority of the treatment participants who read the second article did stick to their original recommendation, the overall final recommendations from those groups (after having exposure to the full amount of information provided) became indistinguishable from the control group. While this finding diverges from the findings of <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lord et al. (1979)</ref>, it does support the idea in naïve realism that sharing or pooling of information may well lead to agreement <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Ross &amp; Ward, 1996)</ref>. We suspect that the topic of the dispute may account for the differences here. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lord et al. (1979)</ref> focused on capital punishment-a well-known issue where people tend to have strong prior opinions. We asked participants about a local, hypothetical scenario-for which they could not have held a prior opinion. Thus, for our participants to change their mind upon learning new information may have been much easier than for participants in the <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lord et al. (1979)</ref> study.</p><p>We see our results as augmenting the theory of naïve realism by illuminating an important, additional psychological bias that catalyzes naïve realism. Specifically, because people assume they have adequate information, they enter into judgment and decision-making processes with less humility and more confidence than they would if they held nagging doubts as to whether the new the whole story.</p><p>How might these doubts make a difference? We suspect that in many real-world situations individuals may not even pause to consider how complete their picture of a situation is before passing judgment. Comedian George Carlin's observation that those who drive slower than we do are idiots and those who drive faster are maniacs is often invoked in discussions of naïve realism (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Gilovich &amp; Ross, 2015)</ref>. We suspect that the mere act of wondering, "do I have enough information?" could infuse humility and a willingness to give more benefit of the doubt. Was the driver who just zoomed past en route to the hospital with a woman in labor? Is the painfully slow driver transporting a fragile family heirloom? These types of questions might dissolve road rage (George Carlin's or our own) before it begins.</p><p>In addition to complementing the theory of naïve realism, this bias may help inform other related theories too. People may commit the fundamental attribution error more to the extent that they assume their knowledge about the situation is adequate <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Ross, Amabile, et al., 1977)</ref>. When anticipating their own future emotional states, perhaps one of the reasons that individuals perform poorly is because they assume that they have adequate information about what their future circumstances will be like; in reality people often fail to account for key details in their affective forecasting efforts <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Gilbert &amp; Wilson, 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">, 2009</ref>.</p><p>In addition to these theoretical implications, we are hopeful that these findings suggest important practical strategies for conflict resolution. Teaching individuals to pause and question how much information they know that they know about a situation could be a helpful disposition to cultivate. Alternatively, perhaps listing out relevant aspects of a situation that they probably need to know more about prior to passing judgment would be even more effective. Interventions designed to help disputants share information and perspectives on how they interpret that information might also be worth experimenting with.</p><p>Some readers may worry that the results of the present study may seem so obvious as to be trivial. In other words, our treatment participants have no way of knowing that there is a whole set of facts that they do not receive; so naturally, they assumed they had adequate information to make a reasonable recommendation. Others may worry that we stacked the deck by presenting the pro-merge participants with almost exclusively pro-merge arguments (and vice-versa for pro-separate participants). However, we suspect these features of our experiment represent exactly how this phenomenon unfolds in many real world situations. People frequently have no way of knowing what they do not know; they are regularly exposed to unrepresentative cross-sections of information but confidently assume that their information is sufficiently representative to act upon.</p><p>To be sure, more investigation needs to be done on this bias. Future research that can investigate this phenomenon across a range of issues-including topics where people have prior knowledge and strongly held prior beliefs-is an important first step. Assuming similar evidence is found across a range of issues, then testing out interventions to mitigate this bias and examine the downstream effects on naïve realism, the false consensus effect, and conflict resolution, will be particularly valuable.</p><p>Although people may not know what they do not know, they may be wise to assume that they are missing some relevant information. In a world of prolific polarization and dubious information, some humility may help our interpersonal relationships.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>illustrates, participants in each condition believed that most other people would reach the same recommendation that they did; Mcontrol = 0.538, t(70) = 2.018, 95% CI [0.501, 0.575); Mpro-merge = 0.624, t(74) = 7.217, 95% CI [0.590, 0.659); and Mproseparate = 0.548, t(70) = 2.713, 95% CI [0.512, 0.584).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 5.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 6.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 7.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 8.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>= 0.615, t(241) = 5200, 95% CI [0.597, 0.634]; Mpro-merge = 0.677, t(477) = 6500, 95% CI [0.662, 0.692]; and Mpro-separate = 0.646, t(462) = 6800 , 95% CI [0.632, 0.60]. See Figure 9.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 9.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 10.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 11.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 12 .</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Panel A. Perceived Key Details Received by Condi on and 95% CIs Panel B. Perceived Lack of Lingering Ques on by Condi on and 95% CIs</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Descrip ve Sta s cs and Correla ons for Study 1 Variables.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Variable</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>SD</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell></row><row><cell>1) Information adequacy</cell><cell>.62</cell><cell>.13</cell><cell>--</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2) Decision making competence</cell><cell>.66</cell><cell>.10</cell><cell>.36***</cell><cell>--</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>3) Decision to merge with other</cell><cell>.69</cell><cell></cell><cell>.20**</cell><cell>.07</cell><cell>--</cell></row><row><cell>school</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>4) Consensus</cell><cell>.57</cell><cell>.16</cell><cell>.19**</cell><cell>.06</cell><cell>.18**</cell></row></table><note>Note. N = 211-218 (7 participants did not answer the information adequacy and decision-making competence items).* p &lt;.05. **p &lt;.01.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Descrip ve Sta s cs and Correla ons for Study 2 Variables.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Mean SD</cell><cell>N</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>13</cell></row><row><cell>1) Information adequacy</cell><cell>.69</cell><cell cols="2">.14 1242</cell><cell>--</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2) Decision-making competence 3) Decision to merge 4) False consensus</cell><cell>.81 .55 .65</cell><cell cols="5">.12 .16 1183 .34 *** .27 *** .16 *** 714 .47 *** --714 .17 *** .04 --</cell><cell>--</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>5) Confidence in recommendation 6) Key details 7) Lingering questions 8) Curiosity 9) Post: Decision to merge 10) Post: False consensus</cell><cell>.70 .64 .49 .70 .52 .62</cell><cell cols="8">.21 1183 .41 *** .33 *** .15 *** .56 *** .23 714 .64 *** .37 *** .11 ** .44 *** .54 *** --.30 714 .35 *** .17 *** .07 .19 *** .25 *** .38 *** --.27 714 .14 *** .17 *** -.04 .05 .02 .02 466 .31 *** .04 -.00 .17 460 .05 .49 *** .22 ***</cell><cell>---.02</cell><cell>--</cell><cell>--.07</cell><cell>--</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>11) Post: Confidence in recommendation</cell><cell>.66</cell><cell>.21</cell><cell>460</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.02</cell><cell cols="2">.31 *** .59 ***</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.08</cell><cell>.56 ***</cell><cell>--</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">12) Post: Information comparison 13) Post: Key Details 14) Post: Lingering questions .51 .82 .68</cell><cell>.24 .22 .30</cell><cell>459 459 459</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.03 .03 .02</cell><cell cols="2">-.12 * -.17 *** .34 *** .45 *** .14 ** .15 **</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.02 .06 .04</cell><cell cols="3">.02 .41 *** .58 *** .01 -.07 --.21 *** .25 *** -.04</cell><cell>--.30 **</cell></row></table><note>* Note.* p &lt;.05. **p &lt;.01. ***p &lt;.001.</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors are grateful for the helpful thoughts and feedback provided by Andrew Ward.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Elkind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Children and adolescents; interpretive essays on Jean Piaget</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospection: Experiencing the future</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1144161</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1144161" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5843</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1351" to="1354" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why the brain talks to itself: Sources of error in emotional prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2008.0305</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2008.0305" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">364</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1335" to="1341" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The wisest one in the room: How you can benefit from social psychology&apos;s most powerful insights</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Free Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The natural principles of love</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gottman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gottman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/jftr.12182</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1111/jftr.12182" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Family Theory &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The growth of logical thinking from childhood to adolescence; an essay on the construction of formal operational structures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Inhelder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Piaget</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trans.). Basic Books</title>
		<editor>A. Parsons &amp; S. Milgram</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adolescent egocentrism and formal operations: Tests of a theoretical assumption</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Lapsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milstead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Quintana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Flannery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Buss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="800" to="807" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Naïve realism and capturing the &quot;wisdom of dyads</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Liberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Minson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2011.10.016</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2011.10.016" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biased assimilation and attitude polarization: The effects of prior theories on subsequently considered evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lord</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lepper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.37.11.2098</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.37.11.2098" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality &amp; Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2098" to="2109" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reactive devaluation of an &quot;Israeli&quot; vs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Maoz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0022002702046004003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0022002702046004003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Conflict Resolution</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="515" to="546" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Palestinian&quot; peace proposal</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Actual versus assumed differences in construal: &apos;Naive realism&apos; in intergroup perception and conflict</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Keltner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.68.3.404</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.68.3.404" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="404" to="417" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social roles, social control, and biases in social-perception processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Amabile</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Steinmetz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.35.7.485</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.35.7.485" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="485" to="494" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The false consensus effect: An egocentric bias in social perception and attribution processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>House</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="301" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Naive realism in everyday life: Implications for social conflict and misunderstanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Jean Piaget symposium series. Values and knowledge</title>
		<editor>E. S. Reed &amp; E. Turiel</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="135" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Naïve realism and affirmative action: Adversaries are more similar than they think</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/S15324834BASP2504_2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/S15324834BASP2504_2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="289" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
