<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mane</forename><surname>Kara-Yakoubian</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Master of Arts</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Toronto Metropolitan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2022</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Dr</roleName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Girard</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<postCode>2023, 2023</postCode>
									<settlement>Toronto, © Mane Kara-Yakoubian</settlement>
									<region>Ontario, Canada</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Dr</roleName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Szpunar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<postCode>2023, 2023</postCode>
									<settlement>Toronto, © Mane Kara-Yakoubian</settlement>
									<region>Ontario, Canada</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Aging</term>
					<term>relevance realization</term>
					<term>explore</term>
					<term>exploit</term>
					<term>moral decision-making RELEVANCE REALIZATION</term>
					<term>AGING</term>
					<term>&amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>One of the markers of human cognitive agency is the capacity for moral cognition. Across a range of societies, older adults are perceived as more moral than younger adults. Interestingly, research shows that compared to younger adults, older adults are more likely to endorse deontological (as opposed to utilitarian) ethics. This age difference has been explained in terms of cognitive decline and socioemotional shifts. In this paper, I consider the Exploration-Exploitation (EE) model of aging, as well as the Relevance Realization (RR) framework, in explaining moral decision-making phenomena across younger and older adults. My analysis reveals that in older age, the mechanisms underlying moral decision-making gravitate toward efficiency-based processing more generally, as opposed to exploitation-based processing more specifically, thereby lending support in favour of the RR framework over the EE model of aging. I conclude that in light of the explanatory breadth offered by RR, the opponency of explorationexploitation alone, a trade-off relationship subsumed by RR, is at times necessary but insufficient in explaining age differences in response to sacrificial moral dilemmas. Accordingly, I suggest that augmenting EE with RR could expand both its theoretical precision and explanatory power, while ameliorating its possible theoretical blind spots. I conclude by discussing the empirical limitations of the RR framework and proposing potential empirical avenues for future research on RR in the context of moral decision-making.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>yet its method of propelling forward is less than one percent effective. In viewing the paramecium as a situated biological whole-that is, an entity that does not merely exist, but organizes itself in response to a dynamic environment-we see that the bacterial cell gravitates toward areas that have greater concentrations of sugar, both by conducting random searchers and following gradients <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">(Thompson, 2007)</ref>. When no sugar gradients are detectable, the cell allows itself to get carried by water currents until it detects the necessary sustenance. At this point, it activates its cilia and swims toward sugar to replenish itself and repeat this cycle. In this way, the paramecium is autopoietic, a term that describes a system that has the capacity to maintain its structural integrity by extracting the necessary external resources from its environment to sustain itself <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Maturana &amp; Varela, 1991)</ref>. The paramecium does not abide by physical laws; rather, the norms that allow for survival emerge from its organization <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Hovhannisyan, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Thompson 2011;</ref>. Its need for sugar is not inherent to sugar either but instead arises as a relational property between the molecular structure of sugar and the paramecium's biological organization, necessitating sugar as a source of energy for autopoiesis.</p><p>It may appear like an odd choice to open a comprehensive paper on moral decisionmaking and aging by describing an obscure microscopic organism that floats around in still waters. But if it is the case that human evolution began with a single cell, then the properties possessed by a primitive organism like the paramecium ought to be embedded in more complex <ref type="bibr">RELEVANCE REALIZATION,</ref><ref type="bibr">AGING,</ref> organisms, like human beings, as well <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Hovhannisyan, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Thompson, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Varela et al., 1991)</ref>. For present purposes, the overlapping characteristic of interest between the paramecium and human beings is that of cognitive agency. Indeed, by studying the paramecium, we come to understand that a defining characteristic of organisms is that they constitutively realize what is relevant for their autopoiesis through their interactions with the environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Hovhannisyan &amp; Dewey, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Thompson, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Varela et al., 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>. This is to say, the paramecium exemplifies a central characteristic of cognitive agency that is shared by human beings as well, although in a tremendously more articulated form, namely the ability to "zero in on relevant aspects of the world" while ignoring noise that is irrelevant to goals that serve its self-preservation <ref type="bibr">(Andersen et al., 2022, p. 1)</ref>. Now, let us zoom out from this microscopic view, fast forward by four billion years <ref type="bibr">(UCSB ScienceLine, 2018)</ref>, and situate ourselves in the Garden of Eden, where there is now man, and man is a self-organizing cognitive agent who has committed a moral transgression against God by consuming the forbidden fruit from the tree of knowledge of good and evil (New International Version Bible <ref type="bibr">[NIV]</ref>, 2011, Genesis 3). The story of Adam and Eve is a wellknown illustration of the first sinners in human history, reaching audiences far beyond followers of Abrahamic religions. For our interests, the significance of this biblical story does not lie in its theological implications. Rather, it is meant to highlight a vitally important dimension of our own cognitive agency: the moral dimension. Unlike the paramecium, we are not simply motivated to survive by seeking sources of sugar in our environment. But like Adam and Eve, our day-to-day decisions are predominantly governed by implicit or explicit understandings of what is right or wrong, good or bad. <ref type="bibr">RELEVANCE REALIZATION,</ref><ref type="bibr">AGING,</ref> Moral psychologists typically study moral decision-making by examining how people respond to and navigate moral dilemmas. In this context, moral dilemmas are less concerned with the consequences of disobeying a God, and instead attempt to elucidate the ethical frameworks humans adopt when engaged in moral decision-making. Two commonly studied ethical frameworks undergirding people's decisions are deontology and utilitarianism.</p><p>Deontology suggests that an act is good or bad according to a set of predefined rules; as such, acts that align with the rules are moral, while those that do not are immoral. On the other hand, utilitarianism differentiates right and wrong by focusing on the outcomes, arguing that the ethical choice is the one that maximizes good for the greatest number of people. Moral psychologists frequently use the Trolley Problem to gauge inclinations toward either ethical theory. This is a scenario in which a malfunctioning trolley is about to run over five people, but the bystander (i.e., the research participant) can intervene and divert it to the other track where there is only one person. The deontological agent's response to this dilemma would be to refrain from acting, arguing that if killing people is wrong, then it is wrong across all contexts. The utilitarian agent would opt to divert the trolley, killing one person to save five others as a means of maximizing good and minimizing harm. There are countless iterations of the trolley dilemma, whereby the individual victim may be a family member, a future Nobel prize winner, or a surgeon who saves lives daily. Some variations involve alterations to the track in which the train loops around, connecting to the alternate track with five people <ref type="bibr">(Bago &amp; De Neys, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Greene et al., 2001</ref>). 1</p><p>For our purposes, we will primarily focus on the classic depiction of sacrificial dilemmas.</p><p>A particularly reliable observation made by moral psychologists concerns differences in ethical leanings during sacrificial moral dilemmas like the trolley problem (utilitarian vs.</p><p>1 Find here an entertaining website dedicated to Absurd Trolley Problems: https://neal.fun/absurd-trolley-problems/ RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 7 deontological) among younger vs. older adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Huang et al., 2021b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">McNair et al., 2019)</ref>. Specifically, when faced with sacrificial moral dilemmas, older adults are more likely to engage in deontological reasoning than younger adults. From a psychological perspective, this immediately raises the question as to whether observed age differences in moral decision-making can be explained as a function of differences in underlying psychological mechanisms between younger vs. older adulthood. The literature on this topic is vast. Thus, I</p><p>begin by focusing on current cognitive and socioemotional accounts of moral decision-making.</p><p>My discussion of this literature underscores the fact that despite the numerous explanations for the aging trends in question, there is a lack of a unified understanding of how these two levels of analysis (i.e., cognitive or socioemotional) ought to be related to and integrated with one another, leaving research in the field in a fragmented and potentially confused state.</p><p>To address this issue, I turn to a recent account by <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner (2021)</ref> that promises to deliver a unified understanding of human aging. By bringing together research on decision-making and the neuroscience of aging, as well as cognitive and affective aging theories, the authors argue that all volitional acts can be reduced to the choice to either exploit prior knowledge toward a more predictable outcome or to explore new sources of information that have more unpredictable returns. They call this the shifting mental mode hypothesis of aging, which postulates that exploration-exploitation trade-offs increasingly lean toward exploitation (over exploration) in older adulthood.</p><p>Despite their claim that all volitional acts can be reduced to either the choice to explore or the choice to exploit, I find there is evidence of other trade-offs at play in cognition that are just as fundamental as the exploration-exploitation trade-off. I make my case by turning to recent work by <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al. (2012)</ref> that has sought to explain cognitive agency in terms of three <ref type="bibr">RELEVANCE REALIZATION,</ref><ref type="bibr">AGING,</ref> trade-off relationships, subsumed under one overarching trade-off relationship, rather than just one of exploration-exploitation. The authors refer to their framework as a theory of relevance realization (RR) because it explains how cognition can effectively zero-in on relevant information while ignoring noise, thereby circumventing the notorious frame problem in cognitive science (discussed in Section "Relevance Realization as a Theory of Cognitive Function"). In this way, <ref type="bibr">Vervaeke et al.'s (2012)</ref> theory of RR can not only benefit <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner (2021)</ref> in their aim to be truly comprehensive but can also benefit our own project of explaining the trends observed in younger vs. older adults' moral decision-making in the context of sacrificial moral dilemmas.</p><p>To support this claim, upon reviewing both <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner's (2021)</ref> explore-exploit (EE) model and <ref type="bibr">Vervaeke et al.'s (2012)</ref> RR model, I proceed to compare the merits of each respective theory by applying both frameworks to the phenomenon of moral decision-making among younger and older adults. My analysis reveals that RR subsumes the explorationexploitation trade-off, and therefore bears greater explanatory power than the EE model-it explains what EE is meant to explain, plus more. Lastly, I discuss the theoretical benefits of RR as well as potential empirical directions for future research seeking to explain aging trends in moral decision-making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Moral Decision-Making Across Adulthood</head><p>Reader, let us return to the Garden of Eden, where Adam and Eve committed a moral transgression against God, resulting in their exile from paradise (NIV Bible, 2011, Genesis 3).</p><p>Ironically, the act of eating the forbidden fruit resulted in the awareness of the knowledge of good and evil. Indeed, this story depicts humans' capacity to sin (hence the label "original sin"), but it is not the oldest writing on morality. The first writings on the topic tracked who owed what <ref type="bibr">RELEVANCE REALIZATION,</ref><ref type="bibr">AGING,</ref> to whom among merchants in ancient Mesopotamia <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Haidt, 2008)</ref>. Fast forward thousands of years, and we see that despite advances in science, moral insights are largely stable. Haidt offers a functionalist definition of morality, defining it as systems of "interlocking sets of values, practices, institutions, and evolved psychological mechanisms that work together to suppress or regulate selfishness and make social life possible" (p. 7). Social scientists have been especially curious in their studies of human cooperation. Morality is undoubtedly implicated in explaining patterns of how we relate to one another.</p><p>The planet is becoming increasingly interconnected. At the same time, births are declining, and we are seeing aging populations across the globe <ref type="bibr">(World Health Organization, 2022)</ref>. Not only should we care about moral decision-making as a stable category of study, but given our populational reality, we should pay particular attention to moral decision-making patterns as we age. This is an especially intriguing line of inquiry considering that older adults are perceived as more moral and as knowing what is moral in Western, Educated, Industrialized, Rich, Democratic (WEIRD) and non-WEIRD societies (including Canadians; <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Sorokowski et al., 2023)</ref>, hinting at a cross-cultural phenomenon. In this section, I draw from <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Daley &amp; Kensinger's (2021)</ref> review to outline aging trends as they relate to moral decision-making. Given the focus of this paper is not the synthesis of moral decision-making research across adulthood, but instead, the application of an emerging framework of cognitive function to this domain of study, I will largely be relying on an existing review to extract insights on the mechanisms underlying moral decision-making across younger and older adults.</p><p>Perhaps unsurprisingly, healthy younger and older adults differ in their performance across a range of tasks. This observation extends to decision-making in the context of sacrificial moral dilemmas, scenarios in which an agent must decide whether they are willing to sacrifice RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 10 one individual to save five others. In such paradigms, older adults tend to make more nonutilitarian decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Huang et al., 2021b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">McNair et al., 2019</ref>; see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2022</ref>). There are several inputs into the observed age difference in these dilemmas, including cognitive, neural, and socioemotional contributors <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. Cognition peaks in young adulthood, and aging is associated with cognitive decline even in healthy individuals.</p><p>Compared to younger adults, older adults maintain or show an increase in crystallized intelligence, while their fluid intelligence begins to suffer <ref type="bibr" target="#b78">(Tucker-Drob et al., 2022)</ref>. But despite worsened performance on standard neuropsychological assessments that may paint a bleak image of cognition in older adulthood, when content is made to be socioemotionally relevant (e.g., remembering the death of Princess Diana vs. a mundane event around the same time), the performance of older adults begins to resemble that of younger adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Duarte &amp; Kensinger, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Kensinger et al., 2014)</ref>. This makes sense, considering that cognition in older adulthood is more sensitive to internal states, such as thoughts and feelings. The complexity here is particularly relevant to moral decision-making, which involves both cognitive and socioemotional processes.</p><p>The dual-process theory of moral decision-making (proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Greene, 2007)</ref> suggests that refraining from the utilitarian choice is reflective of an immediate emotional response when considering sacrificing an individual. In overriding this initial response, which requires slower and more controlled cognitive processing, a participant can make the utilitarian choice. Older adults' deontological decision-making is partially mediated by a self-reported experience of elevated negative affect when considering the dilemma (as well as a greater tendency for moral <ref type="bibr">idealism;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">McNair et al., 2019)</ref>. Thus, in accordance with Greene's dual-process account of moral decision-making, at least one study suggests that older adults may be less inclined to opt for the <ref type="bibr">RELEVANCE REALIZATION,</ref><ref type="bibr">AGING,</ref> utilitarian decision given they are more affected by emotion when faced with these dilemmas.</p><p>Neuroimaging studies have also revealed that deontological and utilitarian reasoning rely more heavily on brain regions associated with emotional and controlled processing respectively <ref type="bibr">(Bago &amp; De Neys, 2019)</ref>. Importantly, older adults may not have the cognitive capacity to override the "gut" emotional response, thereby selecting the easier and quicker deontological choice. Moral decision-making research has been critiqued for its use of stimuli like the Trolley Problem or Footbridge dilemma 2 as the moral choices one can make in response to the dilemma are confounded with the intuitiveness of the moral choice. In other words, are participants making a particular moral decision because that is their ethical leaning or because of how intuitive a given option is <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Kahane, 2015)</ref>?</p><p>To account for the intuitiveness of the moral decision as a potential confound with the utilitarian and deontological choices (e.g., push fat man, refrain from acting), <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Huang et al. (2021b)</ref> presented participants with (non-trolley) dilemmas where both the utilitarian and deontological choices were intuitive. The deontological-intuitive scenario (i.e., whereby the deontological choice was the intuitive one) involved a vignette in which participants imagined being a doctor with five patients on the verge of death due to organ failure, and one young healthy patient. They had the choice of non-consensually transplanting the young man's organs into the bodies of the other five patients, killing one but saving five (utilitarian-counterintuitive choice), or not performing the transplant surgery (deontological-intuitive choice). Alternatively, the utilitarian-intuitive dilemma prompted participants to imagine being a waiter overhearing one of the frequent customers talking about going to jail soon but planning to infect numerous people with HIV in the remaining 48 hours of freedom. Knowing he is severely allergic to poppy seeds that would result in convulsions and hospitalization for at least two days, there were two choices presented: causing a serious allergy attack to prevent him from infecting others with HIV (utilitarian-intuitive choice) or doing nothing (deontological-counterintuitive choice). The results revealed that older (vs. younger) adults were more likely to make deontological choices, but this age difference only emerged for deontological-intuitive dilemmas. Thus, even when accounting for the intuitiveness of the response options in sacrificial moral dilemmas, we still see this age difference in moral decision-making styles <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cognitive Decline Account of Age Differences in Moral Decision-Making</head><p>The age differences in moral decision-making might be attributable to declines in cognitive control, working memory capacity and subsequent reliance on brain regions that are more sensitive to emotional salience. Increased cognitive load has been associated with slower response times for utilitarian, but not deontological, decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Greene et al., 2008)</ref>. This effect was evident in participants who endorsed utilitarian ethics as well as those who did not. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Greene et al. (2008)</ref> suggest that reduced cognitive capacity could disrupt the necessary processes that lead to the endorsement of utilitarian decisions, arguing that their findings provide direct evidence that controlled cognitive processes play a role in utilitarian moral judgement. Other work has highlighted the role of cognitive control in overriding individuals' moral defaults of either honesty or dishonesty <ref type="bibr">(Speer et al., 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Further, processing speed accounts of cognition emphasize that older adults tend to perform more slowly across numerous measures of cognitive function <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">(Salthouse, 1996)</ref>. Older adults' ability to successfully execute complex tasks is likely compromised by their reduced ability to quickly synchronize the relevant cognitive operations. <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Salthouse (1996)</ref> uses a juggling metaphor to make this point: it is substantially easier to juggle (i.e., synchronize) when one can RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 13 throw and catch multiple balls (i.e., execute relevant operations) rapidly. In the study of moral decision-making, deontological (vs. utilitarian) decision-making could be argued to be of poorer quality if there is an imperative to save lives <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. Older adults' slower processing speed might prevent them from engaging the necessary cognitive operations to respond with the utilitarian choice.</p><p>Working memory theories suggest that decline in working memory capacity is associated with poorer performance on tasks that require mental manipulation of content. Thus, when older adults are required to keep track of all the task-relevant content when deliberating on their decision, their inability to do so may lead to greater reliance on affective heuristics, and therefore more deontological decisions, given all the necessary information is not available at the time of decision. Additionally, higher (vs. lower) working memory capacity has been linked to greater likelihood to sacrifice one to save many others as well as more consistent responding across numerous dilemma types (e.g., varying physical directness of killing, intentionality of killing, risk posed to subject, inevitability of death; <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Moore et al., 2008)</ref>. Theories of inhibitory control posit that older adults have a more diffuse attentional spotlight, and experience increased difficulty in ignoring task-irrelevant stimuli <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Hasher et al., 1991)</ref>. Thus, more task-irrelevant content may be available in their attentional field. Compared to younger adults, older adults would be less capable of ignoring the emotional reactions that arise during the decision-making task <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. This would be in line with <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Greene's (2007)</ref> dual-process account, which argues that the deontological decisions older adults arrive at are partially attributable to their focus on the affective reaction elicited by the dilemma and inability to engage reflective processes to weigh potential outcomes 3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Overall, older (vs. younger) adults have more impaired cognitive control, and the agedifferences we see in moral decision-making might be due to the reduced cognitive capacity in older age. As a result, older adults may be less effective at inhibiting their emotional responses when faced with moral dilemmas.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Socioemotional Account of Age Differences in Moral Decision-Making</head><p>There are also differences between younger and older adults' socioemotional motivation.</p><p>Older adults have better memory and attention for affective (vs. neutral) stimuli, as well as a positivity bias, such that they are more attentive to positive (vs. neutral or negative) stimuli (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Charles et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Knight et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Reed et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Socioemotional Selectivity Theory (SST) posits that as life becomes more time limited, like in the case of advancing age, motivations start to shift from future-oriented goals (e.g., career planning) to goals tied to emotion or meaning (spending time with family; <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Carstensen, 1992)</ref>. It follows then that older adults prioritize positive relationships <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Mather &amp; Carstensen, 2005</ref>) and attempt to maintain social cohesion. This might be explained by age-related changes in generativity <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. While older adults exhibit a decline across numerous domains, generativity is not one of them. Priorities begin to shift from the here and now to consideration for the future of future generations <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Carstensen, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Erikson et al., 1989)</ref>. For example, older adults are less likely to involve themselves in conflict, not because of indifference or incompetence, rather because their interpersonal problem-solving strategies (i.e., sensitivity to context, instrumental &amp; emotion-regulation) serve to preserve positive relationships and reduce negative emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Blanchard-Fields, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Carstensen et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Charles &amp; Carstensen, 2008</ref> Mortality salience and positive mood inductions have been used to induce limited time perspectives and positivity biases in younger adults, shifting the motivations of younger adults to become more like that of older adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. Further, mortality salience and cognitive load inductions have been found to be similarly detrimental to moral decision-making, shifting participant responses toward the deontological choice at similar rates <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">(Trémolière et al., 2012)</ref>. Being reminded of impending death might have a depleting effect on cognitive resources due to attempts to suppress the distressing thoughts associated with inevitability, in turn, impacting moral decision-making. Older adults maintain a limited time perspective, thus, when they approach moral dilemmas, the limited temporal horizons-or more salient thoughts of death-are consistently affecting their decision-making.</p><p>If it was the case that cognitive capacity was what solely accounted for age differences in moral decision-making, then older adults with higher cognitive capacity should be performing similarly to younger adults. One study found that older adults with poorer executive functioning were endorsing responses that were like younger adults' <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Maxfield et al., 2012)</ref>. That is, among older adults, executive function positively predicted tolerance toward moral transgressors, with individuals exhibiting lower function endorsing greater punitiveness against bad actors. In the absence of cognitive decline then, aging might be associated with socioemotional shifts that lead to different moral decisions between younger and older adults. Following positive mood inductions, more utilitarian decisions are endorsed on the Footbridge but not Trolley Problem.</p><p>So, it is not just the emotional response elicited by moral dilemmas, but also the affective characteristics of the environment that an individual deliberates within that can affect one's moral decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">(Valdesolo &amp; DeSteno, 2006)</ref>. If older adults are more often in a state of emotion regulation that prioritizes positive mood, then we should expect them to endorse more utilitarian responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. But the tendency toward more deontological decision-making suggests that the emotional response elicited by the moral dilemma overrides the motivational context they are deliberating in.</p><p>Another motivational change that helps explain age differences in moral decision-making is the role of the self. As one ages, the quality of self-representation might shift, in turn affecting performance on tasks that contain social content. Compared to younger adults, older adults have better memory for self-(vs. other-) relevant content <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Kensinger &amp; Gutchess, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b91">Yang et al., 2012</ref>) and represent the self as more continuous across past, present, and future <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Rutt &amp; Löckenhoff, 2016)</ref>. Involvement and representation of the self when making decisions might provide a different social context for older (vs. younger) adults to act within, partially explaining the observed age differences in moral decision-making. For example, compared to younger adults, older adults might experience reduced social distance, or greater overlap between their own self and the other individual in the moral dilemma, identifying with the victim more closely (e.g., "it could be me on that train track instead"), which in turn, influences their moral choice.</p><p>Socioemotional variables such as this may have greater weighting on moral decisions when considering iterations of the classic sacrificial moral dilemma (e.g., the victim is a friend), complicating the predominant belief that there is a "better" utilitarian choice to be made. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Daley &amp; Kensinger (2021)</ref> conclude their review by highlighting the ambiguity regarding where age differences in moral decision-making emerge from, stating that older adults' tendency toward deontological decision-making could be due to cognitive decline, motivational shifts, or an interaction of the two. Even when there are similar patterns across younger and older adults, it remains unclear whether younger and older adults are engaging the same mechanisms to arrive at the same decisions. At this point, it becomes useful to turn to frameworks that explain the psychology of aging more broadly to make sense of older adults' leanings toward deontological moral decision-making at both the level of specific cognitive and socioemotional inputs, and the unified process of moral decision-making. Thus, let us now examine <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner's (2021)</ref> account of human aging, the exploration-to-exploitation shift in aging, which promises to do just that by condensing the two dominant aging trends (i.e., declines in fluid processes and accumulation of knowledge as well as affective shifts) into a criterion shift that favours "exploitation-based over exploration-driven mentation and action" (p. 2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Aging and the Exploration-to-Exploitation Shift</head><p>Spreng and Turner (2021) make the claim that all volitional acts can be reduced to the choice to either exploit prior knowledge toward a more predictable outcome or to explore new sources of information that have more unpredictable returns. The authors bring together decision-making literature, with cognitive and affective aging theories, as well as research in the neuroscience of aging to propose a shifting mental mode hypothesis of aging, which postulates that exploration-exploitation trade-offs increasingly lean toward exploitation (over exploration) in older adulthood. As humans age, the fluid control processes which are necessary for fast and flexible engagement of cognitive resources decline. At the same time, prior knowledge of oneself and the world is on the rise. <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner (2021)</ref> argue that these two trajectories favour an exploitative mental mode, in which the accumulating weight of prior knowledge representation strengthens the prepotency of exploitation over exploration-based decisions. This trend is RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 18 exemplified in expressions like, "been there, done that", whereby older adults are less enamoured by novelty (i.e., exploration) given the rich bank of knowledge (e.g., facts, experiences) they can draw from (i.e., exploitation). Affective changes in older adulthood might also produce an exploitation bias in older adults. Aging is associated with more reliance on positively valenced information and prior knowledge when faced with decision-making tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Carstensen et al., 2006)</ref>, reflecting a shift from exploration to exploitation-based cognition.</p><p>When making decisions, individuals can select a known option or search for new, unknown options. One's environmental (e.g., resource availability/predictability, extraction costs, win/loss probabilities, time horizons, internal/external location of search), individual (e.g., demographics, cognitive/physical/psychological abilities, personality, neurobiology), and social factors (e.g., social competition/cooperation, availability/communal access to knowledge) determine the mental mode threshold to switch between exploration and exploitation.</p><p>The trade-off between exploration and exploitation is grounded in patterns of age-related changes in the brain, including declines in fluid cognition that is needed for directed exploration and accumulation of knowledge throughout a lifetime that reduces the informational value of exploration. These two trends can be consolidated as one unified trajectory, offering a more comprehensive view of cognitive aging. To assess for the combined influence of these trajectories, the relative weighting of each trend must be measured along a single dimension. The choice to exploit (vs. explore) provides an index of the summative influence of cognitive control processes, prior knowledge, and affective influences involved in producing that outcome. Thus, "the threshold at which an exploration-exploitation trade-off occurs, can provide a marker of how these capacities intersect and combine to shape goal-directed behavior" (p. 5). <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner (2021)</ref> argue that the dual trajectories of cognitive aging bias older adults toward exploitation-based decision-making, as evidenced by their higher threshold to shift from exploitation to exploration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reduced Cognitive Control in Older Adulthood</head><p>Older adults prefer known vs. unknown choices in economic games (exploit), while younger adults are keener to investigate unknown possibilities that have the potential for greater reward (explore; e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Harlé &amp; Sanfey, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Roalf et al., 2012)</ref>. This strategy can be influenced by inducing cognitive load; when control demands increase, younger adults begin to make more known decisions, shifting their exploratory search to an exploitative one. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Baror and Bar's (2016)</ref> series of experiments suggest that although activation of knowledge associations is an exploratory process by nature, under high cognitive load, associated activation becomes more confined to the more immediate (or accessible) associations. Cognitive control demands play a role in the selection of exploration vs. exploitation, as well as the ability to flexibly switch between the two strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Hills et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Logan, 2004)</ref>.</p><p>Older adults' propensity tendency toward exploitative behaviours may be explained by declines in cognitive control <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Mata &amp; von Helversen, 2015)</ref>. Performance in classic search and decision-making paradigms reveals a differential age effect, with older adults spending more time exploiting what they know (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021)</ref>. Both exploration and exploitation can be goal-directed in nature and hinge on cognitive control processes. When engaging the exploitation mode, "cognitive control is needed to maintain the search cue, sustain attention while searching through available knowledge stores, and suppress irrelevant prior knowledge" (p. 5). However, across most contexts, greater cognitive control is needed to engage the exploration (vs. exploitation) mode. Given aging is linked to declines in cognitive control, it makes sense that the choices individuals opt for become increasingly biased toward exploitation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 20</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Increased Knowledge in Older Adulthood</head><p>The expanding knowledge repertoire of older adulthood is among the cognitive architectural shifts in aging <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021)</ref>. As experience with the options available in the world increases, the value of untested options decreases, and as such, the risks of exploring these unknown choices with uncertain outcomes increases <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">(Walker et al., 2019</ref>). An agent ought not to waste cognitive resources on exploration if they are satisfied with the reward to come and have nothing to gain by exploring other possibilities. Older adults take advantage of their crystallized knowledge base rather than risking the exploration of new information, which carries the unknown possibility of being either advantageous or disadvantageous. On the other hand, younger adults are more inclined to explore the unknowns given they lack the relevant knowledge foundation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Shifting Motivations in Older Adulthood</head><p>Older adults are less interested in new things, which may be explained by a reduction in the value of new information in older age. Further, the time horizon to extract new information and reduce the potential negative consequences of exploration shrinks for older adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Carstensen, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner 2021)</ref>. Statistically, there is less benefit and greater cost associated with exploration in older age. These factors interact with evolving affective motivations throughout aging. Due to older adults' predisposition to favour positive experiences, they may be inclined to exploit what is familiar and positively valenced prior knowledge (recall SST). Indirectly, this would mean restricting their search, or preventing or delaying a switch from exploitation to exploration. <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner (2021)</ref> conclude there is converging evidence that older adults' bias toward exploitation emerges as a mental mode due to declines in cognitive RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 21 control resources, a vast network of knowledge and experience, and motivational changes, which combined produce (or at the very least favour) exploitation-based decisions.</p><p>Here, let us remind ourselves that <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner's (2021)</ref> account depends on the claim that "every volitional act is the product of a choice to either exploit prior knowledge toward a more predictable outcome, or to explore new sources of information with less certain returns" (p. 1). However, there is evidence that this claim may be left partial. Interestingly, recent work in the cognitive sciences has theorized that the hallmark of cognition is the capacity to engage in relevance realization (RR) through trade-off relationships making use of opponentprocesses like the explore-exploit trade-off articulated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner's (2021)</ref> unified account of aging. Indeed, the explore-exploit trade-off that constitutes the backbone of their theory is but one of the trade-offs outlined by the theory of RR, which proposes a total of four trade-offs rather than just one <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>. To the degree that Spreng and Turner's framework was explicitly set to be a comprehensive theory of aging but omits other potential trade-offs at play than just the explore-exploit trade-off, it ought to be integrated with the theory of RR. Doing so would ameliorate its possible theoretical blind spots while realizing its aim of accounting for aging trends in a more comprehensive manner. Our next task is to review the theory of RR and how the various trade-off relationships it proposes are constitutive of cognitive agency, before we embark on our discussion of how Spreng and Turner's model can be complemented by the theory of RR.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relevance Realization as a Theory of Cognitive Function</head><p>Our discussion of RR must begin with a discussion of the "frame problem" in cognitive science, as RR was originally developed as a means of circumventing the frame problem. To this end, let us turn to a series of vignettes offered by the philosopher Daniel <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Dennett (1987)</ref>  depict the importance and implications of the frame problem. Dennett's illustration begins with R1, a robot that was tasked with obtaining its spare battery from a locked room with a ticking time bomb. The battery happened to be placed on a wagon inside the room, and R1 pulled the wagon out, successfully obtaining the battery while failing to realize the bomb was also on the wagon, resulting in its extinction. Thus, R1D1 was developed to recognize both the effects and potential side-effects of its actions. Placing R1D1 in a similar dilemma prompted the robot to engage in deductive reasoning, realizing that pulling the wagon out of the room would not have implications for the colour of the walls-this process took too long, and the bomb went off.</p><p>Consequently, R2D1 was designed to differentiate between relevant and irrelevant side-effects, with the capacity to ignore what was irrelevant. Placed in a similar scenario, R2D1 sat and tagged each newly generated effect and side-effect of a course of action as relevant or irrelevant.</p><p>When the engineers yelled at it to do something, R2D1 explained that it was busy ignoring the thousands of implications it had found to be irrelevant; once more, the bomb went off. All three robots ran into the frame problem, falling short of R2D2, the fictional robot in Star Wars that was able to engage in problem solving without falling into a state of combinatorial explosion.</p><p>For our purposes, combinatorial explosion refers to a cognitive agent's attempt to conduct an exhaustive search of an indefinitely vast problem space with severely finite cognitive resources-like trying to count to infinity. One such familiar human experience of combinatorial explosion is that of an anxiety attack, during which a person becomes overwhelmed and unable to keep up with all the possible scenarios that may unfold. For example, when faced with the trolley dilemma, a person neither pulls the lever nor withholds from doing so, not because they made an active decision to do as such, but because they became paralyzed by the overwhelming combination of possibilities and implications, unable to put a "frame" around what they were RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL  considering. Yet, how is it that most of the time in the day-to-day, cognitive agents can solve problems while evading combinatorial explosion? Indeed, this is the question posed by the notorious frame problem, which has confronted most theories of cognitive function to date <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Dennett, 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Hovhannisyan &amp; Dewey, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>.</p><p>The theory of RR was proposed as a solution to the frame problem. At any given point, just like Dennett's robot, we are bombarded with vast amounts of information and have limited resources to process it all. It is not cognitively feasible to realize what is relevant by conducting an exhaustive search of the problem space. As such, any real-world cognitive agent must be equipped with the ability to filter through irrelevant information without entertaining combinatorially explosive search strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Dennett, 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Shanahan, 2016)</ref>. How do we focus on the relevant information by putting a "frame" around it? <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al. (2012)</ref> argue that a theory of RR must meet two requirements to circumvent the frame problem. First, it cannot adopt a substantive definition of relevance in explaining how human cognition engages in RR, as relevance is a dynamic and evolving category analogous to biological fitness <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>. Doing so would be akin to trying to explain biological evolution by proposing a fixed criterion of fitness (e.g., physical strength, intelligence, etc.) and a set of mechanisms for realizing it-yet this is contrary to how evolution occurs. In their article, Vervaeke et al. <ref type="formula">2012</ref> with what is relevant, but the set of processes through which cognition is able to realize relevance, otherwise it risks committing a jingle fallacy by treating relevance, a dynamically evolving category, as one that is static.</p><p>The second requirement, according to <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al. (2012)</ref>, is that RR "must evade homuncular fallacies," meaning that the mechanisms used to explain RR cannot tacitly presuppose RR in their explanations (p. 12). For example, the philosopher Christopher Cherniak (1986) tried to explain RR in terms of memory compartmentalization, failing to notice that the processes by which compartmentalization take place presuppose the capacity to realize what is relevant. This is because compartmentalization "depends on relevance realization in the process of developing, selecting, and then compartmentalizing memory" <ref type="bibr">(Hovhannisyan &amp; Dewey, 2017, p. 5)</ref>. Homuncular fallacies entail circular explanations and ought to be avoided in science.</p><p>So then, how does the RR framework meet these two requirements in its explanation of how cognitive agents realize relevance without succumbing to combinatorial explosion? The following exposition of Vervaeke et al.'s (2012) theoretical rationale will illustrate this point, preparing us for our forthcoming discussion on moral decision-making and RR.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 25</head><p>To begin, we find that cognitive agents are normally confronted with problems in their interactions with the world (e.g., finding food). We also find that it is possible to interact with each problem domain using distinct but complementary learning strategies aimed at achieving the same goal (e.g., eat leftovers or dine out). However, since no single strategy on its own can offer a one-size-fits-all solution (e.g., we always eventually run out of food, or restaurants cannot offer us seating when they become fully booked), we realize that the shortcomings of one strategy can be mitigated by pairing it with an opponent but complementary strategy in a tradeoff relationship and setting the pair to optimize for reward in an iterative and self-organized fashion. For example, we can solve the problem of finding food by eating the leftovers in our fridge but shift to dining out once we have eaten all the leftovers.</p><p>Importantly, we also find that cognitive agents are normally confronted not just with a single problem but a problem landscape that involves a cognitive economy of competing goals and problems, and associated opponent-processes facing the agent (e.g., hunger, thirst, procreation, threat avoidance). Therefore, a cognitive agent must be equipped with the capacity to prioritize competing goals to cope with its complex and ever-evolving situation, and the mechanisms for goal prioritization should likewise be realized through opponent-processing, to render the optimization of prioritization in each of the domains possible. It is the optimization of reward across the various problems and timescales at which the agent is operating that ultimately results in the agent realizing what is relevant in a "context-sensitive, evolving, and self-organized fashion in relation to [its] situated interaction with the environment" <ref type="bibr">(Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022, p. 13)</ref>. In other words, optimizing for reward in this manner allows the agent to flexibly shift goals and strategies (e.g., from seeking food to seeking water or avoiding threat) as its problems evolve based on its interactions with the world and environmental feedback.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 26</head><p>We find that an opponent-processing approach like the one outlined above allows us to explain how cognitive agents evade combinatorial explosion by limiting their search space based on the kinds of heuristic strategy being used (e.g., find food by eating leftovers). Additionally, since multiple strategies, rather than one, are at play, opponent-processing allows the agent to realize relevance with respect to a goal without remaining committed to a static definition of which strategies are relevant. This framework therefore meets the first requirement for a theory of RR, namely by concerning itself not with what is relevant but the processes by which relevance is continually realized. The RR framework is also important because by explaining cognitive acts in opponent-processing terms, it makes it possible to evade homuncular fallacies, thereby meeting the second requirement of a theory of RR.</p><p>To support the rationale of their approach, <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al. (2012)</ref> seek to advance their RR theory on general grounds. Specifically, their theoretical task is not to explain how human cognitive agents realize relevance given their organization (e.g., which brain regions carry out RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 27 RR and how) but rather what kinds of processes must be in place to make successful interaction with the world possible for any type of cognitive agent. To use an analogy, the difference between a theory of RR versus a theory of how a cognitive agent does RR is the difference between a theory of metabolism (e.g., as a network of autocatalytic processes) versus a theory of how an organism achieves metabolism given its particular composition (e.g., engaging liver or kidneys or muscles). In this paper, I apply <ref type="bibr">Vervaeke et al.'s (2012)</ref> general theory of RR to demonstrate that the way in which younger and older adults engage in moral decision-making is reflective of RR opponent-processes, with older adults tending toward efficiency-(vs. resiliency) based processing more generally, as opposed to exploitation (vs. exploration) more specifically.</p><p>To understand what is meant by efficiency-based processing, though, we must first closely review the set of opponent-process pairs articulated by the theory of RR.</p><p>There are three opponent pairs (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref>) constraining the functioning of the cognitive economy, enabling an agent to continually engage in RR in an ongoing and contextually sensitive fashion. The first is Cognitive Scope, which trades off demands for special-purpose learning with general-purpose learning. This constraint optimizes for the applicability of an agent's information to its problem landscape. Put differently, applicability refers to the relevance of an agent's frames (or knowledge) to its context, which is being realized through the trade-off between special-purpose learning and general-purpose learning. On the one hand, specialpurpose learning involves the high-rigour processing of information in one domain with the possibility of finding reward but is metabolically costly. The risk here is that there might not be sufficient reward within that domain to "break even" <ref type="bibr">(Hovhannisyan &amp; Dewey, 2017, p. 6</ref>). On the other hand, general-purpose learning is metabolically cheap as it involves low-rigour information processing across multiple domains. However, in this case, there exists a potential RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 28 cost of forfeiting the rigorous examination of domains that yield high rewards. Hard commitment to either special-or general-purpose learning is disadvantageous to the agent, but the pairing of these strategies in a trade-off relationship can optimize for applicability in a self-organized fashion that mitigates the risks of either one. Consider for example a Swiss army knife as opposed to a kitchen knife, a screwdriver, or a hammer. One is a general-purpose tool that can be used across a range of contexts, while the others are fitted to specific contexts. It would be appropriate to carry a multipurpose knife when embarking on a trip along unfamiliar roads. But cooking would call for a kitchen knife, fixing the cabinet door for a screwdriver, and hanging up a new painting for a hammer. As cognitive agents, we have the capacity to engage in trade-off processes, in this case, trading off special-and general-purpose strategies, to effectively optimize for what a given context calls for (e.g., do I use my Swiss army knife to slice an apple, or do I grab a kitchen knife?).  <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Vervaeke et al. 2012)</ref>. When new and pressing needs arise (e.g., avoiding harm), a system prioritizes by focusing on meeting this urgent need. Once this need is met, it can then diversify its attentional resources and attend to other needs in the given context (e.g., hunger). When faced with the trolley dilemma, a hungry agent will likely override the imperative to satiate their hunger by seeking food, and instead focus on saving lives. Once the existential emergency is resolved, they can proceed to attend to their need for food.  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> in <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al., 2012</ref> According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al. (2012)</ref>, governing these constraints are the higher-order For now, we ought to understand that relevance is not merely in one's head or in the environment, but a dynamical process between the brain and the world <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">(Vervaeke, 2021)</ref>. As I write this paper, part of me is pulled toward distractions, such as my neighbour's blaring Adele ringtone, my tea getting colder by the minute, and the presentation I must put together by Thursday evening. Another part of my attention is focusing and selecting, while engaging in the active process of varying what it is selecting for <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">(Vervaeke, 2021)</ref>. This provides me, a cognitive agent, with a salience landscape that makes it feel like I am here in this exact moment, in this state of consciousness, in this specific situation. This experience of connectedness to one's environment is fundamental for cognitive agency; without it, we are no different than pre-  <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Dennett, 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>, and the theory of RR circumvents the frame problem. For this reason, RR is indispensable for explaining how cognition functions. To the degree that moral decision-making is a cognitively involved process, we can ask ourselves in what way RR is implicated in human morality. In other words, how do the processes of relevance realization manifest in moral decision-making? We are now ready to finally return to the question that started our journey.</p><p>We observe life engaging in RR at the level of the single-cell, and in more complex organisms like human beings <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Hovhannisyan &amp; Dewey, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>. One of the oldest intellectual topics plaguing laypeople and psychologists <ref type="bibr">RELEVANCE REALIZATION,</ref><ref type="bibr">AGING,</ref> alike is that of morality. In the next section, we will be revisiting the phenomenon of moral decision-making across adulthood. The differences in younger and older adults' moral decisionmaking are well observed empirically. However, the theoretical explanations for why this age gap may exist appear fragmented or impartial, described much like the musings of "blind men" studying "different features of an elephant" <ref type="bibr">(Wallach, 2010, p. 7)</ref>. The explore-exploit shift proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner (2021)</ref> offers a possible unified explanation of the age-related trends in this domain. However, in applying this model to the phenomenon of moral decisionmaking among younger and older adults, we will see how the model explicates some (but not all) of the RR dynamics. By mapping various trends in aging onto the different constraints of RR, I</p><p>seek to demonstrate the need to adopt a broader lens to fully explain the observed age differences in moral decision-making. Specifically, I make the case that as humans age, there appears to be a broader trend toward efficiency (vs. resiliency) more generally, as opposed to a trend toward exploitation (vs. exploration) more specifically. This, in turn, helps to better explain why older (vs. younger) adults lean toward deontological decision-making when faced with sacrificial moral dilemmas.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Realizing Relevance in the Face of Moral Dilemmas Across Adulthood</head><p>The EE model of aging would suggest that older adults' propensity for deontological decision-making in the context of sacrificial moral dilemmas is due to their bias toward exploitation. In this section, I outline mechanisms underlying moral decision-making as discussed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Daley &amp; Kensinger (2021)</ref> and identify the trends that are suggestive of a bias toward exploitation, as conceptualized by <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner (2021)</ref>. In engaging in this process, we will 1) see that some of the trends that Spreng &amp; Turner have argued to be indicative of exploitation or exploration are more appropriately captured by the Cognitive Scope or Cognitive Prioritization constraints of RR (vs. only Cognitive Tempering), and 2) that some of the observed age differences in moral decision-making cannot be accounted for by the EE model. Importantly, in outlining these cognitive and socioemotional trends in aging, we will see that there is a wider accumulative trend toward efficiency-(vs. resiliency-) based processing in older adulthood.</p><p>There is also a theoretical reason for why I interface EE with the RR model, which brings us back to the frame problem. Given the EE model is concerned with only one constraint that </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Most of the age-related mechanisms implicated in moral decision-making can be</head><p>captured by the EE model-if not fully, at least partially. Older adults' decline in working memory capacity (which leads to the subsequent reliance on emotional salience in sacrificial moral dilemmas), is framed as the compression of information and integration of fewer choice options <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021)</ref>. One way to look at this process being expressive of an exploitative mental mode is that relative to younger adults, older adults are more concerned with the "line of best fit" when faced with a problem, as opposed to the line that will effectively capture all the data points <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>. Therefore, the decisions they make are more likely to be informed by the general rules they have adopted (e.g., do not kill), serving as heuristics to lean on. In this way, older adults "exploit" the cognitive structures that are already in place. As well, older adults are less proficient in holding and manipulating information, which would allow them to opt for the most appealing choice after having sifted through all the available options. Consequently, they are more likely to rely on salient sources of information (e.g., emotions). It may be that the additional options apparent to younger adults are simply outside older adults' perceptual boundaries, and thus cannot be integrated as valid choice options. Alternatively, it could be that because younger adults are more limited in prior knowledge, they must engage in more cognitively taxing processes to arrive at their decision. Given older adults' decaying inhibitory control, task-irrelevant content, such as emotional reactions that may arise when faced with a sacrificial moral dilemma, are more likely to impact a decision. <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner (2021)</ref> argue that older adults' reduced inhibitory control prevents them from overcoming their starting, exploitative, mental mode. We can reconcile these observations by viewing older adults' emotional reactivity as the prepotent response they cannot inhibit as effectively. Emotional goals become increasingly activated as we age and thus require less cognitive control to be kept in working memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021)</ref>. Through repeated activation, these become consolidated within existing schemas; as such, emotional responding favours an exploitative mental mode-it is more metabolically efficient, compared to the alternative of exerting cognitive control to override the default response.</p><p>The RR framework provides a more intricate breakdown of this trend. First, we see that as the inhibitory mechanisms that downregulate emotional reactivity decay in older age, the focus on "System 1" processing (or emotionality) becomes primary. This shift in focus on System 1 processing thus implicates Cognitive Prioritization (i.e., focusing vs. diversifying).</p><p>Once there is a shift toward focusing, exploiting priors such as the emotional heuristics an agent has adopted throughout their lifetime becomes a more reasonable avenue to take, thus implicating Cognitive Tempering, which involves the trade-off of exploitation and exploration.</p><p>And since the agent has adopted an emotional heuristic, they have therefore opted for "line of best-fit" strategy (i.e., a form of data compression), which therefore implicates the trade-off between general-purpose vs. special-purpose learning (i.e., Older adults' slower processing speed may be feeding into deontological decisionmaking by way of preventing the necessary exertion of cognitive control to arrive at the utilitarian choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. Spreng &amp; Turner (2021) do not directly discuss processing speed, but they suggest aging is associated with greater processing efficiency via lower control demands. As in, older adults are more likely to arrive at their decisions by drawing from existing information structures. Though the language is slightly different across these reviews (implicating a jangle fallacy), they both describe the same phenomenon. That is, older adults' decline in processing speed or increase in efficiency emerges from decline in cognitive control. This suggests an exploitative mental mode to the extent that slower processing acts as a unknown). In this trend, Cognitive Scope is implicated through general-purpose learning (data compression). The positivity bias can be viewed as a form of data compression because by viewing information in a positive light, a line of best fit that reduces ambiguity and noise is drawn; this comes at the loss of potentially important detail that is not necessarily positive.</p><p>However, Cognitive Tempering is (correctly) implicated in that the increased propensity to seek known rewards is a way of exploiting known priors. Importantly, both generalization and exploitation are indicative of a broader trend toward efficiency, once again suggesting that the tendency toward deontological decision-making across adulthood reflects a trend toward efficiency-based processing in older age.</p><p>As we age, we experience a shorter temporal horizon. Put crudely, death becomes a more realistic possibility. In the context of moral dilemmas, mortality salience has been shown to shift participants' responses toward the deontological choice, perhaps through the depletion of cognitive resources from attempts to suppress the distressing thoughts associated with inevitability <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021</ref>). The EE model <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021)</ref> suggests that due to older adults' narrowing time horizons, there is a lower value attached to unknown information, and a higher value associated with social intimacy. Reasonably, this would reduce older adults' desire to engage in exploration as a means of finding rewards through novelty and instead promote engagement with what they already find meaningful.</p><p>Reconciling these points, we can see that the deontological choice is an expression of an exploitative mental mode to the extent that 1) depletion of cognitive resources due to attempts at suppressing thoughts of impending death pushes participants to rely on internalized rules (i.e., do not kill), 2) entertaining the utilitarian choice becomes more costly than what it is worth, as there RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 39 is less time to both consider the risks that may come with either choice and mitigate for costs if the plan goes awry, and 3) exploiting social connections becomes a means of cognitive offloading, such that, instead of having to engage in rigorous information processing alone, one can leverage social intimacy to disperse the task across numerous others (i.e., distributed cognition). In this case, the RR framework agrees with the EE model insofar that Cognitive Tempering is implicated in the trend of shrinking temporal horizons that may be feeding into deontological decisions. However, RR would suggest that the expression of a deontological choice that corresponds to reduced exploration via both depletion of cognitive resources and neophobia offers a "line of best-fit" solution (i.e., generalization), thus implicating Cognitive A commonly discussed trend in the aging literature is the accumulation of crystallized knowledge across the lifespan. This has not been discussed as a direct input into moral decisionmaking <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>, but instead a general observation that older adults have a greater knowledge bank to draw from, even if they are not as apt at manipulating novel information (i.e., reduction in fluid intelligence). <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner (2021)</ref> discussed this trend in the context of declining cognitive control (through poor updating based on new information and miscalibration of uncertainty) as well as gains in prior knowledge (including increased certainty and reward value for known options, and drawing from prior knowledge, like schemas, for current mentation). In other words, the EE model explains this trend in terms of the shift from exploration to exploitation. The RR framework agrees with the EE model in that poor learning and reliance on existing knowledge is an exploitative process. However, it also suggests that poor learning, and the expression of existing heuristics and schemas maps onto generalization (e.g., applying a "line of best fit" strategy), implicating Cognitive Scope as well. And since both Cognitive Tempering and Cognitive Scope are being implicated but neither is reducible to the other, this once again provides evidence that these individual processes reflect an increase in efficiency-based processing more generally, rather than an exploitative-based processing more specifically.</p><p>There are some processes involved in moral decision-making that are not directly captured by the EE model <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021)</ref>, namely older adults' greater generativity and evolving representation of the self (see the Section on "Socioemotional Account of Age Differences in Moral Decision-Making"). The EE model cannot neatly be applied to the observation that older adults are more concerned with the future generation nor that older adults are less socially distanced from others, less self-biased, and perceive the self as more continuous <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. The authors discuss social phenomena across aging, consolidating these under the exploration to exploitation shift; however, this is limited to discussion of trends that reflect older adults' motivation toward affective goals (e.g., narrowing time horizons, positivity bias), leaving out two mechanisms implicated in the age differences in moral decisionmaking (i.e., generativity and evolving representation of the self; <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>. The application of RR to these trends likewise faces a similar issue, requiring an application of the theory to the social dimension, which has not been articulated by the authors, as RR is concerned with the agent and the world [as opposed to the agent and (an)other agent(s); <ref type="bibr">Vervaeke et al., RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 43 2012</ref>]. If we find that RR is too limited to account for these trends, then the EE model, which RR subsumes, would also be too limited to account for it.</p><p>Generativity and the representation of the self are likely functions that emerge at the level of social cognition, and so they cannot be accounted for at the level of the individual alone. By definition, generativity involves a relationship with the younger generation. As well, older adults' reduced self-bias and social distancing is reflective of a prosocial tendency. Given we cannot directly apply RR to these trends, for now let us take a slight step back from the RR framework to assess whether these trends likewise reflect the meta-constraint of efficiency.</p><p>Recent work has explored the relationship between RR and the Big Five theory of personality <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke 2022)</ref>. The authors draw on a body of research that argues the five factors of personality can be accounted for by two higher-order factors, or metatraits: Stability and Plasticity <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(DeYoung, 2015)</ref>. Specifically, the authors make the case that meta-traits Stability and Plasticity correspond to the higher-order constraints efficiency and resiliency at the trait (vs. state) level <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022)</ref>. Importantly, under this model, trait Agreeableness falls under meta-trait Stability and is referred to as a proxy for social stability <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(DeYoung, 2015)</ref>. Agreeableness can be decomposed into two distinct systems: politeness, which accounts for the downregulation of antisocial impulses, and compassion, which accounts for the spontaneous bottom-up experience of prosocial impulses (DeYoung, 2015;</p><p>Hovhannisyan . If prosociality is an aspect of agreeableness via compassion, then the more compassionate one is, the more agreeable they are, and the more social stability they experience. Thus, if generativity and agreeableness are connected, and likewise, if agreeableness is implicated in perceiving self-other overlap, then given that agreeableness corresponds to meta-trait stability <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(DeYoung, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022)</ref>, which RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 44 essentially reflects the higher-order constraint of efficiency at the trait level, then an increase in generativity and a reduction in self-bias ought to correspond to an increase in efficiency (G. <ref type="bibr">Hovhannisyan, personal communication, July 7, 2023)</ref>. While both the EE model and RR framework are not directly applicable to these trends given their limitations in discussing social cognition, it still appears these two trends are reflective of an increase in efficiency-based processing, at least at the level of traits (vs. states).</p><p>Conversely, there are some aging trends <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner (2021)</ref> highlight that do not appear to feed into moral decision-making. Regardless, for our purposes, it is worthwhile to consider how these trends are subsumed by RR. For example, older adults' mental flexibility manifests as a reduced ability "to shift search strategies based on changing response contingencies" <ref type="bibr">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021, p.</ref>  reduced capacity for future planning and prospection maps onto general-purpose learning in that it calls for abstracted, low-rigour processing regarding the future, to extract general truths that can be applied across numerous contexts. Importantly, this trend also correctly implicates Cognitive Tempering, given that it is concerned with the interactional problem of projectability. Beyond what has already been discussed, a key limitation to consider is that RR is an emerging theory that lacks direct empirical testing. The only empirical test of this theory that I am aware of is contained within the pages of a dissertation that demonstrates relevance realization taking place at the level of individual differences in personality <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Hovhannisyan, 2023)</ref>. Using a qualitative, case-study approach, <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Hovhannisyan (2023)</ref> found that participants' Big Five personality traits were implicated in the adaptive and maladaptive ways they engaged with, or realized relevance, in the world <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022)</ref>. This dissertation was not a direct test of RR, but nonetheless revealed evidence in support of this theory. Notably, in the above section I have outlined how the cognitive and socioemotional processes involved in moral decision-making (which have been studied extensively -e.g., processing speed, working memory, mortality salience) can effectively be conceptualized through the lens of RR at the level of both subordinate and superordinate constraints, serving as indirect support for the theory.</p><p>Future research could undertake the novel task of directly testing RR machinery, bolstering its authority as a theory of cognitive function. As a starting point, I will propose potential paradigms that could elucidate the extent to which younger and older adults lean toward efficiency (vs. The exploration and exploitation trade-off has commonly been studied via information search tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021)</ref>. I suggest adopting a similar paradigm within the context of trolley dilemmas to study Cognitive Tempering, which deals with the interactional problem of projectability via the explore-exploit trade-off. Younger and older adults would be presented with the classic trolley dilemma with two primary choice options (i.e., pull lever or do nothing), as well as the opportunity to seek unknown, additional information prior to making a decision. In opting to seek new information, the participant would be directed to a page of clickable boxes, whereby each box would reveal content about the victims or situation (e.g., age, occupation, hobbies, how they ended up on the tracks, and so on). Considering older adults are more likely to seek known rewards, rely on priors, and are less interested in novel information, I would expect them to seek additional information to a lesser degree than younger adults, tending to make a decision with the information they already have (i.e., visual presentation of the classic trolley dilemma). Further, among participants who do seek more information, I would predict that older (vs. younger) adults would engage in the exploration of this new information to a lesser extent (i.e., selecting less boxes).</p><p>Cognitive Scope addresses the interactional problem of applicability by trading off special-and general-purpose learning. We can think of these opponent pairs as a line that captures all data points or a line of best fit, respectively. Older adults endorse deontological ethics to a greater extent than younger adults. Adopting rules such as "do not kill" and applying them across contexts may be indicative of heuristic-based reasoning. Heuristics are a type of data compression (i.e., generalization), while approaching different situations with different solutions are more reflective of data particularization (i.e., specialization). Participants could be presented with a series of dilemmas that vary features such as the physical directness of killing, risk posed <ref type="bibr">RELEVANCE REALIZATION,</ref><ref type="bibr">AGING,</ref> to the subject, inevitability of death, and so on, much like in the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Moore et al. (2008)</ref>.</p><p>After responding to each dilemma, participants would provide ratings on various questions that map onto a generalization or specialization strategy, assessing the extent to which it captures their reasoning on a scale of one to seven (e.g., "I thought about as many decision and outcome combinations as I could", "I relied on my morals"). I would expect that older adults would endorse items that reflect general-(vs. special-purpose) learning strategies more so than younger adults. Further, I would predict that older adults would be more consistent in their reasoning across dilemma types, with younger adults showcasing more variability.</p><p>Recall that the interactional problem being tackled by Cognitive Prioritization is that of flexible gambling, a system optimizing its prioritization of cost functions through the strategies of focusing and diversifying. In the review of RR, I gave the example of a hungry agent holding off on eating when faced with an existential emergency of needing to save lives (i.e., focusing on the urgent need, then diversifying attentional resources to meet other needs). One plausible way to gauge participants' engagement with either strategy is by presenting them with the classic Trolley and Footbridge dilemmas, involving pulling a lever or pushing a fat man; these dilemmas would signify low vs. high emotional conflict scenarios respectively (M. H. Turpin, personal communication, October 14, 2023). Participants would be prompted to list the factors they considered in arriving at their decision. Given older adults' declines in working memory and inhibitory control, which implies a reduced ability for mental manipulation of content as well as greater focus on System 1 processing respectively (as discussed above), I would predict that they would generate 1) a fewer number of considerations, as well as 2) more emotionally charged considerations that are not directly relevant to the dilemma at hand (i.e., greater focus on personal emotions, relatability to victim) for both high-and low-conflict scenarios. In contrast, I RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 48 would expect a larger list of considerations from younger adults and greater diversity in the content they generate (i.e., demographic information of victims, personal feelings) for lowconflict scenarios, but performance that resembles older adults' more so for high-conflict scenarios, such that they demonstrate more flexible adaptation to the emotional context of the dilemma compared to older adults. This is not to say younger adults will not attend to emotional cues, but that the relative weight of emotionality will be diminished in this age group. As in prior literature, I would further predict that older adults would endorse deontological decisions more so than younger adults across dilemma types.</p><p>There are likely other ways of operationalizing the RR constraints. The task of this comprehensive paper was not one of proposing experimental paradigms, but of applying an emerging theory to moral decision-making phenomena across younger and older adults, and in doing so, demonstrating that the mechanisms underlying moral decision-making can be conceptualized as being reflective of efficiency-based processing in older adulthood.</p><p>Nonetheless, I have proposed three potential paradigms that could target each of RR's subordinate constraints in the context of sacrificial moral dilemmas, which ought to be taken as blueprints to build and expand upon. Revealing that older adults are engaged in general-purpose learning, exploiting, and focusing strategies when faced with sacrificial moral dilemmas to a greater degree than younger adults would be to show that older adults lean toward efficiency-(vs. resiliency-) based processing more so than younger adults. Future research could explore the possibility of conducting empirical tests of RR in the context of moral decision-making using such paradigms, or perhaps developing a singular paradigm that can effectively capture all four constraints (including the meta constraints).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 49</head><p>We further ought to consider that this comprehensive paper is limited in its discussion of 1) neuroanatomy and 2) non-sacrificial moral dilemmas. To address the first point, discussion of neuroanatomy was simply unfeasible for this project but will be integrated in developing this paper into a manuscript. Importantly, it has already been shown that RR machinery is implicated in both the brain's "firing and wiring", in other words, patterns of neuronal connections and patterns of neuronal activation <ref type="bibr">(Vervaeke &amp; Ferraro, 2013, p. 14)</ref>. Thus, there is a high likelihood that the neuroanatomy producing the observed age differences in moral decisionmaking likewise ties back to the meta-constraint of efficiency. As for the second point, this paper limited the application of RR to sacrificial moral dilemmas to utilize an existing review that addresses the link between aging and moral decision-making (i.e., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Daley &amp; Kensinger, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Once again, this was done to keep the project contained. We ought to expect the same cognitive and socioemotional mechanisms informing moral decision-making in other types of moral scenarios, even if they do so to different degrees compared to what is elicited by sacrificial moral dilemmas. This line of reasoning likewise extends to more complex iterations of sacrificial moral dilemmas (e.g., the individual victim is someone you know); I would expect similar mechanisms underlying the moral decision, though implicated to varying degrees. Indeed, this is all speculation, and further expansion of this work is warranted to make such claims confidently.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Reader, I opened this text by telling you about the paramecium, a single-celled organism that realizes relevance as it floats around in still waters. We fast forwarded by four billion years and found ourselves in the Garden of Eden, where the cell was now man, and man was a selforganizing cognitive agent who sinned before God, with the transgression itself being the awareness of morality. We then delved into the literature on moral decision-making across younger and older adults, closely examining how the cognitive and socioemotional mechanisms that produce a differential age effect in sacrificial moral dilemmas are effectively captured by the Relevance Realization framework, an emerging theory of cognitive function that, as we have seen, subsumes the Exploration-Exploitation model of aging.</p><p>Across all the identified mechanisms involved in moral decision-making, older adults' leanings toward deontological decision-making could be mapped onto greater employment of generalization (vs. specialization), and/or exploitation (vs. exploration), and/or focusing (vs. diversifying). Thus, it is more plausible that the fundamental processes underlying moral decision-making across younger and older adults reflect a higher threshold to switch from efficiency to resiliency-based processing in older age <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>, instead of a higher threshold to switch from exploitation to exploration, as the EE model would suggest <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021</ref>). EE's theoretical precision and explanatory power can be improved by augmenting it with RR and the additional cognitive constraints it offers, including Cognitive Scope and Cognitive Prioritization as opposed to only Cognitive Tempering, as well as the higher-order efficiency-resiliency trade-off. The variables involved in the observed aging trends consequently can become more theoretically tractable, and our explanations of their underlying mechanisms less prone to logical fallacies, such as the jingle-jangle fallacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Grossmann et al., 2020)</ref>, as well as less likely to confront the notorious frame problem of cognition.</p><p>However, there is no reason to believe that the RR framework is a complete theory. What if cognition involves more processes than the trade-offs articulated by RR? That is, trade-offs beyond exploration vs. exploitation, general-purpose vs. special-purpose learning, and focusing vs. diversifying? If this is the case, then adopting RR as it currently stands would, much like EE and other theories of cognition, risk running into the frame problem. Importantly, the authors RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 51 have already made this point <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Vervaeke et al., 2012)</ref>, expressing that the RR framework is meant to serve as a viable starting point for a theory of relevance realization as it pertains to cognition, and suggesting there may indeed be other constraints implicated in how cognition realizes relevance. Nevertheless, the authors view all possible constraints as being encompassed under the fundamental trade-off between efficiency and resiliency (G. <ref type="bibr">Hovhannisyan, personal communication, November 7, 2023)</ref>.</p><p>Reader, let us return to the Garden of Eden one last time and rewind to the moment that God created Adam. Upon doing so, God decided that man should not be alone and so he created Adam's ezer k'negdo. This term is often incorrectly translated to a suitable or fitting helper.</p><p>However, the literal translation of this Hebrew term is a helper who is against him. In other words, Eve was created to fulfill the function of an oppositional, but complementary force to Adam. From the paramecium to our archetypal sinners, Adam and Eve, we see life realizing relevance through opponent-processing. If human evolution indeed began with a single cell, then this final reflection should come as no surprise.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>extend the evolutionary analogy by comparing the processes of relevance realization to the mechanisms of natural selection. Hovhannisyan and Vervaeke (2022) summarize this point as follows: Just as Darwin's theory dispenses with the project of theorizing about biological fitness and instead explains how biological fitness is continually realized in an evolving and self-organized fashion through the mechanisms of natural selection, so too does Vervaeke et al.'s (2012) theory of RR dispense with theorizing about relevance as such; instead, it attempts toexplain the mechanisms by which relevance-i.e., cognitive fitness-is continually realized in a self-organized, evolving, and dynamically situated fashion. We may refer toVervaeke et   al.'s (2012)  approach to the frame problem as an "opponent-processing" approach that replaces the computational metaphor for mental functioning with the metaphor of the mind as a dynamically situated cognitive economy. (p. 13)The key implication here is that a theory of cognitive function should not concern itself</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Finally, since the agent's cognitive economy consists of a host of (competing) opponent-processes that are adapted to a complex problem landscape, what counts as a relevant goal for the agent is likewise bound to shift based on the agent's interactions with the environment (e.g., once I satiate my hunger, I can refocus on editing my comprehensive paper). At no point is the capacity for relevance realization presupposed, but is instead explained as the optimization of reward through trade-off relationships between various opponent pairs.We see thatVervaeke et al.'s (2012)  approach circumvents the frame problem theoretically by proposing a set of non-specific mechanisms (i.e., opponent-processes) that can realize what is relevant (i.e., put a frame around available information) without either adopting a substantive definition of relevance or engaging in combinatorially explosive search strategies.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The second constraint is Cognitive Tempering, optimizing for the projectability of an agent's information by pairing exploitation and exploration. Exploitation maximizes on easy and immediately available rewards, risking opportunities that might not be readily graspable. Exploration mitigates this risk by pursuing more, in turn, risking nearby opportunities at a higher cost. Consider a drive as basic as hunger. A hungry agent can seek food by eating what is available at home or going to the grocery store to get new items. By staying where one is (i.e., exploiting), there is the risk of foregoing potentially better sources of nourishment. But by seeking something novel (i.e., exploration), there lies the risk of losing what one already has and not gaining anything better either. I will later discuss how the EE model of aging (Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021) makes use of this essential constraint (i.e., Cognitive Tempering) but omits the other necessary pairs of opponent-processes implicated in the human cognitive economy. RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 29 The final constraint is Cognitive Prioritization. When a system optimizes for Cognitive Prioritization, it gambles its resources through the trade-off of focusing and diversifying strategies. This constraint concerns the structuring and prioritization of numerous cost functions, as opposed to the heuristic optimization of individual functions</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>constraints of efficiency and resiliency, which manage the agent's overall cognitive economy from the top-down, unifying Cognitive Scope, Cognitive Tempering, and Cognitive Prioritization into a single system. Efficiency serves to reduce variation in the different possible paths of action the cognitive agent can opt for, thereby reducing entropy within the system's functioning. It encompasses general-purpose learning, exploitative learning, and focusing strategies. While it is less metabolically costly, too much efficiency risks the loss of long-term RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 30 adaptability to inevitable change. Resiliency complements efficiency by increasing the possibilities for action through special-purpose learning, explorative learning, and diversification strategies-and therefore increases entropy within the system. Resiliency allows a cognitive agent to adaptively self-organize its resources to fit an ever-fluctuating environment. Too much environmental variation would lead to chaos, depleting an agent's resources, and preventing adaptation to the problem landscape. By optimizing for efficiency and resiliency, the cognitive economy can redesign itself to fit to the environment as needed, realizing relevance "in a contextually sensitive and non-homuncular fashion" (Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022, p. 15). To further illustrate, we can think of efficiency as fitting ourselves to what is variant in the environment. Conversely, resiliency refers to fitting ourselves to what is invariant in the environment. While efficient processing from the lens of RR might look like a person wearing generic hiking boots on outdoor adventures to experience adequate mobility and traction across a range of possible terrains, resiliency would more closely resemble wearing mountaineering boots fitted with crampons to climb snowy mountain peaks. 5 Humans-cognitive agents, engage in a dynamic trade-off relationship between efficiency and resiliency, optimizing for reward depending on the problem domain they find themselves within. As we move forward in this text, I will argue that the cognitive and socioemotional mechanisms implicated in moral decisionmaking lean toward efficiency-based processing more broadly across the lifespan, in turn, manifesting as deontological decision-making in the face of sacrificial moral dilemmas.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>programmed machines. RR explains how we can adaptively self-correct and change our frames over time, realizing relevance while evading combinatorial explosion in our strategies for coping with the inexhaustible information available in our world. At this point, Reader, it is reasonable for you to ask me, what is the link between RR, aging, and moral decision-making, if there is one at all? The existing literature on RR argues that the mechanisms underlying RR are fundamental for understanding how cognition functions (Vervaeke et al., 2012; Vervaeke &amp; Ferraro, 2013a; 2013b; Hovhannisyan &amp; Dewey, 2017; Hovhannisyan &amp; Vervaeke, 2022). The foundation of this claim is theoretically robust insofar as the frame problem confronts all theories of cognitive function</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>trades off exploration-exploitation (i.e., Cognitive Tempering), it necessarily confronts the frame problem by omitting the possibility of a cognitive agent engaging in generalization-specialization or focusing-diversifying trade-off processes (i.e., Cognitive Scope &amp; Cognitive Prioritization respectively). A cognitive agent that is trading off only exploration and exploitation is like Dennett's robot (1987) being entirely indifferent to the applicability of its frames (special-vs. general-purpose learning) or the priority of its goals (focusing vs. diversifying). 6 A robot, and by extension a cognitive agent, that is incapable of trading off the opponent pairs within Cognitive Scope or Cognitive Prioritization is bound to run into the frame problem by employing combinatorially explosive strategies in each of these domains. By initiating this dialogue between EE and RR, I highlight the twofold need to 1) adopt a more comprehensive and nuanced view of human cognition in explaining phenomena like moral decision-making, in a manner that 2) reduces the likelihood of confronting the frame problem in explaining aging trends in human cognition.Daley &amp; Kensinger (2021) explain older adults' deontological decision-making in terms of cognitive decline (i.e., implicating working memory capacity, inhibitory control, processing speed) and socioemotional motivation (i.e., positivity bias, temporal horizons, generativity, and representation of the self), dividing the age-related processes implicated in moral decisionmaking into two distinct arcs. On the other hand,<ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner (2021)</ref> divide the predictors of older adults' exploitative mental mode into three categories, including declines in cognitive control (i.e., implicating learning, working memory, inhibition, mental flexibility, future planning and prospection), gains in prior knowledge (i.e., reward predictability, associative processing, processing efficiency), and motivation toward affective or meaningful goals (i.e., positivity bias, positive reward expectation, and narrowing time horizons).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Importantly, from the RR point of view, information compression is a function of Cognitive Scope, not Cognitive Tempering, because this process is concerned with the interactional problem of how to fit data, not the interactional problem of whether to rely on priors by forfeiting the pursuit of meaningful opportunities that may be out of reach (or even deemed as unnecessary). Recall that the opponent pairs of Cognitive Scope are general-and special-purpose learning, with the pairs concerning the low-rigour (i.e., extract the best-fit trend) and high-rigour (i.e., track all the data points) processing of information, respectively. In light of the distinctions made known by the RR framework, the EE model appears to conflate Cognitive Tempering with Cognitive Scope in outlining the application of declining working memory in older adulthood. Significant constraints in working memory capacity make data particularization (i.e., specialization, such as the line that fits all data points) far less probable, and data compression (i.e., generalization, such as the line of best fit) far more probable as the primary style of processing. Under cognitive constraint, it is more feasible to rely on rules (i.e., generalizations) such as "do not kill", than to weigh context-sensitive pros and cons when faced with a given moral dilemma (i.e., specialization). The RR framework agrees with the EE model insofar as the observation is a trend toward efficiency. However, the RR model makes a differentclassification of the trend as belonging to Cognitive Scope (vs. Cognitive Tempering), as per the interactional problem being faced: applicability, as opposed to projectability. RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 36</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Cognitive Scope). Once again, RR agrees with the EE model insofar as what is observed here is a shift toward efficiency-based processing. However, it makes distinctions that allow us to effectively track the various interactional problems at play, by showing how not only Cognitive Tempering (exploitation), but also Cognitive Prioritization (focusing) and Cognitive Scope (general-purpose learning) are all implicated in the decay of inhibitory control.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>bottleneck on the maximum possible metabolic output of the agent, placing a greater demand on the exploitation of priors, thereby implicating the constraint of Cognitive Scope through data compression, once again. This may manifest as exploiting existing schemas, gist-based knowledge, or general-purpose heuristics (i.e., generalizations; Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021). While the EE model captures a trend toward efficiency-based processing, RR identifies the unique roles played by both Cognitive Tempering and Cognitive Scope insofar as efficiency subsumes both exploitation, a component of the former, and generalization, a component of the latter. The positivity bias and prioritization of emotional well-being in older adulthood may promote deontological decision-making as a means of minimizing the negative emotions elicited by sacrificial moral dilemmas. Spreng &amp; Turner (2021) suggest that older adults' positively valenced and gist-based memories serve to promote known over unknown choices. For example, if doing no harm carries a positive connotation, older adults are more likely to select the choice RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 38 that realizes this bit of positively valenced information, thereby, exploiting what is known (vs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Scope as well. Once again, the EE model identifies a trend toward efficiency-based processing, but RR refines this observation, recognizing the unique roles of both Cognitive Scope and Cognitive Tempering.Most times<ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng &amp; Turner (2021)</ref> and<ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Vervaeke et al. (2012)</ref> are in agreement, such that the EE model will recognize that Cognitive Tempering is implicated, but not consider the other constraints at play in regulating an agent's cognitive economy, like in the case of older adults' slower processing speed, declines in inhibitory control, positivity bias, or shrinking temporal horizons. Additionally, when accounting for the other possible constraints identified by RR, in at least one instance,<ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Spreng and Turner (2021)</ref> conflate Cognitive Tempering with other constraints (i.e., Cognitive Scope), overfitting the EE model, such as in arguing reduced working memory reflects an exploitative mental mode. A likely explanation as to why the researchers overextended their model is because they recognize that exploitation entails greater efficiency, and efficiency is the common theme that accounts for all the functional trends that have been discussed above. RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 40Overall, however, in light of the explanatory scheme offered by RR, we can see that the opponency of exploration-exploitation (i.e., Cognitive Tempering) alone is insufficient in explaining the cognitive and socioemotional trends that produce age differences in sacrificial moral dilemmas. This is because the interactional problems corresponding to each of the constraints are distinct and mutually irreducible, such that, the interactional problem being tackled in Cognitive Tempering, which is that of projectability, cannot be reduced to the interactional problem being tackled by Cognitive Scope, which is that of applicability, nor the interactional problem being tackled by Cognitive Prioritization, which is that of flexible gambling. Put differently, it is the case that exploitation entails efficiency, but it is not necessarily the case that efficiency implies exploitation, since it might instead imply generalization (Cognitive Scope) or focusing (Cognitive Prioritization). Importantly, exploitation, generalization, and focusing are all efficiency-based processes, revealing an aging trend toward efficiency (vs. resiliency) more generally, as opposed to a more specific trend toward exploitation (vs. exploration). This final observation leads us to conclude that the EE model alone is insufficient in explaining the age-related trends implicated in moral decisionmaking across younger and older adults and can effectively be augmented by the RR framework which offers additional cognitive constraints for consideration. With this in mind, let us now proceed to discuss the limitations of the EE model, RR as a theory of cognitive function, and this comprehensive paper.DiscussionAbove I discussed the age-sensitive cognitive and socioemotional inputs of moral decision-making as they relate to the EE model and RR framework. Across all the mechanisms discussed, older adults' greater tendency toward deontological decision-making was reflective of RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 41 greater efficiency, through greater employment of generalization (vs. specialization), and/or exploitation (vs. exploration), and/or focusing (vs. diversifying). Thus, our phenomenon of interest is not so much the reflection of a higher threshold to switch from exploitation to exploration<ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Spreng &amp; Turner, 2021)</ref>, but instead a higher threshold to switch from efficiency to resiliency-based processing. Across all the mechanisms underlying decision-making in the context of sacrificial moral dilemmas, at least one additional constraint than Cognitive Tempering (i.e., exploration vs. exploitation) was implicated in explaining age differencesnamely either Cognitive Scope (i.e., generalization vs. specialization) or Cognitive Prioritization (i.e., focusing vs. diversifying). Thus, given that the interactional problems corresponding to each of the constraints identified by RR are mutually irreducible, the EE model on its own is insufficient in explaining age effects in moral decision-making when considering the additional constraints identified by RR. If it is the case that RR can explain moral decision-making trends, then across all domains where the above discussed cognitive and socioemotional mechanisms are implicated, we should expect RR to successfully fulfill the task of explaining any age differences that arise.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3). This process reflects RR's Cognitive Prioritization constraint (i.e., focusing vs. diversifying) given it is concerned with the optimal structuring and prioritization of cost functions. Older adults' reduced mental flexibility can be framed as a greater tendency to focus their cognitive resources, given the limited capacity to diversify. Thus, reduced mental flexibility is functionally related to Cognitive Tempering (i.e., explore vs. exploit) only through the higher order constraint of efficiency (see Hovhannisyan &amp; Dewey, 2017). Put differently, Cognitive Prioritization and Cognitive Tempering are related only because they are specialized instances of the efficiency-resiliency opponency, not because they are identical processes. Similarly, Spreng &amp; Turner (2021) identify future planning and prospection as a sub-trend in older adults' decline in cognitive control, highlighting the "prospective foraging and mental simulations necessary for directed exploration" (p. 3). Recall that Cognitive Scope trades off demands for special-vs. general-purpose learning. Older adults'</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>However, if both Cognitive Scope and Cognitive Tempering are implicated, then the EE model is insufficient in explaining this trend, once again highlighting RR's edge in explaining aging phenomena, as one that is characterized by a broader trend toward efficiency-based processing.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>resiliency) based processing by capturing the subordinate constraints (i.e., Cognitive Scope, Tempering and Prioritization), at least, in the context of sacrificial moral dilemmas. RELEVANCE REALIZATION, AGING, &amp; MORAL DECISION-MAKING 46</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Opponent-processes underlying relevance realization</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Efficiency</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Cognitive Scope</cell><cell cols="2">Cognitive Tempering Cognitive Prioritization</cell></row><row><cell>General-purpose learning</cell><cell>Exploiting</cell><cell>Focusing</cell></row><row><cell>Special-purpose learning</cell><cell>Exploring</cell><cell>Diversifying</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Resiliency</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Note. Depiction of opponent-process pairs closely derived from</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">These dilemmas have also infiltrated popular culture and are unlikely to be novel stimuli to research participants.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Interestingly,<ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Moore et al. (2008)</ref> argue that the complexity of emotion-cognition integration processes that is evident in moral contexts is not effectively captured by the dual-process account of moral decision-making.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Related to older adults' interpersonal goals, one study found that older adults endorsed altruistic moral decisions that favoured social (over personal) interest to a greater degree than younger adults<ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Rosen et al., 2016)</ref>. This effect was mediated by emotional empathy but not reasoning.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">A purely efficient organism is a "jack of all trades" while a purely resilient organism is a "master of one."</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">For example, a robot indifferent to Cognitive Scope might employ a line of best-fit solution by treating other objects (like the battery) in its environment as explosive (like the bomb) in its attempts at evading the threat of extinction, thereby failing to replenish its reserves. Similarly, just as in<ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Dennett's (1987)</ref> illustration, a robot indifferent to Cognitive Prioritization might fail to determine which side-effects of its actions to tend to in a timesensitive manner, once again risking extinction.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predictive processing and relevance realization: exploring convergent solutions to the frame problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vervaeke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11097-022-09850-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11097-022-09850-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phenomenology &amp; the Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Associative Activation and Its Relation to Exploration and Exploitation in the Brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Baror</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="776" to="789" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797616634487</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797616634487" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Everyday problem solving and emotion: An adult developmental perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Blanchard-Fields</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-8721.2007.00469.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8721.2007.00469.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social and emotional patterns in adulthood: Support for socioemotional selectivity theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carstensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0882-7974.7.3.331</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0882-7974.7.3.331" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology &amp; Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="331" to="338" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Socioemotional selectivity theory and the regulation of emotion in the second half of life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carstensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1024569803230</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1024569803230" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Motivation &amp; Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aging and the Intersection of Cognition, Motivation, and Emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carstensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mikels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1016/B978-012101264-9/50018-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-012101264-9/50018-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of the psychology of aging</title>
		<editor>J. E. Birren &amp; K. W. Schaire</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="362" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unpleasant situations elicit different emotional responses in younger and older adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carstensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology &amp; Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="495" to="504" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/a0013284</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0013284" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Relevance Realization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Aging</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>DECISION-MAKING 53</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aging and emotional memory: The forgettable nature of negative images for older adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carstensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0096-3445.132.2.310</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0096-3445.132.2.310" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">132</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="310" to="324" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive decline, socioemotional change, or both? How the science of aging can inform future research on sacrificial moral dilemmas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Daley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kensinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychology, &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="272" to="299" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Aging</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/13825585.2021.2019183</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/13825585.2021.2019183" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age-related differences in Default Mode Network resting-state functional connectivity but not gray matter volume relate to sacrificial moral decision-making and working memory performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Daley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kensinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2022.108399</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2022.108399" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">177</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">108399</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Robots Dilemma Revisited: The Frame Problem in Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>K. M. Ford &amp; Z. W. Pylyshyn</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Praeger</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Cognitive Wheels: The Frame Problem of AI. 2nd edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cybernetic big five theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Deyoung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jrp.2014.07.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jrp.2014.07.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age-related changes in episodic memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Duarte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kensinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The aging brain: Functional adaptation across adulthood</title>
		<editor>G. R. Samanez-Larkin</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="134" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0000143-005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0000143-005" />
		<imprint>
			<publisher>American Psychological Association</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Vital involvement in old age</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Erikson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Erikson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Kivnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>W. W. Norton &amp; Company</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Relevance Realization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Aging</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moral Decision-Making 54</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why are VMPFC patients more utilitarian? A dual-process theory of moral judgment explains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1016/j.tics.2007.06.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2007.06.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="322" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive load selectively interferes with utilitarian moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Morelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lowenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nystrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2007.11.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2007.11.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1144" to="1154" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An fMRI investigation of emotional engagement in moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sommerville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nystrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Darley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">293</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5537</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2105" to="2108" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The science of wisdom in a polarized world: Knowns and unknowns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Grossmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Weststrate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ardelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Brienza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ferrari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Vervaeke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/1047840X.2020.1750917</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/1047840X.2020.1750917" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Haidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1745-6916.2008.00063</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1745-6916.2008.00063" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Morality. Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social economic decision-making across the lifespan: An fMRI investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Harlé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Sanfey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1416" to="1424" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2012.02.026</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2012.02.026" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age and inhibition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hasher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Stoltzfus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Zacks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rypma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0278-7393.17.1.163</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-7393.17.1.163" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Relevance Realization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Aging</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moral Decision-Making 55</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The central executive as a search process: Priming exploration and exploitation across domains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hills</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Todd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Goldstone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/a0020666</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0020666" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="590" to="609" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Demonstration of Enactivist Personality Assessment Using the Five-Factor Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hovhannisyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>unpublished doctoral dissertation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural &amp; normative dynamical coupling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hovhannisyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dewey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogsys.2016.11.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogsys.2016.11.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Systems Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="128" to="139" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hovhannisyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vervaeke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11097-021-09768-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11097-021-09768-5" />
		<title level="m">Enactivist big five theory. Phenomenology &amp; the Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="375" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Veilof-ignorance reasoning mitigates self-serving bias in resource allocation during the COVID-19 crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bernhard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Barak-Corren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bazerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment &amp; Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1930297500008275</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1930297500008275" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age differences in intuitive moral decision-making: Associations with inter-network neural connectivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Faul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sevinc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mwilambwe-Tshilobo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Setton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lockrow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ebner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Spreng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>De Brigard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/pag0000633</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/pag0000633" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology &amp; Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="902" to="916" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sidetracked by trolleys: Why sacrificial moral dilemmas tell us little (or nothing) about utilitarian judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kahane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="560" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17470919.2015.1023400</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17470919.2015.1023400" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive aging in a social and affective context: Advances over the past 50 years</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kensinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Gutchess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/geronb/gbw056</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/geronb/gbw056" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journals of Gerontology: Series B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Relevance Realization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Aging</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moral Decision-Making</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The effects of age on memory for socioemotional material: An affective neuroscience perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kensinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Allard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Krendl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>P. Verhaeghen &amp; C</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Oxford handbook of emotion, social cognition, and problem solving in adulthood</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hertzog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="46" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199899463.013.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199899463.013.011" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of sad mood on memory in older adults: A test of the mood congruence effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Maines</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0882-7974.17.4.653</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0882-7974.17.4.653" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology &amp; Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="653" to="661" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working memory, task switching, and executive control in the task span procedure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0096-3445.133.2.218</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0096-3445.133.2.218" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="218" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Better with age: Social relationships across adulthood</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Luong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Fingerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Social &amp; Personal Relationships</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0265407510391362</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0265407510391362" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Search and the aging mind: The promise and limits of the cognitive control hypothesis of age differences in search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Von Helversen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/tops.12139</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12139" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="416" to="427" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aging and Attentional Biases for Emotional Faces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carstensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1467-9280.01455</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-9280.01455" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="415" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aging and motivated cognition: The positivity effect in attention and memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Carstensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="496" to="502" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2005.08.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2005.08.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Relevance Realization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Aging</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moral Decision-Making</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Autopoiesis and cognition: The realization of the living</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Maturana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Varela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Springer Science &amp; Business Media</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The moderating role of executive functioning in older adults&apos; responses to a reminder of mortality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maxfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pyszczynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pepin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/a0023902</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0023902" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology &amp; Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age differences in moral judgment: Older adults are more deontological than younger adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mcnair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Okan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hadjichristidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>De Bruin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1002/bdm.2086</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.2086" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Under The Microscope: Paramecium</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mcvean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.mcgill.ca/oss/article/did-you-know-environment/under-microscope-" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-03-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who shalt not kill? Individual differences in working memory capacity, executive control, and moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-9280.2008.02122.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9280.2008.02122.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="549" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">New International Version Bible</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.biblegateway.com/versions/New-International-Version-NIV-Bible/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combinatorial Explosion</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.encyclopedia.com/computing/dictionaries-thesauruses-pictures-and-press-releases/combinatorial-explosion" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A Dictionary of Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Meta-analysis of the age-related positivity effect: Age differences in preferences for positive over negative information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mikels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/a0035194</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0035194" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology &amp; Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Relevance Realization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Aging</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moral Decision-Making 58</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk, reward, and economic decision making in aging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Roalf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Harbaugh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Janowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1093/geronb/gbr099</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/geronb/gbr099" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journals of Gerontology: Series B: Psychological Sciences and Social Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="289" to="298" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empathy mediates the effects of age and sex on altruistic moral decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rosen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kalbe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">67</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From past to future: Temporal self-continuity across the life span</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rutt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Löckenhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/pag0000090</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/pag0000090" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology &amp; Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="631" to="639" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The processing-speed theory of adult age differences in cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Salthouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0033-295X.103.3.403</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.103.3.403" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="428" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Frame Problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shanahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>E. N. Zalta &amp; U. Nodelman</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy. Stanford University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Older people are perceived as more moral than younger people: data from seven culturally diverse countries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sorokowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kowal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hussain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Haideri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Misiak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Chatzipentidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Paruzel-Czachura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ethics &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/10508422.2023.2248327</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/10508422.2023.2248327" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive control and dishonesty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Speer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Smidts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Boksem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2022.06.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2022.06.005" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="796" to="808" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From exploration to exploitation: A shifting mental mode in late life development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Spreng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1058" to="1071" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2021.09.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2021.09.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mind in life: Biology, phenomenology, and the sciences of mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>Belknap Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Relevance Realization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Aging</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moral Decision-Making 59</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Précis of mind in life: Biology, phenomenology, and the sciences of mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consciousness Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5-6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mortality salience and morality: Thinking about death makes people less utilitarian</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Trémolière</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>De Neys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Bonnefon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2012.05.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2012.05.011" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A strong dependency between changes in fluid and crystallized abilities in human cognitive aging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tucker-Drob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>De La Fuente</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Köhncke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Brandmaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Nyberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Lindenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/sciadv.abj2422</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abj2422" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">UCSB) ScienceLine</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-10-11" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manipulations of emotional context shape moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Valdesolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Desteno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-9280.2006.01731.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9280.2006.01731.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="476" to="477" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">John Vervaeke describes relevance realisation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vervaeke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-12-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Post-Apocalyptic Theology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Youtube</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://youtu.be/H-opRmx6C9c" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Relevance Realization and the Neurodynamics and Neuroconnectivity of General Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vervaeke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ferraro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Harvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cavoukian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tomko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Borrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4614-6409-9_6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-6409-9_6" />
		<editor>Hatzinakos, D.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relevance realization and the emerging framework in cognitive science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vervaeke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Lillicrap</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Richards</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Logic &amp; Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/logcom/exp067</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/logcom/exp067" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Relevance Realization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Aging</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>DECISION-MAKING 60</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of uncertainty in attentional and choice exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Luque</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Le Pelley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Beesley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1911" to="1916" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-019-01653-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-019-01653-2" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive models of moral decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Wallach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1756-8765.2010.01101.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1756-8765.2010.01101.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="420" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ageing and health</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/ageing-and-health" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Health Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022-10-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of ageing and divided attention on the self-reference effect in emotional memory: Spontaneous or effortful mnemonic benefits?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Truong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fuss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bislimovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="596" to="607" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/09658211.2012.690040</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/09658211.2012.690040" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
