<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2017-08">August 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gesa-Kristina</forename><surname>Petersen</surname></persName>
							<email>petersen.gk@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Munich School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Ludwig-Maximilians-Universitaet Muenchen</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blair</forename><surname>Saunders²</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Inzlicht</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Rotman School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Munich School of Management</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ludwig-Maximilians-Universitaet Muenchen Schackstrasse 4</addrLine>
									<postCode>80539</postCode>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2017-08">August 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Investor behaviour</term>
					<term>Objective value conflict</term>
					<term>Subjective value conflict</term>
					<term>CN</term>
					<term>ERPs</term>
					<term>EEG</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Individuals struggle when making financial decisions, sometimes preferring lower future rewards over actively making decisions at all. Here, we examine how conflict deriving from objective and subjective value characteristics of stocks, as well as the behavioural and phenomenological correlates of decision conflict, are accompanied by variation in a thus far understudied ERP component, the conflict negativity (CN). In a novel EEG paradigm (N = 53), we simulated a financial decision situation in which participants made incentivized choices between different, sometimes conflicting, stock options. Our results indicate that participants take longer, are more undecided and less pleased, when choosing between conflicting options compared to choices where one option is obviously better than the alternative-even when choosing between two objectively good alternatives. We further provide preliminary evidence that the CN, a negative-going ERP recorded over the medial prefrontal cortex, not only reacts to conflict decisions but also predicts participants&apos; behavioural indecision during choice. What is more, subjective value characteristics of stocks, impressions based on brand perception of the stock options, influenced affective and behavioral reactions over and above objective stock characteristics. While our results are at odds with assumptions made by classic economic theory, they can be applied to real world observations on private investor behaviour.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 3</head><p>Decisions are not easy, and this is especially true when it comes to our finances.</p><p>Financial research and real-world trading data, for example, suggest that investors avoid making even relatively simple investment choices (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Johnson &amp; Goldstein, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Thaler &amp; Benartzi, 2004)</ref>, and levels of trading activity are low, with only one in five individuals with brokerage accounts making no trades at all <ref type="bibr">("Shareownership 2000</ref><ref type="bibr">("Shareownership ", 2002</ref>, a phenomenon commonly known as investor inertia. Planning and saving for retirement, for example, is a form of investment decision that affects almost all individuals. Yet, individuals often avoid difficult decisions in this domain and, in turn, make suboptimal portfolio allocations <ref type="bibr">(Madrian &amp; Shea, 2011</ref>) that result in lower provisions (e.g., savings, income) for old age. But what makes financial decisions, with seemingly rewarding outcomes, so aversive and avoidable?</p><p>Here we explore the neural, behavioural, and phenomenological correlates of indecision during value-guided choices in a simulated stock-market.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Difficulty and discomfort during decision making</head><p>Preference-based decisions in scenarios with uncertain outcomes are often beset by indecision, anticipated regret, and unpleasant experiences-even when people choose between two objectively good alternatives (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Anderson, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr">Richard, Van der Pilgt &amp; De Vries, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Schwarz, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Zeelenberg, 1999)</ref>. In one sense, it seems counterintuitive that such decisions would give rise to aversive experiences. Positive emotion might be expected in situations where favourable outcomes are certain (such as choosing between two equally promising investment options). Philosophical perspectives of free-will, however, have proposed that such paradoxes are prevalent during rational decision making. Aristotle, for example, stated that a person, "…exceedingly hungry and thirsty, and both equally, yet being equidistant from food and drink, is therefore bound to stay where he is…" <ref type="bibr">(350 BC, trans. 1922, book II, part 13)</ref>. As captured in the quotation, a purely rational decision making process is stymied when the agent is forced to deliberate between two equally appealing options. VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL <ref type="bibr">DECISION MAKING 4</ref> While the allegory of the hungry and thirsty man stalling when equally situated between food and drink might sound like hyperbole, modern accounts of affect and motivation suggest that indecision and conflict provoke unpleasant experiences <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Festinger, 1962;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Proulx, Inzlicht, &amp; Harmon-Jones, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2014)</ref>. Empirical evidence also supports the idea that conflicts in value-guided decision making are aversive.</p><p>With regards to occupational choices, neuroscience research using ERPs has demonstrated that decisions involving high conflict (i.e., when two or more response options are similarly valued) lead to higher levels of neurophysiological conflict and slower response times than low conflict decisions in the same domain (i.e., when one option is clearly preferable to the other) <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Nakao et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Nakao, Bai, Nashiwa, &amp; Northoff, 2013</ref>).</p><p>In the current study we explored the integration of neurophysiological and affective correlates of effortful financial decision making using an ERP termed the conflict negativity <ref type="bibr">(CN;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Nakao et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">2013)</ref>. The CN is a negative going ERP that peaks 50-100 ms after a response at frontal/central midline electrode sites <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Di Domenico, Le, Liu, Ayaz, &amp; Fournier, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Nakao et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Nakao et al., , 2013</ref>, and has been source localised to dipole generators within the anterior cingulate cortex (ACC; Di <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Domenico et al., 2016)</ref>. The temporospatial profile of the CN-in addition to the component's putative neural generators-suggests that it likely belongs to a family of performance monitoring related midline ERPs sensitive to conflict, including as the error-related negativity (ERN), feedback negativity (FN), and N2 (cf., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Holroyd &amp; Coles, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Yeung, Botvinick, &amp; Cohen, 2004)</ref>. The CN perhaps bears closest resemblance to the correct-related negativity (CRN; <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Vidal, Hasbroucq, Grapperon, &amp; Bonnet, 2000</ref>) that presents as a small negative deflection 0-100 ms after accurate performance, and is sensitive to variation in conflicts arising during executive functioning tasks such as the flanker paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bartholow et al., 2005)</ref>. While further investigation and source localisation are clearly warranted, it is reasonable to suspect that the CN, ERN, N2, and CRN reflect the VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 5 activity of a common frontocentral monitoring system (see <ref type="bibr">Cavanagh, Zambrano-Vazquez, &amp; Allen, 2011)</ref>.</p><p>One factor that sets the CN apart from other performance monitoring ERPs-and motivates us to retain the distinct nomenclature-is that the CN appears to track conflict during subjective, value-based decision making. That is, the CN arises during decision making conflicts between personal preferences, such as occupational choice <ref type="bibr">(Di Dominico et al., 201;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Nakao et al., 2010)</ref>. This functional characteristic of the CN means that it might be utilised to investigate conflict monitoring across a range of decision making domains that bear closer resemblance to the types of uncertain decisions-those decisions in which there is no concrete right or wrong answer-that we so commonly face in our day to day lives.</p><p>The CN is also distinct from other performance monitoring ERPs in that it is relatively understudied. Consequently, a key goal of the current work was to further explore the functional significance of the CN by testing the ERP's associations with the behavioural and phenomenological correlates of value-guided decision making. In one fMRI study relevant to the current research, high value conflicts during consumer decision making (i.e., selecting between two desirable goods) was associated with increased anxiety relative to choices involving one less desirable product option <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2014)</ref>. Furthermore, this anxiety covaried with canonical conflict-related neural activity in the anterior cingulate cortex-a brain region associated with both negative affect and conflict monitoring <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Shackman et al., 2011)</ref>; whereas, positive affect covaried with activity in the ventromedial prefrontal cortex-a brain region commonly implicated in valuation <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Hare, Camerer, &amp; Rangel, 2009</ref>). In the current study we tested if variation in the CN-also putatively generated in the ACC-would similarly covary with the unpleasant experience of decision conflict during a novel financial decision making task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 6</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Financial decision making</head><p>With regards to normative economic theories (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Schoemaker, 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Fehr &amp; Hoff, 2011)</ref>, facing objectively equal options should induce no conflict at all. If options are equal, and choosing one or the other leads to an equivalent outcome, subjective valuations such as liking should not matter at all. The slightest indication of one option economically dominating the other-even by a single cent-should clearly guide the rational decision maker without conflict. As a logical conclusion, financial decisions should be easy because either it does not matter which option to choose or one option is clearly better than the other. However, as already stated, findings in empirical finance, in addition to the neuroscience of subjective decision making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2014)</ref>, suggest decisions-even between equally valuable options-are not made in this rational manner.</p><p>What is more, in real-world trading data, investors consider subjective in addition to economic factors when making decisions. For example, social information about mutual fund managers such as their ethnicity <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Kumar, Niessen-Ruenzi, &amp; Spalt, 2015)</ref> or gender  influences fund inflows when controlling for objective characteristics (i.e. risk and return characteristics). Thus, subjective preferences seem to influence financial decisions over and above economic factors, perhaps partially explaining why seemingly straightforward financial decisions can become beset with conflict and indecision.</p><p>To sum, though no conflict should arise when making investment decisions based on normative economic models, we propose, based on recent empirical economic data and the affective neuroscience of decision making, that investors will experience conflict and unpleasant emotion when making investment decisions between objectively equal options.</p><p>We further suggest that subjective preference matters over and above objective characteristics. Critically, we examined within-person affective, behavioural, and neurophysiological responses to financial decision conflict.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 7</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Current study</head><p>Based on our propositions, we tested four general hypotheses regarding the role of conflict in financial decision making. First, we expect that decisions between equally valuable options will generate an aversive conflict state characterised by higher levels of behavioural indecision, increased amplitude of the CN (c.f., <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Nakao et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Nakao et al., 2013)</ref>, reduced positive affect, and increased anxiety relative to options with one clearly preferable option. Second, we tested if these conflict effects are amplified by expected value that is if conflict effects are larger when higher rewards are at stake. Third, we predicted that withinparticipant variation in the CN-as a neural correlate of conflict monitoring-would correlate with within-person variation in behavioural indecision, positive affect, and anxiety. In short, the magnitude of neural reactivity to conflict will go hand-in-hand with the behavioural and phenomenological correlates of decision difficulty. Fourth, we tested if subjective preferences for available investment options correlate with the neural, behavioural, and phenomenological correlates of conflict over and above the objective characteristics of the stock options.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants and design</head><p>The study consisted of two parts: An online survey and a laboratory experiment.</p><p>Altogether 56 undergraduate participants from the University of Toronto Scarborough took part in return for course credit. The advertisement to the participant pool offered the chance to play a stock-broker game, for which participants were compensated with course credit; they were also given the opportunity to earn a bonus cash prize. A power analysis using G*Power 3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Faul, Erdfelder, Lang, &amp; Buchner, 2007)</ref> testing a within-between interaction with small effect sizes (f=0.15) in a mixed model suggested collecting 50 (80 % power) to 64 (90% power) participants. We thus aimed to collect close to 60 participants and did not conduct hypothesis testing before termination of data collection. Three participants were excluded VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 8 from the sample because they did not understand the experimental task (for further details see "procedure -learning phase") leaving 53 participants. EEG analyses were conducted with a minimum of four trials per bin (please find results for three and five trials per bin in the supplemental online material: https://osf.io/mpyn3/). 5 participants from the laboratory could not be matched with data from the online survey, so that data from these participants could not be used for combined analyses. Overall, participants were on average 19.17 years old (SD = 2.01 years, 90% CI <ref type="bibr">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr">22]</ref>), lived for 12.22 years in Canada (SD = 7.25 years, 90% CI <ref type="bibr">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr">21]</ref>) and 52.08% of all participants were female.</p><p>Each experimental session lasted ~90 minutes in the laboratory plus 15 minutes for the online pre-test questionnaire. The experiment was approved by the research ethics board at the University of Toronto.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Online survey. Participants first completed an online survey at least 24 hours (M = 6.02 days, SD = 5.80 days, 90% CI [4.67, 7.37]) prior to the start of their laboratory session.</p><p>The goal of this online survey was to elicit each participant's subjective impressions of eight well-known companies from four sectors (technology, finance, retail, and motor manufacturing). These companies were used later for the virtual stock-broker game in the laboratory. In the online survey, participants first bid a price they would be willing to pay for a single share in each of the eight companies, based on the Becker-DeGroot-Marschak method (BDM; <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Becker, deGroot, &amp; Marschak, 1964)</ref>. Deviating slightly from the classic BDM design, participants were given a CAD 100 budget and had to decide how much to invest by freely allocating a dollar amount that they would pay to receive a stock in each company. We changed this part in the design as we considered it to be a better way to approximate relative subjective values. Participants were told that their bid would have real consequences in the laboratory: "…indicate how much you would be willing to pay for these shares from your budget without knowing the actual stock-market value. If your bid for a VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 9 share is equal or higher than the share's real stock-market price, you will have purchased this share, if it is lower than the price you will not have purchased the share." Second, participants answered a series of Likert-type questions assessing a number of dimensions that are potentially relevant to investment decisions ("How much do you like these companies?"; "How much do you trust these companies?" and "How much do you think these companies stand for a good investment?"). Each question was answered on a 5-point scale ranging from "not at all" to "very much".</p><p>Finally, participants indicated their risk aversion by deciding on 10 binary choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Holt &amp; Laury, 2002</ref>; for example: "Which of the following two investment options would you choose from each pair?", e.g., "240 $ with 10 % probability &amp; 192 $ with 90 % probability" vs. "462 $ with 10 % probability &amp; 21 $ with 90 % probability". Participants further indicated their behavioural inhibition (7 items, Cronbach's alpha = .69) and approach style (13 items, Cronbach's alpha = .79) on a 4-point-Likert scale ranging from "strongly disagree" to "strongly agree" using the BIS-BAS scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Carver &amp; White, 1994)</ref>. Data on participants' risk aversion as well as their behavioural inhibition and approach style was left un-analysed. The complete online survey can be found in the supplemental online material (https://osf.io/mpyn3/).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Laboratory.</head><p>The laboratory experiment consisted of five consecutive parts: <ref type="formula">1</ref>preparation for neurophysiological recording, (2) instructions on the stock broker game, (3) a learning phase in which participants got familiar with the stock characteristics and the stock broker game in general, (4) a paper and pencil test in which participants showed that they had understood the stock characteristics relative to a pre-defined criteria, and (5) an investing phase in which participants played the stock broker game.</p><p>Stock broker game. In the stock broker game, participants chose between pairs of stock options from the eight companies introduced during the online survey. The general task was to make investment decisions by choosing one stock from each pair. Participants were VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 10 informed that each decision would add one share of that stock to their portfolio, and that they would build eight portfolios throughout the study. As an incentive, participants were told that they would receive a bonus payment based on the value of one randomly chosen portfolio after completing the study 1 . Laboratory instructions for participants can be found in the supplemental online material (https://osf.io/mpyn3/).</p><p>The available stock options varied along two objective dimensions: gain and chance.</p><p>Gain defined the monetary reward obtained if the stock paid out, and was expressed as varying levels of arbitrary units (range: 2.63-11.55). Participants were informed at the start of the study that one unit equalled 2 cents. The chance dimension determined the probability that a given stock would pay out (range: 20%-88%). This manipulation created four different types of stocks, that varied across three levels of expected return (i.e., gain x chance). Stocks were selected so that they would be familiar to Canadian participants, and two companies were used from four market sectors: technology, banking, supermarkets, and motor manufacturing.</p><p>The technology companies, Apple (gain: 11.5 units, chance: 87%) and Google (gain:</p><p>11.35 units, chance: 88%), had a high chance of winning a large amount of money (high chance/ high gain; high expected share value: ~10 units). This meant that the technology companies were the best possible investment for any stock pairing. The two financial sector companies, TD Bank (gain: 2.66 units, chance: 87%) and Scotiabank (gain: 2.63 units, chance: 88%), had a high chance of winning a small amount of money (high chance/ low gain; medium expected share value: ~2.3 units). The two retail companies were Sobeys (gain: 11.55 units, chance: 20%) and Loblaws (gain: 11 units, chance: 21%), and, as such, they had a low chance of winning a large amount of money (low chance/ high gain; medium expected share value: ~2.3 units). It is important to note that while the supermarkets and banks differed on the levels of gain and chance, they had identical expected monetary value (gain x chance).</p><p>As such, there is no economic reason why investing in the banks would be a better strategy than investing in the supermarkets. Finally, the motor companies were Ford (gain: 2.66 units, chance: 20%) and Chevrolet (gain: 2.63 units, chance: 21%), and were characterized as stocks that have a low chance of paying out a small amount of money (low chance/ low gain; low expected share value: ~0.5 units). As such, the motor companies are always the least valuable option in any stock pairing (see table 1). Learning phase. The study commenced with a learning phase to ensure that participants learned the stock characteristics to predefined criteria. Two stock options were presented on each trial, and the image of each stock contained the company's logo and name, in addition to information on gain and chance. When presented on the computer screen, each pair measured approximately 500 x 236 pixels. Stock options from the same sector (i.e., technology, finance, retail, motor manufacturing) were always presented with the same background colour (red, green, purple, and cyan, respectively). These background colours were fully counterbalanced between participants. Targets were presented until response or for a maximum of 2000 ms. Participants were instructed to press the key "f" to choose the option presented on the left side, and to press the key "j" to choose the option presented on the right side of the screen. Very fast responses (RTs &lt; 150 ms) were excluded from further analyses, and responses made faster than the minimum RT and slower than the maximum were followed by "too fast" or "too slow" feedback for 2000 ms, respectively.</p><p>The general task was to decide, like a stock-broker, which stock to invest on each trial.  Investing phase. In the final part of the study, participants were instructed that they would now start to make investment decisions that will determine their final profit.</p><p>Participants were instructed that they would compose eight different portfolios (i.e., groups of 40 sequential investment decisions), out of which one portfolio would be randomly chosen at the end to determine their final profit. For technical reasons, participants always received CAD 5.20 in profit, which was CAD 1 above the maximum expected return of each portfolio.</p><p>Throughout the investing phase, we removed the written stock characteristics from the After every portfolio, participants were asked to rate their feelings when being offered the respective choices by entering a number from 1 (not at all) to 10 (absolutely). We alternated ratings on positive and anxious feelings so that we asked about participants' positive feelings after four portfolios, and about their anxious feelings after the remaining four portfolios.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EEG recording</head><p>Electroencephalographic <ref type="formula">(</ref> Offline the data were band-pass filtered (0.1 to 15 Hz) and corrected for eye-blinks using regression-based procedures (c.f., <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Gratton, Coles &amp; Donchin, 1983)</ref>. Automatic procedures were employed to detect and reject EEG artefacts. The criteria applied were a voltage step of more than 25 µV between sample points, a voltage difference of 150 µV within 200 ms intervals, voltages above 85 µV and below -85 µV, and a maximum voltage difference of less than 0.05 µV within 100 ms intervals. These intervals were rejected on an individual channel basis to maximize data retention.</p><p>For the response locked ERPs, the continuous EEG was segmented into epochs that commenced 500 ms before the response and lasted for 1100 ms. Response-locked ERPs were averaged separately for each choice type and were baseline corrected using a 100 ms window that started 150 ms before the response. The CN was then operationalized using the mean amplitude in a window 0 to 100 ms after the response at electrode Cz. We chose electrode Cz based on a mixed functional-collapsed localizer method (c.f., Luck &amp; Gaspelin) in which we collapsed over levels of expected value of the best option. Analyses on electrode FCz did not reveal an effect of conflict and are reported in the online supplemental material (https://osf.io/mcf34/). ERPs were averaged separately for each pair of stock options (e.g.,</p><p>Apple vs. Google, TD Bank vs. Ford, Sobeys vs. Google, and so on).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analyses</head><p>Based on our hypotheses, we divided analyses into three sequential steps. ; "How can I estimate effect size for mixed models?"). All analyses were performed in Stata 13.1 (StataCorp., 2013).</p><p>Step 1: conflict as a result of objective value characteristics. In a first step, we tested the influence of objective characteristics of the stock pairs on indecision (mean reaction time and percentage choice), affective responses (positive and anxious feelings), and ERPs (CN). We used MLM with the main effects of conflict (high conflict = 1; low conflict = 0) and the expected return of the best option (~0.5 units = low vs. ~2.3 units = medium vs. ~10 units = high), as well as the interaction between these two main effects. High conflict was defined as occurring when each stock in a pair had an (almost) equal expected return (e.g., Google vs. Apple), whereas low conflict pairs had an obvious difference in expected return between stock pairs (e.g., Scotiabank vs. Ford). The interaction term with the expected return of the best option then allows us to test if conflicts scale with the value of the stocks. For example, do high value conflicts (e.g., Google vs. Apple) elicit more conflict reactions than low value conflicts (e.g., Ford vs. Chevrolet). Each MLM had a two-level structure with repeated measures nested within participant. Random intercepts were estimated per participant applying an independent covariance structure. Analyses were performed using the "</p><p>xtmixed" option in Stata 13.1 (StataCorp., 2013). Simple effect tests were conducted using the "margins" option in Stata 13.1.</p><p>Step 2: CN amplitude and conflict responses. In a second step, we analysed whether the magnitude of neurophysiological responses to decisions predict the behavioural and affective correlates of conflict. In these analyses the CN was person centered in order to isolate within-subject variance in neural conflict monitoring, and reduce between-subject variability (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Saunders, Milyavskaya, &amp; Inzlicht, 2015</ref>, for similar logic). To achieve this we first calculated the mean CN amplitude per participant across all decision types, and then subtracted this from the raw CN score for each of the 28 decision types (e.g., Sobeys vs Ford minus participant's mean CN amplitude). Using this variable-rather than the raw CN amplitude per decision-means that we predict each dependent measure (e.g., positive affect) from within-subject variance in neural conflict monitoring. In other words, this analysis allows us to determine whether within-participant fluctuations in neural conflict monitoring covary with fluctuations in within-person positive affect. A key benefit of this analysis strategy is that our sample is well powered to investigate within-subject variation.</p><p>To constrain these analyses further, we only tested dependant variables for which we found a conflict effect in the previously defined steps. We ran multilevel analyses where repeated measures were clustered in participants investigating if within-participant fluctuations in CN amplitude predicted behaviour and affect. Analyses were performed using the "xtmixed" option in Stata 13.1 (StataCorp., 2013).</p><p>Step 3: conflict as a result of subjective value characteristics. Last, we controlled for participants' subjective impression of the eight companies-measured by the online pretest-on the previously defined dependent measures. To test subjective influences, we first used confirmatory factor analysis to form a latent variable that reflected participants' subjective impressions separately for each of the companies. The participants' ratings (liking, trust, good investment) on the eight companies and the assigned values from the BDM auction generate a latent factor that estimates how positively individuals viewed each of the eight companies. Analyses were performed using the "gsem" option in Stata 13.1 to control for the multilevel structure of the data (StataCorp., 2013). All eight item sets on the subjective impression showed a good fit to a single-factor model 2 and values on latent variables were stored for the main analyses. This created a single subjective impression score for each company, with increasing scores indicating increasing subjective value. We then derived variables from these latent factors to create subjective factors analogous to the main effects included in the analysis of the objective characteristics. Mirroring the conflict main effect, we first calculated absolute difference scores on the subjective values for each choice, to create a subjective value main effect. Here, a score of zero would indicate that two options have an equivalent subjective value (i.e., high subjective conflict), with increasing difference scores indicating that one stock out-values the other (i.e., low subjective conflict). The second main effect coded the subjective value of the best rated item from each pair. Finally, we interacted these two variables to test if subjective conflict scales with increasing subjective value.</p><p>We again conducted multilevel analyses where repeated measures were clustered in participants. Random intercepts were estimated per participant applying an independent covariance structure. In addition to the objective decision characteristics (choice conflict, expected return of the best option and the interaction term), we entered subjective decision characteristics (subjective conflict, value of the subjectively rated best option and the interaction term) into multilevel analyses. Analyses were performed using the "xtmixed" option in Stata 13.1 (StataCorp., 2013). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conflict reactions as a result of objective value characteristics</head><p>We first analysed participants' behavioural reactions (mean reaction time, percentage choice), reported feelings (positive and anxious feelings) and neurophysiological responses (CN) in relation to the objective characteristics of the stock task: objective conflict, the expected return of the best option, and the interaction term of these two variables. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 2</ref> provides an overview of the results. The results from reaction times support our first and second hypothesis in that participants did become slower in their decisions when facing similarly good options of high expected value.</p><p>Percentage choice. Results on percentage choices showed a significant main effect of conflict, (b=-0.07, S.E.=0.03), z=-2.67, p=.008, f² = .004, indicating that participants were more undecided when having to choose between options with equal expected returns (M=54 %, SD = 34 %, 90% CI [0%, 100%]) than options with different expected returns (M=82 %, SD = 28 %, 90% CI [25%, 100%]). As indicated by the significant main effect of the expected value of the best option (b=0.03, S.E.&lt;0.01), z=11.72, p&lt;.001, f² = .096, participants were generally more decided when more money was at stake. However, a significant interaction effect between conflict and expected value of the best option, (b=-0.04, S.E.=0.01), z=-7.03, p&lt;.001, f² = .035 and post-hoc tests revealed that the conflict effect was stronger for high EV options, Chi²=141.69, p&lt;.001 than for low EV options, Chi²=50.88, p&lt;.001, suggesting that participants were less decided between options of equal value when more value was at stake.</p><p>Taken together, the results from percentage choice are in support of our first and second hypothesis: participants are less decided when facing similarly good options, especially when expected returns of both options are high.</p><p>Positive and anxious feelings. As would be expected, higher expected returns of the better option led to higher positive feelings (b=0.24, S.E.=0.01), z=17.24, p&lt;.001, f² = .208.</p><p>This finding suggests that participants report increasingly positive evaluations of options with </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conflict reactions as a result of subjective value characteristics</head><p>In a third step, we tested if participants also pull value information from subjective sources. In all analyses, the effects of objective conflict, value of the objectively best option and their interaction stayed qualitatively the same when including our subjective measures, unless stated otherwise. <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 3</ref> provides an overview of all results on this set of analyses.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Schoemaker, 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Fehr &amp; Hoff, 2011)</ref> meaning that choices between equal options should be straightforward. The investment outcome is the same no matter the choice. However, this is not what our data suggests. When participants decided between stock options of equivalent high monetary value they were slow, undecided, and less pleased than when they decided between options where one option was obviously better than the alternative. Our findings support previous psychological and neuroscientific research indicating that decisions between equally valued options trigger conflict at the behavioural and neural level <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Nakao et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Nakao et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>However, in these previous studies, participants decided between qualitatively different things (dancer vs. chemist; ipod vs. sudoku book). From an economic point of view, these previous results therefore could have been explained with the concept of opportunity costs, stating that "the true cost of something is what you give up to get it" (http://www.economist.com/economics-a-to-z/o). However, in our study decisions were made between options with identical monetary outcomes and conflict was triggered during decisions though participants could not lose anything by design.</p><p>While our results are at odds with assumptions made by classic economic theory, they might shed light on seemingly anomalous observations from finance research. It is well documented, for example, that private investors show low levels of trading activity (e.g., <ref type="bibr">"Shareownership 2000</ref><ref type="bibr">"Shareownership ", 2002</ref>, a phenomenon commonly known as investor inertia. For example, in the domain of retirement savings in the US, private investors largely avoid financial decisions altogether and, as a result, miss opportunities to optimize their portfolios (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Madrian &amp; Shea, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Thaler &amp; Benartzi, 2004)</ref>. Such inertia might be related to the difficulty that arises during financial decision making across behavioural, affective, and neural levels of analysis.</p><p>Our data reveals that the CN amplitude, a negative-going ERP that is thought to represent decision conflict in the medial prefrontal cortex, including the aMCC <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Di Domenico et al., 2016)</ref>, not only reacts to conflict decisions but also predicts participants' affective reactions and behavioural responses. Importantly, the association between reductions in positive affect and CN amplitude should be interpreted with some caution (and merits future replication) given that this effect was not significant at our apriori alpha level (p &lt; .05).</p><p>Nevertheless, these neural results are consistent with recent suggestions that the aMCC not only detects decision conflicts <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Botvinick et al., 2001</ref>), but also with suggestions that aMCC tracks negatively valenced events during cognitive control (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Botvinick, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Inzlicht, Bartholow &amp; Hirsh, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Koban &amp; Pourtois, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Shackman et al., 2011)</ref> and decision making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Saunders, Lin, Milyavskaya, &amp; Inzlicht, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2013)</ref>. To our knowledge, the current results are the first to link the CN to indecision and subjective evaluations that arise during decision making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Subjective preference and investment decisions</head><p>Recent findings from real-world trading data suggest that investors do not only consider objective stock characteristics, but additionally discriminate based on subjective impressions resulting from, for example, social information about ethnicity or gender <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Kumar, et al., 2015;</ref>. Our study supports the suggestion that idiosyncratic preferences predict investment decisions over and above objective stock characteristics (i.e., gain and risk). Participants reacted more quickly and reported more positive feelings about their decisions the higher they subjectively valued one company over the other; and this was over and above the objective characteristics of the stocks. Subjective impressions were based on brand perception of the companies assessed on average six days before the participants entered the experiment. Our results once more underline that private VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 28 investors are influenced by both objective and subjective sources of information. This is particularly surprising in the current context, where participants were trained explicitly and to criterion on the objective stock characteristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations and future research</head><p>Despite conceptually similar designs, our affective results do not fully mirror those of <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Shenhav and Buckner (2014)</ref>. In this earlier study, subjective conflicts between desirable consumer goods (e.g., digital camera vs. camcorder) produced simultaneous increases in anxiety and positive affect relative to less conflicting decisions (e.g., iPod vs. a Sudoku book).</p><p>In our study, however, participants felt more anxious but not more positive towards subjective value conflicts, whereas objective conflict only reduced positive affect. While many differences exist between these studies (e.g., consumer goods vs. financial decision making; fMRI vs. EEG; trial numbers and timing, the learning element in the current investigation), we suggest that the difference in results might be best accounted for by differences in overall value involved for each decision (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Kachelmeier &amp; Shehata, 1992)</ref>, with absolute values being significantly lower in our study.</p><p>Our results are generative for future ERP research exploring the decision making across multiple domains with increasing ecological validity. While some of the evidence reported in the current study should be interpreted with some caution given the exploratory nature of our work, in addition to the high p-values for some effects (e.g., the association between positive affect and CN amplitude), the current methodology provides a paradigm that can be used to test conflicts that more closely resemble the decision we make in our day to day lives across multiple domains in ERP experiments. It is our hope that readers of this work will adopt such methods not only to explore the neural correlates of conflict in the laboratory, but also how these constrained neural reactions predict real-world outcomes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 29</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>We examined how conflict derived from objective and subjective value characteristics of stocks affect investment decisions and their neural correlates. We demonstrated that in a financial context, decisions and affective reactions are influenced by subjective and objective value conflict. Moreover, we provide novel evidence that the CN serves as a neural correlate to objective value conflict and correlates with behavioral indecision. Our key finding is that choosing in a situation where it should not matter which option to pick from an economic perspective, alerts the CN to the extent that investors are more undecided. Our results, thus, may explain empirical observations showing that private investors avoid financial decisions and remain with suboptimal portfolio allocations over time.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>A</head><label></label><figDesc>central fixation cross (learning: 37x38 pixels, investing: 19x19 pixels; random duration: 250-750 ms) preceded the target pictures. Consequently, the response-to-stimulus interval varied randomly between 250 and 1,250 ms. The learning phase consisted of 40 trials in which only choices with a clear best option were presented. As such, no conflicting options (i.e., trials where both stocks have equal expected return) were presented to participants during learning. During the learning phase participants also received feedback on the investment outcome following their decision (duration: 1500 ms), indicating whether the stock option they had chosen would have performed well or poorly, and whether they would have earned (or missed) a high or low gain. The feedback was probabilistic and determined based on the selected stock's chance characteristics. For example, each time an individual invested in Apple, they had an 88% chance of receiving immediate feedback indicating a large gain. Thus, by following the feedback participants were able to learn the characteristics of the stocks over time. Figure 1 provides an overview on decisions in the learning phase.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>experimental trials and only kept company logos overlaid on the background colours from the original learning phase. This omission ensured that participants made decisions based on both the objective characteristics and their own subjective impressions (based on the online portion of the study). Each pair of images was approximately 192x87 pixels on the computer screen.The experimental period consisted of eight portfolios (i.e., blocks) each containing 40 decisions (i.e., trials), resulting in a total number of 320 trials. In each round, participants were presented with 20 conflicting and 20 non-conflicting pairs of stock options. Conflicting decisions occurred when participants decided between two options with (almost) identical expected monetary value (i.e., Apple vs. Google, TD Bank vs. Scotiabank, Sobeys vs.Loblaws, Ford vs. Chevrolet, TD Bank/Scotiabank vs. Sobeys/Loblaws). Non-conflicting decisions occurred when there was a discrepancy in expected monetary value between stocks (i.e., Apple/Google vs. TD Bank/Scotiabank, Apple/Google vs. Sobeys/Loblaws, Apple/Google vs. Ford/Chevrolet, TD Bank/Scotiabank vs. Ford/Chevrolet, Sobeys/Loblaws vs. Ford/Chevrolet). Choices where reaction times were below 100ms were excluded from all analyses.Figure 1provides an overview on decisions in the investing phase.VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING14 Trial structure in the in the learning (top) and investing (bottom) phase.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>The characteristics of the eight different stocks</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Sector</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Technology</cell><cell cols="2">Finance</cell><cell cols="2">Retail</cell><cell></cell><cell>Motor</cell></row><row><cell>Company</cell><cell>Apple</cell><cell>Google</cell><cell cols="2">TD Bank Scotiabank</cell><cell>Sobeys</cell><cell>Loblaws</cell><cell>Ford</cell><cell>Chevrolet</cell></row><row><cell>Gain</cell><cell>11.5</cell><cell>11.35</cell><cell>2.66</cell><cell>2.63</cell><cell>11.55</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>2.66</cell><cell>2.63</cell></row><row><cell>Chance</cell><cell>87%</cell><cell>88%</cell><cell>87%</cell><cell>88%</cell><cell>20%</cell><cell>21%</cell><cell>20%</cell><cell>21%</cell></row><row><cell>EV (units)</cell><cell>10.005</cell><cell>9.998</cell><cell>2.314</cell><cell>2.314</cell><cell>2.310</cell><cell>2.42</cell><cell>0.532</cell><cell>0.552</cell></row><row><cell>EV</cell><cell>High</cell><cell>High</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Low</cell><cell>Low</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">EV = expected return (gain*chance)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Paper and pencil test.</head><label></label><figDesc>Before moving beyond the learning phase, participants conducted a paper and pencil test to ensure that they had learned the characteristics of the stock to pre-defined criterion levels. First, participants were asked to indicate which stocks were of low/high gain as well as low/high chance. Second, we asked participants to provide approximate values for the level of gain and chance for each option. Participants did not pass the test if the approximate numbers they gave exceeded +/-2 units for gain estimates or +/-10 percentage points chance. If participants did not reach this pre-determined criterion for the initial learning phase, the learning process was repeated again until participants passed the test VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 13 or completed 4 learning blocks. On average, participants took 2 learning phases to reach criterion.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Vertical electro-oculography (VEOG) was monitored using a supra-to suborbital bipolar montage surrounding the right eye. During recording impedances were monitored (&lt; 5 KΩ) and the EEG signal was digitized at 1024 Hz using ASA acquisition hardware (Advanced Neuro Technology, Enschede, the Netherlands).</figDesc><table /><note>EEG) activity was recorded from 11 Ag/AgCl sintered electrodes embedded in a stretch-lycra cap. The scalp-electrode montage consisted of midline electrode sites (FPz, Fz, FCz, Cz, CPz, Pz &amp; Oz) referenced to the average activity recorded at bilateral earlobes. We made the decision to record primarily from midline electrode sites because the CN is maximal at these sites, and we had no plans of source localizing the VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 15 electrical signals.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>In a third step, we tested if subjective impressions (i.e., pre-rated evaluations of each company) change results on our DVs over and above the objective characteristics (hypothesis 4). To account for the nested structure in our data, we used multi-level models (MLM) as they are less restrictive than repeated-measures ANOVA(Field, 2013, p. 818 ff.).</figDesc><table><row><cell>MLM, for example, increases statistical power by allowing random effects, and is well able to</cell></row><row><cell>handle missing data points. As a measure of local effect sizes in mixed-effects regression</cell></row><row><cell>modelling, Cohen's f was calculated (cf. Selya, Rose, Dierker, Hedeker, &amp; Mermelstein,</cell></row><row><cell>2012</cell></row></table><note>First, we assessed the effects of objective value characteristics (i.e., objective value conflict and amount of expected value) on our dependent measures (hypothesis 1 &amp; 2). In a second step, we tested if response locked ERPs (CN) predict conflict effects on our behavioural and affective DVs VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 16 (hypothesis 3).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Apple (4 items, χ 2 =0.85, p=.655; CFI=1.00, TLI=1.06, RMSEA&lt;.01 [90% CI=.00, .215]), Google (4 items, χ 2 =0.11, p=.095; CFI=1.00, TLI=1.26, RMSEA&lt;.01 [90% CI=.00, .04]), TD Bank (4 items, χ 2 =0.78 , p=.675; CFI=1.00, TLI=1.09, RMSEA&lt;.01 [90% CI=.00, .21]), Scotiabank (4 items, χ 2 =10.20 , p=.006; CFI=.88, TLI=0.65, RMSEA=.28 [90% CI=.13, .47]), Loblaws (4 items, χ 2 =2.00 , p=.367; CFI=1.00 TLI=1.00, RMSEA&lt;.01 [90% CI=.00, .28]), Sobeys (4 items, χ 2 =1.57 , p=.456; CFI=1.00 TLI=1.04, RMSEA&lt;.01 [90% CI=.00, .26]), Chevrolet (4 items, χ 2 =13.35 , p=.001; CFI=0.77, TLI=0.32, RMSEA=.33 [90% CI=.18, .51]) and Ford (4 items, χ 2 =1.61 , p=.448; CFI=1.00 TLI=1.02, RMSEA&lt;.01 [90% CI=.00, .26]).</figDesc><table><row><cell>VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING</cell><cell>19</cell></row></table><note>2</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>There was no significant main effect of conflict on mean reaction times(b=-13.88, S.E.=13.35), z=-1.04, p=.298, f² &lt; .001. However, mean reaction times became faster as the expected return of the best option increased (b=-25.07, S.E.=1.10), z=-22.88, p &lt; .001, f² = .371. Though not hypothesized, this can likely be explained as a VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 20 motivational effect, where people react more quickly to obtain rewards. This effect was less strong for high conflict trials, as indicated by the significant interaction term of conflict with the expected value of the best option, (b=10.21, S.E.=2.77), z=3.68, p&lt;.001, f² = .009.Altogether, there was a significant effect of conflict on mean reaction time for high EV options, Chi²=20.00, p&lt;.001, but not for lowEV options, Chi²=0.30, p=.582, indicating that    high value conflict leads to slower decisions.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Multilevel regression analyses testing participants' reactions to objective choice</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">characteristics: objective value conflict, expected value of the best option and their</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>interaction.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>variables</cell><cell>mean RT</cell><cell>% choice</cell><cell>positive</cell><cell>anxious</cell><cell>CN</cell></row><row><cell>conflict</cell><cell>-13.88</cell><cell>-0.07**</cell><cell>-0.40*</cell><cell>-0.01</cell><cell>-0.79*</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(13.35)</cell><cell>(0.03)</cell><cell>(0.17)</cell><cell>(0.20)</cell><cell>(0.36)</cell></row><row><cell>EV of best option</cell><cell>-25.07***</cell><cell>0.03***</cell><cell>0.24***</cell><cell>-0.01</cell><cell>-0.04</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(1.10)</cell><cell>(&lt;0.01)</cell><cell>(0.01)</cell><cell>(0.02)</cell><cell>(0.03)</cell></row><row><cell>conflict x EV of best option</cell><cell>10.21***</cell><cell>-0.04***</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell>&lt;0.01</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(2.77)</cell><cell>(0.01)</cell><cell>(0.03)</cell><cell>(0.04)</cell><cell>(0.07)</cell></row><row><cell>intercept</cell><cell>899.20***</cell><cell>0.64***</cell><cell>5.29***</cell><cell>5.04***</cell><cell>0.76</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(22.69)</cell><cell>(0.02)</cell><cell>(0.15)</cell><cell>(0.25)</cell><cell>(0.36)</cell></row><row><cell>observations</cell><cell>1,464</cell><cell>1,484</cell><cell>1,484</cell><cell>1,484</cell><cell>1,281</cell></row><row><cell>participants</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>49</cell></row><row><cell>Standard errors in parentheses</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>*** p&lt;.001, ** p&lt;.01, * p&lt;.05</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Mean reaction time.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 21 increasingly value. Furthermore, participants in general reported slightly lower levels of positive affect for conflicting compared to non-conflicting decisions, (b=-0.40, S.E.=0.17), z=-2.37, p=.018, f² = .004, yet, this effect did not become stronger with increasing values of the expected value of the best option,(interaction term: b=0.01, S.E.=0.03), z=0.38, p=.706,   f² &lt; .001.    </figDesc><table><row><cell>VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING</cell><cell>22 23</cell></row><row><cell>effects on reaction times and percentage choice, this effect did not scale with increasing</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>expected returns.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CN amplitude and conflict reactions</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>With regards to our third hypothesis, we were interested in how the behavioural and</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>affective correlates of conflict that is positive feelings and percentage choice, are associated</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Regarding anxious feelings, higher expected returns of the better option did not lead to with CN amplitude (see table 2).</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>less anxious feelings (b=-0.01, S.E.=0.02), z=-0.36, p=.720, f² &lt; .001. Furthermore, we did</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>not find that participants reported higher levels of anxious feelings for conflicting compared Figure 3. ERP waveforms showing effect on conflict on the CN at electrode Cz.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>to non-conflicting decisions, (b=-0.01, S.E.=0.20), z=-0.03, p=.974, f² &lt; .001. Nor did we</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CN and positive feelings. The CN predicted positive feelings on a 10% alpha level</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>find an interaction effect between conflict and the expected value of the best option, (b=0.02,</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>(b=0.03, S.E.=0.02), z=1.86, p=.062, f² = .047, with modest effect sizes, providing a first</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>S.E.=0.04), z=0.62, p=.535, f² &lt; .001.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>indication that higher neurophysiological conflict reactivity was somewhat accompanied by</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Taken together, the results on reported feelings suggest that high conflict trials lead to</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>reduced positive affect to a decision type. The CN results on reported feelings hence indicate</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>slightly lower positive feelings, while the expected return of the better option increases</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>that neurophysiological conflict reactivity during financial decisions is modestly associated</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>positive affect. Results on positive feelings are generally in support of our first hypothesis</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>with participants' positive feelings.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>stating that conflict is aversive. However, in contrast to past results (e.g., Shenhav &amp; Buckner,</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CN and percentage choice. Running multilevel analyses with the CN predicting</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2014), we do not observe any effects on felt anxiety levels.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>participants' choices, we found that the CN significantly predicted participants' choices</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Figure 2 (top panels) illustrates the results on reported feelings as a function of</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>(b=0.01, S.E.&lt;0.01), z=4.33, p&lt;.001, f² = .026, indicating that higher neurophysiological</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>objective conflict.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>conflict reactivity during choices was associated with increased indecision. Though the effect</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CN. A significant main effect of conflict on CN was found (b=-0.79, S.E.=0.36), z=-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>size is modest, the results indicate that neurophysiological responses directly after financial</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>2.21, p=.027, f² = .004, indicating that high conflict trials induce slightly more conflict-related</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>decisions correlate to participants' indecision.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>negativity than low conflict trials, see figure 3. Expected returns of the best option did not</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>have any influence on CN (b=-0.4, S.E.=0.03), z=-1.35, p=0.178, f² = .002, nor did the</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>interaction of expected return of the best option with conflict (b&lt;0.01, S.E.=0.07), z=0.05, Figure 2. Bar charts showing the effects of objective conflict on reported levels of anxiety and</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>positive affect (top panels) and the independent effect of subjective conflict (difference in p=0.959, f² &lt; .001. Though modest, the results are in-line with our hypothesis 1 and reveal subjective impression) on anxiety and conflict. Low and high subjective conflict reflect plus</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>or minus 1 SD from mean on the difference in subjective value between stock options, that deciding between two equally good options induces higher neurophysiological conflict respectively (lower panels). Estimated means are presented in the bottom panel for display</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>reactions in participants. However, contrary to hypothesis 2 and the observed behavioural purposes only. Error bars reflect within-subject 95% confidence intervals.</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Multilevel regression analyses testing participants' reactions to subjective value characteristics in addition to objective choice characteristics Adding subjective conflict measures to multilevel analyses, we found that a higher value of the subjectively rated best option made participants decide even faster (b=-27.01, S.E.=12.13), z=-2.23, p=.026, f² = .004. Though the effect size is very small, the results suggest that value of the subjectively rated best option goes into the same direction asthe expected value of the objectively best option. No effects on reaction times were found for neither subjective conflict (b=-5.50, S.E.=10.16), z=-0.54, p=.558, f² &lt; .001, nor the interaction of subjective conflict and subjectively rated best option (b=6.86, S.E.=9.69), z=0.71, p=.480, f² &lt; .001. Effects resulting from the subjectively rated best option seem to VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 25 point into the same direction as the effects from the objective counterpart that is the expected value of the best option. No effects on percentage choice were found for subjective conflict (b=0.02, S.E.=0.02), z=1.20, p=.232, f² &lt; .001, the subjectively rated best option (b=0.02, S.E.=0.16), z=2.59, p=.010, f² = .004. However, we found no effects on positive feelings for subjective conflict (b=0.19, S.E.=0.13), z=1.44, p=.150, f² = .002, or the interaction of subjective conflict with subjectively rated best option (b=-0.13, S.E.=0.13), z=-1.04, p=.299, f² &lt; .001. With regards to feelings of anxiety, we found that conflict based on subjective ratings slightly increased anxious feelings in participants (b=0.35, S.E.=0.16), z=2.23, p=.025, f² = .004. No effects were found for the subjectively rated best option (b=-0.12, S.E.=0.19), z=-0.65, p=.514, f² &lt; .001, or the interaction of subjective conflict and the subjectively rated best option (b=-0.10, S.E.=0.15), z=-0.64, p=.522, f² &lt; .001, on felt anxiety. Subjective conflict was the only independent variable that significantly influenced felt anxiety and felt anxiety was the only dependent variable reacting to subjective value conflict. Figure 2 (lower panels) illustrates the results on reported feelings as a function of subjective conflict. CN. We found no effects on CN for either subjective conflict (b=0.27, S.E.=0.29), z=0.94, p=.348, f² &lt; .001, the subjectively rated best option (b=0.11, S.E.=0.34), z=0.33, p=.741, f² &lt; .001, or the interaction of subjective conflict and subjectively rated best option (b=-0.36, S.E.=0.27), z=-1.37, p=.172, f² = .002. Including subjective conflict measures to multilevel analyses, the objective conflict effect on CN only remained significant at a 10% alpha level (b=-0.70, S.E.=0.38), z=-1.82, p=.069, f² = .003. VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING 26DiscussionWe investigated behavioural reactions, reported feelings, and neurophysiological responses to incentivized financial decision conflict. Our results are at odds with classic economic models. Facing objectively equal options should not challenge individuals from an economic perspective (cf.</figDesc><table><row><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Due to technical reasons, all participants were paid CAD 5.20 at the end of the study, which was CAD 1 above the expected return of each portfolio if the participant had always chosen the economically best available option.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author Note</head><p>Gesa-K. Petersen and Blair Saunders contributed equally to this article. This research was supported in part by a grant from the Excellence Initiative of the German Research Foundation (DFG).</p><p>The authors do not have any interests that might be interpreted as influencing the research.</p><p>Correspondence concerning this article should be addressed to Gesa-Kristina Petersen, Munich School of Management, Schackstrasse 4, 80539 Munich, Germany. E-mail: petersen.gk@gmail.com</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of doing nothing: Forms of decision avoidance result from reason and emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-2909.129.1.139</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.129.1.139" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Heavens</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aristotle</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.sacred-texts.com/cla/ari/oth/index.htm" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trans. J.L. Stocks). Retrieved from</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">295</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1922" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic control and medial frontal negativity: Beyond errors and response conflict</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bartholow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pearson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Dickter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fabiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gratton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1469-8986.2005.00258.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-8986.2005.00258.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring utility by a singleresponse sequential method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Degroot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Marschak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="226" to="232" />
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bs.3830090304</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bs.3830090304" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conflict monitoring and decision making: Reconciling two perspectives on anterior cingulate function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/cabn.7.4.356</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/cabn.7.4.356" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="356" to="366" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conflict monitoring and cognitive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Braver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Barch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="624" to="652" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295x.108.3.624</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295x.108.3.624" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral inhibition, behavioral activation, and affective responses to impending reward and punishment: The BIS/BAS Scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="333" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.67.2.319</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.67.2.319" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Theta lingua franca: A common mid-frontal substrate for action monitoring processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zambrano-Vazquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1469-8986.2011.01293.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-8986.2011.01293.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="220" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Basic psychological needs and neurophysiological responsiveness to decisional conflict: an event-related potential study of integrative self-processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>Domenico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ayaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fournier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13415-016-0436-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13415-016-0436-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="848" to="865" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Faul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Erdfelder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Buchner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G*</forename><surname>Power</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/bf03193146</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/bf03193146" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction: Tastes, castes and culture: The influence of society on preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">556</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="412" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1468-0297.2011.02478.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-0297.2011.02478.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Festinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">A theory of cognitive dissonance</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Stanford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1962" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discovering statistics using IBM SPSS statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Field</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Sage</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new method for off-line removal of ocular artifact</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gratton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Coles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Donchin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0013-4694(83)90135-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0013-4694(83" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Electroencephalography and Clinical Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90135" to="90144" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-control in decision-making involves modulation of the vmPFC valuation system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">324</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5927</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="646" to="648" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1168450</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1168450" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of human error processing: Reinforcement learning, dopamine, and the error-related negativity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Holroyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Coles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.109.4.679</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.109.4.679" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">679</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk aversion and incentive effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Holt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Laury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1257/000282802762024700</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1257/000282802762024700" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1644" to="1655" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How can I estimate effect size for mixed models? Stata FAQ</title>
		<ptr target="https://stats.idre.ucla.edu/stata/faq/how-can-i-estimate-effect-size-for-mixed/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>UCLA: Institute for digital research and education</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional foundations of cognitive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Inzlicht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bartholow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Hirsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2015.01.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2015.01.004" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do defaults save lives?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Goldstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1091721</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1091721" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">302</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5649</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1338" to="1339" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Examining risk preferences under high monetary incentives: Experimental evidence from the people&apos;s republic of china</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kachelmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shehata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.jstor.org/stable/2117470" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1120" to="1141" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brain systems underlying the affective and social monitoring of actions: an integrative review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Koban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pourtois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2014.02.014</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2014.02.014" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s in a name? Mutual fund flows when managers have foreign-sounding names</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Niessen-Ruenzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Spalt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/rfs/hhv017</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhv017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of Financial Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2281" to="2321" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The power of suggestion: Inertia in 401 (k) participation and savings behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Madrian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Shea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/003355301753265543</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/003355301753265543" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1149" to="1187" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resting-state EEG power predicts conflict-related brain activity in internally guided but not in externally guided decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nakao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nashiwa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Northoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2012.10.034</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2012.10.034" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-knowledge reduces conflict by biasing one of plural possible answers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nakao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mitsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nashiwa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Takamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tokunaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miyatani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="469" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167210363403</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167210363403" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sex matters: Gender bias in the mutual fund industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Niessen-Ruenzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ruenzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.1957317</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.1957317" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding all inconsistency compensation as a palliative response to violated expectations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Proulx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Inzlicht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Harmon-Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2012.04.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2012.04.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="291" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anticipated affect and behavioral choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Richard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Van Der Pligt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>De Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/(sici)1099-0771(199609)9:3%3c185::aid-bdm228%3e3.0.co;2-5</idno>
		<idno>3&lt;185::aid-bdm228&gt;3.0.co;2-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/(sici)1099-0771" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="199609" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The emotive nature of conflict monitoring in the medial prefrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milyavskaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Inzlicht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2017.01.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2017.01.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What does cognitive control feel like? Effective and ineffective cognitive control is associated with divergent phenomenology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milyavskaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Inzlicht</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1205" to="1217" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/psyp.12454</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/psyp.12454" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The expected utility model: Its variants, purposes, evidence and limitations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schoemaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Literature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="563" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion, cognition, and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/026999300402745</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/026999300402745" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition and Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="440" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A practical guide to calculating Cohen&apos;s f2, a measure of local effect size, from PROC MIXED</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Selya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Rose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dierker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hedeker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mermelstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00111</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00111" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The integration of negative affect, pain and cognitive control in the cingulate cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Shackman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Salomons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Slagter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Winter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nrn2994</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn2994" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://www.nyxdata.com/nysedata/asp/factbook/viewer_edition.asp?mode=text&amp;key=51&amp;category=11" />
		<title level="m">Shareownership</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of dueling affective reactions to win-win choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Buckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/abn0000196</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/abn0000196" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10978" to="10983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">StataCorp. 2013. Stata Statistical Software: Release 13. College Station, TX: StataCorp LP</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Save more tomorrow™: Using behavioral economics to increase employee saving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Benartzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Political Economy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">S1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="164" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1086/380085</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1086/380085" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is the &apos;error negativity&apos; specific to errors?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Vidal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hasbroucq</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Grapperon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bonnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0301-0511(99</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0301-0511(99" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of error detection: conflict monitoring and the error-related negativity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.111.4.931</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.111.4.931" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anticipated regret, expected feedback and behavioral decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zeelenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/(sici)1099-0771(199906)12:2%3c93::aid-bdm311%3e3.0.co;2-s</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/(sici)1099-0771" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="199906" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2&lt;93::aid-bdm311&gt;3.0.co;2-s VALUE CONFLICT DURING FINANCIAL DECISION MAKING</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
