<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Coping through Precise Labeling of Emotions: A Deep Learning Approach to Studying Emotional Granularity in Consumer Reviews</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Faraji-Rad</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Atefeh Jebeli is a PhD student in Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>College Park</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Park</forename><forename type="middle">Ali</forename><surname>Tamaddoni</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Smith School of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>College</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Deakin Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Deakin University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Coping through Precise Labeling of Emotions: A Deep Learning Approach to Studying Emotional Granularity in Consumer Reviews</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>emotional granularity</term>
					<term>coping</term>
					<term>consumer experience</term>
					<term>emotional expertise</term>
					<term>online reviews</term>
					<term>Large Language Models (LLMs)</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>When describing their emotions, people may demonstrate emotional expertise by differentiating between emotions when using emotional labels, or use emotion labels interchangeably to indicate a general valence. The authors develop a novel deep-learning-based method to measure the granularity with which people describe their emotions via language. They examine the role of emotional granularity in consumer decision-making, particularly in how consumers rate unpleasant service experiences (e.g., service failures) in online reviews. Consistent with the notion that granularity in describing negative emotions is associated with more successful self-regulation of negative emotions, consumers who express their negative emotions more granularly in review texts tend to rate businesses less negatively following service failures. Furthermore, a greater temporal distance between an experience and describing it leads to greater granularity in describing negative emotions. Consequently, a greater temporal distance between the service experience and writing the review predicts more positive ratings following service failures. The results have implications for a) understanding the role of emotional granularity in consumer decision making; b) understanding the predictors of online review ratings, as an important category of consumer decisions; and c) profiling consumers based on emotion regulation abilities inferred from the online content they generate.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>Consumers often use a variety of emotion labels (e.g., angry, frustrated, stressed, etc.) to describe how they feel as a result of consumption experiences. Research in psychology over the past three decades has shown that people differ in the degree of granularity with which they describe their emotions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Barrett et al. 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Barrett 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr">Erbas et al. 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Kashdan, Barrett, and McKnight 2015)</ref>. Often viewed as an indicator of "expertise in emotion" , emotional granularity describes individuals' ability or skill to represent their emotional experience in a nuanced and specific manner, often marked through language <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Lee, Lindquist, and Nam 2017)</ref>. A substantial stream of empirical research shows that granularity in negative emotions predicts more successful coping strategies and improves self-regulation to minimize the unwanted impact of negative emotions on behaviors such as binge drinking and aggression <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Kashdan et al. 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Kashdan et al. 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Starr et al. 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Tomko et al. 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Despite the documented significance of emotional granularity in predicting people's behaviors, its role in consumer decision making has not been investigated.</p><p>In this research, we investigate the role of granularity in negative emotions in consumer decision making, following unpleasant service experiences (e.g., service failures), in the context of online reviews. As an empirical setting, online reviews include an overall rating, which is a holistic judgment about the business, as well as textual descriptions of the consumer experience.</p><p>These textual descriptions provide valuable insights into the psychological processes that led to the holistic judgement (i.e., the rating). Furthermore, a consumer's decision about the rating to assign to a business after a (failed) service experience is extremely important to the business' success <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Chevalier and Mayzlin 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Floyd et al. 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Proserpio and Zervas 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">Vana and Lambrecht 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b82">Varga and Albuquerque 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Wu et al. 2015)</ref>. Thus, we seek to provide more insight on what shapes this managerially important type of consumer decision.</p><p>Methods developed to measure emotional granularity in extant research primarily measure the construct at the trait level (i.e., individual differences in ability) . However, the construct may also be conceptualized at the situation-level <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Barrett and Gross 2001)</ref>, which is more relevant for studying it in the context of consumer experience. We utilize the BERT Large Language Model <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Devlin et al. 2018)</ref> to develop a novel deep-learning-based method that enables us to measure the granularity with which consumers describe their emotions in online reviews. We then investigate how the granularity in negative emotions expressed in the online review text impacts consumers' rating of businesses following service failures. Furthermore, we investigate how the temporal distance between the consumption experience and the writing of the review, as a situational factor, predicts reviewers' granularity when describing their negative emotions, and ultimately impacts the rating assigned to the business.</p><p>We present novel propositions by building on previous research which shows an association between granularity in negative emotions and successful emotional self-regulation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Barrett et al. 2001)</ref>. First, we propose that, particularly when the overall service experience is negative, greater granularity in describing negative emotions is associated with more positive ratings of the business. This proposition stems from the fact that describing negative emotions more granularly may be associated with better self-regulation to minimize the unwanted impact of negative emotions on one's rating decision (i.e., lower likelihood of 'penalizing' the business) after a negative consumption experience. Second, we propose that a greater temporal distance between a negative consumption experience and the writing of a review increases reviewers' granularity in describing the negative emotions, which then contributes to more positive ratings of negative service experiences.</p><p>Our research primarily contributes to the stream of research on the role of context specificity of emotions in consumer decision making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Cavanaugh, Bettman, Luce 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr"></ref> Allard and White 2015; <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Raghunathan and Pham 1999)</ref>, the factors that influence consumer review ratings <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Aerts, Smits, and Verlegh 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Huang et al. 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Schoenmueller, Netzer, and Stahl 2020)</ref>, and the psychology of consumer language (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Berger et al. 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Boghrati and Berger 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Packard and Berger 2023</ref>).</p><p>In the following, we present the theoretical background of our research, followed by an explanation of the method we have developed to measure emotional granularity in language use.</p><p>We then present our empirical work which includes seven (presented as five main and two auxiliary) controlled studies, in addition to two field studies analyzing about 13 million reviews from Yelp and Tripadvisor. Finally, we discuss the contributions and implications of our research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONCEPTUAL BACKGROUND</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Emotional Granularity</head><p>A large body of research in psychology over the past three decades has shown that while some people are skilled at using differentiated and discrete emotion categories (e.g., agitated, angry, sad) to describe their emotions, others are not so skilled. This latter group instead communicates the general valence of how they feel by interchangeably using similarly valenced emotion labels (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Barrett et al. 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Barrett 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr">Erbas et al. 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Kashdan et al. 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Psychological interest in emotional granularity stems largely from a broader interest in understanding people's competencies in recognizing and using their emotions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Barrett 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Quoidbach et al. 2014)</ref>. Valence and arousal provide a foundational framework for understanding core affect, which represents the fundamental physiological responses associated with an emotional experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Russell and Barrett 1999)</ref>. However, emotions are not merely physiological responses-they are actively constructed through a complex interplay of contextual factors, cognitive processes, and social interpretations that give them meaning and specificity <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Barrett 2006)</ref>. Individuals draw on this rich repository of contextual knowledge, beyond core affect, to categorize an experience into an emotion <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Barrett 2006</ref>). This contextual knowledge includes the causes of the event (e.g., "angry with someone," "sad about something"; <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Barrett 2001)</ref> and its cultural meaning <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Mesquita and Frijda 1992)</ref>. It also includes individuals' cognitive (re)appraisals of the event <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Lazarus 1991)</ref>. For example, whether one (re)frames a disappointing outcome as an unavoidable difficulty or a personal failure, impacts whether they categorize their emotion as frustration or sadness. These (re)appraisals are influenced not only by the relevance and alignment of the event's outcome with one's various goals, but also by attributions of responsibility, which is itself influenced by the extent to which one adopts the perspective of other parties involved <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Lazarus 1991)</ref>.</p><p>While the theory of emotional granularity does not primarily concern which specific labels people assign to different emotions (e.g., whether they call a feeling "sadness" or "frustration") 1 , it argues for variances in people's ability to take into account contextual <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The theory of emotional granularity is built upon the Theory of Constructed Emotion <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Barrett 2017)</ref>, which argues that emotions are not innate, fixed responses but are instead, dynamically constructed by the brain through core affect (valence and arousal) combined with conceptual knowledge. In this view, what one person calls "sadness" may be a very different emotional experience from what another person calls "sadness." This contrasts with Functional Views of emotion, which propose that core emotions have distinct neural and physiological signatures. While a lively scientific debate between constructionist and functionalist perspectives of emotion continues, this debate is less central to our research, as our predictions hold regardless of one's stance on the issue.</p><p>information when experiencing and articulating emotions. Accordingly, those with high emotional granularity have developed a more diverse set of mental representations associated with different emotional experiences and thus categorize similarly valenced emotional experiences into a broader set of categories using different emotion labels <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Barrett 2006</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Barrett's (2006)</ref> example of two participants responding to the events of <ref type="bibr">September 11, 2001</ref>, helps illustrate emotional granularity and differentiate it from other constructs. Participant A said, "My first reaction was terrible sadness ... But the second reaction was that of anger, because you can't do anything with the sadness." In contrast, Participant B said, "I felt a bunch of things I couldn't put my finger on. Maybe anger, confusion, fear. I just felt bad on September 11 th . Really bad." Participant A clearly differentiated between sadness and anger by associating distinct contextual cues with them (e.g., anger's action-oriented nature compared to sadness).</p><p>Participant B, however, used multiple emotion labels (sadness, confusion, fear) interchangeably to describe a generalized unpleasant state. Despite using fewer labels, Participant A demonstrates higher emotional granularity by precisely distinguishing between emotions.</p><p>This example highlights several aspects of emotional granularity. First, emotional granularity reflects having differentiated cognitive structures for various emotions, rather than simply reflecting the number or variety of emotion labels used. Just like a researcher with expertise in consumer experience uses terms like 'satisfaction,' 'loyalty,' or 'repeat purchase' with precision-applying each term only when it aligns with the research focus or distinguishing between them when they all apply-an individual with high emotional granularity is similarly selective in their use of emotion labels, employing them only when they precisely capture the nuanced emotions they are experiencing. As such, emotional granularity emphasizes the ability to precisely identify and label emotions. It does not make assumptions about people's abilities or propensity to experience different emotions. Thus, emotional granularity differs from the complexity or variety of negative emotions experienced; or emotional ambivalence (i.e., whether people have experienced negative and positive emotions together) .</p><p>Second, emotional granularity is distinct from the intensity of the felt emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Rocklage et al. 2018)</ref> or one's certainty in their emotional reaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Rocklage et al. 2023)</ref>. In this example, both participants were similarly unsettled and certain that their reaction was negative. However, the less granular Participant B uses negative emotion labels interchangeably because they do not have differentiated cognitive structures for these similarly valenced emotions. The seemingly uncertain language used by Participant B-i.e., "I felt a bunch of things I couldn't put my finger on"-does not reflect uncertainty about the negativity of the experience but rather uncertainty about which specific label to use, stemming from a lack of differentiated cognitive structures.</p><p>Third, emotional granularity reflects one's "expertise" in their emotions specifically , and not in their consumption-domain expertise (e.g., photography, coffee, etc.). While both these forms of expertise involve having differentiated cognitive structures, emotional granularity involves cognitive structures for emotions (e.g., "sadness" is different from "frustration") whereas domain expertise involves cognitive structures for domain knowledge (e.g., "cold brew" is different from "espresso"). Finally, emotional granularity is not necessarily linked to lower emotional focus (lower "emotionality"; . People with high granularity may still experience emotions with engagement. Rather than dampening emotional engagement ("emotional numbness"), emotional granularity allows for a more nuanced understanding and expression of emotions. The third and final distinction clarify how our work differs from prior research concerning the effect of consumption-domain expertise on reducing the "emotionality" of individuals' emotional descriptions , as both the key predictor and outcome variables in our work differ from the earlier work.</p><p>Emotional Granularity and Improved Self-Regulation in the Face of Negative Emotions Prior research has primarily used experience sampling methods to examine the associated outcomes of emotional granularity at the trait level. Experience sampling involves prompting participants to rate the intensity of a set of predetermined emotions across various emotionevoking situations. The underlying assumption in experiment sampling is that different life situations are unlikely to elicit the same set of similarly valenced emotions. Hence, a person whose ratings consistently correlate across different situations is considered to have low emotional granularity because this correlation reflects an inability to distinguish between emotions of the same valence.</p><p>Importantly, given the qualitative difference between positive and negative emotions, researchers have usually investigated the effects of granularity in negative and positive emotions separately (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Barrett et al. 2001)</ref>. Much of this research has focused on negative emotions, consistently demonstrating that greater granularity in negative emotions is associated with improved emotional self-regulation, more effective coping strategies, and, consequently, enhanced psychological health and well-being (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Kashdan et al. 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Granularity in negative emotions is associated with having a broader set of mental representations for negative emotions, which also includes a broader set of coping and selfregulation strategies that can be tapped into when needed <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Barrett and Gross 2001)</ref>. Furthermore, because individuals with higher negative emotional granularity identify and consider the context in which they had a negative experience, they exert better self-regulation to minimize the unwanted impact of these emotions on behaviors. For example, <ref type="bibr">Tomko et al. (2015)</ref> found that higher granularity in negative emotions predicts lower impulsivity among individuals with borderline personality disorder even after accounting for the overall levels of negative affect.</p><p>Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Kashdan et al. (2010)</ref> found that, even at similar levels of intense negative emotions, individuals with high negative emotional granularity are less likely to engage in alcohol abuse.</p><p>Furthermore, individuals with high emotional granularity are less likely to allow external manipulations of incidental negative emotions to influence their moral judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Cameron, Payne, and Doris 2013)</ref>. This body of evidence suggests that although coping in the context of emotional granularity may sometimes involve reducing the intensity of negative emotions, it also involves a greater ability to manage and minimize the unwanted influence of negative emotions on one's decisions and behavior through better self-regulation. In our research we focus on the effect of this second form of coping, and use the term "coping success" consistent with this latter effect: success in reducing the unwanted impact of negative emotions on one's decisions.</p><p>While extant research has primarily investigated the association between negative granularity and coping success at the trait level, one can also conceptualize the construct at the situation level. Previous conceptualizations of the construct account for situation-level variance in emotional granularity: even when emotional granularity is considered as an individual-level skill, one can agree that individuals' ability and/or motivation to use this skill varies from one situation to another. Thus, situation-level variances in experiencing and/or recalling one's emotions granularly have been previously theorized <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Barrett and Gross 2001)</ref>. However, there is no prior empirical evidence showing that an individual would more successfully cope with a specific negative experience if they used negative emotion labels more granularly to describe this experience (i.e., situation-level analysis). Thus, our research is the first to test the association between granularity in negative emotions and coping success at the situation level through language use, and to study the implications of this association in terms of how consumers rate businesses on online review platforms following service failures.</p><p>We note that while most existing research on emotional granularity has focused on granularity in negative emotions, a smaller body of trait-level evidence suggests that granularity in positive emotions is associated with improved health and well-being outcomes as well (see Tan, Wachsmuth, and Tugade 2022 for a review). This line of research argues that positive emotional granularity enables individuals to 'broaden and build' their mental resources, equipping them to better navigate negative emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Fredrickson 2001)</ref>. In our research, for two reasons, we will focus our theoretical discussions and predictions on negative emotional granularity. First, given the trait-level nature of findings in prior research, it is possible that the previously observed effects of positive emotional granularity are partially driven by correlations between negative and positive granularity, as individuals who are more granular in their negative emotions are also likely to be granular in their positive emotions (the "broaden-and-build" argument itself implies an effect of positive granularity through negative granularity). Second, our focus in this paper is on individuals' situation-level descriptions of their emotions following negative service experiences (e.g., service failures). Considering the motivational differences between negative and positive emotions, and the greater relevance of negative emotions in the service-failure context, we find a focus on negative emotional granularity more appropriate for the scope of our research. That said, we will include exploratory analyses of the effects of granularity in positive emotions in our empirical investigations, where applicable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Granularity in Negative Emotions, Emotional Self-Regulation, and Online Review Ratings</head><p>The rating (usually on a 5-star scale) that a consumer posts on review platforms indicates a decision that they make about the business after a consumption experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">(Sridhar and Srinivasan 2012)</ref>. This decision is subject to various psychological processes and is not merely an objective score of the negativity or positivity of the experiences. Consistently, previous research has shown that beyond the quality of the experience itself, processes related to social influence and conformity <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Goes, Lin, and Au Yeung 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Moe and Trusov 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Sridhar and</ref> Srinivasan 2012), psychological distance <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Huang et al. 2016)</ref>, the design of the review platform <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Aerts et al. 2017)</ref>, and reviewer status <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Zhang, Wei, and Zeng 2020)</ref> influence customer ratings.</p><p>While the role of coping and emotional self-regulation in consumer decision making has been explored extensively (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Duhachek 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Duhachek and Kelting 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Faraji-Rad and Lee 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">St. James, Handelman, and Taylor 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Raghunathan et al. 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Raghunathan and Pham 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr">)</ref>, to the best of our knowledge, previous research has not examined how these processes affect consumers' online review ratings. However, it is reasonable to expect that consumers' ability to regulate the impact of their negative emotions on their behavior would affect how they rate businesses following service failures. Specifically, consumers are often aware of the potentially detrimental effects that extremely low ratings can have on a business' success. As a result, they may be motivated to control their negative emotional response, and hesitate to give excessively negative ratings, even when faced with dissatisfaction. Still, not providing an extremely low rating despite a low-quality service experience-i.e., not punishing the business despite service failure-requires some level of emotional self-regulation to minimize and control the unwanted impact of the unpleasant emotions on the rating decision. We argue that granularity in describing one's negative emotions will be associated with better selfregulation of the impact of the negative emotions on the rating decision; and thus, granularity in describing negative emotions in the online review text will be associated with a more positive rating of the business. Furthermore, the self-regulation of negative emotions is most applicable in situations where service quality has been particularly low (e.g., service failures) and the overall experience has been negative. While one may have minor quibbles about positive experiences (e.g., "this was the best hotel I've been to, but the price of drinks was shocking"), such instances are less likely to require emotional regulation. Consistent with this argument, previous research has demonstrated that the effects of emotional granularity are stronger when individuals' overall experience is more negative (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Kashdan et al. 2010)</ref>. Thus, we expect the effect of negative emotional granularity on ratings to be especially strong when the overall experience has been negative.</p><p>While the primary focus of our research is to investigate how situation-level negative granularity impacts rating decisions, it is also worth considering whether marketers can leverage reviewers' negative granularity on review platforms as a psychological targeting or profiling tool <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Matz and Netzer 2017;</ref>. Specifically, marketers might infer individuals' traitlevel negative granularity from their earlier reviews to predict their future ratings. Such an approach could be valuable for practitioners, as it suggests that marketers might selectively solicit new reviews (e.g., through email campaigns) from reviewers who exhibit higher negative granularity in their past online reviews. In line with our situation-level proposition, we propose that reviewers who, on average, demonstrate higher historical negative granularity in their previous reviews will provide more positive ratings for service failures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Temporal Distance and Emotional Granularity</head><p>A last question to consider is how the passage of time between an experience and describing one's emotions from it influences the granularity with which individuals describe their negative emotions. While one might argue that the passage of time could contribute to forgetting and reduce the consideration of contextual cues in descriptions, prior research suggests otherwise. Specifically, individuals' memories for emotion-laden events tend to be particularly robust and more enduring than their memories for objective details (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Rocklage and Luttrell 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Kensinger 2009)</ref>. Thus, even as some specific details of the service experience may fade over time, the emotional essence and its related context are likely to persist.</p><p>Instead, with the passage of time, individuals are more likely to engage in cognitive reappraisal, a process that involves reinterpreting the emotional experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Lazarus 1991)</ref>. As emotional reactions to events become less visceral over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Chang and Pham 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Ekman and Davidson 1994)</ref>, these reappraisals allow individuals to better process and contextualize their negative emotions, potentially leading to more granular descriptions of negative emotions. Therefore, we propose that greater temporal distance between the time of receiving a service and the time of reviewing the business (hereafter, "temporal distance") will be positively associated with granularity in describing negative emotions in the review text. Consequently, this increased granularity should contribute to more successful self-regulation of negative emotions for service failures. Thus, we propose that a greater temporal distance will be associated with a more positive rating of the business following service failures.</p><p>We should note that the effect of temporal distance on review rating has been investigated in previous research. Specifically, <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Huang et al. (2016)</ref> has shown that greater psychological distance, including temporal distance between the experience and the review, increases the positivity of ratings. Our research adds to the findings by <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Huang et al. (2016)</ref> by recognizing the mediating role of emotional granularity in this effect, and introducing the overall service experience moderator: we propose that the effect of temporal distance is particularly strong when the overall service experience is negative and thus, self-regulation of emotions is relevant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MEASURING EMOTIONAL GRANULARITY THROUGH TEXTUAL DATA</head><p>As explained, experience sampling, which for the past three decades has been the main method used to measure emotional granularity (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Larsen and Cutler 1996)</ref>, produces a traitlevel assessment of individuals' emotional granularity, which is not ideal for addressing situation-level research questions. The method also requires a high degree of participant involvement, which is problematic in the applied field of marketing because it reduces the actionability of the construct in practice. Finally, to avoid participant fatigue, only a finite set of emotion labels can be used in experience sampling, which limits the range of emotions that can be captured using this method. Given the limitations of experience sampling, there have been calls in psychological research to develop methods that directly infer individuals' emotional granularity from their language <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Kashdan et al. 2015)</ref>. Furthermore, in the marketing domain, there has been an increasing interest in relying on the richness of the unstructured data to study consumer behavior <ref type="bibr">(Berger et al. 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Packard and Berger 2023)</ref>.</p><p>We propose that, given the close relationship between emotional granularity and language, an individual's level of emotional granularity in a given text can be assessed by examining whether they use different emotion labels in distinct meaning contexts. The theory of emotional granularity suggests that individuals with higher granularity possess more differentiated cognitive structures for different emotions, making them less likely to use multiple emotion labels to describe the same feeling. Experience sampling methods have been applied consistently with this theory: assuming that different life situations do not elicit the exact same set of emotions, researchers ask participants to rate their experience of a predetermined set of emotions across various situations. An individual who reports their emotions in a highly correlated manner across different situations is considered less granular, as this pattern suggests difficulty in distinguishing between the different emotions evoked by distinct life experiences.</p><p>However, in a situation-level analysis, we lack access to the person's emotional experiences across multiple situations. Therefore, to evaluate granularity within a single situation, we can invert the logic of the experience sampling method and ask: if an individual uses multiple emotion labels in their description of the situation, do they apply these labels to convey different contextual meanings (e.g., describe different aspects of the experience)? Using different emotion labels to describe the same situational context implies less precision in distinguishing between different emotional states/labels and hence lower granularity.</p><p>To elaborate further with the example of participants from <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Barrett (2006)</ref> discussed earlier, the more granular Participant A, has used "sadness" and "anger" in more distinct manner in their description, whereas the less granular Participant B has used these labels less distinctly.</p><p>Swapping "sadness" and "anger" in Participant A's description would significantly alter its meaning, whereas making the same switch in Participant B's description would have a less pronounced effect.</p><p>Thus, to measure the emotional granularity expressed in a text, a researcher must first identify the emotion labels used in the text, code how each label is applied based on dimensions that capture its distinctiveness in context, and finally use these dimensions to assess how differently the emotion labels have been used from one another.</p><p>Identifying emotion labels. The first step in our method involves distinguishing words that describe an emotion (e.g., "sad," "apprehensive," "hesitant") from words that do not. Two relevant glossaries for this purpose are the dictionaries from the Linguistic Inquiry and Word Count (LIWC) software <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Pennebaker et al. 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">Tausczik and Pennebaker 2010)</ref> and the Evaluative Lexicon <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">(Rocklage, Rucker, and Nordgren 2018)</ref>. LIWC includes a dictionary of words with positive and negative associations, which also includes non-emotion labels. The Evaluative Lexicon provides a dictionary of evaluative adjectives such as "wonderful" and "fantastic," which may not include a full set of emotion labels. We instructed a language expert (with a PhD in linguistics) to produce a comprehensive set of positive and negative emotion labels by a) considering all terms in these dictionaries; b) excluding any terms that would not be considered as emotion labels (e.g., "rapist," "protest"); c) referring to the English dictionary to include any additional emotion labels; d) coding whether each label in the final list of labels describe positive or a negative emotion. This exercise resulted in a glossary of 1,379 negative and 887 positive emotion labels which we use to classify each word in a given text (e.g., a review) into one of three categories: (1) non-emotional (no match in the glossary), (2) negative (matches a negative emotion label), or (3) positive (matches a positive label). We match words by considering their stems. Given the qualitative differences between negative and positive emotions, we compute granularity separately for each category when applicable.</p><p>BERT Embeddings as Context Encodings. The second step is to code how each label is applied in the text, based on dimensions that capture its contextual distinctiveness. Core to this step is the use of the Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers (BERT) encoder <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Devlin et al. 2018)</ref> to "encode" the context surrounding each word used in a given text into a feature vector. The BERT encoder is a deep-learning-based Large Language Model (LLM) that was trained, in part, by masking a random selection of 15% of the words in a large corpus of text and predicting each masked word using its adjacent words (see Web Appendix A for graph). The BERT encoder generates a 768-dimensional feature vector for each word in a text. This feature vector captures contextual information around the focal word by summarizing the surrounding words-the same information the model would rely on to predict the focal word if it were masked. Notably, BERT produces different feature vectors for identical words appearing in different linguistic contexts because it encodes how a word is used in the text (the word context) rather than the word itself. 2 (See <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> for an illustration of how our method captures differentiation based on the context in which an emotion label is used, rather than solely relying on the specific emotion label itself.). 3</p><p>Computing Differentiation between Feature Vectors. Once the feature vectors for each emotion label in a given piece of text are calculated, we use the Cronbach's alpha statistic to capture the degree of differentiation between the contexts in which these words are used. The Cronbach's alpha statistic is traditionally used to measure the internal consistency of a set of items (e.g., survey questions) that are intended to assess the same underlying construct. <ref type="bibr" target="#b92">2</ref> BERT encodings are structurally different from word embeddings produced by other models such as Word2Vec <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Mikolov et al. 2013)</ref> and GloVe <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Pennington, Socher, and Manning 2014)</ref>, which have been used in earlier consumer behavior research <ref type="bibr">(Berger et al. 2019)</ref>. In Word2Vec and GloVe, a word's embedding is the global representation of that word across the entire training corpus. Thus, these models produce the same embedding for identical words regardless of the context in which the word is used. However, BERT produces the feature vector representing a word's context, which is needed to predict the target word. This is why for two identical words that are used in different contexts, BERT produces different feature vectors. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We have included the vanilla Python code for measuring emotional granularity using our approach in Web Appendix A. Our implementation customizes this vanilla code by incorporating optimizations such as vectorization, memory management, and multi-core/parallel processing to enhance processing speed. Both versions produce identical results. On the same machine (using a GPU), the vanilla code would take approximately 75 days to process all the field data in our paper, whereas our optimized implementation reduces this time to about 7 days. each word's vector representation as an item and considering the set of emotion labels as the "construct" (the "construct" in our application could be viewed as the contextual meaning represented by these "items"). A high Cronbach's alpha (closer to 1) would indicate that the feature vectors (i.e., the "items") represent highly overlapping contextual meanings. Conversely, a low Cronbach's alpha (closer to 0) would suggest greater differentiation, implying that the words are used in distinct contextual meaning spaces. For ease of interpretation, we subtract this statistic from 1 so that a higher score indicates higher differentiation and granularity. 4 Note. An illustration of how our measurement approach captures the context in which emotion labels are used, rather than focusing solely on the labels themselves. In each example, differentiation scores are calculated by computing the 768-dimensional BERT feature vector of the words uncomfortable (from Sentence 1) and irritated (from Sentence 2), calculating the Cronbach's alpha statistic of these two vectors, and subtracting the result from 1. Despite the focal words being identical across all examples, the differentiation scores vary. In Example 1, the words are used with slightly different contextual information (mention of sick child in Sentence 2 but not in Sentence 1), thus the differentiation score is higher compared to scores in Examples 2 or 3, where the words are used with identical contextual information. It is important to note that while this illustration computes differentiation scores across separate sentences for clarity and control, our actual method does not require breaking the text into sentences. Instead, we compute the feature vectors of different words within the full text, allowing us to assess differentiation based on the broader context in which the words are used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STUDY 1: ASSESSING OUR MEASUREMENT APPROACH</head><p>The main purpose of study 1 was to evaluate our proposed method for calculating the emotional granularity in language by comparing it with the commonly used experiencesampling-based measurement of emotional granularity, which is currently the predominant method being used to measure emotional granularity in psychological research. Experience sampling studies often involve measuring participants' emotions several times a day through the course of several weeks. However, <ref type="bibr">Cameron and colleagues (2013)</ref> have successfully adapted the method for a single experimental session. Specifically, to measure participants' granularity in negative emotions, these authors presented their participants with a set of 10 images and measured the extent to which participants felt anger, guilt, sadness, and shame in response to each image. They then computed participants' trait-level granularity in negative emotions by computing the intra-class correlation coefficients (ICCs) of these ratings. In study 1, we adapted these authors' method to the consumer behavior context to measure participants' experiencesampling-based granularity in negative emotions. More Specifically, we recruited 605 participants (MAge = 42.8, SD = 13.1, 53.5% females) from CloudResearch and presented them with 10 short consumption scenarios (e.g., "You've been a loyal customer to a brand for years, but you notice they send personalized discounts to new customers and not to you."; see Web</p><p>Appendix B for stimuli). For each scenario, we asked participants to rate how much it would make them feel anger, guilt, sadness, and shame on scales ranging from 1 = not at all to 5 = extremely. Following Cameron et al. (2013) we computed the z-score normalized ICCs of these ratings for each participant and multiplied this number by -1 to compute the degree of trait-level negative emotional granularity of each participant. stimuli) and asked participants to imagine themselves going through this experience. Next, we asked participants to indicate how many stars (out of five) would they give to this restaurant if they were to rate it on a website like Yelp. Finally, we asked participants to write a review of this restaurant in about 50 words as if they were reviewing it on Yelp. We computed the granularity of negative emotions expressed in this review using the deep-learning-based method described earlier (a total of 211 reviews did not receive granularity scores because they did not include 2 or more negative emotion labels).</p><p>We reasoned that if our measure indeed captures participants' situation-level emotional granularity in expressing their negative emotions in text, as a conservative test, the negative emotional granularity score computed through our method should correlate with the trait-level scores produced using the experience sampling method. Results support the validity of our proposed method by confirming a correlation between the two negative emotional granularity scores (r = .104, p = .040).</p><p>Furthermore, if emotional granularity in negative emotions is associated with emotional self-regulation 5 and more positive rating of unpleasant service experiences, both the experiencesampling-based negative granularity measure (trait-level) and our deep-learning-based negative granularity scores (situation-level) should correlate with more positive ratings of the restaurant.</p><p>Supporting our theoretical predictions, both the experience-sampling-based (r = .086, p = .031) and the deep-learning-based (r = .118, p = .019) negative emotional granularity scores were correlated with higher ratings of the restaurant.</p><p>Another goal of study 1 was to explore whether granularity in negative emotions can be distinguished from other emotion-related constructs. To assess the distinctiveness of the negative emotional granularity from complexity of negative emotions, we computed the number of unique negative emotion labels used in the review text, because using more negative emotion labels may indicate higher complexity. The number of unique negative emotion labels in the review text was not associated with emotional granularity scores derived from experience sampling (p = 0.833).</p><p>This result supports the distinction between emotional granularity, as a trait-level skill, and emotional complexity. The number of unique negative emotion labels in the review text was negatively correlated with granularity in expressing negative emotions within the review (r = -0.575, p &lt; 0.001). This latter result does align with our conceptualization of emotional granularity: A single context can evoke only a limited range of emotions. Because more granular individuals have a more precise cognitive structure for different emotions, they choose emotion labels more selectively, and only if the labels apply to the specific context, which causes a negative correlation when descriptions of a single context (i.e., the restaurant experience) are considered.</p><p>Furthermore, to assess the distinctiveness of granularity in negative emotions from extremity of negative emotions, emotional certainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Rocklage et al. 2023)</ref>, and participants' degree of focus on negative emotions (i.e., negative "emotionality"; Rocklage et al. 2015), we used The Lexical Suite (see Rocklage and Fazio 2015 for operationalization of variables in The Lexical Suite), to compute the review text's score on each of these constructs. (Since our granularity measure focuses on negative labels, we focused on the emotionality and extremity scores that the Lexical Suite produces for negative emotions). None of these variables predicted the experience-sampling-based negative granularity scores <ref type="bibr">(p-values &gt; .196)</ref> or the deeplearning-based negative granularity scores (p-values &gt; .335). <ref type="bibr" target="#b95">6</ref> These results suggest differentiation between emotional granularity and these other constructs.</p><p>The results of study 1 provide preliminary validation of our method to measure emotional granularity in text, while disentangling the construct from other emotion-related constructs. The correlation table of all measured variables are presented in Web Appendix E.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STUDY 2: MANIPULATING THE CONTEXTUALIZATION OF EMOTIONS</head><p>The aim of study 2 was to validate our assumption that our deep learning-based method for measuring emotional granularity in language effectively captures individuals' likelihood of contextualizing their emotions. A total of 393 students (MAge = 20.1, SD = 1.5, 47.1 females) from a large public university in the US participated in the study for course credit. All participants watched a short news clip about Delta Airlines removing a family with an infant from an overbooked flight. Importantly, we manipulated participants' likelihood of contextualizing their emotions by instructing them to either focus solely on the emotions they might have experienced during the incident or to consider the contextual factors that led to the incident. More specifically, participants in the control condition were asked to "put yourself in the mistreated customers' shoes. Focus on the emotions they might have experienced during the incident. Make an effort to imagine what it would feel like to be in their situation and to experience those emotions." Those in the contextualization condition were instead asked to "imagine yourself in the airline's position. Consider the possible reasons behind the airline's decision, such as policies or procedures they may have been required to follow that didn't account for an unexpected situation like this. Focus on understanding the context that could explain why the airline acted as it did, even if the outcome was unfortunate." Thus, the manipulation influenced participants' likelihood of contextualizing their emotions by either directing them to focus solely on the raw emotional responses caused by the event or prompting them to incorporate nuanced contextual factors into their emotional appraisals <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Lazarus 1991)</ref>.</p><p>After watching the video all participants were asked to take a few minutes "to describe in detail the negative emotions that you experienced from watching the video." We calculated the negative granularity scores of these descriptions to investigate whether participants who were instructed to consider contextual information would describe their negative emotions more granularly than participants in the control condition. We were able to calculate the negative granularity scores for 170 participants in the contextualization condition and 190 participants in the control condition. As expected, an ANOVA showed that participants' expressions of their negative emotions were more granular if they were instructed to contextualize their emotions (M = .25, SD = .11) than not (M = .20, SD = .09; F(1, 358) = 16.79, p &lt; .001, h 2 p = .045).</p><p>Furthermore, to dissociate our construct from other emotion-related constructs, we calculated all the variables that were calculated from the review text in the previous study to explore the effect of our manipulation on them. Participants who were instructed to consider the context, used fewer unique negative emotion labels (M = 3.10, SD = 1.49) than those who were not (M = 3.91, SD = 1.60; F(1, 391) = 26.68, p &lt; .001, h 2 p = .064), which is again consistent with the idea that emotional granularity is correlated with being selective in using emotion labels. However, the effect of the manipulation on the granularity expressed in the reviews persisted if controlling for the number of unique negative emotion labels (F(1, 357) = 4.33, p = .038, h 2 p = .012), demonstrating that our measure of emotional granularity captures more nuanced information within the text beyond this correlated measure. The manipulation did not influence the extremity of negative emotions (F(1, 360) &lt; 1; p = .627), the negative emotional focus ("emotionality") (F(1, 360) &lt; 1; p = .731), or the certainty (F(1, 368) &lt; 1; p = .499) expressed in the essays. 7</p><p>These findings further validate our measure by demonstrating that it captures individuals' tendency to contextualize their emotions, while other emotion-related constructs do not show the same sensitivity to this distinction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STUDY 3: EMOTIONAL GRANULARITY AND REVIEW RATINGS</head><p>The purpose of study 3 was to test our propositions regarding the relationship between granularity in describing negative emotions in the review text and review ratings using a large dataset of online consumer reviews. We collected over 11 million reviews from over 52,000 Yelp reviewers, ensuring that the dataset includes all reviews from each reviewer in the sample.</p><p>We have predicted that higher granularity in describing negative emotions in the review text is associated with a more positive rating of the business, but especially in the case of negative service experiences. We used the LIWC software to measure the overall positivity of the text of the review as a proxy for the quality (positivity) of the service experience. We investigated how the granularity with which negative emotions are described in the review text,</p><p>interacts with the quality of the service experience to predict the 5-star rating given in the review.</p><p>In addition, we explored the potential applicability of granularity in describing negative emotions as a psychological targeting and profiling tool. We thus computed a historical granularity index for each reviewer at the time of writing each review by averaging all the negative granularity scores of the reviewer across all their reviews written prior to the focal review. We investigated how this historical granularity index interacts with the quality of the service experience to predict the review rating.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data and Measures</head><p>Review data. The data for this study was gathered from Yelp. Yelp reviews include qualitative textual comments and a star rating on a 5-point scale. The platform also allows users to create a profile and to follow other users and be followed by them. We adopted a snowball sampling approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Zhang et al. 2020)</ref> to create our dataset. As the first step, we began with one prolific reviewer on Yelp and collected all reviews written by this individual. In the second step, from this reviewer's profile, we extracted the list of their friends and collected all reviews written by a random sample of 20% of them. Finally, from the reviewers in our second step sample, we identified a random sample of 20% of their friends and collected all their reviews. This sampling approach ensured that our data includes all the reviews of each reviewer in our dataset. Given that our text analysis approach was limited to English, we removed all non-English reviews from our dataset. Through this process, we obtained 11,272,283 reviews, written by 52,804 reviewers, in a period between July 2000 and September 2021.</p><p>Perceived Experience Quality (Review Valence). As a measure of the overall positivity of the service experience, we computed a perceived experience quality index for each review using the LIWC software <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Pennebaker et al. 2001)</ref> by subtracting the percentage of negative words from the percentage of positive words in each review.</p><p>Granularity in Negative Emotions. For each review, we computed the granularity with which the reviewer has described their negative emotions in that review using our method explained earlier. Since some reviews contained less than two negative emotion labels, a total of 3,343,739 reviews did not receive a negative granularity score.</p><p>Granularity in Positive Emotions. We used the same method to also compute granularity in positive emotions (but this time by considering positive emotion labels) to be used as a control variable and to explore the effects of granularity in positive emotions. Again, because some reviews contained less than two positive emotion labels, 398,244 reviews did not receive a positive granularity score.</p><p>Linguistic Precision. One may wonder if the effects observed in our results are because reviewers specifically use negative emotion labels with precision or because they simply use all words in the vocabulary with precision, perhaps because of higher language sophistication. To remedy this concern, as a control variable, we calculated a linguistic precision index for each review by applying our method to all non-emotional words in the review, excluding stop words (e.g., "this", "and", etc.). A total of 811 (very short) reviews did not receive a score.</p><p>Historical Granularity and Linguistic Precision Indexes. We computed a historical negative granularity index for each reviewer at the time of writing each review by averaging all negative granularity scores of the reviewer for their reviews that were written prior to the focal review. We also computed similar historical indices for positive granularity and linguistic precision.</p><p>Other Control Variables. As other control variables we computed the number of unique positive and unique negative emotion labels used in the review to control for possible effects of emotional complexity and ambivalence. We also included the word count of each review as a control variable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses and Results</head><p>Granularity in Review Text and Review Ratings. We conducted a multi-level regression (Model 1.1 in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>), predicting review rating with the fixed effects of negative granularity, perceived experience quality, and their interaction, while controlling for the fixed effects of positive granularity, positive granularity  perceived-experience-quality interaction, linguistic precision, number of unique negative emotion labels, number of unique positive emotion labels, and the word count of the review. We also included the reviewer random intercept in the model.</p><p>For the ease of interpretation of the results, we Z-score normalized all independent variables in this model and all subsequent models. The full results of this regression are presented in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>For brevity, we discuss only the results that are central to testing our predictions. The more granularly the reviewer described their negative emotions in the review text, the more positively they rated the business (b = .07, S.E. = .0005, t = 142.72, p = .000, 95% CI = [0.069, 0.071]). We had predicted that the effect of negative emotional granularity on rating would be stronger when perceived experience quality is negative because self-regulation of negative emotions is most relevant to experiences that are negative overall. In support of this prediction, we observed a significant negative granularity  perceived-experience-quality interaction effect (b = -.14, S.E. = .0005, t = -272.40, p = .000, 95% CI = [-0.141, -0.139]). As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, simple slope analysis revealed that, in reviews that described a more negative overall experience (M-SD), the more granularly the reviewer described their negative emotions within the review text, the more positively they rated the business (b = .19, S.E. = .00, t = 286.73, p = .00). However, the effect of emotional granularity on rating was attenuated for reviews that described an overall positive experience (M+SD; b = .00, S.E. = .00, t = 3.19, p = .00).</p><p>Interestingly, granularity in positive emotions was associated with more negative ratings (b = -.16, S.E. = .0006, t = -251.56, p = .000, 95% CI = [-.161, -.158]). We had not made a priori predictions regarding the effects of positive granularity. However, a post-hoc interpretation of this effect may be that describing one's positive emotions more granularly is associated with a higher likelihood of considering the representativeness and relevance of one's feelings for the rating judgement (i.e., "I enjoyed my coffee at this caf, but the weather-though unrelated to the caf-contributed to this feeling"; Pham 1998), which may reduce the total sum of the impact of positive feelings on ratings. Furthermore, we also observed a significant positive granularity  perceived-experience-quality interaction effect (b = .03, S.E. = .0005, t = 57.62, p = .000, 95% CI = [.029, .031]). Simple slope analysis suggests that the association between positive granularity and negative ratings was stronger in reviews that described a more negative experience quality (M-SD; b = -.19, S.E. = .00, t = -309.46, p = .00) than a more positive service quality (M+SD; b = -.15, S.E. = .00, t = -190.10, p =.00). This interaction effect, which was much smaller than the one with negative granularity, is not parallel to what was observed with negative granularity: a parallel result would be to observe a stronger association in reviews that describe a more positive experience. A post-hoc interpretation of this interaction may be that when the experience-quality is negative, contextualizing positive emotions leads to an even lower attribution of the positive emotions to the business ("The only thing good about this hotel was its beach but that's because all beaches on this Island are nice").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FIGURE 1</head><p>THE EFFECT OF NEGATIVE GRANULARITY AND PERCEIVED SERVICE QUALITY Historical Emotional Granularity and Review Ratings. To investigate whether the effects found in Model 1.1 with situation-level negative granularity hold by considering historical negative granularity scores, we conducted another multi-level regression (Model 1.2 in <ref type="table">Table 2)</ref> that predicts the rating of each review with the fixed effects of that experience quality, the historical negative emotional granularity index of the reviewer of that review, and the interaction of these two factors. In this model, we also controlled for the fixed effects of the reviewer's historical positive emotional granularity index, the historical positive granularity  experience quality interaction, the reviewer's historical linguistic precision scores, the number of unique negative and positive emotion labels in the review, and the word count of the review. We also included the reviewer random intercept in the model. The full results of this regression are also presented in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. Consistent with our situation-level analysis from Model 1.1, we observed that reviewers' greater propensity for describing negative emotions in their prior reviews was = 0.00, t = 78.49, p = .00). However, we observed a negative association between the historical negative granularity and ratings if the focal review described a positive experience (b = -.02, S.E. = 0.00, t = -34.13, p = .00).</p><p>Exploring the effects of positive granularity, as with the situation-level analysis, we observed a significant negative association between historical granularity in positive emotions and ratings (b = -.04, S.E. = 0.001, t = -41.52, p = .00, 95% CI = [ -.042, -.038]). We also observed a significant historical positive granularity  experience quality fixed interaction effect (b = -.01, S.E. = .0003, t = -29.39, p = .000, 95% CI = [-0.011, -0.009]). However, as opposed to the situation-level analysis before, the association between positive granularity and negative ratings was stronger in reviews that described a more positive experience quality (M+SD; b = -.04, S.E. = .00, t = -49.30, p = .00) than a more negative experience quality (M-SD; b = -0.03, S.E. = 0.00, t = -29.45, p = 0.00). A possible interpretation is that individuals' historical positive granularity may also capture some of the variance in individuals' trait-level self-regulation abilities in managing negative emotions, as one expects those with higher granularity in negative emotions to also have higher granularity in positive emotions.</p><p>Robustness Checks. To check the robustness of our results if controlling for extremity of negative emotions, emotional certainty and the negative "emotionality" expressed in the reviews, we conducted the two regressions above while controlling for these variables as calculated by the Evaluative Lexicon. The conclusions from our results remain unchanged (see Web Appendix F for robustness check results, and Web Appendix E for correlation tables of all measured variables). Note. All p-values are significant below the .0001 level.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In study 3, we used a large sample of reviews from reviewers on Yelp to conduct an analysis of the relationship between granularity in describing negative emotions in the review text and reviewer ratings. First, we found evidence consistent with the notion that the granularity in describing negative emotions is associated with better self-regulation of negative emotions.</p><p>Self-regulation of negative emotions is most relevant in situations where the overall service experience has been of low quality. We measured the overall negativity of the review text as a proxy for the perceived quality of the service experience. Accordingly, we observed that especially when perceived experience quality was low, granularity in describing negative emotions was associated with more positive ratings of the business. We observed this effect at two levels. First, at the situation level, we observed that granularity in negative emotions in a specific review resulted in the above effect. Second, we observed that a reviewer's historical granularity in describing their negative emotions in their prior reviews is associated with more positive ratings, particularly for low quality service experiences. This latter result is important because of its implications for consumer targeting and profiling, as the analysis uses traits inferred from reviewers' earlier reviews to predict their future ratings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STUDY 4: MANIPULATION OF THE LIKELIHOOD OF EMOTION REGULATION</head><p>The purpose of study 4 was to provide process evidence that the observed effect of granularity in negative emotions on ratings is because granularity facilitates the self-regulation of the unwanted impact of negative emotions on rating decisions. If the effect is driven by emotional self-regulation, then instructing participants to avoid regulating their negative emotions should weaken the correlation between granularity in describing negative emotions and ratings. To test this, we recruited 404 participants (MAge = 41.15, SD = 13.6, 49.5% females)</p><p>from Prolific and randomly assigned them to either a control or an avoid-regulation condition.</p><p>We first asked all participants to recall a recent unpleasant service experience and to describe the negative emotions from it in about 50 words. Afterward, participants in the control condition were asked to provide a star rating for the business (1 = 1 Star, 5 = 5 Stars), as if reviewing it on a platform like Yelp. Those in the avoid-regulation condition were also instructed to rate the business at this stage, but with the additional instruction to focus solely on how bad they personally felt due to the experience and to rate the business based only on this feeling. Thus, compared to the control group, participants in the avoid-regulation condition were explicitly discouraged from regulating their negative emotions when forming their rating-i.e., regardless of whether the emotions were attributable to the business or not.</p><p>We were able to compute negative granularity scores for 359 participants. We conducted a linear regression to predict ratings with condition (0 = control, 1 = avoid-regulation), negative granularity scores (centered), and their interaction. As expected, instructions to avoid self- These results support the idea that granularity in negative emotions is associated with more positive ratings of the business because contextualizing emotions helps individuals selfregulate the impact of their negative emotions on their rating decisions. Notably, additional</p><p>regression analyses we have conducted shows that the effect of extremity in negative emotions, the focus on negative emotions (negative "emotionality"), and emotional certainty-calculated using The Lexical Suite from participants' essays-on ratings, is not moderated by our manipulation (all interaction p-values &gt; .479), further dissociating our construct from these other constructs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STUDIES 5A AND 5B: TEMPORAL DISTANCE AND EMOTIONAL GRANULARITY</head><p>We argue that the lower viscerality of negative emotions resulting from temporal distance enables individuals to consider the context in which they experienced those emotions and to express them more granularly. In studies 5A and 5B we investigated the causal effect of temporal distance on the granularity with which individuals express their negative emotions.</p><p>In study 5A, we leveraged the presidential debate between Kamala Harris and Donald</p><p>Trump on September 10, 2024, which was widely perceived as a victory for Kamala Harris, and thus an unpleasant experience for Trump supporters. We recruited a total of 574 (MAge = 43.2, SD = 13.7; 52.4% females) Trump supporters through CloudResearch. We utilized the platform's prescreening surveys to target US participants who had indicated "very" or "somewhat" favorable attitude towards Donald Trump, were planning to vote for Donald Trump, and were planning to watch the presidential debates. Participants were simply asked to spend a few minutes describing, in about 50 words, the emotions that they experienced from watching the debate. Importantly, a total of 301 participants completed the survey 2 days after the debate whereas 273 participants completed it 10 days after (we intended to recruit 300 participants for the second group. However, there were not enough participants on CloudResearch with the prescreened characteristics and we stopped the survey after two days of inactivity). We were able to compute negative granularity scores for 242 participants in the first group and 229 participants in the second group. As expected, participants who wrote their essay 10 days after the debate (M = .34, SD = .13) expressed their negative emotions more granularly than those who wrote it 2 days after (M = .31, SD = .12; F(1, 469) = 4.29, p = .039, h 2 p = .009).</p><p>To dissociate emotional granularity from the other emotion-related constructs, we also computed the additional set of variables that were calculated in the previous studies. The manipulation did not influence the number of unique negative emotions labels used in the essays (F(1, 572) &lt; 1; p = .383), the extremity of the negative emotions (F(1, 438) = 1.71; p = .192), the degree of emotionality of the negative emotions (F(1, 438) = 2.03; p = .155), or the certainty (F(1, 528) = 2.03; p = .544) expressed in the essays.</p><p>In study 5B, we adopted a more controlled approach. We recruited a total of 505 participants (MAge = 37.6, SD = 12.5; 59.8% females) from CloudResearch and asked them to first watch a short clip of the movie "The Champ", which depicts a young actor grieving their deceased father, and has been used in previous research as a sad stimulus (e.g., Faraji-Rad and Lee 2022). Participants were then asked to describe in detail the emotions that they experienced from watching the clip. Importantly, one randomly assigned group of participants (no-time-gap condition) described their emotions immediately after watching the video; whereas the other group (time-gap condition) were first asked to write about a typical day in their life and then write about their emotions.</p><p>We were able to compute negative granularity scores for 211 participants in the time-gap condition and 224 participants in the no-time-gap condition. As expected, participants who wrote their essay with a time gap after watching the clip (M = .26, SD = .11) expressed their negative emotions more granularly than those who wrote it immediately after (M = .23, SD = .09; F(1, 433) = 9.28, p = .002, h 2 p = .021).</p><p>In contrast to the previous study, in this study, participants in the time-gap condition (M = 3.09, SD = 1.85) used fewer unique negative emotion labels than those in the no-time-gap condition (M = 3.66, SD = 1.77; F(1, 503) = 12.59, p &lt; .001, h 2 p = .024). However, the effect of the manipulation on emotional granularity remained marginally significant when controlling for the number of unique negative labels (F(1, 432) = 3.48, p = .063, h 2 p = .008). The extremity of the negative emotions (F(1, 425) = 1.23; p = .268), the "emotionality" of negative emotions F(1, 425) &lt; 1; p = .331), or certainty (F(1, 452) &lt; 1; p = .543) expressed in the essays were not affected by the manipulation.</p><p>The results of these two studies provide causal evidence that individuals describe their negative emotions from an experience more granularly if there is a greater temporal distance between the experience time and the description time. Furthermore, the observation that the temporal distance manipulations in these studies do not consistently influence the other emotionrelated constructs helps further differentiate the emotional granularity construct from the other emotion-related constructs: if the different measures were measuring the same construct, we would expect them to behave similarly in response to the manipulation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STUDY 6: TEMPORAL DISTANCE, GRANULARITY, AND REVIEW RATINGS</head><p>In study 6, we used a sample of reviews from TripAdvisor.com that included all reviews of all hotels in New York and Las Vegas listed on TripAdvisor. The study's first objective was to replicate the interactive effect of experience quality and granularity in describing negative emotions on review ratings. To ensure the robustness of our findings, we used two proxies for experience quality. As the first proxy, consistent with study 3, we used the valence of the focal review's text, which captures the reviewer's own description and perceptions of the service experience. The second proxy was the normative average of the experience qualities described across all other reviews for the business, excluding the focal review. This measure provides a more objective-and more conservative-assessment of service quality beyond the perspective of the focal reviewer.</p><p>The second purpose of the study was to test our propositions regarding the effects of temporal distance between a service experience and the writing of the review using information extracted from TripAdvisor.com. In studies 5A and 5B we observed that the temporal distance between an experience and describing one's emotions from it increases the granularity with which negative emotions are described. In study 6, we tested whether a greater temporal distance is associated with greater granularity in describing negative emotions in the review text.</p><p>Furthermore, we investigated whether the increased negative granularity resulting from the greater temporal distance predicts a more positive rating of the business, especially when overall experience quality is negative.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data and Measures</head><p>Review data. We collected the entire set of reviews for all hotels in New York and Las Vegas on TripAdvisor.com that were available up to the time of data collection. This resulted in a total of 1,343,518 reviews spanning 18 years (2003-2020) from 591 hotels. Similar to Yelp,</p><p>TripAdvisor enables users to share and evaluate their experience with service providers in the form of qualitative textual comments and a star rating on a 5-point scale. We collected review texts, review ratings, when each review was posted, and when the service was provided.</p><p>Temporal Distance. TripAdvisor provides the month when the visit to the hotel took place (e.g., Dec 2023). Thus, to measure temporal distance, we counted the number of months between the time of the visit and the date when the review was posted. This number was then log transformed for incorporation into the model. We excluded a total of 1,278 reviews that produced a negative temporal distance, which suggested that either the reviewer reviewed the service before visiting it, or that the time of the visit was incorrect.</p><p>Perceived and Normative Experience Quality. We computed a perceived experience quality index for each review following the approach used in study 3. Additionally, the structure of our dataset, which includes all reviews for each hotel, allowed us to derive a second measure of experience quality: the normative average of the experience qualities from all other reviews of the focal business, excluding the focal review itself. This measure provides a more objective assessment of experience quality, as it reflects the collective experiences of other reviewers and is less likely to be confounded with variables specific to the focal review. However, it serves as a conservative estimate, as a hotel's service quality can vary over time and across customers.</p><p>Therefore, we use it to test the robustness of our results based on the first measure.</p><p>Granularity in Negative Emotions. Using the proposed method explained earlier, for each review, we computed the granularity with which the reviewer has described their negative emotions in that review. Since some reviews contained less than two negative emotion labels, a total of 573,752 reviews did not receive a negative granularity score.</p><p>Granularity in Positive Emotions. For use as a control variable and also to explore the effects of granularity in positive emotions, as in study 3, we computed a positive granularity score for each review. Again, some reviews contained less than two positive emotion labels.</p><p>Therefore, a total of 42,646 reviews did not receive a positive granularity score.</p><p>precision index for each review. Six very short reviews did not receive a score. As other control variables we computed the number of unique positive and unique negative emotion labels used in the review, as well as the word count of each review.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis and Results</head><p>Granularity in Review Text and Review Ratings. We first tested whether the results of study 3 on the relationship between negative granularity and review rating would be replicated with the current dataset. We conducted a multi-level regression (Model 2.1 in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>), predicting review rating with the fixed effects of negative granularity, perceived experience quality, and their interaction, while controlling for the fixed effects of positive granularity, positive granularity  perceived-experience-quality interaction, linguistic precision, number of unique negative emotion labels, number of unique positive emotion labels, and the word count of the review. We also included the hotel random intercept in the model. The full results of this regression are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. We focus on the results that are pertinent to testing our predictions. Replicating the results of the previous study, negative emotional granularity was associated with higher ratings (b = .12, S.E. = .001, t = 76.94, p = .000, 95% CI = <ref type="bibr">[.118, .122]</ref>).</p><p>We again observed the predicted negative granularity  perceived-experience-quality interaction effect (b = -.15, S.E. = .002 t = -93.19, p = .000, 95% CI = <ref type="bibr">[-.154, -.146]</ref>). As in study 3, simple slope analyses revealed that in reviews describing an overall negative service experience (M-SD), the more granularly the reviewers described their negative emotions, the more positively they rated the business (b = .27, S.E. = .00, t = 129.50, p = .00). However, the effect of emotional granularity on rating was attenuated for reviews describing an overall positive experience (M+SD) (b = 0.06, S.E. = .00, t = 31.88, p = .00).</p><p>Exploring the effects of positive granularity, we observed effects that were consistent with model 1.1 in study 3. We will thus not discuss them further here.</p><p>The Effect of Temporal Distance on Negative Granularity. We predicted that a greater temporal distance increases reviewers' likelihood of describing their negative emotions granularly. To provide support for this prediction, we conducted another multi-level regression (Model 2.2 in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>), in which we predicted negative granularity of the reviews with the fixed effects of temporal distance, perceived experience quality, and their interaction, while controlling for the same control variables that were included in Model 2.1. The full results of this regression are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. As expected, we observed that greater temporal distance is associated with a higher level of granularity in describing negative emotions in the review (b = .01, S.E. =.001, t = 12.26, p = .000, 95% CI = [0.008, 0.012]).</p><p>The Effect of Temporal Distance on Review Rating. We have predicted greater temporal distance to be associated with higher review ratings, especially when the overall service quality is low. To test this, we estimated another multi-level regression (Model 2.3 in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>) to predict review rating with temporal distance, perceived experience quality, and their interaction, while also including the same control variables that were included in Models 2.1 and 2.2.</p><p>The full results of this regression are also presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. A greater temporal distance (b = .03, S.E. = 0.001, t = 40.43, p = .000, 95% CI = [0.028, 0.032]) was associated with more positive ratings. However, importantly, we also observed a temporal distance  perceivedexperience-quality interaction (b = -.03, S.E. = .001, t = -42.05, p = .000, 95% CI = [-0.032, -0.028]. When perceived experience quality was low, greater temporal distance was associated with a more positive rating of the business (b = .06, S.E. = .00, t = 57.18, p = .00). Interestingly, however, when perceived service quality was positive, a greater temporal distance was only minimally associated with the review rating (b = -.00, S.E. = .00, t = -2.06, p = .04), which is consistent with our self-regulation/coping-based argument of the effect of temporal distance:</p><p>when the overall experience is positive and thus, emotional self-regulation does not apply, reviewers' improvement in negative granularity caused by temporal distance does not contribute to more positive ratings.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref>, were consistent with what was observed with the reviewer-level service quality scores <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table 3)</ref>, demonstrating the robustness of our findings across both quality scores.</p><p>Furthermore, similar to study 3, we tested whether the conclusion from results would substantively change if we controlled for extremity of negative emotions, emotional certainty, and degree of focus on negative emotions. They do not (see Web Appendix G for these robustness check results, and Web Appendix E for correlation tables of all measured variables).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Study 6 replicated the result of study 3 by showing that particularly when the overall experience is negative, higher granularity in describing negative emotions in the review text is associated with a more positive rating of the business. We observed this effect both when considering the reviewers' own perceived experience quality expressed in the review, and when considering the normative experience quality of the hotel as described by other reviewers. Consistent with the causal evidence of the effect of temporal distance on negative emotional granularity in studies 5A and 5B, we also observed that temporal distance is associated with higher granularity in describing negative emotions. Importantly, we also observed the consequences of this increased granularity on the rating assigned to the business through a moderated mediation analysis. We observed that when the overall experience is negative, greater temporal distance is associated with more positive ratings, and this effect is mediated by granularity in describing negative emotions. On the other hand, when the experience is positive, and coping is not relevant, temporal distance does not improve ratings. These results are important as they demonstrate that individuals' granularity in describing their negative emotions may be impacted by situational factors, with implications for coping with negative experiences and review ratings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GENERAL DISCUSSION</head><p>Studies show that over 90% of consumers use online reviews as a source of information to guide their purchases <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Forbes 2022)</ref>, and even a single review rating has a strong effect on consumers' purchase likelihood <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">(Vana and Lambrecht 2021)</ref>. These facts make consumers' decisions on how to rate a business, following negative service experiences (e.g., service</p><p>failures) an important one to study. We studied consumer's online review rating decisions from the perspective of consumer coping, and by considering the degree of granularity with which reviewers describe their negative emotions in their reviews. Although the notion of emotional granularity has received considerable attention in the psychology domain over the past three decades (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Barrett and Gross 2001;</ref>, to date, research in marketing and consumer behavior has not investigated its implications for consumer decision making.</p><p>Our research contributes to the online review literature by providing evidence of the impact of granularity in negative emotions on review ratings, following service failures. We built on previous research, which has demonstrated the association between negative emotional granularity and successful self-regulation of negative emotions. We observed that reviewers provide a more positive rating of a business, following unpleasant service experiences, if they describe their negative emotions more granularly in the review text, both at the situation-level and when the reviewers' historical granularity in their previous reviews is considered.</p><p>Furthermore, consistent with the idea that temporal distance reduces the viscerality of emotions and enables individuals to more successfully consider contextual information in their emotional reappraisals, we observed causal evidence that temporal distance increases the granularity with which individuals describe their negative emotions. We further observed that the granularity with which consumer describe their negative emotions in their reviews is higher when there is greater temporal distance between receiving the service and writing their review, with implications for ratings of negative service experiences. While <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Huang et al. (2016)</ref> have earlier demonstrated a positive link between temporal distance and review ratings, our results extend their findings by studying the effect through the lens of emotional granularity and coping success, and uncovering an important boundary condition of the effect: the effect holds only for low quality service experiences.</p><p>Our research also contributes to the line of research on the role of feelings and emotions in consumer decision making, which has been studied extensively (e.g. types of emotions in decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allard and White 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Cavanaugh et al. 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Raghunathan and Pham 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Raghunathan et al. 2006)</ref>. However, previous research on consumer decision making has not investigated whether consumers' propensity to differentiate between their emotions, as an indicator of their emotional expertise, also influences their decisions. Future research could investigate the impact of emotional granularity on outcomes other than the one we focused on here. For example, how does emotional granularity affect interpersonal influence, the likelihood of sharing online content, or trust in misinformation?</p><p>Future research could also explore whether the effects of emotional granularity are influenced by product-related moderators, such as the hedonic versus utilitarian nature of the product.</p><p>Additionally, with potential managerial relevance, future research could investigate demographic and/or psychometric predictors of emotional granularity. Such insights would be valuable for targeting and profiling efforts, helping businesses better understand and engage with consumers based on their emotional processing tendencies.</p><p>Future research could also explore the role of granularity in positive emotions in consumer decisions, and further disentangle the effects of positive versus negative granularity on decisions. The focus of our research was on negative granularity because negative emotions are more relevant to the context of our current research, which is self-regulation of negative emotions following unpleasant service experiences. Still, in exploratory analyses we observed that granularity in positive emotions reduces the positivity of review ratings. Although not a priori predicted, we consider this observation to be consistent with the feeling-as-information theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">(Schwarz and Clore 1983)</ref>. Reviewers who explain their positive emotions more granularly are possibly more likely to consider the representativeness of these emotions to their evaluation of the business <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Pham 1998)</ref>. This may reduce the total sum impact of positive feelings on their decision because some of these positive feelings may be judged to be nonrepresentative and/or non-relevant to the decision. From considering only the main effect of granularity in positive versus negative emotions observed in our studies, one may wonder if the effect of granularity on decisions can be summed up to stating that granularity simply reduces the impact of felt emotions on decisions. While we agree that granularity reduces the direct influence of emotions on decisions by prompting individuals to analyze and contextualize their feelings, we do not believe its effects can be fully captured by this characterization. Instead, the process through which granularity operates likely depends on the motivational and functional differences between positive and negative emotions, influencing decision-making in distinct ways.</p><p>Consistently, in our results, we observed that the effect of granularity in negative versus positive emotions diverges once we consider the overall quality of the experience as a moderator, which likely captures reviewer's self-regulation motivations. Furthermore, some exploratory analysis we report in Web Appendix H shows that unlike with negative emotions, granularity in positive emotions is reduced with temporal distance. These results are consistent with previous research showing that positive and negative emotions are motivationally asymmetric <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Baumeister et al., 2001</ref>)-for example, whether individuals search for the sources of their moods depends on mood valence <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">(Schwarz and Clore 1983)</ref>. It is possible that, because the motivational direction of reappraisal differs for negative and positive emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Lazarus, 1991)</ref>, as emotions become less visceral over time, individuals engage in distinct reappraisal processes depending on the valence of the emotion. In sum, while we focused on negative emotions in our research, we believe there is much to explore regarding the divergent effects of emotional granularity across emotional valence, which we leave to future research.</p><p>Our research also contributes to the broader research on emotional granularity in psychology by developing a deep-learning-based approach that enables the measurement of the construct at the situation level. Specifically, it is the first to demonstrate that situation-level differences in describing negative emotions related to unpleasant experiences predict successful coping with these experiences. Thus, mere possession of the skills to understand emotions granularly may not be enough for one to successfully cope with unpleasant situations; it is also important to use these skills within each situation to review, process, and granularly describe one's negative emotions stemming from that situation to successfully cope with the negative feelings. Therefore, in addition to interventions intended to develop individuals' emotional skills <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Brackett et al. 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Kircanski, Lieberman, and Craske 2012)</ref>, interventions that remind or 'nudge' people to use these learned skills may also help individuals to successfully cope with negative experiences of interest. Future research may, for example, benefit from investigating the role of effort and cognitive engagement in how granularly people describe their emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Barrett and Gross 2001)</ref>. While study 2 showed that prompting participants to consider context increased their granularity in negative emotions, future research may examine whether more subtle interventions, such as emotion-labeling tasks, yield similar effects. This future research avenue connects to ongoing debates about whether granular emotion labeling is merely a secondary byproduct of how people experience emotions or whether labeling itself alters the emotional experience (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Lee et al. 2017)</ref>. In addition, because most prior evidence on the effect of emotional granularity on coping comes from behavioral lab studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Barrett et al. 2001)</ref>, the magnitude of the impact of emotional granularity in real-world settings was not empirically tested. Our research tests the effect in a real-world service context and demonstrates that this magnitude is not trivial.</p><p>Further research could also explore whether consumption-related activities, such as the act of writing reviews of businesses by prolific reviewers, have the potential to influence individuals' emotional granularity. As explained earlier, emotional granularity is conceptualized as a learned skill , which like most skills would be expected to improve with practice. Consistently, recent evidence shows that participants in experience sampling studies demonstrate greater emotional granularity in the later stages of the study than in the early stages <ref type="bibr">(Erbas et al. 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Erbas et al. 2022;</ref>, presumably because the practice of rating their various emotions several times a day helps them to learn to better consider the contextual cues associated with felt experiences. Research has also shown that classroom exercises that enable students to learn about nuanced differences between emotional labels improve students' emotion regulation abilities and academic performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Brackett, Rivers, Reyes, and Salovey 2012)</ref>. Reviewing products and services, especially among prolific reviewers, involves recalling, describing, and justifying one's negative emotions to a broader audience, and receiving feedback on these descriptions through feedback mechanisms on review platforms. Thus, it is possible that as reviewers write more reviews on a review platform, they progressively describe their negative emotions more granularly in their reviews. Some preliminary analysis we have conducted on study 3's data, supports this possibility (see Web Appendix I). However, further research is needed to investigate this effect more causally, and to investigate if the effect extends to other life domains as well.</p><p>Furthermore, the marketing field's interest in utilizing the richness of unstructured textual data to study consumer behavior has increased in the past few years <ref type="bibr">(Berger et al. 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Researchers have used various methodological approaches in these studies, including manual coding, bag of words, and topic modeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Berger and Packard 2023)</ref>. Our research is among the few in an emerging line of research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Boghrati and Berger 2023</ref>) that uses the advances in NLP and deep learning methods to study textual consumer-generated data. Methodologically, our research is novel as it acknowledges the ability of LLMs such as BERT to code the context of each word, rather than coding the global representation of the word from a training corpus, as is done by classic word embedding models such as Word2Vec and GloVe. Future research may benefit from studying the application and implications of our methodological approach in other areas of marketing (e.g., coding the context surrounding brand names instead of emotion labels, as an indicator of consumers' brand expertise in different domains).</p><p>Finally, our research has downstream implications for the emerging research on psychological targeting and profiling <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abdurahman et al. 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Bhatia and Walasek 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Matz et al. 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Matz et al. , 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Matz and Netzer 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Neumann, Tucker, and Whitefield 2019)</ref>. In our data, we observed that the effects of negative emotional granularity are parallel whether the construct is measured at the situation level or if individuals' historical negative granularity is considered. Individuals' emotional expertise ) is a significant predictor of their development (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Izard et al. 2001)</ref>, decision making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Shiv et al. 2005)</ref>, professional success (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Pirsoul et al. 2023)</ref>, and health and well-being <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">(Starr et al. 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Tomko et al. 2015</ref>). This suggests that our deep learning-based method, which measures emotional granularity unobtrusively, by merely analyzing what people say, may be applied to predict outcomes that have been shown to correlate with expertise in emotions (e.g., job candidates' success in coping with work-related stress). Future research is needed to test this effect and to understand the privacy implications of such profiling <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Matz et al. 2020)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BASED METHOD</head><p>The BERT Encoder where 15% of the words in a given sentence are randomly masked. The model is trained by having to predict the original masked words based on their surrounding context. This process forces BERT to learn rich semantic relationships between words, making its embeddings context sensitive. Thus, BERT derives the word's meaning dynamically from context. Training requires substantial computational resources and is typically performed only once on large datasets before the model is used in real-world applications.</p><p>training can be applied to unseen text without modifying BERT's internal parameters. In our work, we use a pretrained BERT model. During inference, a text is fed into the model, and BERT produces contextualized word embeddings for each word based on its learned representationsas if the model is encoding the information needed to predict each word based on the contextual words. These embeddings can then be used for downstream natural language processing tasks such as ours.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>WEB APPENDIX FIGURE 1: MASKED LANGUAGE MODELLING IN BERT</head><p>Note. During training, BERT is fed a large corpus of text and iteratively updates its internal parameters until it converges (achieves a low error rate). Through this iterative process, it learns model parameters to later produce embedding for new, previously unseen text. During inference, it uses these (now fixed) internal parameters to produce feature vectors for each word in a given text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assessing the Internal Consistency of Feature Vectors</head><p>The Cronbach's alpha statistic is traditionally used to measure the internal consistency of a set of items (e.g., survey questions) that are intended to assess the same underlying construct. It is calculated using the following formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">=  1 '1   ! " # " *</formula><p>Where:</p><p> N = Number of items In our case, we adapt it to evaluate the internal consistency of the set of feature vectors of focal labels being investigated in a given text (e.g., negative/positive emotion labels in a single review), with the goal of assessing whether these labels have been used in similar contextual meanings. The feature vectors associated with each label code the underlying contextual meaning of that label in the text; thus, each feature vector may be considered an item in our use case; with the underlying "construct" being the contextual meaning represented across these items. The more consistency is observed across these "items," (higher alpha) one can infer that they represent the same underlying meaning-i.e., they are more likely to represent the same "construct," thus, the labels are used in similar contextual meanings. To elaborate, if one were evaluating a proposed psychological scale using Cronbach's alpha, each proposed item or scale question would be represented as a column, and each participant's responses would be represented as a row. The researcher would then conduct a Cronbach's alpha to investigate the (rows). In our application, different emotion labels represent the different columns, and the feature items of each of these labels represent the rows. We conduct Cronbach's alpha to investigate the internal consistency of these emotion labels based on the variations represented in their feature items. The lower the variations, the less inconsistency exists in the meanings represented by these items, suggesting that they are used in the same contextual meaning. The figure below demonstrates our method using the example of two participants from <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Barrett (2006)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>THROUGH LANGUAGE</head><p>Note. An example of how our method captures the negative emotional granularity in a given text, using how Participants A and B from <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Barrett (2006)</ref> explained their emotional reaction to September 11, 2001. For a given text, we use a 768-dimensional feature vector (fi) to encode the context in which each negative emotion label is used. We then compute the Cronbach alpha of all these feature vectors. Negative granularity of that text is computed by subtracting the Cronbach alpha from 1. Using this method, Participant A (more granular) receives a higher granularity score than Participant B. The feature vectors of two identical emotional labels that are used in different contexts will differ from one another because their contexts are different.</p><p>The use of the Cronbach's alpha in our method is novel. A more common method in NLP research is to use cosine vector similarity scores to calculate the similarity between two vectors <ref type="bibr">(Berger et al. 2019)</ref>. As a given text often includes more than two target labels, one can adopt the cosine-similarity-based approach to capture similarity between more than two vectors by calculating the average pairwise cosine similarity (APCS) between feature vectors-i.e., calculating the cosine similarity between all possible pairs and then averaging them together.</p><p>Still, we consider the approach of using Cronbach's alpha as methodologically superior to the APCS approach because the latter approach is more error-prone: Cronbach's alpha-developed explicitly to measure internal consistency-directly considers item variance and total variance, and thus retains rich information about individual item contributions. However, APCS only considers pairwise similarity (i.e., the angle between the vectors), and thus does not account for how each item contributes to overall variance. This issue is especially problematic when working with high dimensional data and is known in the computer science literature as the curse of dimensionality (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Aggarwal, Hinneburg, and Keim 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr">Radovanovic, Nanopoulos, and</ref> Ivanovic 2010) <ref type="bibr" target="#b97">8</ref> . We believe that, while not central to the focus of the current research, one additional contribution of our work to the NLP literature is to introduce Cronbach's Alpha as a simple alternative to APCS in high-dimensional settings to mitigate the abovementioned issue by explicitly accounting for total variance rather than relying solely on pairwise similarity measures.</p><p>However, we acknowledge that more formal tests are needed to assess the relative performance of our method compared with other methods.</p><p>We also acknowledge that the properties of BERT feature vectors may violate certain statistical assumptions of Cronbach's Alpha (e.g., linearity, normal distribution). These violations can lead to under-or overestimation of reliability scores. Such issues would be a concern if we were interpreting absolute values (e.g., treating ".8 as a good score"). However, our primary use of Cronbach's Alpha is to compare relative differences in granularity rather than to interpret absolute values. Because of this, any bias in estimation due to assumption violations can manifest in two ways: (1) if the bias affects all comparisons equally, it shifts the baseline but does not impact relative differences, which are the focus of our analysis; or (2) if the bias affects comparisons differently, it introduces noise, contributing to error variance rather than systematic distortion of our conclusions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b97">8</ref> Aggarwal, Charu C., Alexander Hinneburg, and Daniel A. <ref type="bibr">Keim (2001)</ref>, "On the surprising behavior of distance metrics in high dimensional space," In International conference on database theory, pp. <ref type="bibr">420-434. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2001. Radovanovic, Milos, Alexandros Nanopoulos, and</ref><ref type="bibr">Mirjana Ivanovic (2010)</ref>  research, which employs consistency measures (i.e., ICCs) to assess the construct; and</p><p>Cronbach's alpha is used widely by researchers in consumer behavior and psychology literatures, simplifying our method for this audience. While a full comparison of methods for measuring differentiation among feature vectors is beyond the scope of the current research, we provide evidence supporting the validity of our chosen approach in the paper. We also note that, in reality, we do observe a high correlation between granularity scores if we derive them using Cronbach's alpha or APCS <ref type="bibr">(r-values ~ .7-.8)</ref>, and the conclusions from the results remain identical using the measures when there is substantial power (e.g., in our field data).</p><p>For further details into the implementation details of our method, we provide a simplified code snippet to calculate granularity scores from a given text below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PYTHON CODE SNIPPET</head><p>Essay Negative Granularity I was annoyed, frustrated and disgusted by the flight attendant's behavior. How can you tell me paying customer that I have to give up the seats that I paid for because you decided to overbook the flight? And then she said that my kids would be taken away from me and gave problems but no solutions 0.036 While watching this and putting myself in the family's shoes, i was enraged and frustrated myself. I can also imagine the anxiety felt from the uncertainty of how that family was going to get home. Watching the clip of the other passenger physically dragged off the plane also made me mad and upset. 0.047 I felt annoyed and frustrated at the delta workers on how they were handling the situation. But also feeling sympathetic and also distraught for the family as well. Watching that video made me upset at the entire situation as a whole from how delta handled it due to the fact that they had overbooked 0.052 I felt annoyed and confused on why these passengers had to give up their seats to sit other passengers. Like on what priority do these people have that they can take their seats on the plane. The emotions I had from watching this video is frustrated and upset. 0.060 I experienced anger and disgust due to the situation the consumers had to go through. II also felt fear after threats were put in place towards the consumers. I also felt sadness for the situation in which the consumers were put through. 0.072 I was very disgusted by the actions of Delta and had I been in these people's situation I would never fly with Delta again. I think it is ridiculous why the family could be kicked off and the flight attendants were incredibly rude even as the father stayed relatively calm for the situation he was in 0.258 I was upset for the family and the children having to leave the plane. There was a sense of unfairness, just because Delta oversold the flight they had to be kicked off. I worried for their teenage son who they mentioned left by himself on an earlier flight.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>0.260</head><p>I found myself getting increasingly more mad as the situation escalated. The flight attendant had no right to talk to the passenger that way and it seemed that she had no idea what she was talking about. It was also frustrating to see only one attendant address them and not have some sort of manager 0.368 While watching this video, I experienced some frustration, particularly because I have faced a similar position before. My flight was cancelled very late at night, right after I arrived at the terminal gate, and the airline told us we were on our own. I also felt pity for the family.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>0.372</head><p>Disappointed to see how the family was treated with a lack of gentleness. Watching that incident put me in a defensive position as I was imagining myself being treated that way. As a regular passenger, I was asking myself how come the company did not have any other good alternative for the family.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>0.422</head><p>All I know is that if I was in his position I would have never given my seat up. They would've had to drag me off the plane like that other guy. It's ridiculous that they overbooked the flight and he has to suffer the consequences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>0.466</head><p>I was getting really annoyed at how the flight attendant was talking to the dad who was just worried for the safety of his children. It also annoyed me how no one else stepped in to help them out. I just do not understand what compelled the flight attendant to say those things without any emotion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>0.540</head><p>Note. Examples of participant essays from study 2. As shown, as participants use emotion labels more distinctly in the essays (from top to bottom of the table), their negative granularity scores increase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fictitious Restaurant Experience</head><p>Imagine the following restaurant experience: You arrive after battling heavy traffic and struggle to find parking. Rain begins just as you rush inside, where the foyer is packed with people attending a big local event. Despite the host's friendly welcome, the busy waiting area feels tense. Once seated, the warm dcor hints at a relaxing meal-until a nearby birthday party erupts with cheers every few minutes. Your server, juggling multiple tables, apologizes for the delay, but the food is what you had expected. However, the crowded atmosphere, constant phone calls at the host stand, and the storm outside overshadow your overall enjoyment. You skip dessert to head home early.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>WEB APPENDIX C: AUXILIARY STUDY 1</head><p>The purpose of auxiliary study 1 was to explore whether the experience-sampling-based measure of granularity in negative emotions used in study 1 predicts individuals' self-reported coping and emotional self-regulation abilities. We recruited 502 participants from CloudResearch (MAge = 43.3, SD = 13.4, 47% female) and first measured their experience-sampling-based granularity in negative emotions identically to how it was measured in study 1. We then asked participants to self-report their general coping and emotional self-regulation abilities using five items ranging from 1 = strongly disagree to 5 = Strongly agree: "I feel confident and composed in high-pressure situations"; "I am able to effectively control and reduce my stress and anxiety levels before and during stressful events"; "I can stay focused and maintain my composure when unexpected challenges arise"; "I am able to remain calm before and after stressful events"; "I am skilled at managing my emotions and maintaining a positive attitude when I encounter challenging situations" (a = .94). As expected, we observed a correlation between the two measures (r = .111, p = .013). This result is consistent with previous research on emotional granularity which has shown that granularity in negative emotions is associated with coping and emotion regulation abilities. The results also support study 1's stimuli for measuring trait-level granularity in negative emotions using experience sampling.</p><p>The purpose of auxiliary study 2 was to explore whether participants' granularity in describing their negative emotions from an unpleasant service experience is associated with their self-reported coping and emotional self-regulation abilities. We recruited 200 participants from Prolific (MAge = 43.3, SD = 13.4, 47% female). Participants were first asked to imagine going through the same restaurant experience as the one in used in study 1. We then asked them to describe the negative emotions they would have in such a situation in about 50 words. We then asked participants to self-report their general coping and emotional self-regulation abilities using five items identical to auxiliary study 1 (a = .93). We calculated the negative granularity scores of participants' essays. Participants' granularity in describing their negative emotions were associated with their self-reported emotion regulation abilities (r = .169, p = .022), which supports our arguments that granularity in negative emotions, measured through textual descriptions using our method, is associated with coping and emotion regulation abilities. Furthermore, to dissociate our construct from extremity of negative emotions, focus on negative emotions (negative "emotionality"), and emotional certainty, we calculated these variables from participants' essays using The Lexical Suite. First, these variables were not correlated with granularity in negative emotions expressed in the essays (p-values &gt; .410).</p><p>Second, none of these additional variables calculated through The Lexical Suite were associated with participants' self-reported emotion regulation abilities (p-values &gt; .135). Note. Except for temporal distance  experience quality and unique positive labels in Model 2.3.A all p-values are significant below the .0001 level. The Lexical Suite produces missing values for the computed variables if the focal text does not include the terms in its dictionary. Treating these observations as missing values in the regression, would effectively limit our regression analysis to the labels included in The Lexical Suite dictionary. To remedy this issue, we use imputation: if a Negative Emotion Extremity, Certainty, or Negative Emotion "Emotionality" score is a missing value, we impute it with the average score of that hotel on the variable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rating</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EMOTIONS (STUDY 3)</head><p>In study 3, we also computed a measure of reviewer's reviewing history at the time of writing each review by counting the number of reviews that the individual had written prior to the focal review. For model estimation, this variable was log-transformed.</p><p>We conducted a multi-level regression (see <ref type="table">Table below</ref>) to predict the granularity with which negative emotions are described in a review, with the fixed effects of the reviewer's review history (at the time of authoring that review), perceived-experience-quality, and their interaction, while controlling for the fixed effects of positive granularity, positive granularity  perceived-experience-quality interaction, linguistic precision, number of unique negative emotion labels, number of unique positive emotion labels, and the word count of the review. We also included the reviewer random intercept in the model. We observed a significant effect of reviewing history on granularity in negative emotions, showing that as reviewers wrote more reviews, they progressively described their negative emotions more granularly in their reviews (b = .002, S.E. = .00, t = 7.22, p = .000, 95% CI = [.0014, .0026]). To explore downstream consequences of this increase in negative granularity on review ratings, we conducted another multi-level regression, predicting review rating with the fixed effects of reviewing history, perceived experience quality, and their interaction, while controlling for the fixed effects of positive granularity, positive granularity  perceived-experience-quality interaction, linguistic precision, number of unique negative emotion labels, number of unique positive emotion labels, and the word count of the review. We also included the reviewer random intercept in the model.</p><p>We observed a significant effect of reviewing history on ratings, showing that as reviewers wrote more reviews, they progressively provided more positive ratings (b = .09, S.E. =.0004, t = 207.87, p = .000, 95% CI = [.089, .091]). We observed a significant reviewing history  perceived-experience-quality interaction effect as well (b =-.003, S.E. =.0003, t = -10.41, p = .000, 95% CI = [.0036, .0024). The association between reviewing history and ratings was somewhat stronger when perceived-experience-quality was negative (M-SD; b = .09, S.E. = .00, t = 177.52, p = .000 than when it was positive (M+SD; b = .08, S.E. = .00, t = 172.71, p = .000).</p><p>These results are consistent with previous research which has shown that negative granularity is a learned skill: as reviewers progressively wrote more reviews, their negative granularity increased, which may contribute to their progressively more positive ratings as they wrote reviews. Note. All p-values are significant below the .0001 level.</p><p>From these results, one may wonder if reviewing history similarly influences the granularity with which positive emotions are described. As a further exploratory analysis, we also conducted another multi-level regression to predict the granularity with which positive emotions are described in a review, with the fixed effects of the reviewer's review history (at the time of authoring that review), perceived-experience-quality, and their interaction, while controlling for the fixed effects of negative granularity, negative granularity  perceivedexperience-quality interaction, linguistic precision, number of unique negative emotion labels, number of unique positive emotion labels, and the word count of the review. We also included the reviewer random intercept in the model. Interestingly, we did not observe an effect of reviewing history on how granularly positive emotions are describe (t = 1.497, p = .134).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>positive ratings in the focal review (b = .02, S.E. = 0.001, t = 27.29, p = .000, 95% CI = [.018, .022]). Importantly, as expected, this effect was moderated by the quality of the experience described in the review (b = -.04, S.E. = 0.0003, t = -125.71, p = .000, 95% CI = [ -0.040, -0.039]): again, we observed a positive association between a reviewer's historical negative granularity and ratings if the focal review described a negative experience (b = .05, S.E.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>regulation reduced ratings (b = -.26, S.E. = .10, t = -2.60, p = .009, 95% CI = [-0.460, -0.064]). Granularity in negative emotions was associated with more positive ratings (b = 1.64, S.E. = .59, t = 2.79, p = .006, 95% CI = [0.483, 2.80]). However, this effect was moderated by condition (b = -1.81, S.E. = .86, t = -2.15, p = .032, 95% CI = [-3.483, -0.154]). The association between granularity in negative emotions and positivity of ratings, which was observed in the control condition (b = 1.64, S.E. = .59, t = 2.79, p = .006, 95% CI = [0.483, 2.80]), was not significant in the avoid-regulation condition (b = -.176, S.E. = .61, t = -.29, p = .772).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, Avnet, Pham, Stephen 2012; Cohen, Pham, and Andrade 2018; Chang and Hung 2018; Faraji-Rad and Pham 2017;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>of the total score (sum of all items)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>"Hubs in space: Popular nearest neighbors in high-dimensional data" Journal of Machine Learning Research, 11, Sept (2010): 2487-2531.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>TABLE 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>EXAMPLE OF MEASURING EMOTIONAL GRANULARITY THROUGH LANGUAGE</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Example 1</cell><cell>Example 2</cell><cell>Example 3</cell></row><row><cell>Sentence 1</cell><cell>I had to stand in line, which made me feel uncomfortable.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Sentence 2</cell><cell>I had to stand in line carrying my sick child, which made me feel irritated.</cell><cell>I had to stand in line carrying my sick child, which made me feel irritated.</cell><cell>I had to stand in line, which made me feel irritated.</cell></row><row><cell>Differentiation Score</cell><cell>.16</cell><cell>.11</cell><cell>.11</cell></row></table><note>I had to stand in line carrying my sick child, which made me feel uncomfortable.I had to stand in line, which made me feel uncomfortable.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>TABLE RESULTS</head><label>RESULTS</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">OF MODELS 1.1 AND 1.2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Model 1.1</cell><cell></cell><cell>Model 1.2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>DV: Rating</cell><cell></cell><cell>DV: Rating</cell></row><row><cell>Fixed Effects</cell><cell>b</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>b</cell><cell>t</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>3.89</cell><cell>2277.26</cell><cell>3.94</cell><cell>2541.09</cell></row><row><cell>Negative Granularity</cell><cell>.07</cell><cell>142.72</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Historical Negative Granularity</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.02</cell><cell>27.29</cell></row><row><cell>Experience Quality</cell><cell>.34</cell><cell>591.10</cell><cell>.22</cell><cell>613.91</cell></row><row><cell>Negative Granularity  Experience Quality</cell><cell>-.14</cell><cell>-272.40</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Historical Negative Granularity  Experience Quality</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.04</cell><cell>-125.71</cell></row><row><cell>Unique Negative Labels</cell><cell>-.18</cell><cell>-246.99</cell><cell>-.33</cell><cell>-675.78</cell></row><row><cell>Unique Positive Labels</cell><cell>.29</cell><cell>336.43</cell><cell>.47</cell><cell>764.18</cell></row><row><cell>Word Count</cell><cell>-.17</cell><cell>-183.01</cell><cell>-.18</cell><cell>-238.39</cell></row><row><cell>Positive Granularity</cell><cell>-.16</cell><cell>-251.56</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Positive Granularity  Experience Quality</cell><cell>.03</cell><cell>57.62</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Historical Positive Granularity</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.04</cell><cell>-41.52</cell></row><row><cell>Historical Positive Granularity  Experience Quality</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.01</cell><cell>-29.39</cell></row><row><cell>Linguistic Precision</cell><cell>-.02</cell><cell>-18.52</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Historical Linguistic Precision</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.04</cell><cell>-46.66</cell></row><row><cell>Variance of Random Intercept</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.11</cell></row><row><cell>Number of Reviews (Reviewers)</cell><cell cols="2">7,796,024 (52,313)</cell><cell cols="2">11,206,100 (52,800)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>TABLE 3 RESULTS</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Note. Except for the effect of unique positive labels in Models 2.2 and the temporal distance  experience quality interaction effect in Model 2.2, all p-values are significant below the .0001 level.The Mediating Effect of Negative Granularity. As argued, higher granularity in describing negative emotions should enable coping when coping is relevant (i.e., when the overall experience is negative), which suggests that negative granularity should mediate the temporal distance  perceived experience quality moderation effect on review ratings. The currently available packages for testing moderated mediation have difficulty processing our data due to its large size and multi-level nature. Therefore, we wrote custom code (using R version 4.3.0, with 'lme4' and 'boot' packages) to test moderated mediation. We included rating as the outcome variable, temporal distance as the predictor variable, negative granularity as the mediator, and To test whether the effects would replicate by considering the normative experience quality score instead of the experience quality perceived by the reviewer, we conducted three additional regression models (Models 2.1.1, 2.2.1, and 2.3.1) parallel to the original models, but replacing the reviewer's perceived experience quality terms in the original models with the normative experience quality scores. The results, which are reported fully in</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">OF MODELS 2.1, 2.2, AND 2.3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Model 2.1</cell><cell cols="2">Model 2.2</cell><cell cols="2">Model 2.3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">DV: Rating</cell><cell cols="2">DV: Neg. Granularity</cell><cell cols="2">DV: Rating</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>b</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>b</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>b</cell><cell>t</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>4.04</cell><cell>291.97</cell><cell>.47</cell><cell>147.57</cell><cell>4.11</cell><cell>308.42</cell></row><row><cell>Negative Granularity</cell><cell>.12</cell><cell>76.94</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Experience Quality</cell><cell>.34</cell><cell>185.52</cell><cell>.10</cell><cell>78.36</cell><cell>.16</cell><cell>170.24</cell></row><row><cell>Negative Granularity  Experience Quality</cell><cell>-.15</cell><cell>-93.19</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Temporal Distance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.01</cell><cell>12.26</cell><cell>.03</cell><cell>40.43</cell></row><row><cell>Temporal Distance  Experience Quality</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.001</cell><cell>-1.07</cell><cell>-.03</cell><cell>-42.05</cell></row><row><cell>Unique Negative Labels</cell><cell>-.19</cell><cell>-86.47</cell><cell>-.83</cell><cell>-637.49</cell><cell>-.44</cell><cell>-325.94</cell></row><row><cell>Unique Positive Labels</cell><cell>.29</cell><cell>123.12</cell><cell>.004</cell><cell>2.26</cell><cell>.32</cell><cell>175.19</cell></row><row><cell>Word Count</cell><cell>-.16</cell><cell>-62.78</cell><cell>.26</cell><cell>142.67</cell><cell>-.12</cell><cell>-57.83</cell></row><row><cell>Positive Granularity</cell><cell>-.25</cell><cell>-126.77</cell><cell>.02</cell><cell>14.02</cell><cell>-.17</cell><cell>-148.25</cell></row><row><cell>Positive Granularity  Experience Quality</cell><cell>.05</cell><cell>33.75</cell><cell>.04</cell><cell>35.54</cell><cell>.13</cell><cell>152.28</cell></row><row><cell>Linguistic Precision</cell><cell>.13</cell><cell>69.20</cell><cell>.14</cell><cell>99.02</cell><cell>.12</cell><cell>111.62</cell></row><row><cell>Number of Reviews (Hotels)</cell><cell cols="2">746,265 (591)</cell><cell cols="2">745,470 (591)</cell><cell cols="2">1,299,629 (591)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>TABLE 4 RESULTS</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Note. Except for the effect of unique positive labels in Model 2.2.1 and also the temporal distance  normative experience quality effect in Model 2.2.1, all p-values are significant below the .0001 level. A moderated mediation analysis with 5000 bootstrap samples, which included rating as the outcome variable, temporal distance as the predictor variable, negative granularity as the mediator, normative experience quality as the moderator of the link between negative granularity and rating, and all control variables included in Models 2.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">OF MODELS 2.1.1, 2.2.1, AND 2.3.1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Model 2.1.1</cell><cell cols="2">Model 2.2.1</cell><cell cols="2">Model 2.3.1</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">DV: Rating</cell><cell cols="2">DV: Neg. Granularity</cell><cell cols="2">DV: Rating</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>b</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>b</cell><cell>t</cell><cell>b</cell><cell>t</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>4.02</cell><cell>383.58</cell><cell>.45</cell><cell>160.81</cell><cell>4.13</cell><cell>461.95</cell></row><row><cell>Negative Granularity</cell><cell>.17</cell><cell>105.46</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Normative Experience Quality</cell><cell>.16</cell><cell>20.46</cell><cell>.03</cell><cell>13.33</cell><cell>.15</cell><cell>23.50</cell></row><row><cell>Negative Granularity  Normative Experience Quality</cell><cell>-.02</cell><cell>-13.73</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Temporal Distance</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.01</cell><cell>14.44</cell><cell>.03</cell><cell>38.09</cell></row><row><cell>Temporal Distance  Normative Experience Quality</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-.001</cell><cell>-.71</cell><cell>-.01</cell><cell>-16.97</cell></row><row><cell>Unique Negative Labels</cell><cell>-.27</cell><cell>-121.36</cell><cell>-.84</cell><cell>-655.52</cell><cell>-.48</cell><cell>-358.55</cell></row><row><cell>Unique Positive Labels</cell><cell>.32</cell><cell>138.71</cell><cell>.003</cell><cell>1.92</cell><cell>.32</cell><cell>171.18</cell></row><row><cell>Word Count</cell><cell>-.17</cell><cell>-66.97</cell><cell>.26</cell><cell>145.12</cell><cell>-.09</cell><cell>-44.49</cell></row><row><cell>Positive Granularity</cell><cell>-.37</cell><cell>-227.00</cell><cell>-.04</cell><cell>-31.01</cell><cell>-.27</cell><cell>-255.87</cell></row><row><cell>Positive Granularity  Normative Experience Quality</cell><cell>.02</cell><cell>22.23</cell><cell>.01</cell><cell>11.14</cell><cell>.05</cell><cell>61.57</cell></row><row><cell>Linguistic Precision</cell><cell>.20</cell><cell>105.32</cell><cell>.16</cell><cell>121.52</cell><cell>.19</cell><cell>171.78</cell></row><row><cell>Number of Reviews (Hotels)</cell><cell cols="2">746,263 (589)</cell><cell cols="2">745,468 (589)</cell><cell cols="2">1,299,627 (589)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">1-2.3 supported moderated</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">mediation (moderated mediation index = -0.0002; 95% CI = [-0.0002 to -0.0001].</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Note. All correlations are significant below the .01 level.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Model 2.1.A</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Model 2.2.A</cell><cell>Model 2.3.A</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Negative Granularity</cell><cell>Positive Granularity</cell><cell cols="3">Experience Quality b</cell><cell cols="4">Historical Negative Granularity DV: Rating t</cell><cell cols="2">Historical Positive Granularity</cell><cell cols="2">Historical Linguistic Precision b</cell><cell cols="2">Unique Positive Labels DV: Rating</cell><cell>Unique Negative Labels t</cell><cell>Word DV: Neg. Granularity Linguistic Negative Count Precision Extremity b t</cell><cell>Negative Emotionality</cell></row><row><cell>Negative Granularity</cell><cell>0.193</cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">4.04</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">300.10</cell><cell cols="3">4.10</cell><cell>319.99</cell><cell>.47</cell><cell>153.63</cell></row><row><cell>Positive Granularity</cell><cell>-0.196</cell><cell>0.197</cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Quality Experience Negative Granularity 0.279</cell><cell>0.212</cell><cell>-0.106</cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.12</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">75.99</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Historical Experience Quality</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.31</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">170.19</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.15</cell><cell>159.89</cell><cell>.11</cell><cell>81.03</cell></row><row><cell>Negative</cell><cell>0.067</cell><cell>0.246</cell><cell>0.211</cell><cell>0.116</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Granularity Negative Granularity  Experience Quality</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">-.14</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-88.18</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Historical</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Positive Granularity Temporal Distance -0.052</cell><cell>0.174</cell><cell>0.368</cell><cell>0.067</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.52</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.03</cell><cell>38.67</cell><cell>.01</cell><cell>11.84</cell></row><row><cell>Historical</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Linguistic Temporal Distance  Experience Quality 0.002 0.166 0.294</cell><cell>0.183</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.489</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.734</cell><cell>1</cell><cell cols="2">-.03</cell><cell>-41.43</cell><cell>-.001</cell><cell>-1.18</cell></row><row><cell>Precision</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Unique Positive Unique Negative Labels 0.101</cell><cell>-0.351</cell><cell>-0.696</cell><cell cols="4">-0.061 -.19</cell><cell cols="2">-0.356</cell><cell cols="2">-83.86</cell><cell>-0.467</cell><cell cols="3">-0.421 -.42</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>-314.25</cell><cell>-.83</cell><cell>-635.61</cell></row><row><cell>Labels</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Unique Unique Positive Labels</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.28</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">121.83</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.32</cell><cell>172.54</cell><cell>.004</cell><cell>2.44</cell></row><row><cell>Negative</cell><cell>-0.215</cell><cell>-0.721</cell><cell>-0.333</cell><cell>-0.28</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.36</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.331</cell><cell cols="2">-0.347</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.635</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Labels</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Word Count</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">-.16</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-63.61</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-.12</cell><cell>-59.64</cell><cell>.26</cell><cell>141.60</cell></row><row><cell>Word Count</cell><cell>-0.058</cell><cell>-0.466</cell><cell>-0.506</cell><cell cols="2">-0.204</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-0.394</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.439</cell><cell cols="2">-0.442</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.862</cell><cell>0.788</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Precision Linguistic Positive Granularity 0.012</cell><cell>0.308</cell><cell>0.454</cell><cell>0.263</cell><cell cols="3">-.24</cell><cell>0.258</cell><cell cols="4">0.397 -124.64</cell><cell cols="3">0.505 -.16</cell><cell>-0.558</cell><cell>-0.475 -144.31</cell><cell>-0.605</cell><cell>.02</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>16.82</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Negative Extremity Positive Granularity  Experience Quality -0.132 -0.04 0.059</cell><cell cols="2">-0.191</cell><cell cols="2">.05</cell><cell>-0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">32.47</cell><cell>0.045</cell><cell cols="3">0.035 .12</cell><cell>-0.022</cell><cell>0.076 148.06</cell><cell>0.022</cell><cell>.04</cell><cell>0.006</cell><cell>1 37.71</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Negative Emotionality Linguistic Precision -0.062</cell><cell>-0.032</cell><cell>0.022</cell><cell cols="2">-0.199</cell><cell cols="2">.13</cell><cell cols="2">-0.009</cell><cell cols="2">70.65</cell><cell>0.025</cell><cell cols="3">0.017 .12</cell><cell>0.012</cell><cell>0.082 111.00</cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell>.14</cell><cell>-0.009</cell><cell>0.598 97.26</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Certainty</cell><cell>0.157</cell><cell>0.047</cell><cell>-0.037</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.052</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.009</cell><cell cols="2">0.046</cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.015</cell><cell>-0.077</cell><cell>-0.041</cell><cell>0.043</cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.023</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Negative Emotion Extremity</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">-.11</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-95.08</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">-.11</cell><cell>-111.67</cell><cell>-.02</cell><cell>-25.73</cell></row><row><cell>Certainty</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.06</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">51.84</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.07</cell><cell>88.84</cell><cell>.02</cell><cell>18.18</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Negative Emotion "Emotionality"</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.02</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">21.29</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">.02</cell><cell>23.93</cell><cell>.04</cell><cell>42.69</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Number of Reviews (Hotels)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="5">746,261 (588)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">1,299,623 (588)</cell><cell>745,466 (588)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Our use of Cronbach's alpha is a novel approach compared to traditional methods in NLP research, such as relying on cosine similarities. While other approaches could also be potentially used, we chose Cronbach's alpha because: (a) it aligns with the tradition in emotional granularity research, which employs consistency measures (i.e., ICCs) to assess the construct; (b) it is widely used and intuitive for psychology and consumer behavior researchers; and (c) it is explicitly designed to measure internal consistency and accounts for total variance of items, reducing the need for additional normalization steps, which simplifies the method. Additional discussions on our method, including the use of Cronbach's alpha, are provided in Web Appendix A.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">We have conducted two auxiliary studies (see Web Appendixes C and D for details) to directly test the relationship between granularity in negative emotions and coping/emotion-regulation abilities. In auxiliary study 1, we observed that individuals' experience-sampling-based granularity in negative emotions, measured similarly to study 1, is associated with their self-reported emotion-regulation abilities. In auxiliary study 2, we observed that individuals' deep-learning-based negative emotional granularity scores, also measured similarly to study 1, is associated with their self-reported emotion-regulation abilities.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">One may wonder whether the lack of correlation between the computed negative granularity scores from review text and the variables computed using The Lexical Suite is because different glossaries are used to compute them. To remedy this concern, we computed the negative granularity scores of the reviews using the negative labels from The Lexical Suite dictionary. Again, we did not observe significant correlations (all p-values &gt; .461).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">Differences in degrees of freedom are due to missingness in the scores computed by The Lexical Suite.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">* Correlation is significant at the 0.05 level. ** Correlation is significant at the 0.01 level.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Note. All p-values are significant below the .0001 level. The Lexical Suite produces missing values for the computed variables if the focal text does not include the terms in its dictionary. Treating these observations as missing values in the regression, would effectively limit our regression analysis to the labels included in The Lexical Suite dictionary. To remedy this issue, we use imputation: if a Negative Emotion Extremity, Certainty, or Negative Emotion "Emotionality" score is a missing value, we impute it with the average score of that reviewer on the variable. Note. Except for Unique Negative Labels, all p-values are significant below the .0001 level.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>POSITIVE EMOTIONS (STUDY 6)</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A deep learning approach to personality assessment: Generalizing across items and expanding the reach of survey-based research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suhaib</forename><surname>Abdurahman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huy</forename><surname>Vu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wanling</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sudeep</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The platform shapes the message: How website design affects abstraction and valence of online consumer reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goele</forename><surname>Aerts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Smits</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Peeter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Verlegh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Support Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="112" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-domain effects of guilt on desire for selfimprovement products</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Allard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="401" to="419" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumers&apos; trust in feelings as information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tamar</forename><surname>Avnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><forename type="middle">Tuan</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Stephen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="720" to="735" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feelings or words? Understanding the content in self-report ratings of experienced emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="266" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Solving the emotion paradox: Categorization and the experience of emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How emotions are made: The secret life of the brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<pubPlace>Houghton Mifflin Harcourt</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion representation and regulation: A process model of emotional intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Emotions: Current Issues and Future Directions</title>
		<editor>T. Mayne and G. Bonnano</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="286" to="310" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowing what you&apos;re feeling and knowing what to do about it: Mapping the relation between emotion differentiation and emotion regulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tamlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Benvenuto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition and Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="713" to="724" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bad is Stronger than Good</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baumeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><surname>Bratslavsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catrin</forename><surname>Finkenauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Vohs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of General Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="370" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wisdom from words: The psychology of consumer language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonah</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grant</forename><surname>Packard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Consumer Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonah</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashlee</forename><surname>Humphreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephan</forename><surname>Ludwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Moe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oded</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uniting the tribes: Using text for marketing insight</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Schweidel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting implicit attitudes with natural language data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sudeep</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lukasz</forename><surname>Walasek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">120</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantifying cultural change: Gender bias in music</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reihane</forename><surname>Boghrati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonah</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">152</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2591" to="2602" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhancing academic performance and social and emotional competence with the RULER feeling words curriculum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Brackett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rivers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Reyes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Salovey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Learning and Individual Differences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="218" to="224" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Morality in High Definition: Emotion Differentiation Calibrates the Influence of Incidental Disgust on Moral Judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cameron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Keith</forename><surname>Daryl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Doris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="719" to="725" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feeling Love and Doing More for Distant Others: Specific Positive Emotions Differentially Affect Prosocial Consumption</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cavanaugh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Frances</forename><surname>Bettman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Luce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="657" to="673" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mirror, Mirror on the Retail Wall: Self-focused Attention Promotes Reliance on Feelings in Consumer Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iris</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="586" to="599" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affect as a decision-making system of the present</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Michel Tuan Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of word of mouth on sales: Online book reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judith</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Chevalier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dina</forename><surname>Mayzlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The nature and role of affect in consumer behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduardo</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Michel Tuan Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Andrade</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Consumer Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="306" to="357" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bert: Pre-training of deep bidirectional transformers for language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming-Wei</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenton</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1810.04805</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coping: A multidimensional, hierarchical framework of responses to stressful consumption episodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Duhachek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coping repertoire: Integrating a new conceptualization of coping with transactional theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Duhachek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katie</forename><surname>Kelting</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="485" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The nature of emotion: Fundamental questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Ekman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Richard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yasemin</forename><surname>Erbas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eva</forename><surname>Ceulemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elise</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kalokerinos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marlies</forename><surname>Houben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Koval</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Madeline</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why I don&apos;t always know what I&apos;m feeling: The role of stress in within-person fluctuations in emotion differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Pe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kuppens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">179</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Momentary Emotion Differentiation: The derivation and validation of a framework to study within-person fluctuations in emotion differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Erbas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elise</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Yasemin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Kalokerinos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kuppens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eva</forename><surname>Sjoerd Van Halem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ceulemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="700" to="716" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Banking Happiness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Faraji-Rad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leonard</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="336" to="358" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncertainty increases the reliance on affect in decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Faraji-Rad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><forename type="middle">Tuan</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How online product reviews affect retail sales: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristopher</forename><surname>Floyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Freling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saad</forename><surname>Alhoqail</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hyun</forename><forename type="middle">Young</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Traci</forename><surname>Freling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Retailing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="249" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Online Reviews: The Customer Reference That Never Sleeps. 2023(28/11/2023)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Forbes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2022/08/16/online-reviews-the-customer-reference-that-never-sleeps/?sh=3b0966852921" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Role of Positive Emotions in Positive Psychology: The Broaden-and-Build Theory of Positive Emotions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Fredrickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">218</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Popularity effect in user-generated content: evidence from online product reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paulo</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Goes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingfeng</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ching-Man Au</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Systems Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Expertise in Emotion: A Scoping Review and Unifying Framework for Individual Differences in the Mental Representation of Emotional Experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katie</forename><surname>Hoemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catie</forename><surname>Nielson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashley</forename><surname>Yuen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Gurera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karen</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Quigley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">Feldman</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1159" to="1183" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional granularity increases over the course of experience sampling: Methodological and individual factors influence how much</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katie</forename><surname>Hoemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">Feldman</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karen</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Quigley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of multiple psychological distances on construal and consumer evaluation: A field study of online reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ni</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><surname>Burtch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yili</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evan</forename><surname>Polman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="482" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion knowledge as a predictor of social behavior and academic competence in children at risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carroll</forename><surname>Izard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Fine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allison</forename><surname>Mostow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Ackerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Youngstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Magical thinking and consumer coping</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>St</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jay</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yannik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shirley</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Handelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="632" to="649" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion differentiation as resilience against excessive alcohol use: An ecological momentary assessment in underage social drinkers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kashdan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">Lorraine</forename><surname>Patty Ferssizidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Muraven</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1341" to="1347" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unpacking emotion differentiation: Transforming unpleasant experience by perceiving distinctions in negativity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kashdan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lisa Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mcknight</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Remembering the Details: Effects of Emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kensinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feelings into words: Contributions of language to exposure therapy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katharina</forename><surname>Kircanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lieberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Craske</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1086" to="1091" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The complexity of individual emotional lives: A within-subject analysis of affect structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Larsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cutler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Social and Clinical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Emotion and Adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lazarus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional granularity effects on eventrelated brain potentials during affective picture processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ja</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kristen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lindquist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Big Data as a window into consumers&apos; psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Matz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oded</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Money buys happiness when spending fits our personality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Matz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Joe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Gladstone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Stillwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="715" to="725" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological targeting as an effective approach to digital mass persuasion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Matz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Kosinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gideon</forename><surname>Nave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stillwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12714" to="12719" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy in the age of psychological targeting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Matz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ruth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Appel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kosinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cultural variations in emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Batja</forename><surname>Mesquita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nico</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Frijda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="204" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1301.3781</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The value of social dynamics in online product ratings forums</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Moe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Trusov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="456" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontiers: How effective is third-party consumer profiling? Evidence from field studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nico</forename><surname>Neumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Whitfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="918" to="926" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The emergence and evolution of consumer language research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grant</forename><surname>Packard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonah</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic inquiry and word count: LIWC</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roger</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Booth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mahway</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GloVe: Global Vectors for Word Representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representativeness, relevance, and the use of feelings in decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="144" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affect as an Ordinal System of Utility Assessment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Faraji-Rad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Toubia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leonard</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">131</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional intelligence and career-related outcomes: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Pirsoul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Parmentier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurent</forename><surname>Sovet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frdric</forename><surname>Nils</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Resource Management Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online reputation management: Estimating the impact of management responses on consumer reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Davide</forename><surname>Proserpio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgios</forename><surname>Zervas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="665" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emodiversity and the emotional ecosystem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordi</forename><surname>Quoidbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">June</forename><surname>Gruber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moira</forename><surname>Mikolajczak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexsandr</forename><surname>Kogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilios</forename><surname>Kotsou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">All negative moods are not equal: Motivational influences of anxiety and sadness on decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rajagopal</forename><surname>Raghunathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><forename type="middle">Tuan</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informational properties of anxiety and sadness, and displaced coping</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rajagopal</forename><surname>Raghunathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><forename type="middle">Tuan</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Corfman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="596" to="601" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Lexical Suite: Adjective Use as a Means of Assessing and Distinguishing Attitude Valence, Extremity, and Emotionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rocklage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Fazio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attitudes based on feelings: Fixed or fleeting?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rocklage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Luttrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="364" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Evaluative Lexicon 2.0: The measurement of emotionality, extremity, and valence in language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rocklage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Derek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Loran</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Rucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nordgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1327" to="1344" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotionally Numb: Expertise Dulls Consumer Experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rocklage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Derek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Loran</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Rucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nordgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="373" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond Sentiment: The Value and Measurement of Consumer Certainty in Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rocklage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharlene</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Derek</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Loran</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Nordgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="870" to="888" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Core Affect, Prototypical Emotional Episodes, and Other Things Called Emotion: Dissecting the Elephant</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="805" to="819" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Polarity of Online Reviews: Prevalence, Drivers and Implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Verena</forename><surname>Schoenmueller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oded</forename><surname>Netzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Stahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="853" to="877" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mood, Misattribution, and Judgments of Well-Being: Informative and Directive Functions of Affective States</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerald</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Clore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">513</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investment behavior and the negative side of emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baba</forename><surname>Shiv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Bechara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanna</forename><surname>Damasio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonio</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Damasio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="439" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social Influence Effects in Online Product Ratings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shrihari</forename><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raji</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="70" to="88" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The perils of murky emotions: Emotion differentiation moderates the prospective relationship between naturalistic stress exposure and adolescent depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Starr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Hershenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zoey</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Shaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">Irina</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angela</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Santee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">927</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating the effect of status changes in review platforms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tamaddoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Seenivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Pallant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Skiera</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Research in Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="209" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional Nuance: Examining Positive Emotional Granularity and Well-Being</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tse</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Louise</forename><surname>Yen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michele</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tugade</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychological meaning of words: LIWC and computerized text analysis methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yla</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Tausczik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Language and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Tomko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hayley</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Pronove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Whitney</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Treloar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Marika</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Undifferentiated negative affect and impulsivity in borderline personality and depressive disorders: A momentary perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phillip</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Solhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Trull</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Abnormal Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">740</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Effect of Individual Online Reviews on Purchase Likelihood</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasad</forename><surname>Vana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anja</forename><surname>Lambrecht</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="708" to="730" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Impact of Negative Reviews on Online Search and Purchase Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marton</forename><surname>Varga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paulo</forename><surname>Albuquerque</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Economic Value of Online Reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chunhua</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hai</forename><surname>Che</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Tat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xianghua</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="739" to="754" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A matter of reevaluation: Incentivizing users to contribute reviews in online platforms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingyue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuan</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel Dajun</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TABLE OF CONTENTS Web Appendix A: Details and Discussions of the Deep-Learning-Based Method Web Appendix B: Study 1 Stimuli Web Appendix C: Auxiliary Study</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="158" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Decision Support Systems</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Web Appendix D: Auxiliary Study</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Web Appendix E: Correlation of Variables in Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Web Appendix F: Robustness Checks for Study 3</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Web Appendix G: Robustness Checks for Study 6</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Effect of Temporal Distance on Granularity in Positive Emotions</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Study 6</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Web Appendix I: Reviewing History and Granularity in Negative Emotions</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Study 3</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Experience Sampling Scenarios 1. You and another customer both provide detailed feedback to a company about their product. However, only the other customer is publicly thanked and rewarded by the brand on social media</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">You register for an exclusive product launch event or promotion, but the company cancels it at the last minute without offering an explanation</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">After submitting a complaint about a negative shopping experience, the company unexpectedly sends you a gift card as an apology</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">You leave a review about a product explaining its shortcomings, but the company publicly responds dismissively, blaming you for misusing it</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">You and your friends organize a group purchase for a bulk discount</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>One friend forgets to pay their share. leaving you to cover the cost</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A customer testimonial is highlighted by the company, and you realize their story is almost identical to yours</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>but your contribution wasn&apos;t acknowledged</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A service provider who previously gave you a poor experience reaches out with a heartfelt apology and a promise to do better</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">You order a product for an important event, but it arrives late due to unforeseen shipping issues, leaving you scrambling for alternatives</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">You post a review about a product on the company&apos;s social media page</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>but you accidentally include incorrect details about the product. Another customer points out the mistake publicly in the comments, and others join in laughing at your error</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
