<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">DataPruebas: An Online Platform for Data Collection</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gustavo</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Juantorena</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratorio de Inteligencia Artificial Aplicada</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Instituto de Ciencias de la Computación</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Universidad de Buenos Aires -CONICET</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lara</forename><surname>Gauder</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratorio de Inteligencia Artificial Aplicada</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Instituto de Ciencias de la Computación</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Universidad de Buenos Aires -CONICET</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pablo</forename><surname>Laciana</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Instituto de Ciencias de la Computación</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Universidad de Buenos Aires -CONICET</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luciana</forename><surname>Ferrer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratorio de Inteligencia Artificial Aplicada</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Instituto de Ciencias de la Computación</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Universidad de Buenos Aires -CONICET</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juan</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kamienkowski</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratorio de Inteligencia Artificial Aplicada</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Instituto de Ciencias de la Computación</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Universidad de Buenos Aires -CONICET</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Departamento de Computación</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Buenos Aires</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">FCEyN-FI</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>UBA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">DataPruebas: An Online Platform for Data Collection</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>online cognitive experiments</term>
					<term>dataset collection</term>
					<term>community research</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We introduce DataPruebas, a user-friendly platform developed in Spanish to streamline scientific data collection. The platform leverages public interest in contributing to scientific research. Participants can register, browse, and participate in various experiments either online with instant access or asynchronously through a flexible scheduling system. For researchers, the platform simplifies the process of uploading experimental protocols and specifying participant criteria based on demographic variables such as age, place of birth, and other relevant characteristics. It is compatible with multiple open-source experiment frameworks, including PsychoPy, jsPsych, and lab.js, allowing researchers to integrate existing paradigms with minimal adaptation. This flexibility makes it easy to migrate previously developed experiments or design new ones using familiar tools. The platform has already been used to collect data on decision-making, attention, memory, and survey-based studies, among others. In addition to supporting traditional behavioral experiments, DataPruebas is designed to facilitate the creation of high-quality datasets for machine learning research. It enables the collection of diverse data modalities, including audio recordings, webcam-based eye tracking, and mouse trajectories, allowing researchers to build multimodal datasets tailored to real-world applications.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Reliable data acquisition plays a fundamental role in research across disciplines such as cognitive science and artificial intelligence. This potential was demonstrated by the pioneering work of Luis von Ahn, creator of reCAPTCHA <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(von Ahn et al., 2008)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">Duolingo (von Ahn, 2013)</ref>, and the concept of games with a purpose <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Ahn, 2006)</ref>. His research showed how mass online participation can be harnessed to solve computational problems and collect meaningful data at scale.</p><p>Crowdsourcing has emerged as a powerful model for collecting scientific data at scale, enabling researchers to reach diverse participant pools through the Internet. Several platforms exist, each with different strengths and limitations. In terms of cognitive experiments: Pavlovia <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bridges et al., 2020)</ref> supports PsychoPy-based studies but charges per participant and manages data externally. Gorilla <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Anwyl-Irvine et al., 2020)</ref> offers an intuitive experiment builder with integrated hosting, though it requires a paid subscription. Cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Vidal, 2020)</ref> supports jsPsych-based studies with flexibility, though it lacks built-in participant management. Free options like JATOS <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Lange et al., 2015)</ref> and IBEX <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Schwarz &amp; Zehr, 2021)</ref> also exist: JATOS offers full control but requires self-hosting and infrastructure management, while IBEX avoids self-hosting but is limited by a custom mini-language that restricts flexibility and modern integration. On the other hand, platforms such as Amazon Mechanical Turk (Amazon Web Services, Inc.) and Scale AI (Scale AI, Inc.) are widely used for large-scale data annotation tasks, particularly in machine learning. They are effective at distributing microtasks, such as image labeling, audio transcription, or text classification, to a broad crowd of workers. However, these platforms come with important limitations: they offer little to no experimental control, lack long-term participant tracking, and provide only basic or limited demographic filtering.</p><p>While these tools have enabled significant progress in web-based research, many remain costly or technically demanding and are primarily designed for English-speaking participants, further limiting accessibility and inclusivity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2</head><p>What is DataPruebas?</p><p>We developed DataPruebas (https://datapruebas.org/) as an open-access platform to streamline the process of scientific data collection. Designed specifically for the Spanish-speaking community and using modern web stack (Django 1 for backend and React 2 for frontend), the platform provides an accessible and intuitive interface for participants to register, explore available studies, and contribute to ongoing research.</p><p>DataPruebas supports two different modes of participation: asynchronous and synchronous experiments. In the former, participants complete tasks on their own schedule, using different devices with Internet access. This format is particularly effective for reaching large and diverse samples, as it eliminates the need for real-time coordination. In contrast, synchronous experiments are scheduled sessions that involve real-time interaction between the participant and the researcher, often using video conferencing tools or built-in communication features, but also for in-person studies. This approach is more appropriate for tasks that require supervision, or immediate feedback. By offering both modes, the platform accommodates a wide range of experimental designs while making participation more accessible.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Platform interfaces</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Participant's view</head><p>Participants access the platform by creating an account using email and password and completing a brief profile that includes key demographic variables such as birthdate, gender, place of birth and residence, and education level. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> illustrates the application's login interface. The design includes an explanatory section outlining the purpose of participating in DataPruebas, along with a user-friendly layout to encourage engagement.</p><p>The registration information helps match participants with relevant studies while preserving anonymity and ensuring ethical data handling. After the subject participates in an experiment the researchers can access participant information through an interface that displays only demographic data, excluding any personally identifiable information.</p><p>Once registered, participants can browse available experiments and filter them based on participation mode (asynchronous, completed anytime, or synchronous, requiring live interaction with a researcher). For synchronous experiments, the platform includes a calendar view that allows participants to schedule an appointment at their convenience. <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref>. On the left, we can observe DataPruebas's login screen, while on the right is the form that participants must complete when accessing the site for the first time. This allows us to access the demographic data of the participant.</p><p>To join an asynchronous study, participants select an experiment and begin the task immediately. Depending on the study's design, they may pause and return later to complete it at their convenience. In the case of synchronous studies, participation requires selecting an available time slot in advance through the platform's calendar interface. Participants must await researcher's approval confirming their acceptance for the requested date. Upon approval, they will receive the necessary details to participate in the experiment on the scheduled date.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Researcher's view</head><p>General. For asynchronous experiments, researchers can develop their tasks using standard web technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, or opt for specialized frameworks such as jsPsych (de Leeuw, 2015), lab.js <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Henninger et al., 2022)</ref>, or PsychoPy/PsychoJS <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Peirce et al., 2019)</ref>. The latter provides a particularly accessible entry point, allowing researchers with limited coding experience to design experiments using the PsychoPy graphical interface and have them automatically compiled into JavaScript. Since these frameworks were primarily designed to be hosted on platforms like Pavlovia, we have made a concerted effort to create easy-to-follow documentation to help researchers adapt their experiments for use with our API, whether hosted on their servers or other external platforms. Researchers can choose to upload their experiments directly to our servers or simply provide an external URL, using the participant base and built-in features of DataPruebas (such as recruitment filters, scheduling, and data tracking) without having to fully migrate their infrastructure.</p><p>Synchronous studies follow a slightly different process. Researchers need to describe their experiment and define the blocks of time available for scheduling. The platform allows them to manage appointments through a built-in calendar interface and efficiently track participant sessions.</p><p>All experiments, regardless of modality, must go through a review and approval process from the administrators before being published. This ensures compliance with ethical standards and helps maintain the quality and reliability offered to participants.</p><p>Experiment setup. Researchers can create and configure experiments by entering metadata (title, description), uploading materials (e.g., images, consent forms), and configuring parameters such as duration, repeatability, technical requirements (e.g., webcam), and eligibility criteria (e.g., age, gender, location). Participant activity is tracked in real time through an execution panel. Raw session data (timestamps, responses, metadata) can be exported in formats like JSON or ZIP for analysis and reproducibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Current limitations and future work</head><p>While DataPruebas offers a flexible infrastructure for online experimentation and data collection, there are still some important limitations. First, the platform is centrally hosted and maintained by our team, and researchers have the possibility of storing data outside our servers (for example, by modifying the experiment code to send data to a custom endpoint). However, this process is not yet supported through our official API, which limits the ease of integration with external databases or institutional infrastructures. Making this feature more accessible is a key goal for future development.</p><p>Second, experiment creation currently relies on programming knowledge or external tools. DataPruebas does not yet include a built-in visual interface for experiment design, which can present a barrier for researchers without technical backgrounds. However, this limitation can be partially addressed by using the PsychoPy Builder, which allows the design of experiments graphically.</p><p>Looking ahead, we plan to enhance the participant experience by introducing gamification elements, such as points based on task completion, time contributed to research and performance. These features will be used to build leaderboards and offer participants a sense of progress and recognition for their contributions to science.</p><p>Finally, while the platform is already freely available, we plan to release it as open-source software to enable broader use, adaptation, and self-hosting. This step will support transparency, encourage collaboration, and allow research communities to take ownership of the infrastructure in their local or institutional contexts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>DataPruebas represents more than just a technical solution, it is a growing community of researchers and participants committed to advancing science through accessible, scalable, and ethical data collection. With several experiments running and a steadily increasing number of registered participants, the platform already has a diverse range of studies and contributes to creating high-quality datasets.</p><p>We believe that local development is crucial. Building open-source, non-profit infrastructure in Latin America empowers researchers in underrepresented regions, reduces dependency on costly external tools, and helps foster a sustainable research ecosystem rooted in the needs and realities of our communities. This also entails the challenge of continuously maintaining and enhancing these tools.</p><p>The platform is designed with flexibility in mind: it supports popular frameworks, allows for both internal and external hosting, and provides built-in tools for participant management and data export. This balance between low technical barriers and financial accessibility makes it an ideal option for researchers seeking full control over their studies without sacrificing usability.</p><p>DataPruebas is an invitation to collaborate, share, and build a more inclusive and participatory scientific future.</p></div>			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">https://react.dev/ 1 https://www.djangoproject.com/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://www.mturk.com/" />
		<title level="m">Amazon Mechanical Turk</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Amazon Web Services, Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gorilla in our midst: An online behavioral experiment builder</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Anwyl-Irvine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Massonnié</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Flitton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kirkham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Evershed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The timing mega-study: Comparing a range of experiment generators, both lab-based and online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bridges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pitiot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Macaskill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Peirce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7717/peerj.9414</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.9414" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PeerJ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">jsPsych: A JavaScript library for creating behavioral experiments in a Web browser</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>De Leeuw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">lab.js: A free, open, online study builder</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Henninger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shevchenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mertens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kieslich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hilbig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="556" to="573" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Just Another Tool for Online Studies&quot; (JATOS): An Easy Solution for Setup and Management of Web Servers Supporting Online Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lange</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kühn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Filevich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">130834</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PsychoPy2: Experiments in behavior made easy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Peirce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Macaskill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Höchenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sogo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kastman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Lindeløv</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="203" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Scale</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">n.d</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Inc</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">n.d</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://scale.com/" />
		<title level="m">Accelerate the Development of AI Applications | Scale AI</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tutorial: Introduction to PCIbex -An Open-Science Platform for Online Experiments: Design, Data-Collection and Code-Sharing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://escholarship.org/uc/item/1ng1q4c6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page">43</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vidal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cognition.run" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition. Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Duolingo: Learn a language for free while helping to translate the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Von Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="2" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">reCAPTCHA: Human-Based Character Recognition via Web Security Measures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">; L</forename><surname>Von Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Maurer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mcmillen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Abraham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer. von Ahn</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1465" to="1468" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Science</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
