<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The evil of banality: When choosing between the mundane feels like choosing between the worst</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amitai</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
							<email>amitai_shenhav@brown.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Cognitive, Linguistic, and Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brown Institute for Brain Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carolyn</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Cognitive, Linguistic, and Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brown Institute for Brain Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uma</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Karmarkar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Global Policy and Strategy</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Rady School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>San Diego</addrLine>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thayer</forename><surname>St</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Box</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University Providence</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02912</postCode>
									<region>RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The evil of banality: When choosing between the mundane feels like choosing between the worst</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:14+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Our most important decisions often provoke the greatest anxiety, whether we seek the better of two prizes or the lesser of two evils. Yet many of our choices are more mundane, such as selecting from a slate of mediocre but acceptable restaurants. Previous research suggests that choices of decreasing value should provoke decreasing anxiety. Here we show that this is not the case. Across three behavioral studies and one fMRI study, we find that anxiety and its neural correlates demonstrate a U-shaped function of choice set value, greatest when choosing between both the highest value and lowest value sets. We show that these counterintuitive findings can be accounted for by decision-makers perceiving low-value items as aversive rather than simply unrewarding. Decision-makers thus experience anxiety from competing avoidance motivations when forced to select among such options, comparable to the competing approach motivations they experience when choosing between high-value items.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>People often struggle with their decisions. Choosing between a set of competing options can feel effortful and anxiety-provoking <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Iyengar &amp; Lepper, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Patall, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Schwartz, 2004)</ref>, and can lead people to avoid making a decision by whatever means possible <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Anderson, 2003)</ref>. Our most important decisions tend to provoke the greatest anxiety, whether they are between the better of two excellent options <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2014)</ref> or the lesser of two evils <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Botti, Orfali, &amp; Iyengar, 2009</ref>). Yet many of the decisions we make involve mundane options and lower stakes, for instance when selecting between a slate of mediocre but acceptable restaurants. Here we investigate these seemingly trivial choices, and find that they are less trivial than they may seem.</p><p>Though it might seem that low-value choices should cause little distress, there is reason to second-guess that intuition. Research has shown that our responses to potential rewards are reference-dependent and that they adapt to the range of options that an individual observes in a given setting <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Louie &amp; Glimcher, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Louie, Khaw, &amp; Glimcher, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Rangel &amp; Clithero, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1981)</ref>. In particular, people are known to treat potential rewards as aversive if social norms <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Sanfey, Rilling, Aronson, Nystrom, &amp; Cohen, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Thaler, 1988)</ref> or other salient reference points <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Coricelli et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Coricelli &amp; Rustichini, 2010)</ref> set them up to expect greater rewards. Thus, even if a set of items is not aversive per se, it can theoretically take on a negative value when contrasted with the opportunity to engage with more interesting options. This makes the interesting prediction that as choice options become sufficiently unimportant (or low in value) they generate greater and greater avoidance motivation. The resulting avoid-avoid conflict between those options could provoke increasing anxiety.</p><p>At first glance, previous findings would appear to contradict this prediction. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shenhav &amp; Buckner (2014)</ref> had participants choose between pairs of everyday items that varied in subjective value, and found that choosing between options with high subjective value increased feelings of positive affect as well as anxiety. Choosing between low-value options produced the opposite profile: low positive affect and low anxiety. Across their two fMRI studies (N=84), choice anxiety is best explained as a linear function of the choice set value (i.e., the average value of the choice options), with no indication that anxiety increased at the lowest values <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2</ref>, left; <ref type="table">Table S1</ref>). These studies also identified a set of brain regions -including dorsal anterior cingulate cortex (dACC) and anterior insula (AI) -that consistently tracked levels of anxiety experienced while making these choices, demonstrating lower levels of activity for low value choices.</p><p>However, these studies suffered from a common limitation: they excluded a large subset of items that participants had rated as "zero value" in a willingness-to-pay procedure performed prior to the main decision task. Because these lowest-value items were omitted, participants in these studies only chose between moderate to high value items. Based on the finding that lower-value choice sets generated lower anxiety (within that moderate to high value range), one could extrapolate that choice sets with values even lower than those tested should produce even less anxiety and less activity in associated brain regions. However, if the omitted items are somehow treated as more aversive, rather than less rewarding then choices between them could engender avoid-avoid conflict, analogous to the approach-approach conflict found in high value choices. Based on previous research on conflicts involving truly aversive outcomes (e.g., electric shock) <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Botti et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Lewin, 1935;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Miller, 1944)</ref>, we would then predict that these lowest-valued choices will increase feelings of anxiety and anxiety-related patterns of brain activity.</p><p>Here we test this prediction across three behavioral studies and one fMRI experiment. We examine behavior, affective experience, and neural activity while participants choose between "lowest-value" choice sets, using an experimental design modified to include and increase the granularity of subjective values for individuals' least desired items. We find that anxiety levels and anxiety-related neural activity were greatest both when choosing between the highest and lowest value choice sets (i.e., a U-shaped effect). We additionally show behavioral and neural evidence that evoked anxiety can be best explained by considering how much better or worse a choice set is than average, or by how much the choice options are wanted or unwanted. These findings are consistent with the possibility that choosing between the least rewarding items can feel like choosing between the worst ones.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>In order to test whether low-value choice sets generate more or less anxiety than moderate-value choice sets, Study 1 used a procedure similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shenhav &amp; Buckner's (2014)</ref> studies. Participants made a series of choices between sets of four items that varied in subjective value, and subsequently rated the anxiety they had experienced while making those choices. Unlike previous studies, Study 1 included choices between items with the lowest subjective value, and an item rating procedure that increased the granularity of ratings at the low end of the scale. This allowed us to test how anxiety varied within this previously untested range of choice set values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants. Our sample was based on effect sizes observed in previous studies using this within-subject design <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2014)</ref>. For Study 1, 25 individuals were recruited from Brown University and the general community. Of these, three individuals were excluded for generating item ratings with insufficient variance 1 , leaving 22 participants (68.2% female, M age = 18.7, SD age = 0.9) for our analysis. Participants in Studies 1-3 provided informed consent in accordance with the policies of the Brown University Institutional Review Board.</p><p>Procedure. At the start of the experiment, participants completed some or all of the following personality inventories: the Behavioral Inhibition/Activation Scales (BIS/BAS), Neuroticism subscale of the NEO Five Factor Inventory, Intolerance for Uncertainty Scale, and Need for Cognition. These are not analyzed further. Participants then performed the main experiment in four phases, which occurred sequentially within the same experimental session <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>). In Phase 1, participants evaluated how much they would hypothetically like to have each of a series of individual products. They evaluated each product on a computerized visual analog liking scale, anchored at 0 ('not at all') and 10 ('a great deal'). Male and female participants evaluated overlapping but slightly different product sets (males = 338 products; females = 362 products; 317 products overlapping). Participants were encouraged to distribute their item ratings across the 0-10 scale.</p><p>In Phase 2, participants made hypothetical choices between sets of four products. For each choice set, they clicked on the product they preferred most out of the set. Choice sets were individually tailored based on each participant's own Phase 1 ratings by rank ordering them and then splitting the distribution into tertiles (Low, Mid, High). Similar-value product sets were generated by selecting 60 non-overlapping sequences of four consecutively rank-ordered products (20 from each tertile). Mixed-value sets were generated by randomly sampling four products from across the entire value distribution (without replacement). Sets were constructed such that each product would appear exactly twice (once in a similar-value set, once in a mixedvalue set), but each choice set was only seen once during the choice task. Participants made a total of 120 choices. Task timeline for Studies 1-3. Participants rated products individually, then chose between sets of four products. After making these choices, participants viewed the choice sets again and (in separate blocks) rated how much they liked the set overall, how anxious they were about the choice, and how confident they were in their earlier choice. For Study 4, Phase 2 was performed while undergoing fMRI, and interleaved with set liking trials.</p><p>In Phase 3, participants viewed each choice set again and rated each of the following in separate blocks: (1) how stressed/anxious they had felt when facing each set, (2) how confident they were with the choice they had made, and (3) how much they liked the set as a whole. Each of these experiences was rated on a 5-point scale. Phase 4 consisted of a final individual item evaluation, similar to Phase 1, but with different instructions. Participants re-rated each product from Phase 1 on a bipolar scale, anchored at -10 ('dislike a great deal) and 10 ('like a great deal'). Participants performed the tasks at their own pace throughout Phases 1-4.</p><p>Analysis. Data were analyzed using linear mixed-effects regressions (Matlab's fitlme function), fitting fixed and random (subject-specific) slopes for each variable, as well as random intercepts for each participant. We estimated degrees of freedom for our fixed effects using Satterthwaite approximation. Decision time was log-transformed to reduce skew, and all variables were normalized (z-scored) prior to analysis.</p><p>Visualization. Figures displaying projected values ( ) and standard errors of a given dependent variable were generated using Matlab's predict function, based on the relevant mixed-effects regressions. For ease of interpretation, these figures (and their associated regressions) use nonstandardized versions of each variable (e.g., anxiety, average value). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>We first replicated the previous finding -shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> (left) -that anxiety increases linearly for moderate to high value choice sets. Specifically, we tested whether anxiety correlated with set value (i.e., the average value of the items in a choice set), using only the half of choice trials with the most valuable choice sets. As expected, for choices in this range of moderate to high value, we find a positive linear relationship between set value and anxiety (β = 0.42, t(17.9) = 4.82, p &lt; 0.001). As set value increased, choice anxiety increased. However, this relationship does not hold when focusing instead on choices in the lower half of the set value range. Instead, we found that this correlation reversed. As set value decreased below the median set value, anxiety increased (β = -0.38, t(18.9) = -2.96, p = 0.008). Across all choice sets, we therefore observed a significant quadratic (U-shaped) effect of set value on anxiety <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 2</ref>, right; β = 0.22, t(20.9) = 4.99, p &lt; 0.001).</p><p>We hypothesized that this surprising pattern reflected our participants' experience of low-valued products as aversive rather than simply unwanted. If this were the case, such patterns of choice anxiety might be better explained as a response to the overall motivational salience of the choice sets -that is, the degree to which the competing options are approach-worthy or avoidanceworthy -than as a response to set value per se. In other words, participants may have felt like they were choosing the best of four good options when it came to highest-valued sets, but the least of four "evils" when it came to lowest-valued sets.  <ref type="formula">2014</ref>, item values were determined by a WTP procedure and $0.00 items were excluded. Anxiety was primarily a linear function of average set value <ref type="table">(Table S1</ref>). Right: In Study 1, item values were determined by liking ratings and no items were excluded (see also <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>). Anxiety instead only exhibited a quadratic relationship with set value. Shaded error bars reflect s.e.m.</p><p>We tested this motivational-salience hypothesis in a number of ways. First, for each participant we calculated a grand mean, or average value they assigned all of the products in Phase 1, as a way of estimating their possible "true zero value" or neutral value midpoint. As a proxy for the motivational salience of a choice set, we then calculated the absolute difference between that imputed neutral midpoint and the average value of the products in each choice set, such that high salience values reflected sets with much higher value or much lower value than that participant's grand mean product rating. We then regressed trialwise anxiety ratings on this measure of set salience, along with set value (the mean value of the four items in the set) and the spread of individual item values (e.g. max value-min value). As shown in Column 1 of <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, the motivational salience of a set was a significant predictor of anxiety (p &lt; 0.001), consistent with our hypotheses ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>). Value spread also predicted anxiety, such that more similarly valued choice sets caused greater anxiety (p = 0.003). Set value, however, was no longer a significant predictor of anxiety using this complete range of choice set values (p &gt; 0.250).</p><p>We next tested whether the costs of motivationally salient choices could be detected in the time it took participants to make a given choice. Using a similar regression model to examine response time, we found that participants took longer to decide when facing more salient choice sets (β = 0.07, t(20.8) = 2.66, p = 0.015), even when controlling for effects of the value spread and the average value of the set (both of which led to faster decision times; value spread: β = -0.20, t(19.9) = -8.61, p &lt; 0.001, set value: β = -0.11, t(17.2) = -3.58, p = 0.002). Taken as a whole, these findings suggest that more salient choices were more costly both in terms of decision time and experiences of anxiety. Importantly, though, the relationship between set salience and anxiety is robust to controlling for decision time (β = 0.17, t(21.8) = 6.33, p &lt; 0.001), suggesting that anxiety reflects subjective decision costs over and above deliberation time.</p><p>The set values calculated above are based on Phase 1 item ratings, in which participants rated each product on a unipolar positive scale (from 0 to 10), similar to methods used in prior research. However, our motivational salience account assumes that participants are treating the lowest value items as negative, rather than as weakly positive. To explore whether participants would explicitly label these items as negative, Phase 4 in this study had participants re-rate all products using a bipolar rating scale (-10 to 10; anchored at "dislike a great deal" and "like a great deal"; average Pearson's correlation with Phase 1 rating = 0.84). This enabled participants to rate items relative to an explicit zero (neutral) midpoint. When re-analyzing choice anxiety using these bipolar ratings, we again found that these experiences were better predicted by the salience of the set (i.e., distance from the fixed zero point on the scale; β = 0.18, t(16.0) = 5.33, p &lt; 0.001) than by the set value (β =-0.03, t(19.3) = -0.34, p &gt; 0.250).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>This study demonstrates that choice anxiety is a U-shaped function of set value, greatest for the highest and lowest value sets. This raises two questions, which we address in the next two studies. First, is the difference between item rating procedures (and associated omissions of zerovalued items) sufficient to explain the discrepancy between (a) the quadratic relationship we observe between set value and anxiety and (b) previous findings of a linear relationship between these variables (compare left and right panels in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>)? Second, to what extent is the significant association between anxiety and bipolar rating salience in Study 1 an artifact of participants having previously rated these products on a unipolar scale?</p><p>Study 2 addresses the first question by testing whether we can replicate both the quadratic and linear set value effects within the same participants, simply by altering how products are evaluated and incorporated into the participant's choice set. In particular, Shenhav &amp; Buckner's linear effect was observed when participants performed an auction-like willingness to pay (WTP) procedure during Phase 1. As in other studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kang, Rangel, Camus, &amp; Camerer, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Krajbich, Lu, Camerer, &amp; Rangel, 2012)</ref>, this procedure resulted in a substantial number of products being rated as having zero value. As noted, these zero-value items were excluded from choice sets. Study 2 tests whether these exclusions caused earlier studies to omit meaningful variance arising from negative motivational salience that might have otherwise generated greater anxiety.  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Linear mixed-effects regression estimates predicting anxiety ratings within each study. Set Value refers to the average of Phase 1 ratings for the items in a choice set, while Set Salience refers to the (unsigned) difference between a given set value and a central reference point determined either by the participant-specific grand mean item value (Studies 1, 2, and 4) or the fixed midpoint on a bipolar rating scale (Study 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>Study 2 employed two sets of product evaluations: a procedure that encouraged participants to distribute their ratings across a liking rating scale (Phase 1; as in Phase 1 of Study 1), and a standard WTP-based procedure (Phase 4; as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2014)</ref>. We tested whether the form of the relationship we observed between set value and anxiety would transform from quadratic to linear depending on the type of product evaluation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants. 22 individuals were recruited from Brown University and the general community. Of these, three others were excluded for generating item ratings with insufficient variance, leaving 19 participants (50.0% female, M age = 19.3, SD age = 1.2) for our analysis.</p><p>Procedure. Phase 1-3 of this study were identical to Study 1. However, the Phase 4 evaluation consisted of indicating their willingness to pay (WTP) for each item. Participants were asked to imagine that each trial was an independent event in which they had $20.00 to spend. They were asked to indicate how much of this money they would give up to obtain that trial's product, assuming that they would keep any unspent money 2 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Focusing on the product liking ratings derived from Phase 1, we replicated our Study 1 finding that anxiety increases with set salience (p &lt; 0.001) and not set value (p &gt; 0.250) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Figure 3, left</ref>; <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). To directly compare these data with Shenhav &amp; Buckner (2014), we then restricted our analysis to the kinds of choice sets that were included in that paper. This was done by excluding sets with zero-valued items, as defined by Phase 4's WTP ratings. Consistent with past research, participants indicated $0.00 as their WTP for 29% of items, compared to 5% of items being rated as 0 on a liking scale (compare histograms in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>). This resulted in 53% of choice sets being excluded. Regressing anxiety on set value in this zero-excluded subset did yield a linear effect of set value on anxiety for these same participants (β = 0.24; t(14.4) = 2.88, p = 0.012; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>, right). Within this subset of choices, a linear model provided a better fit (Akaike Information Criterion [AIC] = 2738.5) than a model that included both linear and quadratic terms (AIC = 2744.5). These results help resolve the apparent conflict between the U-shaped relationship between anxiety and set value observed in Study 1, and the linear relationships reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shenhav &amp; Buckner (2014)</ref>. In Study 2, we again observe a quadratic relationship between anxiety and set value (left) but this becomes a positive linear relationship when we exclude choice sets that include a zero-valued bid (based on a follow-up item WTP rating). Projected anxiety ratings are overlaid on histograms of item ratings based on the two rating procedures, demonstrating a pronounced peak at $0.00 for the WTP procedure. Shaded error bars reflect s.e.m.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Both Studies 1 and 2 demonstrate that people experience greater anxiety for lowest-value choice sets compared to moderate value choices. Ratings from a secondary evaluation in Study 1 further suggest that this may have resulted from participants treating law-value items as aversive (rather than simply unrewarding) and therefore experienced choices between such items as forms of avoid-avoid conflict. To test this hypothesis more directly, Study 3 used a bipolar product evaluation in Phase 1 to construct the Phase 2 choice sets directly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>Study 3 provides a more direct test of whether anxiety towards low-valued items is related to a desire to avoid those items, by using a bipolar rating scale for the initial evaluation of those items (Phase 1) and subsequent choice set construction. This scale provides an objective midpoint (neutral rating) for measuring set salience and its relationship with choice anxiety.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants. 27 individuals were recruited from Brown University and the general community. One individual was excluded due to a technical issue, leaving 26 participants (88.5% female, M age = 18.5, SD age = 0.9) in our analysis.</p><p>Procedure. Study 3's procedure was identical to Phase 1-3 of Study 1 with one exception. In Phase 1 participants rated each product on a bipolar scale anchored at -10 ('dislike a great deal) and 10 ('like a great deal'), rather than Study 1's unipolar (0 to 10) scale. The choice sets used in the rest of the experiment were constructed based on these Phase 1 values. Phase 4 was omitted for this study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>As in Study 1, we found that anxiety is best described as a quadratic function of set value, as defined by our bipolar rating scale (β = 0.13, t(24.3) = 4.19, p &lt; 0.001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>, left). However, unlike for Phase 1 ratings in Studies 1-2, the midpoint of this quadratic function had a fixed definition across subjects, corresponding to zero motivational salience (i.e., neither positive nor negative). We therefore calculated a motivational salience measure for each choice set based on this fixed zero point rather than the participant-specific grand mean (used in Studies 1-2). Based on this measure, we again find that anxiety linearly increased with the salience (p = 0.007) but not the average value (p &gt; 0.250) of the choice set <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Figure 4</ref>, right; <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). In Study 3, we again observe a quadratic relationship between set value and anxiety, but in this case a bipolar rating scale was used (-10 to 10) and we see that anxiety is minimal around the zero point. Right: Anxiety increases linearly with the distance between a given set value from the fixed zero midpoint on the rating scale. Shaded error bars reflect s.e.m.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Studies 1-3 demonstrate that anxiety has a U-shaped relationship with set value. Study 2 further demonstrates how extrapolating from a limited range of set values can lead to misinterpretations of this relationship, and Study 3 suggests a potential explanation for the nonlinearity in terms of the relationship between anxiety and the strength of approach-approach or avoid-avoid conflict. One natural question this raises is whether this nonlinear pattern is a general property of any affective reaction to choice sets. Our study design allowed us to address this question. In addition to rating anxiety, our participants also provided an appraisal of the overall attractiveness of each choice set (i.e., how much they liked the set as a whole). (Note that this is distinct from the estimate of set value used in the experimental analyses, which was derived from the average value of the items in the set rather than the participant's overall appraisal of the set.) Across all three studies, these appraisals increased monotonically with set value, thereby demonstrating a pattern of affective reactions dissociable from the U-shaped pattern observed for experiences of anxiety <ref type="table">(Table S2</ref>; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref>).</p><p>A limitation of the experiments so far is that they rely primarily on self-report to demonstrate the costs associated with choosing between low-value or high-value sets. As a result, they do not speak to whether the anxiety over low-value sets is driven by the same underlying mechanisms as the anxiety over high-value sets. These studies are also unable to address the question of whether anxiety is elicited by salient choice sets per se, or specifically by the need to make a choice between those salient choice options. To explore this more directly, in Study 4 we scanned participants using fMRI and tested whether anxiety-related regions of the brain would reflect the quadratic pattern observed in self-reported anxiety, and whether these regions selectively responded to salient options when a choice was required.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 4</head><p>Study 4 tested whether the U-shaped pattern observed in affective ratings would be mirrored in neural responses within anxiety-related brain regions. We further tested our prediction that these anxiety-related neural responses specifically reflected the need to choose between salient options, by comparing such responses to trials where subjects observed equally salient options but were instead asked to appraise the overall value of the choice set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants. 31 individuals were recruited from Harvard University and the general community. Of these, one was excluded for excessive head motion, leaving 30 participants (56.7% female, M age = 24.9, SD age = 4.5) in the final analysis. Participants provided informed consent in accordance with the policies of the Harvard University Institutional Review Board.</p><p>Procedure. Phase 1 was conducted similarly to Studies 1-2, using a product set that was tailored towards this community (males = 310 products; females = 328 products). Here, Phase 2 was performed while undergoing fMRI (see details below). On each trial, participants viewed choice sets that were constructed as in Studies 1-3 (Low, Mid, High; Mixed) and were prompted to perform one of two tasks: (1) select the product they most prefer (Choose trials) or (2) evaluate how much they like the set as a whole, on a 4-point scale (Like trials) 3 . To ensure that all products were identified before the explicit evaluation period, the set appeared for 3s at the start of each trial, after which a LIKE or CHOOSE cue appeared to indicate the task on the current trial. To separate evaluation and response selection periods, after the cue appeared participants were instructed to press a key only to indicate once they had completed their evaluation and made their choice (without a deadline). After pressing a key to end this Evaluation period, participants viewed a fixation cross for a variable inter-trial interval (ITI; 2-7s) and then the four options re-appeared in a random horizontal arrangement, in parallel with either the numbers 1-4 (on Like trials) or pound (#) symbols (on Choose trials). Participants used the keypad to move a cursor left (right index finger) or right (right ring finger) before submitting their response (right middle finger). Participants were required to provide an answer in the Selection period within 5s, encouraging them to determine their response prior to this period (during the Evaluation period).</p><p>While in the scanner, participants viewed each choice set once and performed the Choose task for half of the trials and the Like task for the other half (with the distribution of choice set values matched across the two tasks). This was counterbalanced outside of the scanner; participants once again viewed all of the choice sets, performed the opposite task for each set (i.e., Like ratings for sets that were previously in the Choose condition, and vice versa). This procedure ensured that each participant made an appraisal and choice for every set. Participants then completed Phase 3, involving anxiety and confidence ratings as in the previous behavioral studies. This study omitted Phase 4.</p><p>Imaging Parameters. Scans were acquired on a Siemens Trio 3T scanner with a 12-channel phase-arrayed head coil, using the following gradient-echo planar imaging (EPI) sequence parameters: repetition time (TR) = 2500 ms; echo time (TE) = 30 ms; flip angle (FA) = 90°; 2.5mm voxels; 0.50 mm gap between slices; field of view (FOV): 210 x 210; interleaved acquisition; 37 slices. To reduce signal dropout in regions of interest, we uses a rotated slice prescription (30° relative to AC/PC) and modified z-shim prepulse sequence. The slice prescription encompassed all ventral cortical structures but limited regions of dorsal posterior parietal cortex. Structural data were collected with T1-weighted multi-echo magnetization prepared rapid acquisition gradient echo image (MEMPRAGE) sequences using the following parameters: TR = 2200 ms; TE = 1.54 ms; FA = 7°; 1.2 mm isotropic voxels; FOV = 192 X 192. Head motion was restricted with a pillow and padded head clamps. Stimuli were generated using Matlab's Psychophysics Toolbox and were viewed through a mirror mounted on the head coil. Participants used their right hand to respond with an MR-safe response keypad.</p><p>fMRI Analysis. fMRI data were analyzed using SPM8 (Wellcome Department of Imaging Neuroscience, Institute of Neurology, London, UK). Preprocessing consisted of realigning volumes within participant, resampling to 2mm isotropic voxels, nonlinear transformation to align with a canonical T2 template, and spatial smoothing with a 6 mm full-width at half-max (FWHM) Gaussian kernel.</p><p>Preprocessed data were submitted to a linear mixed-effects analyses, using a two-step procedure. First, we generated BOLD signal change estimates for each trial using a first-level general linear models (GLM) in SPM. This GLM separately modeled stick functions onsetting at the Evaluation and Selection period of each trial. We compared two versions of this GLM: one version that locked the onset of the Evaluation period around the appearance of the task prompt, and another version that locked the Evaluation onset to the time when the participant indicated that they completed their evaluation. Trials were concatenated across the two task blocks, and additional regressors were included to model within-block means and linear trends. Finally, the GLM was estimated using a reweighted least squares approach (RobustWLS Toolbox; <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Diedrichsen &amp; Shadmehr, 2005)</ref> in order to minimize the influence of outlier time-points (e.g., due to head motion). After estimating this first-level GLM, we extracted average beta estimates for each trial from our primary region of interest (ROI; see below), transformed these beta estimates with the hyperbolic arcsine function (to achieve normality), and then analyzed trial-totrial variability in these BOLD estimates with linear mixed-effects regressions (using Matlab's lmefit function).</p><p>We drew our a priori ROI for regions associated with choice anxiety from the results of two fMRI experiments reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shenhav &amp; Buckner (2014)</ref>. Specifically, we generated a binary mask that reflected the conjunction of the regions that reliably tracked choice anxiety in those two studies (with both input maps individually thresholded at a voxelwise p&lt;0.001 and cluster threshold of 50 voxels). The resulting whole-brain mask consisted primarily of regions of dACC and AI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Study 4 again replicates the correlation between anxiety ratings and set salience <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. We next tested for neural correlates of these anxiety ratings in an a priori network previously implicated in choice anxiety (comprising regions in dACC and AI; <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> inset). Activity in these regions during the choice period was positively correlated with anxiety. This correlation held irrespective of whether we analyzed activity in this ROI early in the trial (β = 0.08, t(875.3) = 3.04, p = 0.002) or closer to when the participant responded (β = 0.14, t(137.9) = 5.09, p &lt; 0.001). Since the latter effect was substantially stronger, we locked our remaining analyses to the time of response 4 . The relationship between neural activity and anxiety during this period was robust to controlling for RT (β = 0.12, t(109.8) = 4.43, p &lt; 0.001). Critically, consistent with the patterns we observe underlying anxiety reports, we find that activity in anxiety-related regions was significantly correlated with the salience of the choice set (β = 0.07, t(1542.2) = 2.81, p = 0.005) but not with the average value of that set (β = 0.01, t(761.9) = 0.34, p &gt; 0.250).</p><p>An important aspect of the study design allowed us to compare neural data from participants both when they were making choices (when we expect them to experience choice anxiety) and when they were appraising the value of sets (when we do not expect them to experience such anxiety). Unlike the correlation observed during choice, during appraisal activity in our ROI was not significantly correlated with anxiety (β = 0.03, t(26.5) = 0.93, p &gt; 0.250) nor set salience (β = -0.01, t(659.2) = -0.60 p &gt; 0.250). Consequently, we found that activity in these regions exhibited a significant interaction between task type (choice vs. appraisal) and anxiety (β = 0.09, t(29.2) = 2.05, p = 0.049). We observed a similar interaction between task type and set salience (β = 0.08, t(85.5) = 2.36, p = 0.021) ( <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>). <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. BOLD activity in anxiety-related regions correlates with anxiety (left) and set salience (right) when participants are making a choice but not when they are just "browsing" the set (i.e., appraising the overall value of the set). The a priori mask (defined by previous anxietyrelated activations) is shown in the left inset. Shaded error bars reflect s.e.m.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Study 4's findings demonstrate a set salience effect in anxiety-related brain regions (dACC/AI), consistent with correlates of self-reported anxiety observed across all four studies. They further show that these neural responses do not merely reflect a property of the choice sets themselves (such as their salience). Rather, they specifically reflect situations in which the participant was required to choose between salient items (rather than form an overall appraisal of the set).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>When making choices, people commonly find that the more valuable their options are, the more difficult and anxiety-provoking the decision becomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Chernev &amp; Hamilton, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shenhav &amp; Buckner, 2014)</ref>. Across four studies we demonstrate that this kind of anxiety can also arise from choices between items that have little to no value. Overall, we show behavioral and neural evidence that anxiety is a U-shaped function of choice set value; people are most anxious for the lowest and highest value choice sets. Notably, our neuroimaging results show this anxiety seems to be absent when participants are simply evaluating how much they like a set of items rather than choosing between them. This suggests that the negative affective response arises from an interaction between the choice set's overall value and the specific task of comparing the options to select just one of them.</p><p>The U-shaped relationship between anxiety and set value may be explained by participants treating low-value sets as items that were to be avoided to a similar degree as the high-value sets were to be approached. In other words, low-value sets took on a negative but high motivational salience, generating choice conflict for the same reason that avoid-avoid conflicts between several aversive outcomes (e.g., electric shock) would. Interestingly, though, none of the individual low-value items were intrinsically aversive, nor did they engender anxiety when participants were performing a simple set appraisal task (Study 4). Instead, these sets appeared to accrue their negative salience in the context of the observed range of items. This hypothesis is supported by the findings in Study 3, in which participants rated items on a bipolar scale (allowing negative values) and anxiety increased with more negative ratings.</p><p>However, an alternative, unipolar account of these findings might suggest that low-value choice sets did not acquire negative salience but instead were merely insufficient to trigger or activate any approach-related responses. Under this account, anxiety for low-value sets is a reflection of this state of insufficient motivation (and perhaps surrounding frustrations) whereas anxiety for high-value sets may reflect a state of "over-activation" and the associated increase in conflict. This U-shaped function could therefore be related to the nonlinear functions previously reported in research on arousal and performance (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Nakamura &amp; Csikszentmihalyi, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Yerkes &amp; Dodson, 1908)</ref> rather than to low-value sets obtaining negative value. While this account is difficult to rule out with the current data, it is noteworthy that our fMRI data showed that the same regions track anxiety for both low and high value choice sets, arguing for common rather than distinct sources of anxiety experienced at the two ends of the U.</p><p>Under the assumption that participants track the difference between the overall value of the current choice set and the overall value of the average choice set, our findings also resonate with observations of unsigned prediction error (i.e., surprise) signals in our anxiety-related regions (dACC and AI; <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Alexander &amp; Brown, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Cavanagh &amp; Frank, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Shenhav, Cohen, &amp; Botvinick, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Ullsperger, Danielmeier, &amp; Jocham, 2014)</ref>. This raises the possibility that anxiety more generally reflected surprise towards the value of the choice set. However, our data do not straightforwardly fit this interpretation. First, low-value choice sets in Shenhav &amp; Buckner's studies would be equally surprising under these criteria, but neural and affective responses did not engender the U-shaped pattern observed in our data. Second, and more importantly, Study 4 qualifies surprise-related interpretations by demonstrating that dACC and AI respond to these quantities in a task-specific manner. In other words, to the extent that these regions reflect the salience of the choice set, they do not do so in a "bottom-up" manner but rather only when a choice is required. This is particularly notable given that participants were paying much closer attention to overall set value when performing the alternate task in this study (set appraisal), whereas the choice task primarily drew their attention to the differences in value between the items.</p><p>Similarly, previous findings have associated the dACC and AI with salience rather than value <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bartra, McGuire, &amp; Kable, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blair et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Kahnt, Park, Haynes, &amp; Tobler, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Litt, Plassmann, Shiv, &amp; Rangel, 2011)</ref>, demonstrating increases in activity for both highly rewarding and highly aversive reinforcers. Our findings are consistent with these findings but also serve to qualify them in interesting ways. In addition to demonstrating the task-specificity and affective relevance of putative salience-related neural signals in our study, we also show that signals of negative salience in these regions -previously observed with aversive stimuli such as electric shock and monetary loss -can be found for nominally rewarding items that are simply considered to be low in value.</p><p>Finally, this research also underscores a critical and often overlooked methodological consideration when asking individuals to estimate value. First, though monetary measures such as WTP and/or BDM auctions have significant benefits, our findings highlight the limitations they tend to impose on the resulting distributions of item values. Specifically, auction-like procedures -where participants weigh how much money to part with in order to obtain an itemtend to engender irregular distributions of subjective values, with many items are valued at zero dollars <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Figure 3</ref>) (see also, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kang et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Krajbich et al., 2012)</ref>. As a result, the interpretation or omission of zero-value items can be highly consequential because the zero-point can be truncating or masking a range of low values. Second, our findings provide initial evidence that the overall range of items observed during item valuation phases commonly used in decision-making research may influence the reference point by which participants evaluate later choice sets. This can, in turn, produce linear or quadratic patterns of anxiety and associated neural activity depending on the subset of the value range incorporated into the choice sets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>It is well-known that anxiety increases with the importance of potential choice outcomes, whether one has to choose between the best options (e.g., dream jobs) or the worst ones (e.g., life-threatening medical procedures). We have shown that a comparable U-shaped effect can be observed when making everyday choices, but that the negative arm of this U includes potential rewards that are simply much less desirable than the other options available. These findings explain why mundane decisions can be aversive, and suggest that we can be better off choosing between items we value moderately than those we have little interest in.  <ref type="table">Table S1</ref>. Linear mixed-effects regression estimates predicting anxiety ratings in Studies 1-2 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shenhav &amp; Buckner (2014)</ref> and the current Study 1, based on a linear or quadratic model. Unlike these previous studies, Study 1 did not observe a significant linear effect of set value.  <ref type="table">Table S2</ref>. Linear mixed-effects regression estimates predicting appraisal ratings (i.e., how much participants liked each choice set overall) across Studies 1-4. Unlike anxiety ratings, these appraisals demonstrate a monotonic relationship with set value <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Supplementary Figure 1)</ref>. See <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> legend for additional details about each of the variables. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>. Relationship between anxiety and set salience, shown here collapsed across Studies 1-2 (the two behavioral studies that used the same estimates of set value). See <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> for individual study statistics, and see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> for a plot of Study 3's findings. Shaded error bars reflect s.e.m. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref>. Relationship between set appraisal and set value, shown here collapsing across Studies 1-2. Across all studies, set appraisal is a monotonic function of set value, with a nonlinearity (plateauing) observed for the lowest set values (potentially reflecting a floor effect). Shaded error bars reflect s.e.m.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplemental Tables</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplemental Figures</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Task timeline for Studies 1-3. Participants rated products individually, then chose between sets of four products. After making these choices, participants viewed the choice sets again and (in separate blocks) rated how much they liked the set overall, how anxious they were about the choice, and how confident they were in their earlier choice. For Study 4, Phase 2 was performed while undergoing fMRI, and interleaved with set liking trials.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Left: In Shenhav &amp; Buckner</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. In Study 2, we again observe a quadratic relationship between anxiety and set value (left) but this becomes a positive linear relationship when we exclude choice sets that include a zero-valued bid (based on a follow-up item WTP rating). Projected anxiety ratings are overlaid on histograms of item ratings based on the two rating procedures, demonstrating a pronounced peak at $0.00 for the WTP procedure. Shaded error bars reflect s.e.m.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Left:</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Our automated choice construction process relied on splitting the items into ranked tertiles with nonoverlapping value ranges, before distributing them into our designated choice types. Some participants generated rating distributions with insufficient variance to construct 120 choice sets based on this procedure. In these cases, the number of choice sets was iteratively decreased to a number that could be generated for that participant, while holding constant the proportion of choices per choice type. Because they experienced a different number of trials than the remaining participants, we have excluded such participants from our analyses, but all of our findings are robust to their inclusion.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">This procedure represented a hypothetical version of the incentive compatible WTP task used in<ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shenhav &amp; Buckner (2014)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Findings pertaining directly to Study 4's appraisal/choice manipulation are reported elsewhere(Shenhav  &amp; Karmarkar, in prep).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Note that this analysis choice could not be determined a priori based on Shenhav &amp; Buckner's studies because those used a short response deadline and therefore could not differentiate between these two trial periods, however the choice itself does not unfairly bias our remaining analysis.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors are grateful to Wasita Mahaphanit and Anna Xu for assistance in stimulus development; Elizabeth Beam, Marina Burke, Ayenna Cagaanan, Erin Guty, Emily Levin, Wasita Mahaphanit, and Erik Nook for assistance in data collection; and Randy Buckner and Ian Krajbich for helpful discussions.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Medial prefrontal cortex as an action-outcome predictor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Alexander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1338" to="1344" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of doing nothing: Forms of decision avoidance result from reason and emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The valuation system: A coordinate-based meta-analysis of BOLD fMRI experiments examining neural correlates of subjective value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bartra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mcguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kable</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="412" to="427" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choosing the lesser of two evils, the better of two goods: specifying the roles of ventromedial prefrontal cortex and dorsal anterior cingulate in object choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Marsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Morton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vythilingam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mondillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11379" to="11386" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tragic choices: Autonomy and emotional responses to medical decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Botti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Orfali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="352" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frontal theta as a mechanism for cognitive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="414" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assortment size and option attractiveness in consumer choice among retailers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chernev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="410" to="420" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regret and its avoidance: a neuroimaging study of choice behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Coricelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Critchley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Joffily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O'doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sirigu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1255" to="1262" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counterfactual thinking and emotions: regret and envy learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Coricelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rustichini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">365</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="1538" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting and adjusting for artifacts in fMRI time series data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Diedrichsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shadmehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="624" to="634" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When choice is demotivating: Can one desire too much of a good thing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Iyengar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lepper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="995" to="1006" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disentangling neural representations of value and salience in the human brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kahnt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-D</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tobler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5000" to="5005" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hypothetical and Real Choice Differentially Activate Common Valuation Areas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Camus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="468" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The attentional drift-diffusion model extends to simple purchasing decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Dynamic Theory Of Personality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lewin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1935" />
			<publisher>Mcgraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissociating Valuation and Saliency Signals during Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Litt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Plassmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Shiv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cerebral Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient coding and the neural representation of value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Louie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Glimcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Normalization is a general neural mechanism for context-dependent decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Louie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Khaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Glimcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6139" to="6144" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experimental Studies of Conflict</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Personality and the Behavior Disorders</title>
		<editor>J. M. Hunt</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Ronald Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1944" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="431" to="465" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The concept of flow Handbook of positive psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nakamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Csikszentmihalyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="105" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Motivational Complexity of Choosing: A Review of Theory and Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Patall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>R. Ryan</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="249" to="279" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Oxford Handbook of Human Motivation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value normalization in decision making: theory and evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clithero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Neurobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="970" to="981" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of economic decision-making in the ultimatum game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sanfey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rilling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Nystrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">300</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1755" to="1758" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Paradox of Choice: Why More is Less</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<pubPlace>New York; Ecco</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural correlates of dueling affective reactions to winwin choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Buckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10978" to="10983" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dorsal anterior cingulate cortex and the value of control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1286" to="1291" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Karmarkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The neural correlates of appraisal versus choice</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in prep</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anomalies: The ultimatum game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The framing of decisions and the psychology of choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">211</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4481</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="458" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neurophysiology of Performance Monitoring and Adaptive Behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ullsperger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Danielmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Jocham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physiological reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relation of strength of stimulus to rapidity of habitformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yerkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dodson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Comparative Neurology and Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="459" to="482" />
			<date type="published" when="1908" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
