<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Variability and accessibility of information guide gaze dynamics in decision-making</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<email>douglasglee@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tel Aviv University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">School of Electrical and Electronic Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College Dublin</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Konstantinos</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bristol</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giovanni</forename><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Cognitive Sciences and Technologies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Research Council of Italy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitzan</forename><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tel Aviv University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Sagol School of Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tel Aviv University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tel Aviv University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Sagol School of Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tel Aviv University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Variability and accessibility of information guide gaze dynamics in decision-making</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:14+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>information seeking</term>
					<term>process tracing</term>
					<term>visual fixations Lee, Tsetsos, Pezzulo, Shahar, &amp; Usher 3</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Experimental research in decision-making often relies on tasks that provide participants with all the information they need to make their decisions. Here we consider the process by which decisionmakers seek information about their choice alternatives when it is not immediately provided. Recent advances in computational theories have proposed that people will seek to process more information about options for which they are less certain about the value. Specifically, they will allocate more attention to options with lower certainty in order to increase their certainty by processing additional information. We tested this hypothesis with a behavioral and eye-tracking experiment in which participants observed pairs of random streams of numerical stimuli and were incentivized to report which streams were generated by the distributions with the greater means. We induced uncertainty by manipulating the variance of the value distribution for each option. In addition, we randomly replaced some of the stimuli with meaningless letters. This decreased the accessibility of information about the options. The results show that people fixate more on options with lower accessibility and to a lesser extent options with greater value. Interestingly, this pattern changes across response time, with early fixations driven by variability and accessibility, and late fixations driven by value and accessibility. Moreover, people were more likely to choose options with greater accessibility, and they felt more confident about their choices when accessibility was greater. This research could help illuminate the process of information seeking to reduce uncertainty during choice deliberation.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>There is a vast literature showing that people carry out decisions via a process of integration to boundary. In binary, evidence-based decisions (such as perceptual, medical, or legal decisions), the integrated variable corresponds to the likelihood ratio of the two hypotheses (given a sample of information) 1 . In preference-based decisions, the integrated variable corresponds to a difference in the value estimates associated with each alternative. As both likelihood ratios (given a sample of evidence) and value representations are noisy <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Gold &amp; Shadlen, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Tajima et al., 2016)</ref>, the decision mechanism needs to integrate multiple samples across time to enhance the signal-to-noise ratio. Integration to boundary is the most efficient algorithm for executing simple decisions, achieving the fastest response time (RT) for a given accuracy level <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">(Wald, 1945)</ref>, and is also supported by neural data <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Gold &amp; Shadlen, 2001</ref>). This decision mechanism accounts well for behavioral data, including the speed-accuracy tradeoff <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bogacz et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Schouten &amp; Bekker, 1967;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b88">Wickelgren, 1977)</ref> and the shape of choice-RT distributions, and it has been formalized as the drift-diffusion model (DDM; <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">(Ratcliff, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Ratcliff et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Ratcliff &amp; McKoon, 2008)</ref>).</p><p>The DDM is equivalent to normative Bayesian models for simple decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bitzer et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Gold &amp; Shadlen, 2001</ref>).</p><p>While there is much behavioral and neural data in both humans and animals supporting the notion of information accumulation as a mechanism for generating choices, less is known regarding the process of information acquisition itself. For example, when choosing among multiple options (of anything from snacks to stocks), the decision maker often needs to gather information about the individual optionsseparately and sequentiallyby focusing attention (often proxied by visual gaze in behavioral experimental data; <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Armel et al., 2008a</ref>)) on one option accumulation process begins to show a preference favoring one option, attention is more drawn to that option, causing more information to be sampled from it; <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Gluth et al., 2018)</ref>). Also, attention has been proposed to be attracted towards individual samples with large numerical values <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">(Tsetsos et al., 2012)</ref> or towards samples of information that match the decision goal <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Glickman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Sepulveda et al., 2020)</ref>. Moreover, previous studies have reported that extreme values tend to be more memorable and to impact decisions to a greater degree <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Ludvig et al., 2018)</ref>. Another variable that is likely to modulate the search for information is the uncertainty associated with the choice alternatives. In decisions from experience, people seek more information about options that present higher variability in the possible outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Lejarraga et al., 2012)</ref>. The strategy of seeking more information for less certain options would be normative under the probabilistic approach to reasoning, where decision-making behavior is driven by an understanding that the world is inherently uncertain <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Friston et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Oaksford &amp; Chater, 2001</ref>). The literature on curiosity <ref type="bibr">Lee,</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsetsos,</ref><ref type="bibr">Pezzulo,</ref><ref type="bibr">Shahar,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; Usher 5</ref> has shown that people seek information that reduces their uncertainty about the world in addition to information that has a positive valence, although that literature investigates information seeking that is non-instrumental to the current decision (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">(van Lieshout et al., 2020</ref>) for a review).</p><p>Some recent theoretical studies have proposed that decision makers should aspire to tune their information processing to maximize decision efficiency. For example, sampling more information about an option for which one is already quite certain of its value would not yield much benefit, as the value of information would be low <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Howard, 1966)</ref>. It would be much more useful to instead sample information about an option for which the value estimate is less precise (or more uncertain). This may be a dynamic process. As one observes more samples for an uncertain option, one becomes more certain about it; at some point, the relative certainty about the options might change direction, and it would then become more useful to start observing samples for a different option. This idea has been formalized in recent computational modeling studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Callaway et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Jang et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Song et al., 2019)</ref> and is supported by evidence showing that people can assess their feelings of value certainty about different options <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(De Martino et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Gwinn &amp; Krajbich, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lee &amp; Hare, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Polanía et al., 2019)</ref> and should therefore be able to adjust their behavior as a function of certainty. There is also some preliminary evidence that people indeed look more at options with greater uncertainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Cassey et al., 2013)</ref>, but there is still more work to be done in terms of directly demonstrating the links between value, certainty, and attention. Providing evidence in that direction is a central aim of this study. To that end, we designed an experimental paradigm that allows us to control (not only to measure) the temporal uncertainty of choice options as people make decisions based on noisy fluctuating evidence, while we continuously monitor their gaze trajectories. <ref type="bibr">Lee,</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsetsos,</ref><ref type="bibr">Pezzulo,</ref><ref type="bibr">Shahar,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; Usher 6</ref> Uncertainty makes decisions more difficult, but it is often reducible, in principle, by considering more information. As a real-world example, consider a decision between stocks of different companies that you are considering investing in. In this example, your initial uncertainty about the average performance of a stock (e.g., based on your observation of its performance on a single day) could be reduced by observing its performance over longer periods of timeyou will become more certain about the average daily return it generates when you observe its performance on more days <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bhui &amp; Jiao, 2023)</ref>. Recent work has shown that people do incorporate this concept of reduceable (or epistemic) uncertainty in their value estimations, and that they are aware of how it can impede their accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Olschewski &amp; Scheibehenne, 2024)</ref>. In this study, we examine a classical source of decision uncertaintyvalue variabilityas well as an additional source related to a new variable that we introduceinformation accessibility. We use the term accessibility to refer to the availability of information to be processed about choice options, as well as the ease with which the information can be processed. This could relate to stimulus characteristics such as contrast or clarity for perceptual choices, or to the frequency or recency of previous experiences with an option for memory-based choices. From this perspective, accessibility (or the lack thereof) should affect uncertaintywhen a portion of the observed samples of evidence are noninformative, a decision maker will be less certain about the true average value than if all samples were informative. Variability should similarly affect uncertaintythe more stochasticity in the observed samples, the less certain a decision maker will be about the true average value.</p><p>With respect to the process by which decision makers select what to sample while deciding, we think both sources of uncertainty outlined above might be significant factors. In brief, the reduction of uncertainty that is purported to take place when attending to an option during a decision should occur at a higher rate both when the observed samples are less variable and when <ref type="bibr">Lee,</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsetsos,</ref><ref type="bibr">Pezzulo,</ref><ref type="bibr">Shahar,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; Usher 7</ref> accessibility to meaningful samples is higher. Below, we first describe our experimental paradigm and then outline our general predictions with respect to variability and accessibility.</p><p>Our experimental paradigm displays pairs of sequences of numerical values (on the left and right sides of the computer screen). This could correspond to returns of pairs of stocks, for example. The numbers are samples drawn from two overlapping Gaussian distributions, which change from trial-to-trial but are fixed within each trial. Sometimes a numerical sample is replaced by a meaningless pair of letters, which decreases the accessibility of the decision-relevant information for the associated option. The samples for both options are simultaneously updated at a rate of three times per second, and they continue to update until participants report their decision (about which sequence corresponds to the generating distribution with the greater mean; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure   1</ref> for an illustration). Using this paradigm, we can orthogonally manipulate the option properties (mean, variability, and accessibility) on each trial. The participants maintained control over where they focused their gaze at any point in time while figuring out which option to choose (the direction of which we monitored and recorded) as well as the time at which they terminated each decision. Importantly, the small font size of the displayed samples along with the speed with which they were updated ensured that participants would need to fixate on them in order to properly perceive them. With this design, we were able to make a number of specific predictions (see below) and validate them with the experimental data. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predictions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Gaze fixations</head><p>We predict that people will spend more time (on average within each trial) looking at the option with higher mean, higher variability, and lower accessibility. In general, people tend to look more at an option when they think it is the best response to the task at hand <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Armel et al., 2008b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cavanagh et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Fiedler &amp; Glöckner, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Shimojo et al., 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Previous theoretical work has also proposed that people should look more at uncertain options in order to reduce that uncertainty by focusing their attention <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Callaway et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Jang et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Song et al., 2019)</ref>. The more attention an option receives, the more information should be processed about that option. With more information, the initial uncertainty should be reduced to a greater extent than if the option had low uncertainty to begin with <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Cassey et al., 2013)</ref>. There is also initial evidence that people look less at options that are highly accessible ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Gwinn &amp; Krajbich, 2020)</ref>; in that study, accessibility was operationalized in a very different way than in our <ref type="bibr">Lee,</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsetsos,</ref><ref type="bibr">Pezzulo,</ref><ref type="bibr">Shahar,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; Usher 9</ref> experimentparticipants were asked whether or not they would be willing to consume individual snack foods, and the RT with which they responded was taken as a measure of accessibility for the option; RT was first regressed on rating extremity, and the residuals served as the measure of accessibility). People should pay more attention to poorly accessible options simply because when samples contain less information, more samples will need to be accumulated to achieve the same amount of uncertainty reduction. This should impact where people allocate their attention, as it might behoove them to look more at options with low accessibility in order to extract sufficient information about them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Choices</head><p>Our first set of behavioral predictions relates to value mean. We predict that choice accuracy will be higher, RT will be lower, and confidence will be higher when the mean difference between the options (often termed choice ease) is greater. This prediction is a critical one, as it will simultaneously serve to demonstrate whether participants performed the task properly and whether our main difficulty manipulation was successful. We also predict that RT will be lower and confidence will be higher when the mean sum of the options is greater. Previous studies have shown that people decide more quickly and with higher confidence when the total overall value across choice options is higher <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Frömer et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Hunt et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lee &amp; Hare, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Polanía et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2019)</ref>. It has sometimes also been observed that choices are more accurate when the value sum is greater <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">(Shevlin et al., 2022</ref>), but we withhold from making a prediction about this until more corroborating evidence is available.</p><p>Our second set of behavioral predictions relates to value variability. We predict that accuracy will be lower, RT will be higher, and confidence will be lower when either the sum of <ref type="bibr">Lee,</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsetsos,</ref><ref type="bibr">Pezzulo,</ref><ref type="bibr">Shahar,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; Usher 10</ref> variability across options or the variability of the higher-valued option is greater. Feelings of uncertainty that people have about the value of choice options under consideration have previously been shown to influence choices. Specifically, decisions seem to be facilitated (i.e., they are more accurate, faster, and more confident) when there is less uncertainty about the set of options <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Gwinn &amp; Krajbich, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lee &amp; Hare, 2023)</ref>.</p><p>Similar results were found when the higher-valued option was less uncertain relative to the lowervalued option <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lee &amp; Hare, 2023)</ref>. We anticipate similar effects in our data.</p><p>Our third set of behavioral predictions relates to the key new variable that we examine in this study: information accessibility. We predict that accuracy will be higher, RT will be lower, and confidence will be higher when either the sum of accessibility across options or the accessibility of the higher-valued option is greater. We expected accessibility to impact choice behavior in a way similar to variability. The idea is that when information signals are less accessible (here operationalized as a greater probability of meaningless letters being displayed within the streams of numbers), a decision maker will be less certain about the value of the corresponding option. Note that with our experimental design, lower accessibility would necessarily result in longer RT if participants were to adopt a strategy of seeking comparable amounts of information about all options before deciding. A prediction of longer RT for trials with lower overall accessibility, therefore, is tantamount to predicting that participants will indeed adopt such a strategy. Our predictions for how accessibility should relate to the various decision variables align with the results from previous studies showing that choices between options that are more easily accessible in memory result in faster response times <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Fazio et al., 1992)</ref>, that options that are more accessible in memory are more likely to be chosen <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Gwinn &amp; Krajbich, 2020)</ref>, and that options that feel more familiar are both more likely to be chosen and chosen more quickly and confidently <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Lee, 2024)</ref>. They also conceptually align with previous evidence showing that, in general, people prefer options that are easier to process <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Oppenheimer, 2008)</ref> or that processing fluency magnifies the informational content of the stimuli <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hertwig et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Landwehr &amp; Eckmann, 2020)</ref>. Such factors might be analogous to one option having greater accessibility, hence our anticipation of the potential impact of accessibility difference.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>To test the theoretical predictions, we designed an experiment in which we orthogonally manipulate mean, variability, and accessibility. We record gaze fixation patterns with an eyetracking setup. Our core analyses are based on mixed effects regression models. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>The stimuli used in this study were sequential numerical displays. Each option on each trial consisted of a stream of two-digit numbers randomly generated from a Gaussian distribution with a predetermined mean and standard deviation. Randomly interleaved within each stream were pairs of English letters in the place of the numbers. The displays updated three times per second. We independently manipulated three factors for each option on each trial: mean, variability, and accessibility. The mean corresponded to the mean of the Gaussian distribution from which the individually-displayed numbers were drawn. The variability corresponded to the standard deviation of the distribution from which the numbers were drawn. The accessibility corresponded to the probability that each display sample would be a number (rather than a pair of letters, which were explained to be task-irrelevant distractors). We created pairs of options using a 2x2x2 design for mean difference, variability difference, and accessibility difference (low vs high for each variable). Specifically, we created each pair as follows. We set the value of one of the options (randomly assigned to the left or right) to a random sample from a uniform (40,55) distribution.</p><p>We then set the value of the other option to the value of the first option plus either 4 (low mean difference condition) or 8 (high mean difference condition). We set the variability of one of the options (randomly assigned to the left or right) to 6 and the variability of the other option to either 8 (low variability difference condition) or 12 (high variability difference condition). We set the accessibility of one of the options (randomly assigned to the left or right) to 90 and the accessibility of the other option to either 80 (low accessibility difference condition) or 70 (high accessibility difference condition). Crucially, we manipulated these three factors independently so that they were orthogonal to each other, meaning that knowing something about the accessibility of one option does not provide any information about the mean or variability of the other option on any trial. Once all the choice pairs had been created, we shuffled them such that trials from the eight conditions would appear in a random order across the experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants were asked to report which stream of numbers (the left or right option) they believed came from the distribution with the greater mean. They were instructed to consider the true generating means of the random processes, not the exact means of the specific samples they observed. They were instructed to ignore the letters that sometimes appeared instead of numbers, as there was no significance to them and they served only as distractors. All participants confirmed that they understood the instructions and were able to successfully explain the task back to the experimenter. Participants were informed that the experiment would consist of 200 trials, without any time limits. They were informed that all trials were independentthey should respond only according to the current trial without considering the previous trials. After every 40 trials, participants were given the opportunity to take a self-paced break before continuing.</p><p>On each trial, a pair of options was presented on the computer monitor (one on the left side of the screen at 25% of the width of the screen starting from the left, one on the right side at 75% of the width of the screen starting from the left; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). Importantly, the distance from the center, the fairly small font size (50 point), and the rapid rate of change rendered it impossible for participants to see what was displayed on a given side of the screen unless they diverted their gaze towards that side. This was confirmed by debriefing during pilot testing. At the top of the screen, the question "Which sequence has the greater average?" was displayed. Trials were self-paced; the displays continued to update until participants entered a response. Participants used the left and right arrows on the computer keyboard to enter their choice of the left or right option, respectively.</p><p>After reporting their choice on each trial, the options disappeared, and a vertical slider scale for choice confidence appeared at the center of the screen. Participants were asked, "How sure are you about your choice?" They used the up and down arrow keys to move a cursor along the scale anywhere from "Not at all!" (minimum confidence) to "Absolutely!" (maximum confidence).</p><p>They submitted their confidence rating by pressing the space bar. After reporting the confidence on each trial, the scale disappeared, and participants received feedback about their performance on that trial. Specifically, if they answered correctly on that trial, a green "+1" appeared at the center of the screen; if they answered incorrectly, a red "-1" appeared. Thus, on each trial, participants either gained or lost one point. At the end of the experiment, we converted the cumulative point total to a monetary bonus payment at the rate of 10 points = 1 shekel. A participant who responded correctly on all trials would therefore earn a bonus of 20 shekels; a participant who responded randomly (or otherwise performed at or below chance level) would not earn any bonus. (No participants earned negative points, but if they had, the amount of their bonus would have been zero, not a reduction of their base payment).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Eye tracking</head><p>We recorded eye gaze fixation location (with a particular interest in the x-coordinates) continuously throughout the experiment using a Tobii-Pro eye tracker. We set the sampling rate to 120 Hz. Each participant performed the default calibration task prior to commencing the experiment. After collecting the data, we divided it into epochs for each trial (for each participant) using the "trial onset" and "response" triggers that we included in our data collection script. We averaged the x-coordinates for the left and right eyes and used that as our measure for the gaze location. For any points in time where the eye tracker failed to record a signal (e.g., during blinks), we interpolated from the surrounding signals. Specifically, for any contiguous gaps, we set the values within those gaps equal to the average of the immediately preceding and subsequent values.</p><p>Finally, we classified gaze direction as being toward the left at any point in time if the x-coordinate was somewhere less than 40% of the width of the screen and as being toward the right if the xcoordinate was somewhere greater than 60% of the width of the screen. Whenever the x-coordinate was somewhere between 40% and 60% of the width of the screen, we classified gaze direction as being toward the center. In all relevant analyses reported below, we ignored gazes toward the center and only considered gazes toward the left and right (i.e., toward the choice options).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Before undertaking our main analyses, we first checked to see if any participants failed to meet our performance threshold of 60% accuracy. We determined this threshold by calculating the standard error of a binomial distribution of random choice (p = 0.5) and adding three times the standard error to chance level. Two participants performed worse than this threshold, so we excluded those participants from our analyses. We also excluded four additional participants because their eye-tracking data did not record properly. All analyses reported below are therefore based on the remaining 44 participants. We note that the behavioral results did not change when we repeated the analyses without excluding the four participants with missing eye-tracking data, but we decided to exclude them nonetheless for consistency with reporting the gaze-related results.</p><p>For each participant, we excluded from analysis all trials with outlier response times (RTs)defined as within-participant median log(RT) +/-three times the within participant median average deviation of log(RT). For the model-free analyses reported below, all significance levels were determined by two-sample t-tests. For the regression analyses, we used the fitlme function in <ref type="bibr">Lee,</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsetsos,</ref><ref type="bibr">Pezzulo,</ref><ref type="bibr">Shahar,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; Usher 16</ref> MATLAB. All regression analyses were based on mixed effects models with participants as random effects (both intercepts and slopes). In each of our regression models, we replace all predictor variables with their z-score transformations and keep the outcome variables in their original form. By doing so, the resultant regression coefficients are semi-partial correlations between the independent and dependent variables and can thus provide an objective indication of effect sizes that is easy to interpret.</p><p>As a preliminary check for the general quality of our data, we performed a series of crossparticipant tests. First, we observed a clear speed-accuracy tradeoff across participantsthose who achieved higher accuracy had longer average RT (r = 0.57; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2a</ref>). Second, we observed metacognitive calibration (subjective confidence aligned well with objective accuracy) across participantsthose whose accuracy was higher had higher average confidence levels (r = 0.43; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2b</ref>). Third, we observed metacognitive sensitivity. Specifically, when separating trials according to a median split on confidence (within participant), high confidence trials corresponded to accuracy levels significantly greater than those for low confidence trials (mean difference = 0.117, p &lt; .001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2c</ref>). Fourth, we observed a negative relationship between confidence and RTwhen separating trials according to a median split on confidence (within participant), low confidence trials corresponded to significantly greater RT than did high confidence trials (RT zscored within participant; mean difference = 0.332, p &lt; .001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2d</ref>). For the remaining analyses, we computed what we call the observed input variables to use instead of what we call the generative input variables. The generative (i.e., hypothetical or steadystate) input simply refers to the trial-by-trial parameters that we established in our experimental design: the mean and standard deviation of each Gaussian random number generator and the probability that each display update would contain a number rather than a letter. The observed input refers to parameters that summarize what the participants actually saw on each trial. Because we designed the experiment such that participants would not likely be able to see the stimulus on the right side of the screen while their gaze was focused toward the left (and vice versa), we decided that it made the most sense for us to include as input data only the information from stimuli that the participants explicitly gazed at. We were able to do this because on each trial, we recorded the exact streams of numbers and letters that were displayed as well as the exact timing of when participants were looking at the left or right options. We thus know exactly which sets of numbers and letters participants observed for each option on each trial. Our observed input for each option is the mean and standard deviation of these observed sets of numbers, and the percentage of numbers contained within each set 2 . From this point forward, when we refer to the mean, variability, and accessibility variables, we refer to these observed input variables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dependency of gaze on decision variables</head><p>We wanted to test how the decision variables (mean, variability, and accessibility) might affect gaze allocation across the full duration of each trial. We thus first calculated the percentage of time within each trial that the gaze was to the left or to the right (or neither). We calculated the percentage of time within a trial that the gaze was to the left minus the percentage to the right (ignoring gazes toward the center) and labeled this variable as gaze percentage difference (dGaze).</p><p>We then regressed dGaze on differences in each of the decision variables (dMean, dVar, and dAccess; all left minus right). All variables were z-scored across trials and participants before entering the regression design matrix. We found that participants gazed more at the option (within a choice pair) with the higher mean (regression coefficient = 0.05, p = .006) and less at the option with higher accessibility (regression coefficient = -0.11, p &lt; .001), in line with our predictions.</p><p>However, we did not find our predicted effect of variability on gaze allocation (p = .821). Together, our regressors accounted for 37% of the variance in gaze percentage difference (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3a)</ref>. We thought it might be possible that the drivers of gaze allocation were dynamic in the sense that they might develop across decision time. Specifically, the impact of each decision variable on gaze might differ from the beginning to the end of each trial. The idea is that people would look more at uncertain options at the beginning of the trial in order to gather more information and increase their certainty about the mean estimates, whereas towards the end of the trial, people might instead look more at the options for which their mean estimates were highest.</p><p>To test this, we divided the data into quarters based on time from stimulus onset until eventual response (within each trial for each participant). We regressed dGaze during the first quarter of each trial on the same regressors as before (dMean, dVar, dAccess) except now calculated using <ref type="bibr">Lee,</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsetsos,</ref><ref type="bibr">Pezzulo,</ref><ref type="bibr">Shahar,</ref><ref type="bibr">&amp; Usher 20</ref> only the samples that the participants observed during the first quarter of each trial. We then regressed dGaze during the second, third, and fourth quarters of each trial (Q1-4) on dMean, dVar, and dAccess, now calculated according to all samples that participants observed through that time interval (i.e., Q2 included samples from Q1-2, Q3 included samples from Q1-3, Q4 included samples from Q1-4). This is because during each quarter of a trial, participants would retain the information that they had acquired during the previous quarters of that trial. The values of dGaze for each quarter were calculated in a similar manner. All variables were z-scored across trials and participants before entering the regression design matrix. We found that at the beginning of trials, participants did indeed gaze more at more uncertain options (regression coefficient = 0.17, p &lt; .001). They also gazed less at more accessible options (regression coefficient = -0.09, p &lt; .001).</p><p>We did not find a significant effect of mean on early gaze fixations (p = .189). The pattern was different at the end of trials. Now, mean did have a significant impact on gaze allocation, with participants looking more at the higher-valued option (regression coefficient = 0.05, p = .007) as well as the lower-accessibility option (regression coefficient = -0.10, p &lt; .001). We did not find a significant effect of variability on where participants looked towards the end of each trial (p = .974). This differentiation between early and late effects seems to have arisen across time, as demonstrated by the gradual change in regression coefficients from Q1-4 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3b</ref>). The gradual increase in weight for mean was only a trend, but the decrease in weight for variability was statistically robust for every time bin (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Material)</ref>.</p><p>Finally, we tested whether the duration of fixations changed across time (within trials). We found that the duration gradually decreased, with early fixations lasting longer and later fixations reaching an apparent lower asymptote (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>). This could possibly be explained by assuming that early fixations need to endure longer to enable the decision maker to establish the "context" (e.g., which option has greater variability or information accessibility) for the current decision. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Are the observed gaze patterns normative?</head><p>From a normative perspective, as participants refine the precision of their mean estimates, they should sample more when the samples they observe are either less accessible or more variable.</p><p>We tested for such normative behavior by examining the streams of samples that participants observed. First, we counted the observed meaningful samples (i.e., numbers rather than letters) for each option on each trial for each participant. We then calculated the mean of the count of meaningful samples for each participant (across trials and options), separately for low and high accessibility options (median split within participant). We found that there was no significant difference between the low and high accessibility options (low = 13.22, high = 13.87, difference p = .154). This suggests that participants used a similar sampling strategy for options with low or high accessibility, after accounting for the meaningless samples. We then tested for correlations between accessibility and number of meaningful samples (within participant). Across participants, we found a significant average correlation (0.05, p = .018). This qualitatively differs from the average correlation between accessibility and number of total samples (-0.06, p &lt; .001). This demonstrates that participants appropriately observed more total samples for options with lower accessibility, but that they might not have fully compensated for lower accessibility by observing enough additional samples (possibly due to an increasing cost of sampling or an urgency signal encouraging a response).</p><p>We repeated the above analyses with respect to variance instead of accessibility. We did not find a significant difference between the low and high variability options (low = 13.36, high = 13.39, difference p = .823). This suggests that participants used a similar sampling strategy for options with low or high variability, after accounting for the meaningless samples. We then tested for correlations between variability and number of meaningful samples (within participant).</p><p>Across participants, we did not find a significant average correlation (0.02, p = .105).</p><p>The theoretical benefit of observing more samples when estimating the mean of a distribution would be to reduce the standard error of the mean estimate (SEM). We thus tested whether participants seemed to sample in a manner that might best achieve this goal. For each option for each trial for each participant, we traced the evolution of the SEM across the observed samples. Then, for each trial, we recorded both the final SEM of each option at the time of the response and the maximum SEM for each option over the course of the trial. We then divided individual options based on accessibility (median split within participant) and pooled the options across participants. We found that there was no difference in either the max SEM (low mean = 5.68, high mean = 5.64, difference p = .362) or the last SEM (low mean = 2.59, high mean = 2.52, difference p = .069) between low and high accessibility trials. We performed a similar test based on low versus high variability options and found a significant difference in max SEM (as expected; low mean = 5.17, high mean = 6.12, difference p &lt; .001) as well as in last SEM (low mean = 2.36, high mean = 2.75, difference p &lt; .001). The difference in last SEM, however, was much smaller than the difference in max SEM (-0.39 versus -0.95, p &lt; .001). Together, this suggests that participants considered the accessibility and to a lesser extent the variability of observed samples when determining how long to continue sampling, perhaps with the notion of achieving a target level of SEM for each option before deciding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relationships between decision variables and choice behavior</head><p>We then examined choice behavior (accuracy, RT, and confidence) to test our predictions.</p><p>We tested for effects of all our independent decision variablesmean sum (sMean), mean difference (dMean), variability sum (sVar), variability difference (dVar), accessibility sum (sAccess), and accessibility difference (dAccess)on each of our dependent variables separately.</p><p>Recall that all independent variables were calculated based only on the samples (numbers and letters) that the participants actually observed for each option on each trial. All the difference terms were calculated based on the higher-mean-valued option minus the lower-mean-valued option. In this way, the correlations that would have otherwise existed between sVar and dVar and between sAccess and dAccess are nullified (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Material)</ref>. Accuracy is based on the greater true generative mean for each trial, which is what participants knew they had to report. To test for potential effects when examining all independent variables simultaneously, we conducted a series of mixed effects regression analyses. The fixed effects regressors in each model were the independent variables listed above. All variables were z-scored across trials and participants before entering the regression design matrix. The models included a logistic regression of accuracy and linear regressions of log(RT) and confidence.</p><p>As expected, there was a strong effect of mean difference on all three behavioral variables (regression coefficients: accuracy: = 0.11, p &lt; .001; RT = -0.16, p &lt; .001; confidence = 0.06, p &lt; .001). Consistent with previous findings, there was a significant effect of mean sum on RT (regression coefficient = -0.03, p = .003) and confidence (regression coefficient = 0.02, p &lt; .001), but not on accuracy (p = .515). Consistent with previous findings, there was an effect of variability sum on all three behavioral variables (regression coefficients: accuracy = -0.02, p &lt; .001; RT = 0.02, p = .029; confidence = -0.01, p = .001). There was a significant effect of variability difference on all three behavioral variables, but the pattern of results was the opposite of what has previously been reported (regression coefficients: accuracy = 0.03, p &lt; .001; RT = -0.02, p = .005; confidence = 0.01, p = .004). As we predicted, there was a significant effect of accessibility sum on RT (regression coefficient = -0.07, p &lt; .001), but we did not find our predicted effect of accessibility sum on accuracy or confidence (p = .186 and p = .153, respectively). As we predicted, there was a significant effect of accessibility difference on accuracy (regression coefficient = 0.02, p &lt; .001) and confidence (regression coefficient = 0.01, p &lt; .001), but we did not find our predicted effect of accessibility difference on RT (p = .961). Together, our regressors accounted for 13%, 60%, and 42%, respectively, of the variance in accuracy, log(RT), and confidence (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref>). Next, we examined the eye-tracking data to test for associations between gaze and choice, while accounting for the primary explanatory variables analyzed above. First, we ran a logistic regression of choice (probability of choosing the left option) on the differences (left minus right) of mean, variability, accessibility, and gaze percentage (i.e., the percentage of time within a trial that the gaze fixation was to the left minus the percentage to the right). All fixed effects coefficients were positive and significant (mean difference = 1.90, variability difference = 0.23, accessibility difference = 0.09, gaze difference = 0.14; all p-values &lt; .001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6a</ref>). In particular, this was true for the coefficient reflecting the relationship between gaze and choice (beyond the effects of mean, variability, and accessibility), which replicates previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Gwinn &amp; Krajbich, 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Interestingly, but in line with the results reported above, the coefficient for variability difference shows that people were more likely to choose the option associated with greater variability, which is counter to previous findings as well as our prediction. We also note that the intercept term was positive and significant (0.50, p &lt; .001), indicating that participants tended to prefer the option on the left. Together, our regressors accounted for 58% of the variance in choice probability.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6b</ref>). Note that the simplified model performs at a level identical to that of the more complex model (both r 2 = 0.58), suggesting that information sampling rate is the critical element whether controlled by the experimenter (via accessibility) or the participant (via gaze fixation). We repeated the regression again this time replacing dAccess and dGaze with dN, where dN was the difference (left minus right) in the total count of numerical samples observed for each option within a trial. Again, the results were very similar (regression coefficient for dN = 0.41, p &lt; .001; r 2 = 0.57).</p><p>A correlation matrix of the main decision variables, a summary of the correlations between generative parameters and observed parameters, and a histogram of gaze fixation locations are provided in the Supplementary Material.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In this study, we examined the drivers of gaze fixation patterns across decision time in a two-alternative forced choice paradigm. Specifically, we sought to validate recent theoretical claims that fixations should be directed more towards choice options whose values are more uncertain. Attention to a specific option is thought to trigger additional information processing about that option, which in turn should help reduce the uncertainty about its value. Fixations should thus be directed towards options with higher variability in noisy evidence about their true value.</p><p>For similar reasons, fixations should be directed towards options with lower information accessibility. The beneficial information processing that attention can enable will be reduced when the accessibility of information about an option is lower, meaning that people would have to maintain their gaze fixation longer on that option in order to extract information about it. Our data only partially validated these hypotheses. At the full-trial level, relative gaze dwell time favored options whose observed stimulus samples were less accessible (i.e., more of the samples were meaningless letters), but not those whose samples were more variable (i.e., the standard deviation of the observed numerical values was greater).</p><p>The former is consistent with the idea that the purpose of a gaze fixation is to allocate attention to an option with the intention of extracting information about it. Non-numeric samples directly reduce the information content in a given stream. Once people shift their gaze towards an option, the informativeness of the samples that they obtain might determine how long they linger before shifting their attention towards the other option. It thus seems that people might behave at least somewhat normatively when deciding how long to fixate on each option, at least with respect to information accessibility. It could be that the goal is to extract a specific amount of information about each option and to respond when a pre-defined certainty criterion has been achieved for one estimate being greater than the other. Our findings related to the final standard errors of the mean estimates on each trialirrespective of accessibilitysupport this idea. Future studies are needed to identify the putative normative criterion to terminate a fixation, which should depend on participant-specific parameters for how costly accumulating evidence is and how beneficial increased certainty is <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Fudenberg et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Tajima et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Our participants seemed to pay more attention to highly variable streams of numerical samples at the beginning of each trial. However, as noted above, it seems that they did not pay more attention to highly variable streams of numerical samples across the full duration of a trial.</p><p>This might make sense if gaze fixations serve to enable information gathering. People may accumulate information across fixations rather than within them, in which case they may simply observe a series of samples for each option before switching their attention back to the other option hence, at the whole-trial level, they would have no need to look more at the option with greater variability.</p><p>With respect to value, people should seek information about both options (at least at the beginning of each trial). The purpose of a fixation might thus be to extract information regardless of its content, because developing a sense of the average value of an option would benefit from obtaining both high-and low-valued samples. However, after multiple fixations to each option, people may start to form a belief about which is more valuable, and they will respond when this belief becomes strong enough. By the end of the trial, people will start to look more at the option that they are preparing to choose. This could explain our finding that our participants fixated more on the option with the higher mean across the full trialand especially late in the trial.</p><p>According to our interpretation of the gaze allocation results discussed above, we expected a different pattern early in the trial that would gradually transform into the full-trial pattern as information accumulated across the trial. Indeed, this is what we found. Specifically, we found that our participants did not pay more attention to more valuable options at the beginning of the trial, but that a bias in attention gradually increased with longer time epochs. We also found that our participants paid more attention to the more variable options at the beginning of the trial, and that this bias in attention gradually disappeared when considering increasing time epochs. With respect to accessibility, we found that our participants paid more attention to options with lower accessibility, both early on and across the whole trial. This is interesting because it distinguishes the detriment to mean estimation caused by variability from that caused by accessibility. When people seek more information by initiating an additional fixation, the presence of distractor samples never provides any information. In that case, people may maintain their fixations longer as they wait for the information that they continue to seek. This explanation for the dynamic pattern of these results also aligns with our finding that early fixations endured longer than later fixations.</p><p>It could be that at the beginning of each trial, uncertainty is maximal, so more samples are needed when the variability of the samples is high. Later in the trial, samples obtained from additional fixations might simply be accumulated together with earlier samples to fine-tune the emerging value representations. In that case, fewer samples (i.e., shorter fixations) would be needed to revise a value representation (later in the trial) than to establish it in the first place (early in the trial). This speculative interpretation of our findings remains to be fully tested in future studies.</p><p>Previous studies have reported a "gaze bias" in which people choose options that they viewed for longer, even after controlling for value difference. This has been shown in preferential choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Gluth et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Sepulveda et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2019)</ref>, risky choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Fiedler &amp; Glöckner, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Stewart et al., 2016)</ref>, and even perceptual choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">(Tavares et al., 2017)</ref>. We show that this effect also holds in the domain of numerical averaging. This is intriguing since there was no subjective component to our taskparticipants simply had to form rough latent estimations of the means of the two numerical streams and report which one was greater. Our finding aligns with the interpretation that attention magnifies information that aligns with any decision goal <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Sepulveda et al., 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Although previous studies have interpreted the observed effect of gaze on choice as a bias, this is not the only possible interpretation. It could be that looking longer at an option is tantamount to collecting more information samples about that option, in which case the subjective precision about the value estimate of that option would be greater than for the other option. Since people prefer options for which their subjective precision or certainty is greater <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Frömer et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020)</ref>, this could be a simple explanation for the "gaze bias". In our experimental paradigm, gazing longer at an option is synonymous with observing more samples about it, holding constant the accessibility rate. For any option, the relative gaze time multiplied by the relative accessibility rate directly computes the relative number of informative samples about that option.</p><p>We validated this logic by showing that a regression of choice that included the difference in accessibility*gaze provided results indistinguishable from those of a model including the difference in accessibility and the difference in gaze proportion as independent regressors. Furthermore, a model that replaced accessibility and gaze with a direct count of numerical samples (left option minus right option) was also nearly indistinguishable.</p><p>With our behavioral results, we demonstrated the importance of information accessibility and its influence on choice: accuracy, response time (RT), and confidence. We found that choices are significantly faster when there is greater overall accessibility across the options. This makes sense, because it means that the same amount of information can be gained sooner as the potential rate of information processing is higher. This increase in speed was not matched with an increase in confidence, as is usually the case. Perhaps this is because people often use the speed with which they could determine their response as an indicator of the likelihood that they were correct, whereas in this case, this correspondence is polluted by the inclusion of distractors. Simply put, people might realize they are slower when accessibility is lower not because the trial is more difficult, but simply because they have to wait longer to ignore the distracting letters. We also found that our participants were more accurate and more confident when the correct option had greater accessibility than the incorrect option. This could be due to the apparent preference that they had for choosing the option with greater accessibility (and thus they would be more accurate when that option was the correct one).</p><p>The preference that our participants showed for options with high accessibilityon top of their preference for high meanis intriguing. Perhaps when accessibility is low in our task, the presence of many distractor letters makes mean estimates less precise, and this lack of precision deters participants. Future work could test this hypothesis by requiring participants to report mean estimates and confidence levels for individual options with different accessibility levels. A tendency to prefer high accessibility options could also be indicative of a leaky accumulation process while people are developing a value estimate from incoming input signals <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(Usher &amp; McClelland, 2001</ref>). The latent mean estimates that participants form during our task could be updated optimally (e.g., in a Bayesian manner) with each new numerical sample that they observe. But, when they observe letters rather than numbers, their value representations might decay towards their (flat) priors. Future work should investigate this issue further, possibly by varying the length of time between stimulus updates and/or the presence of distractors versus empty space.</p><p>Our behavioral results replicate many previous findings, including the unsurprising result that high mean difference corresponds to higher accuracy, faster RT, and higher confidence. We also replicated the intuitive result that the sum of variability in information about a pair of options corresponds to lower accuracy, slower RT, and lower confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lee &amp; Hare, 2023)</ref>. Interestingly, we also replicated the finding that the sum of values across options corresponds to faster RT and higher confidence. This has been show in preferential choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Frömer et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lee &amp; Hare, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">Smith &amp; Krajbich, 2019)</ref>, risky choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Hunt et al., 2012)</ref>, and even perceptual choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Polanía et al., 2014)</ref>. We show that this effect also holds in the domain of numerical estimation. This might suggest that individual samples with large numerical values are inherently salient, causing them to be processed faster because they receive more attentional resources. Or it might simply be that "large" stimuli contain more information, regardless of the form that the information takes. The idea would be that neural activity in response to the query, "How large is this (in whatever relevant dimension)?" would be greater for largervalued samples and thus allow the response to be formed more quickly.</p><p>Perhaps the most unexpected of our behavioral results was the apparent preference that participants had for the option with the greater variability (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6</ref>). Participants were also more accurate, faster, and more confident on trials where the correct option displayed more sample variance than the incorrect option. This is the opposite of what has been reported in preferential choice, where people favor options for which they feel more certain about the values <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Frömer et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Lee &amp; Coricelli, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lee &amp; Hare, 2023)</ref>. It is also opposite to the very concepts of ambiguity aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Ellsberg, 1961)</ref> and risk aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Pratt, 1964)</ref>.</p><p>However, it is in line with the tenets of Selective Integration (SI) Theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Glickman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">Tsetsos et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">Usher et al., 2019)</ref>. According to that line of work, when participants must choose between a pair of numerical streams (as in our experiment), they are biased in favor of the option whose samples are generated by the distribution with the greater variance. The theory explains this phenomenon by proposing an increase in the relative weighting of the sample draw (left or right) that is greater in numerical magnitude at any point in time. The option with the greater variance will have more numerically high sample draws, which will receive an increased weighting. The same option will also have more numerically low sample draws, but those will effectively be ignored because attention will be directed toward the other option during those time epochs. The net effect is that the comparison of mean estimates ends up being biased in favor of the high-variance option. A key difference between the designs in the SI studies and ours relates to the ability to view both streams of numbers simultaneously. In those previous studies, the stimuli displays were positioned close together on the computer screen, intentionally allowing participants to view everything at the same time. In our study, we intentionally positioned the stimuli displays far apart on the computer screen because we wanted to be sure that participants could only observe one option at a time by directing their gaze towards one side of the screen. Therefore, we cannot directly apply the SI theory (as it has previously been described) to our current work. However, it is possible that the fundamental principles of the theory nevertheless apply. If numerically larger samples are more salient than numerically smaller samples, this would trigger a larger automatic arousal when larger numbers are displayed. The increase in attention caused by the arousal would in turn give those samples a greater weight as they are combined with other samples to form an estimate of the mean. The end result would be that people would overestimate the means for streams of numbers with high variance relative to low. If true, this would explain the preference for options with greater variability that we observed in our data. Preliminary <ref type="bibr">(unpublished)</ref> evidence from our team supports thisin a task where participants had to estimate the means of solitary streams of numbers, there was an average overestimation and the degree of overestimation positively correlated with the standard deviation of the observed samples (but see <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Olschewski et al., 2021)</ref> for conflicting evidence). Future work might attempt to better understand this curious result and resolve its origin. Perhaps the explanation is something as simple as: when people see a very high outlier sample for an option, it makes it seem obvious that that is the option with the greater mean; since the task is precisely to find the option with the greatest mean, there might not be a similar effect for very low outlier samples.</p><p>Finally, there is an interesting relationship between the concepts of variability and inaccessibility. In some ways, the concepts are similar. For example, variability and inaccessibility both reduce the efficiency of information sampling. They both, therefore, likely interfere with the ability of participants to estimate the mean values of the number streams in our experiment. Yet the concepts are also different in some fundamental respects. For example, variability (in the form of sample distribution variance) makes it more difficult to infer the mean value but inaccessibility should only slow it down (i.e., a display of letters should not impact the latent value representations). However, inaccessibility might also make the task more difficult if the dynamic mean estimation process has a leak or decay. In that case, the precision of the option value representations that develops over time by incorporating additional numerical samples might dissipate when letters are instead observed. This could explain why low accessibility (sum) and high variability (sum) showed very similar effects in the behavioral data (choice, RT, and confidence). This speculative interpretation of our findings remains to be fully tested in future studies that include computational modeling. and accessibility: sMean, dMean, sVar, dVar, sAcc, dAcc). We did not find any correlations (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>). When designing our experiment, we established discrete levels of mean, variability, and accessibility, which in turn resulted in pre-determined discrete levels of the sums and differences of each decision variable (sMean, dMean, sVar, dVar, sAcc, dAcc). These pre-determined levels were used to generate the samples that each participant was shown on each trial. However, our analyses were based on the actual samples that participants observed, not on the generative levels of each variable. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref> summarizes the relationship between the generative levels and the observed levels of each decision variable across participants and trials. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S2</ref>. Generative versus observed decision variables. For each primary decision variable, the pre-determined discrete generative values resulted in a range of observed values across trials and participants. Each blue dot represents one trial.</p><p>Our gaze fixation location analyses relied on a simple coarse classification of left versus right. However, it could have been the case that participants frequently viewed towards the middle of the screen as they attempted to simultaneously view both options in their peripheral vision. Or perhaps participants might have gazed towards other parts of the computer screen in ways that we did not anticipate. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure S3</ref> shows that the momentary gaze location across all trials and participants was predominantly towards either the left or right options, with a high degree of precision. Gaze was very rarely directed towards the center of the screen (this typically occurred only at the beginning of each trial). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure S3</ref>. Gaze location distribution. Across all trials and participants, gaze location was almost always directed toward the choice options (either left or right) and only rarely toward the center (mostly at the beginning of each trial). Solid red lines indicate the exact center of each stimulus.</p><p>Dotted red lines indicate the frontiers by which we defined whether a gaze was directed toward the left, center, or right side of the screen.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Test for significance of changes in regression weights for gaze across time bins</head><p>In the main text, we showed that the drivers of gaze allocation might be dynamic in the sense that they seemed to develop across decision time (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3b)</ref>. As a reminder, we divided the data into quarters based on time from stimulus onset until eventual response (within each trial for each participant). We regressed dGaze during the first quarter of each trial on the same regressors as before (dMean, dVar, dAccess) except now calculated using only the samples that the participants observed during the first quarter of each trial. We then regressed dGaze during the second, third, and fourth quarters of each trial (Q1-4) on dMean, dVar, and dAccess, now calculated according to all samples that participants observed through that time interval (i.e., Q2 included samples from Q1-2, Q3 included samples from Q1-3, Q4 included samples from Q1-4).</p><p>The values of dGaze for each quarter were calculated in a similar manner. We found that at the beginning of trials, participants gazed more at more uncertain options and less at more accessible options. We found that at the end of trials, participants gazed more at the higher-valued option as well as the lower-accessibility option. This differentiation between early and late effects seems to have arisen across time, as demonstrated by the gradual change in regression coefficients from Q1-4 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3b</ref>). To test whether these changes were statistically significant, we combined the design matrices and outcome vectors from all of the separate regressions (for each time bin) into one expanded design matrix and one expanded outcome vector. In this expanded model, we also included the following indicator variables: "includes Q2" for the data from quarters 2-4, "includes Q3" for the data from quarters 3-4, and "includes Q4" for the data from quarter 4. The regression model thus consisted of each primary regressor (mean, variability, and accessibility) plus the interactions of each primary regressor and each of the indicator variables. The main effects of variability and accessibility were significant (variability beta = 0.18, p &lt; .001; accessibility beta = -0.10, p &lt; .001), showing that these variables had an impact on gaze in Q1. The interaction effects for variability were all significant ("includes Q2" beta = -0.04, p = .005; "includes Q3" beta = -0.06, p &lt; .001; "includes Q4" beta = -0.09, p &lt; .001), showing that the impact of variability on gaze reliably diminished across trial time. The interaction effects for mean were not statistically significant ("includes Q2" beta = 0.01, p = .584; "includes Q3" beta = 0.00, p = .799; "includes Q4" beta = 0.01, p = .466).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>An illustrative example of a choice trial.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>A</head><label></label><figDesc>total of 50 people participated in the experiment (28 female; age: mean = 24 years, SD = 5, range 19-45). All participants were recruited via Tel Aviv University Sona Systems, either through the Department of Psychological Sciences or the Behavioral Lab at the Coller School of Management. All were self-declared fluent English speakers. As compensation for approximately one hour of time, each participant received either a payment of 40 shekels (approximately $11) or course credit. Each participant also received up to 20 shekels as a bonus payment calculated according to performance. The experimental procedure was approved by the Ethics Board of the Department of Psychological Sciences at Tel Aviv University. All participants gave written informed consent prior to commencing the experiment.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Cross-participant relationships between accuracy, response time, and confidence. Dots represent individual participant averages. Error bars represent means +/-standard errors. *** p &lt; .001</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Regression coefficients for gaze percentage difference. Shown here are the fixed effects coefficient estimates when regressing gaze percentage difference (left minus right) on differences (all left minus right) in mean (dMean), variability (dVar), and accessibility (dAccess). Plot a shows the effects at the full trial level. Plot b shows the effects for the first, second, third, and fourth quarters of each trial (Q1-4; see legend for color code). The regressors within each time interval are based on an accumulation of observed samples since trial onset. Error bars represent 95% C.I.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fixation duration across time. Early fixations (within each trial) had longer gaze duration than later fixations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Regression coefficients for choice behavior. Shown here are the fixed effects coefficient estimates when regressing accuracy (plot a), log(RT) (plot b), and confidence (plot c) on mean sum (sMean), mean difference (dMean), variability sum (sVar), variability difference (dVar), accessibility sum (sAccess), and accessibility difference (dAccess). Error bars represent 95% C.I.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Regression coefficients for choice probability. a) Fixed effects coefficient estimates when regressing choice (probability of choosing the left option) on differences (all left minus right) in mean (dMean), variability (dVar), accessibility (dAccess), and gaze percentage (dGaze). b)Fixed effects coefficient estimates when regressing choice on dMean, dVar, and the difference in the product of accessibility and gaze proportion (d(Acc*Gaze)). Error bars represent 95% C.I.Gaze time and accessibility rate both represent different aspects of a similar phenomenon: accumulating information. The number of total samples observed is determined by gaze time, and the percentage of those samples that are informative is determined by accessibility rate. Together, this means that the combination of the two (gaze*accessibility) represents the number of informative samples observed for an option. To validate our hypothesis that gaze and accessibility were two parts of a unified variable, we repeated the regression of choice this time replacing dAccess and dGaze with d(Acc*Gaze). The results were very similar (regression coefficient for d(Acc*Gaze) = 0.16, p &lt; .001;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure S1 .</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Correlation of decision variables. None of the primary decision variables correlated with each other.</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">We also considered an alternative approach, in which the input variables were "accumulated". Specifically, within each gaze fixation, we weighted the contribution of each sample according to the amount of time that it was observed. This basically meant that samples at the beginning and end of each fixation were given less weight than the other samples. The results of all analyses reported below were qualitatively identical and quantitatively similar when using these accumulated input variables.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Constraints on Generality</head><p>The participants in our study were predominantly Israeli citizens. We have no good reason to believe that the results should differ in participant pools of other origins, but that is an empirical question. Similarly, our participants were predominantly aged in their early 20s, so we cannot be sure if testing older adults would yield similar results. The choice options in the dataset we analyzed were all snack foods, so we cannot be sure if similar results would arise in other domains.</p><p>We believe that different elicitation methods for or different operalizations of the concept of familiarity or information availability should yield similar results, though we acknowledge that that is an empirical question.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data and Code Availability</head><p>The data and analysis code used in preparation of this manuscript are publicly available on the Open Science Framework at https://osf.io/tzam2/ <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Lee, 2023)</ref>. We designed our experiment such that the differences in the generative mean, the generative variance, and the generative accessibility (probability of each sample being a number rather than letters) of the options within each trial would be orthogonal to each other. However, due to the manner in which we established the parameters for each trial, the sum and difference of variability and the sum and difference of accessibility were perfectly correlated. Nevertheless, the fact that we based on analyses on observed samples rather than generative parameters and our definition of difference to be the measure of the higher-mean-valued option minus the measure of the lower-mean-valued option should have removed such correlations. To validate that the intended orthogonality held for the observed variables that we included in our analyses, we tested for correlations across all primary decision variables (sums and differences in mean, variability,</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biasing simple choices by manipulating relative visual attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Beaumel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="403" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1930297500000413</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1930297500000413" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biasing simple choices by manipulating relative visual attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Beaumel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1930297500000413</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1930297500000413" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention Constraints and Learning in Categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bhui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Jiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1287/mnsc.2023.4803</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2023.4803" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5394" to="5404" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceptual decision making: Drift-diffusion model is equivalent to a Bayesian model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bitzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Blankenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kiebel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnhum.2014.00102</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fnhum.2014.00102" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of the speed-accuracy tradeoff</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nieuwenhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Neurosciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tins.2009.09.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2009.09.002" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fixation patterns in simple choice reflect optimal information sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Callaway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1008863</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1008863</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1008863" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive Sampling of Information in Perceptual Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Cassey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Evens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A R</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J H</forename><surname>Ludwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0078993</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0078993" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye tracking and pupillometry are indicators of dissociable latent decision processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cavanagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Wiecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kochar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0035813</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0035813" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">143</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1476" to="1488" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence in value-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">De</forename><surname>Martino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.3279</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3279" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsetsos</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">37</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk, Ambiguity, and the Savage Axioms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ellsberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1884324</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/1884324" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="669" />
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Peripheral Visual Information Halves Attentional Choice Biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Eum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dolbier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">09567976231184878</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/09567976231184878</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/09567976231184878" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Functional Value of Attitudes: The Influence of Accessible Attitudes on the Ease and Quality of Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Fazio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Blascovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Driscoll</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="401" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167292184002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167292184002" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Dynamics of Decision Making in Risky Choice: An Eye-Tracking Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fiedler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00335</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.frontiersin.org/arti-cles/10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00335" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Active inference and epistemic value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Friston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rigoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ognibene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mathys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17588928.2015.1020053</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17588928.2015.1020053" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Considering what we know and what we don&apos;t know: Expectations and confidence guide value integration in value-based decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Frömer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Callaway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/2sqyt</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/2sqyt" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Goal congruency dominates reward value in accounting for behavioral and neural correlates of value-based decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Frömer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dean Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shenhav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-019-12931-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-12931-x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Speed, Accuracy, and the Optimal Timing of Choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fudenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Strack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Strzalecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1257/aer.20150742</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1257/aer.20150742" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsetsos</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">38</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The formation of preference in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Sharoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Niebur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Stuphorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007201</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007201" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attentional Selection Mediates Framing and Risk-Bias Effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2010" to="2019" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797618803643</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797618803643" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value-based attention but not divisive normalization influences decisions with multiple alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kortmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Vitali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-020-0822-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-0822-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="634" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Value-based attentional capture affects multialternative decision making. eLife, 7, e39659</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Spektor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.39659</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.39659" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural computations that underlie decisions about sensory stimuli</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/s1364-6613</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/s1364-6613" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1567" to="1576" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attitudes and attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gwinn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103892</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103892" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103892</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fluency heuristic: A model of how the mind exploits a by-product of information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Herzog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schooler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Reimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1191" to="1206" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0013025</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0013025" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information Value Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/TSSC.1966.300074</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/TSSC.1966.300074" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Transactions on Systems Science and Cybernetics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IEEE Transactions on Systems Science and Cybernetics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mechanisms underlying cortical activity during value-guided choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kolling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Soltani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Woolrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F S</forename><surname>Rushworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E J</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.3017</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsetsos</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">39</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Optimal policy for attention-modulated decisions explains human fixation behavior. eLife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63436</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.63436</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.63436" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual fixations and the computation and comparison of value in simple choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1298" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.2635</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2635" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The nature of processing fluency: Amplification versus hedonic marking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Landwehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Eckmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2020.103997</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2020.103997" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103997</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsetsos</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.17605/OSF.IO/TZAM2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/TZAM2" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Supply and Demand Approach to Information Processing in Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/vc7jk</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/vc7jk" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Empirical Test of the Role of Value Certainty in Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Coricelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.574473</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.574473" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choosing what we like vs liking what we choose: How choiceinduced preference change might actually be instrumental to decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0231081</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0231081" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trading mental effort for confidence in the metacognitive control of value-based decision-making. eLife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63282</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.63282</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.63282" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value certainty and choice confidence are multidimensional constructs that guide decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13415-022-01054-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13415-022-01054-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="521" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsetsos</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">40</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How choice ecology influences search in decisions from experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lejarraga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gonzalez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogni-tion.2012.06.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogni-tion.2012.06.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="334" to="342" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Living near the edge: How extreme outcomes and their neighbors drive risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mcmillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xge0000414</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0000414" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1905" to="1918" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The probabilistic approach to human reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Oaksford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S1364-6613(00)01699-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S1364-6613(00)01699-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="357" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valuation and estimation from experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Olschewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Oberholzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Scheibehenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="729" to="741" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.2241</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.2241" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s in a sample? Epistemic uncertainty and metacognitive awareness in risk taking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Olschewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Scheibehenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2024.101642</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2024.101642" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">101642</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The secret life of fluency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Oppenheimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2008.02.014</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2008.02.014" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural oscillations and synchronization differentially support evidence accumulation in perceptual and value-based decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polanía</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grueschow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2014.03.014</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2014.03.014" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="709" to="720" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient coding of subjective value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polanía</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41593-018-0292-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-018-0292-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk Aversion in the Small and in the Large</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Pratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1913738</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/1913738" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>/2), Article 1/2</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.85.2.59</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.85.2.59" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsetsos</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">41</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Diffusion Decision Model: Theory and Data for Two-Choice Decision Tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="873" to="922" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/neco.2008.12-06-420</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/neco.2008.12-06-420" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion Decision Model: Current Issues and History</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2016.01.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2016.01.007" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reaction time and accuracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Schouten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A M</forename><surname>Bekker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0001-6918(67</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0001-6918(67" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90054" to="90060" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Visual attention modulates the integration of goal-relevant evidence and not value. eLife, 9</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sepulveda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Benson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ortoleva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Martino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.60705</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.60705" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-value decisions are fast and accurate, inconsistent with diminishing value sensitivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R K</forename><surname>Shevlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hausfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2101508119</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2101508119" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaze bias both reflects and influences preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shimojo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Simion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shimojo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Scheier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn1150</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn1150" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention and choice across domains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xge0000482</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0000482" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1810" to="1826" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaze Amplifies Value in Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797618810521</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797618810521" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Proactive Information Sampling in Value-Based Decision-Making: Deciding When and Where to Saccade. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnhum.2019.00035</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fnhum.2019.00035" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye Movements in Risky Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hermens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.1854</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.1854" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsetsos</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">42</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal policy for value-based decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tajima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pouget</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/ncomms12400</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms12400" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Attentional Drift Diffusion Model of Simple Perceptual Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tavares</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Perona</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnins.2017.00468</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.frontiersin.org/ar-ticles/10.3389/fnins.2017.00468" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Salience driven value integration explains decision biases and preference reversal</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1119569109</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1119569109" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9659" to="9664" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The time course of perceptual choice: The leaky, competing accumulator model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcclelland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="550" to="592" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Selective Integration: An Attentional Theory of Choice Biases and Adaptive Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsetsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0963721419862277</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0963721419862277" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="552" to="559" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why so curious? Quantifying mechanisms of information seeking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Van Lieshout</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>De Lange</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cools</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="112" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cobeha.2020.08.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cobeha.2020.08.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Sequential Tests of Statistical Hypotheses. The Annals of Mathematical Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1945" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Speed-accuracy tradeoff and information processing dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wickelgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0001-6918(77</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0001-6918(77" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90012" to="90021" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsetsos</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
