<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Optimal Allocation of Time in Risky Choices under Opportunity Costs</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Olschewski</surname></persName>
							<email>sebastian.olschewski@unibas.ch.</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Basel</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Warwick Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mullett</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Warwick Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Neil</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Warwick Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Kvam</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mikhail</forename><surname>Spektor</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenjia</forename><forename type="middle">Joyce</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Basel</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Missionsstrasse 62A</addrLine>
									<postCode>4056</postCode>
									<settlement>Basel</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Optimal Allocation of Time in Risky Choices under Opportunity Costs</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:20+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>risk taking</term>
					<term>risky choice</term>
					<term>collapsing boundaries</term>
					<term>drift diffusion model</term>
					<term>optimal decision making</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>for their valuable feedback. This version updates all previous versions with extensive model comparisons, and conclusions are updated accordingly.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Optimal Allocation of Time in Risky Choices under Opportunity Costs</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>In times where hundreds of food delivery options, movies, and investment opportunities are accessible at almost any time, it is crucial to determine when to search for information about the possible options and when to make a choice. As options differ in their characteristics and people differ in their preferences, some information search is indispensable. Otherwise, one suffers from the costs of poor decision-making, such as investing one's retirement savings into overpriced financial products. Yet, given the high number of options, of which many are equally good, it is also obvious that information search has to be stopped at some point. Otherwise, one endures the opportunity costs of reduced time for making other potentially rewarding choices or for activities to increase well-being more generally. Consequently, for adaptive decision making it is important to determine how much time to spend on a choice problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Hsiung et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Payne et al., 1992)</ref>. This holds true both for important decisions, which can take months to make, such as investing in a certain stock, but also for everyday decisions, which can take just seconds, such as buying a lottery ticket at a kiosk.</p><p>Behavioral research has advanced our knowledge about how to decide in isolated choice problems under risk and uncertainty, using latent concepts such as risk preferences, probability weighting, loss aversion, or ambiguity aversion (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Holt &amp; Laury, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Ellsberg, 1961;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Markowitz, 1952)</ref>. Often, these studies stressed how deciders deviated from utility maximization in individual choice problems (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979)</ref>. Finding out which option maximizes one's utility is effortful and timeconsuming <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Lee &amp; Usher, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Oud et al., 2016)</ref>. Recent economic and psychological models of decision-making account for the perception, representation, and integration of numeric information <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bhui &amp; Gershman, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Cheyette &amp; Piantadosi, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Frydman &amp; Jin, 2022</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barretto-García et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Olschewski &amp; Scheibehenne 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Oprea, 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr">Polania et al., 2019)</ref>. These models stress that numeric information about choice options is not precisely and instantaneously available to the decider, but rather that attention, effort, and time has to be allocated to examine this information. As attention, effort, and time are limited resources, they are costly and should be used efficiently <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Lieder &amp; Griffiths, 2020)</ref>. And given that numeric information is only represented with noise, this trade-off between the costs and benefits of information processing applies both to explicit information search such as when looking for more information, but also when processing information that is readily available in front of oneself. Taking these cognitive costs into account means that spending enough time to always choose the best, utility maximizing option is not necessarily rational.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">Risky choices under opportunity costs and drift diffusion models</head><p>Here, we broaden the research question from maximizing utility in an isolated choice problem without opportunity costs to the arguably more realistic case, where the maximization of utility in a given choice problem needs time that then cannot be spent on other opportunities. To do this, we make use of models of latent information search, developed for epistemic or perceptual decision-making, in which evidence accumulation requires time <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Churchland et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Cisek et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Drugowitsch et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bhui, 2019A;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Gluth et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Khodadadi et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Malhotra et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Ratcliff, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Ratcliff et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Ratcliff &amp; Rouder, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">van Maanen et al., 2016)</ref>. In these decisions the task consists of finding which of two hypotheses is correct or which of two stimuli has a higher value on a specific scale, therefore preferences should play no role. Under plausible assumptions, the sequential probability ratio test, or the simple drift diffusion model (DDM) that developed from the former, is the optimal solution for these tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bogacz et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">Wald &amp; Wolfowitz, 1948</ref>; but see <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Moran, 2015)</ref>. Here, optimal means that this algorithm maximizes the accuracy rate for a given level of evidence, or minimizes the evidence necessary for a given accuracy rate.</p><p>The simple DDM consists of a drift that accumulates evidence for either of the two options and symmetric thresholds or decision boundaries that are constant over the duration of evidence accumulation. A decision is made as soon as the relative evidence for one option surpasses its respective boundary. This model is visualized in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1A</ref> left panel, where decision boundaries are ±α and the blue line depicts an exemplar accumulation process starting at 0 (no bias) with a drift towards the upper boundary. Importantly, previous research on perceptual decision making showed that deciders can voluntarily move the decision boundaries according to task demands <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bogacz et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Heitz, 2014)</ref>. In that sense, response times can reflect decision strategies about information search and sampling in analogy to explicit search tasks.</p><p>The DDM has recently been applied to preferential or value-based decision making to theoretically analyze how people should optimally use their time to make decisions in this domain <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Fudenberg et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Tajima et al., 2016)</ref>. In binary preferential choice, accumulating evidence can be conceptualized as learning about the difference in subjective utility or value between two options (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Busemeyer &amp; Diederich, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Busemeyer &amp; Townsend, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Chen &amp; Krajbich, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Diederich, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Gluth et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Hare et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Hutcherson et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Milosavljevic et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr">, Teoh et al., 2020</ref>. In choices under risk or uncertainty in particular, the difference in subjective utility between options is usually unknown to the decision maker ahead of starting to make a choice.</p><p>As an example, when deciding between a stock market fund or a savings account for retirement savings, one usually does not know by how much one prefers the one option over the other before examining both options more closely. Under these conditions and assuming that time is costly, it has been shown recently that the simple DDM with constant boundaries is not optimal and that decision boundaries should instead collapse over time ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1A</ref> right panel) <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Fudenberg et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Tajima et al., 2016)</ref>. Intuitively, when preference for one option as well as the difference in utility between options has to be examined simultaneously, time elapsed without hitting either of the two boundaries is an indication of the similar utility of both options. When the utility of both options is very similar, little is gained by taking more time to sample evidence to find out which of two similar options is actually better.</p><p>Collapsing boundaries act to terminate search when time has passed but little evidence has been accumulated to favor one option over the other. DDMs with uniformly distributed noise around every drift rate. D: Simulated data from a mixture of two DDMs with higher and lower accumulation noise. For details of the simulation see the main text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">The current studies</head><p>To examine the allocation of time in risky choices we first used simulations to find signature behavioral characteristics of evidence accumulation with constant and collapsing boundaries, and under low and high opportunity costs. We demonstrate that the expected behavioral characteristics for constant and collapsing boundaries are subject to additional assumptions about the decision process. In a subsequent step, we show that nonetheless evidence for constant or collapsing boundaries can be recovered in a model comparison when fitting constant and collapsing boundary DDMs to simulated data for which we know the data-generating process.</p><p>We conducted two studies. In Study 1, we compared choices and RTs in a condition in which the utility differences varied from trial to trial and were unknown to participants before viewing the choice options (unknown difficulty) with a condition in which the utility difference remained constant across trials and was known in advance, though the direction of the difference was not (known difficulty). As explained before, it is optimal to use evidence accumulation with collapsing boundaries when the utility difference is unknown to the decision maker, and constant boundaries when the utility difference is known. As collapsing boundaries should only be used if elapsed time is costly, we additionally applied a block time limit in the unknown difficulty condition. This should make opportunity costs more salient and thus increases the difference between both conditions. To state it differently, if we do not observe evidence for a switch in boundaries in this experimental set-up, this will be a strong indication that participants do not respond adaptively to prior information.</p><p>In Study 2, we examined how participants allocate their time in response to varying opportunity costs. According to the theoretical framework in <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fudenberg et al. (2018)</ref>, in a setting in which collapsing boundaries are optimal, the adaptive response to increasing opportunity costs is to move in the decision boundaries and to collapse them faster. To test this prediction, we created conditions in which the utility difference was always unknown, allowing us to focus on the scenario in which collapsing boundaries should be used. To examine situations with different opportunity costs we varied the block time limit (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Starns &amp; Ratcliff, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Simen et al., 2009)</ref>. Unlike time pressure manipulations that put participants under a strict deadline for every individual choice (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Kirchler et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Olschewski &amp; Rieskamp, 2021)</ref>, a block time limit is a less direct manipulation. It allows participants the freedom to spend varying amounts of time on choice problems with different subjective difficulty. At the same time, it increases the time cost because additional time spent on a given choice problem means less time for a future choice problem. In the block time limit manipulation, we set the time limit so that participants usually could not make informed choices in all choice problems. That way, the cost of time incorporates the expected utility gain forgone by making informed choices in future choice problems instead of randomly selecting an option.</p><p>In an additional manipulation, Study 2 examined the effect of heterogeneity in evidence accumulation by comparing behavior in binary lottery choices with and without rare outcomes. According to the theoretical framework in <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fudenberg et al. (2018)</ref> this manipulation should not affect behavior. However, from the perspective of behavioral decision making, rare outcomes can affect how evidence for an option is accumulated <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Lieder et al., 2018)</ref> and heterogeneous accumulation processes can change the behavioral predictions of DDMs (see next section). From a cognitive perspective, both studies examine whether and to what extent human decision makers can systematically adjust their decision criteria between blocks (with varying prior information or opportunity costs) or within a decision (using collapsing boundaries) in sequences of risky choices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The drift diffusion model with constant and collapsing boundaries</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Computational set-up</head><p>Within the drift diffusion modeling framework, we assume that the utility difference between the two available options Zt is internally accumulated by the decision maker according to a standard Brownian motion Bt with volatility α√2 and a drift δ</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Z = δ + α√2B .<label>(1)</label></formula><p>To fit this model to the observed (or simulated) data, we approximate it by a random walk with small time steps <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">(Tuerlinckx et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bhui, 2019B)</ref>. In this random walk approximation, the drift is represented by the probability of a discrete upward step, p, which is truncated between zero and one. This probability is a function of the utility difference between the two options dmu and the noise with which this utility difference is translated into the probability as a free parameter θ. Higher θ values mean that the accumulation process is noisier with respect to the underlying utility difference of the two options dmu. Hence, θ approximates the volatility of the Brownian motion α√2. Finally, τ is a technical parameter that regulates the step size and where smaller values mean more accurate approximations to the diffusion process. In all applications we set τ = 0.05. Hence the probability calculates as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">= 1/2 • (1 + | | • √ θ ).<label>(2)</label></formula><p>To better fit the random walk approximation to the observed response time distribution, the non-decision time ndt is added as an additional free parameter to all models.</p><p>Accumulation of the utility difference is terminated as soon as the accumulator hits one of the two boundaries representing the two available choice options. At this point the elapsed time represents the response time predictions and the boundary position (either upper or lower)</p><p>determines which of the two options is chosen. For the constant boundary model, the boundary separation is constant across the whole accumulation process and is a free parameter b. For the collapsing boundary model, we used the hyperbolic functional form, ( ) = 1 +ℎ× proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fudenberg et al. (2018)</ref> as an approximation of optimal stopping behavior. In this function t is the accumulation time and h is a free parameter representing the decay of the boundary over time, while g is a free parameter representing the boundary separation at t = 0.</p><p>In the random-walk approximations t is replaced by a sequence with intervals of τ. In all models we assume that the starting point of the accumulator is exactly in the middle of the boundary separation, thus there is no starting point bias.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Simulating behavioral predictions</head><p>For visualizing the behavioral predictions of different DDMs, we plotted the proportion of trials where the lottery with lower expected utility was chosen (henceforth, an error) against the RT (pooled over both correct and error trials). To do this, we simulated choice and RT for 40,000 samples each per condition from DDMs with either constant or collapsing boundaries and four different levels of utility difference or drift rate (similar to the rating scale in Study 1). We then estimated a generalized linear model for the simulated choice data with a logit link function and RT as the only predictor for each condition and drift rate level separately. Based on this model, we calculated model predictions and plotted these predictions as lines ranging from the mean of the fastest 20% of simulated RTs until the mean of the slowest 20% of simulated RT on a log-odds scale. The plots resemble the famous Latency-Probability plots used by <ref type="bibr">Ratcliff and others (e.g., Ratcliff &amp; Rouder, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>. Crucially, the plots presented here distinguish between varying utility differences. Further, we focus on the relation between RT and error rate, and do not examine the RT distributions for correct and error choices independently, because the shapes of both distributions do not differ in the theory-based models examined here. This is the case because in these models there are no starting point biases nor trial-by-trial variability in parameters once controlling for the utility difference.</p><p>In our first simulation ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1B</ref>), collapsing boundaries lead to a positive relation between RT and error: the longer it takes to make a choice, the higher the error rate ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure   1B</ref>, right panel). More errors at longer RTs occur because boundaries collapse towards zero and thus less evidence is required to make a choice as time elapses. In contrast, when decision boundaries are constant, RT and error rate are uncorrelated for a given difference in utility between two options ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1B</ref>, left panel).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Whereas these stylized patterns distinguish between constant and collapsing boundary</head><p>DDMs if all assumptions of the models are valid, in the next simulations we show that different patterns can emerge in the RTerror-rate space if some of the assumptions are relaxed. Therefore, we cannot directly infer the underlying shapes of the decision boundaries from the above presented stylized patterns. In the next simulation ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1C</ref>), we assumed noise in the measurement of the utility difference. That is, we drew the utility difference for each drift rate level from a constant uniform distribution with a range similar to that which we observed empirically in Study 1. Note that this resembles DDMs with drift rate variability that are sometimes used to fit empirical choice data <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">(Voskuilen et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Ratcliff et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Rather than a mechanism to fit data, in our analysis, drift rate variability reflects the fact that the utility differences in our models are latent variables for risky choices that can only be measured noisily in an empirical investigation. The simulations show that measurement noise in the utility difference can lead to a positive relation between RT and error rate even under constant boundaries. To see this, consider what would happen if observations from the nomeasurement-noise were shuffled between two different drift rates: The trials with a higher drift rate would be on average faster with less errors than those with a lower drift rate, thus creating a positive relation between RT and error rate. To summarize thus far, if decision boundaries are collapsing then the error-by-RT plot will be positively sloped for a given utility difference, but noise in measuring the drift rate can also cause an artefactual positive slope.</p><p>We then conducted a simulation where participants use different decision strategies.</p><p>Past research demonstrated the use of different strategies in preferential choices in the framework of the adaptive decision maker <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Payne et al., 1992)</ref>, dual-process models <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Diederich &amp; Trueblood, 2018)</ref>, or models of attentional search <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Maier et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Roberts et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr">Sullivan et al., 2014)</ref>. In contrast, the DDMs examined so far assumed that only a single accumulation process is used consistently. To examine the behavioral patterns with heterogenous accumulation processes, we implement two prototypical decision strategies within the DDMs: one decision strategy has a noisier accumulation process (higher θ); this could represent a heuristic one-reason decision strategy because it is relatively noisy with respect to the presented information and requires less time to make a choice. The other decision strategy has a less noisy accumulation process (lower θ), representing a process closer to expected utility maximization. At the same time, we assume that for both decision strategies, participants consistently either use constant or collapsing boundaries. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1D</ref>, we see that this mix of two strategies leads to a non-increasing relation between RT and error rate, even when implementing collapsing boundaries. The reason is that the mix of two decision strategies overshadows the effect of relatively more errors for longer RTs within one decision strategy under collapsing boundaries: when two decision strategies as described above are intermixed in the observed data, decisions made through the first strategy are faster and more error prone, while decisions made through the second strategy are slower and less error prone.</p><p>Finally, we also simulated the resulting behavioral predictions of both DDMs when opportunity costs increase (the pale dotted lines in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures 1B, C</ref>, and D). For constant boundaries, an increase of opportunity costs moves decision boundaries inwards (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bogacz et al., 2010)</ref>. In the case of collapsing boundaries in the optimal model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fudenberg et al. (2018)</ref>, an increase in opportunity costs increases both the reciprocal of the boundary separation at t = 0 (g) and decay rate (h) proportionally. This means that opportunity costs move the starting point of the boundaries inwards and increase the speed of the decay over time proportionally. For both constant and collapsing boundaries, the optimal decision boundary with higher opportunity costs is always inwards compared to the optimal decision boundary with lower opportunity costs. As a result, for every choice at a given RT and utility difference, less evidence is evaluated and hence the error rate is higher when opportunity costs are higher compared to when these costs are lower. This result also holds under measurement noise and strategy heterogeneity. To sum up, increasing opportunity cost should normatively increase errors for any given RT and utility difference in a single choice, at the benefit of moving on to other choices more quickly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Model recovery</head><p>As we demonstrated that the model predictions of the constant and collapsing boundary DDM in the RTerror-rate space are not invariant to some relaxations of auxiliary assumptions about the data generating process, we now examine how accurately a model comparison between constant and collapsing DDMs with fitted parameters from the data can identify the data generating process. For this we again simulated data either from a constant or a collapsing boundary DDM model. As data-generating model parameters we took the median values across all participants in Study 1. As input to the accumulation process, we used four levels of utility differences again in line with the stimuli presented in Study 1. We then fitted both models to the simulated data to see how well the data generating model can be recovered. To conduct the model comparison, we used simulated choice and RT data in quantities similar to the amount of data available for one participant in our empirical studies (i.e., 80 trials).</p><p>As a result, when simulating data from a constant boundary DDM, the correct model was identified by means of BIC or likelihood ratio test in 88% of cases when the competing model was a DDM with collapsing boundaries. When simulating data from a collapsing boundary DDM, the correct model was identified in 66% of cases. Thus, in particular when the model comparison favors collapsing boundaries, there is a high probability that the datagenerating process indeed contained collapsing boundaries (rather than constant boundaries).</p><p>These recovery analyses assumed that there is no measurement noise in the utility differences and a single decision strategy. However, as we saw from the simulations above, similar patterns on the RTerror-rate space for constant and collapsing boundary models can occur under measurement noise and heterogenous decisions strategies. Hence, it is important to show that data from constant boundary models are correctly classified with our modeling comparison tools, even though under these assumptions, stylized behavioral patterns are similar to those stemming from collapsing boundary models. We, therefore, focus on recovery rates for the constant boundary model in the presence of measurement noise and heterogeneous strategies.</p><p>First, if we introduce noise to the simulated drift of a constant boundary DDM, we still manage to identify the constant over the collapsing boundary model in 81% of the cases correctly. Second, if we introduce strategy heterogeneity in the simulation of a constant boundary DDM, we manage to identify the constant over the collapsing boundary model in 97% of the cases correctly. The latter result demonstrates that even when participants have two different strategies in making their choice, resulting in model predictions different from those predicted under the assumption of a single strategy, we would still only very rarely confuse a data-generation process with constant boundaries as a collapsing boundary DDM with our model comparison. To conclude, although identifying the true model is more challenging when it follows the collapsing than the constant boundaries DDM, model comparison using fitted parameters remains a viable approach for determining which model better explains the empirical data in our studies, even when some assumptions about the datagenerating process are relaxed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Study 1</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Method</head><p>Both empirical studies consisted of a rating session followed by a choice session (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>) and examined whether, and under what conditions, participants used constant or collapsing boundaries in risky choice. Differences in ratings were used as a measure of the subjective utility difference between two choice options. We implemented the known utility difficulty condition by informing participants in advance about their previous rating difference between the two lotteries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1.">Procedure and incentives</head><p>The experiment was implemented in oTree <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Chen et al., 2016)</ref>. Participants conducted both phases of the experiment at their own computers approximately one month apart. All instructions were presented on the computer and could be read at the participant's own pace.</p><p>It was explained to participants that all lottery outcomes in the experiment were displayed in experimental pounds and were exchanged into British pounds for the monetary bonus in the ratio 20 experimental pounds : 1 British pound. After the instructions, there was a practice block of 8 trials to familiarize participants with the stimulus presentation and the response format. In the practice trials we presented participants with the whole range of possible lottery values to make participants' answers well calibrated from the start of the experiment.</p><p>In the rating phase, participants saw 60 lotteries and rated each of them on a 7-point Likert scale by clicking on one of seven radio buttons distributed horizontally across the browser window (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> left). We asked participants to answer the following question:</p><p>"How attractive is this lottery to you?". The radio buttons were labelled from 1 to 7 and to the left-most radio button the words "least attractive" and to the right-most radio button the words "most attractive" were added. Participants repeated the rating of the 60 lotteries twice in two consecutive blocks. The presentation order was randomized in each block and for each participant. This part took 25 minutes on average. To incentivize ratings in line with the participants' preferences, at the end of the rating phase, we randomly selected two lotteries and the participants played the lottery that they gave the higher rating. If the participants gave the same rating to both lotteries, one lottery was randomly chosen by the computer. The chosen lottery was then played out according to the stated probabilities and participants got the randomly drawn outcome converted into British pounds together with the fixed participation fee of £2.50.</p><p>In the choice phase of the experiment, participants had 8 blocks. Participants saw two lotteries, one to the left and one to the right of the browser. To choose either of the lotteries,</p><p>In this block there are 20 choices and you can take as much time as you need to make your choices.</p><p>Choose the more attractive lottery</p><p>In this block you have 1:20 minutes to make up to 40 choices. participants were recommended to use the keyboard and pressed &lt;F&gt; for the left and &lt;J&gt; for the right lottery. Alternatively, participants could also click at the respective lottery on the screen to make it possible to conduct the study without a keyboard. The positions of the lotteries on the screen as well as the order of the trials were randomized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Low costs</head><p>In the four known difficulty blocks, participants faced a fixed number of trials <ref type="formula">20</ref>and no time pressure. In these four blocks we presented only lottery pairs with the same rating difference, either 1, 1.5, 2.5, or 3. Before these blocks participants were informed about the rating difference and about the fact that all trials in the upcoming block had the same rating difference. In the four unknown difficulty blocks, participants had a time limit that was stated at the beginning of the block and participants were informed that the two lotteries had varying rating differences. The time limit was introduced to stress opportunity costs and thus increase the power of the manipulation to induce the use of collapsing boundaries. Not finding a qualitative difference between conditions with this setting, rules out that participants are fully adapted to conditions with known and unknown difficulty. In contrast, finding no difference between the known and unknown difficulty condition without a task time limit could be attributed to low opportunity costs, which may have weakened the behavioral effect of collapsing boundaries to the point where it was no longer detectable in our analyses. For the four unknown difficulty blocks, we constructed lottery pair sequences that consisted of 47 lottery pairs in total in each block with varying rating differences: eight from each of the target lottery pairs with rating differences of 1, 1.5, 2.5, and 3; the other lottery pairs were fillers with other rating differences. In the data analyses we refrained from analysing filler trials in order to keep the subjective utility differences equal between the known and the unknow difficulty condition. During these blocks, a red timer counted down, and when it reached zero, the block ended, preventing any further choices. The time limit was set to 90s, determined by approximating the time that was needed to complete 30 choices per block across participants on average in a pilot test. The block order alternated in pairs of two between conditions, with the starting block type randomized.</p><p>Again, to incentivize participants choosing the option they truly preferred, at the end of the choice phase of the experiment, one trial was selected randomly for payout. If the participant made a choice in this trial, then the chosen lottery was played out. If no choice was made (i.e., a trial in the unknown difficulty block that was not presented due to timeout), the computer randomly selected a lottery for the participant. The chosen lottery was played out and the randomly drawn outcome was transformed into British pounds and was added to the participation fee of £2.50. The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of the University of Warwick, HSSREC 219/19-20 (submission ID: 52050574).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2.">Stimulus design</head><p>Lotteries consisted of two outcomes and their corresponding probabilities. They were constructed randomly according to some boundary conditions to cover a large range of expected values (EVs) and standard deviations (SDs). We randomly drew two distinct outcomes from a range of 1 to 99 in experimental £. The boundaries to draw the corresponding probabilities for the lotteries were split into three different conditions:</p><p>Probabilities were either exactly 0.50, or were randomly drawn from the range of either 0.35 to 0.45 or 0.25 to 0.35. To systematically vary the resulting EVs we implemented five target <ref type="bibr">EVs (35,</ref><ref type="bibr">48,</ref><ref type="bibr">55,</ref><ref type="bibr">62,</ref><ref type="bibr">75)</ref> and the resulting lotteries were forced to be always within ±1 of these targets. Finally, we had four target SDs of the lotteries (2.5, 5, 10, 20) and the resulting lotteries were forced to be within ± 0.1 × SD of these targets. Crossing all 3 conditions led to 60 different lottery types. We drew outcomes and probabilities randomly as long as all 60 types were satisfied and excluded all lotteries that did not fulfil any of the above conditions.</p><p>The aim of the lottery construction was to obtain a large variety in terms of subjective attractiveness for the average participant. We deliberately avoided lotteries with rare events of probabilities below 0.25 or above 0.75 to minimize strategy heterogeneity (see Study 2).</p><p>To construct a bespoke binary choice set in the second phase of the experiment for each participant, we used the previously recorded ratings. Since each lottery was rated twice, we took the average of the two ratings. We examined choices that varied in average rating differences by 1, 1.5, 2.5, or 3. For each of these four rating differences, we constructed 52 different lottery pairs. In addition, we constructed filler lottery pairs for the unknown difficulty blocks: Eight had a rating difference of 0, eight had a rating difference of 4 and 44 had a rating difference of 2. These filler lottery pairs were equally distributed across all unknown difficulty blocks. Filler lottery pairs had the function of increasing the number of choice problems in the unknown difficulty condition and, together with the time limit, made opportunity costs salient.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.3.">Participants</head><p>We aimed for a sample size of 125 participants. To approximate our power to detect behavioral group-level differences between our two conditions, we calculated the minimum effect size, we can detect with this sample size in a paired t test with 80% power, which is Cohen's d = 0.26. To sample from the general population, we recruited participants online through Prolific and inclusion criteria were English as the first language, current residence in the UK, and an approval rate above 80% from prior studies.</p><p>We elicited ratings from 322 participants. Of these, 230 participants (71%) used the rating scale in a way that allowed us to construct all necessary choice pairs for the subsequent choice phase. We excluded the 10% of these participants with the lowest rating consistency.</p><p>From 141 participants, who took part in the choice phase, we again excluded the 10% of participants with the highest choice error rate (with respect to prior average ratings), which left us with 127 participants for all reported analyses. All these exclusion criteria were preregistered. We excluded based on rating consistency and consistency between average rating and choice because our empirical approach rests on the assumption that ratings are a measure of latent subjective utility. We thus excluded participants for whom these assumptions held the least.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Results</head><p>In line with the pre-registration, we excluded the 5% slowest and fastest responses from each participant in every condition for all analyses. We assumed that the responses with the most extreme response-times were not representative of the cognitive process under study here, because they might be tarnished by other factors such as lapses in motor control or external distractors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1.">Behavioral analyses</head><p>We deviated from the pre-registered behavioral analysis plan because the preregistered random-effects models were not appropriate, as the participant random-effects were not normally distributed. The results of the pre-registered analysis are nonetheless in the Supplementary Information <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table S1</ref>) and do not contradict any of the results presented here.</p><p>First, we standardized RTs by dividing them by the participant's mean RT across all trials to account for individual heterogeneity in average RTs. Second, we analyzed data independently for each of the four levels instead of grouping them in two levels of rating difference as participants were empirically more sensitive than expected to these differences (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Information)</ref>. Finally, we used generalized linear models to estimate coefficients and constructed bootstrapped confidence intervals and p values for inference. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> presents the error rates, defined as the rate of choices for the option with the lower rating, for five bins of mean-standardized RTs separately for the known and unknown difficulty condition and the rating differences. The lines represent the predictions of regression models with mean-standardized RT as predictor and the error rate as the dependent variable. There was a positive relation between RT and error rate in both conditions. Under no measurement noise, such a positive relation can be an indication of collapsing boundaries (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1B)</ref>. The point estimates of the slopes were very similar in both conditions, in the known difficulty condition it reached significance (Cohen's d = 0.28, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref> Model 1), and in the unknown it did not (due to higher SE; d = 0.10; Model 2). As an example, in the known difficulty condition and a rating difference of 1.5, the error rate increased from 18% in the fastest to 24% in the slowest mean-standardized RT bin.</p><p>Note that the aggregation across different participants can introduce a confound to this analysis. Whereas the mean-standardization prevents the effect of individual differences on average RTs, it does not preclude an effect of individual differences on the RTerror-rate slopes. Therefore, we estimated the slope also with rank RTs, where trials were ranked separately for each participant and each condition from slowest to fastest. This analysis found significantly positive slopes both in the known and in the unknown difficulty condition (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Information)</ref>. Finally, when contrasting the known and unknown difficulty blocks, we see that for every given mean-standardized RT and rating difference, the error rate was higher when the rating difference was unknown compared to known (d = 0.41, <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref> Model 3). As a caveat, as shown in the simulations above, a positive relation between RT and error rate can also occur when boundaries are constant, but there is measurement noise in the subjective utility difference (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1C</ref>). Because each lottery was rated twice, we can estimate this measurement noise by examining the differences in ratings for the same lottery at the two measurement points.   In addition, we also report the parameter estimates for both models and conditions in for differences between conditions in the starting point of the boundary g. But we found support that collapsing was stronger, that is the decay rate h higher, in the unknown (M = 0.058, Med = 0.070, SD = 0.038) than in the known difficulty condition (M = 0.039, Med = 0.025, SD = 0.035; t(118) = 6.68, p &lt; .001. This can explain the higher error rate for a given RT in the unknown compared to the known condition reported in the behavioral analyses section. Further, the reduced decay rate in the known compared to the unknown difficulty condition could indicate a shift, albeit not far enough, towards the optimal model in the known utility condition. However, according to the model comparison we found evidence for the use of collapsing over constant boundaries in both conditions. As constant boundaries would have been optimal for the known utility condition (but see empirical limitations discussed in Section 5), this speaks against an optimal (full) adaptation of participants to the experimental conditions. Note. Cells contain the median parameter estimates from independent model fits for the constant and the collapsing boundary models and the known and unknown conditions.</p><p>Interquartile ranges of the individual parameter estimates in brackets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Study 2</head><p>In Study 2 we focused on the condition with unknown difficulty and examined different levels of opportunity costs. Given that participants seemed to not be able to switch between constant and collapsing boundaries adaptively, we wanted to examine another dimension of optimal decision making, namely whether participants can take different levels of opportunity costs into account while using collapsing boundaries in risky choices. To study this in a more general choice environment, we introduced more heterogenous lottery choices compared to Study 1. For lotteries with rare events, preference reversals between valuations of individual lotteries and choices between two lotteries have been observed (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Grether &amp; Plott 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Slovic &amp; Lichtenstein, 1983</ref>), so we implemented a rating task that elicited relative ratings between two options (rather than individual lottery ratings as in Study 1). That way, this task directly elicits relative preferences and also establishes a rank order within a concrete pair of lotteries.</p><p>In this experiment the rating differences were unknown on all trials and varied within each block. In addition, we implemented a block time limit in half of the blocks, while keeping the lottery pairs the same. Thus, the aim of this study was to provide a decision environment in which collapsing boundaries were optimal and in which opportunity costs varied. According to the theoretical framework of <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fudenberg et al. (2018)</ref> an optimal agent should react to an increase in opportunity costs by moving in the boundaries and increasing the rate of collapse. This means, we predict that for a given RT and utility difference, less evidence will be accumulated and thus the error rate should increase.</p><p>We introduced lotteries with rare events to manipulate consistency between ratings and choices for the same levels of utility difference. According to the simulations in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure   1C</ref>, the expected increased inconsistency or measurement noise for rare event lotteries could cause steeper slopes in the RTerror-rate space for the rare event than the common event lottery condition. Post-hoc, we realized that another prediction can be made: a use of heterogeneous strategies, introduced through the rare event lotteries, can lead to nonincreasing slopes in the RTerror-rate space, even when the decision maker uses collapsing boundaries (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1D</ref>). Heterogeneous strategies could be induced by the inclusion of rare and extreme events, as these events may encourage the use of one-reason decision strategies (e.g., choose the lottery with the high rare and extreme event or avoid the lottery with the low rare and extreme event). The observed decisions could then result from a mix of strategies, with some based on a single piece of information and others on the integration of all available information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1.">Procedure and incentives</head><p>We made the following changes compared to the design of Study 1: In the rating session participants saw 80 lottery pairs (rather than single lotteries) and rated each of them by clicking on a grey bar that signified the range of possible ratings. That is, participants rated the difference between pairs of lotteries rather than rating single lotteries as in Study 1. In this way, the object that participants rated-a lottery pair-was the same as the object of choice. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2.">Stimulus Design</head><p>The lottery pairs were created by random sampling and were split into two conditions: common events (0.30 ≤ probability ≤ 0.70; excluding 0.50). For both conditions we randomly drew lottery outcomes from 11 to 99 (without replacement). We systematically varied the range of EV-differences between lotteries for each lottery pair condition in 8 levels <ref type="bibr">(-23, -15, -7</ref>.5, -2, +2, +7.5, +15, +23) each ±1 sampling tolerance, and the range of SD-differences between lotteries for each lottery pair condition in 5 levels <ref type="bibr">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr">6,</ref><ref type="bibr">12,</ref><ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">30)</ref>  of the 40 trials. Finally, we also ensured that both the riskier option and the higher EV option appeared on the left-hand side between 18 and 22 of the 40 trials. We then used the same shuffling of lottery pairs for all presentations, sessions, and participants to minimize measurement noise when aggregating the data within and across participants. Each of the eight blocks had an equal amount of rare and common event lotteries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.3.">Participants</head><p>We aimed for a similar power as in Study 1, but due to the additional withinparticipant manipulation of rare versus common event lotteries, which is expected to increase measurement noise, we approximately doubled the target sample size to 250. We recruited 378 participants for the rating session from the same subject pool as in Study 1. Of these, we excluded 29 participants for not using the rating scale sensibly indicated by either making very extreme (&gt; 60% of ratings are more extreme than ±90) or very narrow (&gt; 60% of ratings between -20 and +20) ratings, or not using the full rating scale (range of ratings lower than 150 or absolute range lower than 75). Afterward, we excluded the 10% of participants with the lowest rating consistency (35 participants). We invited the remaining 314 participants to the choice session, and 287 of them participated in the study within two days. Of them, we excluded the 10% participants with the lowest consistency of their choices with the ratings, the 5% with the highest absolute auto-correlation in their choices (i.e., those who were either more likely to choose the option on the same side as in the previous trial or to switch to the option on the opposite side of the one previously chosen), and the 5% each with the fastest or slowest median RT. The last criterion was selected because we think that the fastest participants might have not paid enough attention to make sensible choices; whereas the slowest 5% might have used very time-consuming strategies or got distracted; in short, the participants with the most extreme response times might have followed other cognitive processes than the one we seek to examine. It turned out that some participants fulfilled more than one of these exclusion criteria and we therefore ended up with 240 participants for the reported analyses. All exclusion criteria were pre-registered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Results</head><p>For all presented analyses we applied the same pre-registered trial exclusion criteria as in Study 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1.">Behavioral analyses</head><p>We deviated from our pre-registered analysis and used the participant meanstandardized RT, rather than the rank RT, to make RTs better comparable between conditions with different group distributions of RT. However, all reported results are consistent with the results obtained when using rank RT (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Information)</ref>.</p><p>We did not find a significant positive association between RT and error rate in any of the four cells of our experimental design (time limit or no time limit and common or rare event lotteries; see <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>). Hence, assuming no strategy heterogeneity, these patterns are not consistent with participants using collapsing boundaries. We even found a significantly negative slope in the time limit condition when outcomes were rare (d = -0.32, <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2 Model   4</ref>). Regarding the effect of opportunity costs, we found a significant positive main effect of the time limit condition on error rates, while controlling for RTs and ratings (d = 0.63; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4A</ref> and <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>, Model 5).</p><p>As demonstrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1D</ref> non-increasing slopes in the RTerror-rate space are possible even when the decision maker uses collapsing boundaries when there is between-trial heterogeneity in the decision strategies. There is indeed evidence that our manipulation of common and rare event lotteries affected decision strategies. First, the measurement noise in the utility difference ratings was affected by the rare event manipulations, as the absolute rating difference for repeated ratings of the same lottery pairs was higher for rare (M = 40.57, Mdn = 39.89, SD = 10.62) than for common event lotteries <ref type="bibr">(M = 35.62,</ref><ref type="bibr">Mdn = 33.16,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD = 10.42;</ref><ref type="bibr">b = 4.95,</ref><ref type="bibr">95% CI [3.88,</ref><ref type="bibr">6</ref>.03], d = 0.59, p &lt; .001). Consequently, participants also made more errors in the choice task in rare compared to the common event lotteries (d = 0.37; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4B</ref> and <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>, Model 6). Second, participants were also faster in rare event lottery choices than in common event lottery choices (b = -0.19, 95% CI [-0.24, -0.14], d = -0.48, p &lt; .001). Both effects controlled for rating differences.</p><p>This difference in RT and error rate between rare and common event lottery decisions may indicate that due to the inclusion of rare event lotteries, decision strategies became more heterogeneous. For example, one prototypical decision strategy could be based on less, or fewer pieces of information (e.g., focusing only on the rare and extreme event) and therefore lead to faster and more noisy decisions, whereas another strategy uses more information (e.g.,</p><p>integrating probabilities and outcomes), hence leading to slower and less noisy decisions.</p><p>Such a combination of strategies can lead to non-increasing slopes in the RTerror-rate space even if decision makers use collapsing boundaries as demonstrated in the simulations in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1D</ref>. For a more unambiguous inference method of whether decision makers used constant or collapsing boundaries, we next examine again the model comparison.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2.">DDM model comparison</head><p>We fitted constant and collapsing boundary models to the conditions of low and high opportunity costs and examined overall model fit correcting for complexity with likelihood ratio tests. In this analysis, we had to exclude five additional participants because their estimation of at least one of the models did not converge. Likelihood ratio tests comparing the collapsing boundary and nested constant boundary models favor the collapsing boundary model on the group level, X 2 (235) = 3565.96, p &lt; .001 in the no time limit, and X 2 (235) = 3503.52, p &lt; .001 in the time limit condition. As discussed before, under the standard assumptions, a collapsing boundary model should lead to upward slopes in the RTerror-rate space, which was not observed in this study. So why does the DDM with collapsing boundaries still provide a better fit to the data than the DDM with constant boundaries? The better fit of the collapsing boundary model can be explained by taking a look at the predicted RTs of the fitted DDM models in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> (and comparing it to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4A</ref>). Whereas the constant boundary DDM predicts too high response times for the longest 20% of the RTs of each rating difference level, the collapsing boundary model predicts this part of the RT distribution more accurately. At the individual level, we found that 189 participants in the no time limit and 196 in the time limit condition had a likelihood ratio test with p &lt; .050 (out of 235 participants), providing individual-level evidence for collapsing boundaries.</p><p>We now examine the difference in the model parameter estimates in the time limit and no time limit conditions. Summary information about all parameter estimates is presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 4</ref> and 5. We expected both the reciprocal of boundary separation at t = 0 and the decay rate to be higher under the time limit than under the no time limit condition. Consistent with Finally, we also fitted the constant and collapsing boundary models separately for the rare and the common event lotteries. To retain enough power for the individual participant model fits, we pooled over the time limit and the no time limit condition in this analysis. We excluded eight participants from this analysis because their estimations did not converge.</p><p>Similar to the previous modeling results, when splitting the data in rare and common event lottery choices, we found again group-level evidence for collapsing boundaries according to likelihood ratio tests, X 2 (235) = 2053.23, p &lt; .001 for the rare event and X 2 (235) = 2193.21, p &lt; .001 for the common event lottery conditions. Summary statistics of the parameter estimates separated for the rare event and common event lottery conditions are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 5</ref>. Of interest for our research question are the estimates for the accumulation noise θ in the collapsing boundary DDMs, which were smaller in the common event (M = 8.78, Med = 7.52, SD = 4.75) than in the rare event lottery condition <ref type="bibr">(M = 10.44,</ref><ref type="bibr">Med = 8.06,</ref><ref type="bibr">SD =7.93;</ref><ref type="bibr">t(231)</ref> = -3.33, p &lt; .001. The higher estimated noise parameter in the rare event lottery trials in our model specification can explain the increased error rates as well as the faster RTs for rare event lottery trials reported in the behavioral analysis. Furthermore, the difference in noise and RT between rare and common event lottery choices while controlling for the rating differences is consistent with the idea that a different mixture of integration processes are involved in common and rare event lottery decisions. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. Predictions of the constant and collapsing boundary models for the data of Study 2 with parameters fitted to the data individually for each participant and for both the time limit and the no time limit condition while pooling over the rare-and the common event lotteries.</p><p>Error bars are 95% confidence intervals.   Note. Cells contain the median parameter estimates from independent model fits for the constant and the collapsing boundary models and the time limit and no time limit condition while pooling over rare-and common-event lotteries. Interquartile ranges of the individual parameter estimates in brackets. Note. Cells contain the median parameter estimates from independent model fits for the constant and the collapsing boundary models and the rare event and common event lotteries while pooling over the time limit conditions. Interquartile ranges of the individual parameter estimates in brackets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Discussion</head><p>We examined whether people behave optimally as they make a series of risky choices, considering the effort required to identify the best option and the opportunity costs associated with that effort. We followed the evidence accumulation analysis of <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fudenberg et al. (2018)</ref> which concluded that people should use constant decision boundaries when they know the utility difference in advance and collapsing boundaries when they do not. We found across two studies, with parameter fitting and model comparison between constant and collapsing boundary DDMs, that in aggregation decision makers used collapsing boundaries in situations where this was optimal, but also in a condition where this was not optimal, as the utility differences was known prior to the display of the choices. This finding is also consistent with the idea of an internal urgency signal to make a decision (see e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Churchland et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Cisek et al., 2009)</ref>. This may indicate that participants are unable to adaptively switch between constant and collapsing boundaries, consistently collapsing their boundaries instead.</p><p>As a consequence, participants' accuracy in choosing in accordance with their preferences decreased with RT, even when the reward from a utility maximizing decision was known and constant.</p><p>A potential reason for collapsing boundaries under known utility difference could be that in most real-world risk-taking situations, the utility difference between options is unknown a priori. In these scenarios, elapsing time without a decision provides evidence for a low utility difference, which makes it beneficial to reduce the target amount of evidence (under opportunity costs). Hence, participants in our experiment might overgeneralize from this environment to the more artificial condition where they knew the utility difference in advance and elapsing time does not signal a lower reward from a utility maximizing choice.</p><p>Future theories of optimal decision making could incorporate this finding, for example, by additionally assuming switching or learning costs for adjusting boundary shapes between task environments.</p><p>In the design of Study 1 we intentionally combined the unknown utility difference condition with an additional block time limit to increase the perceived difference to the known utility difference condition. As we did not find a qualitative difference in decision strategies between these two conditions, where the block-time limit should amplify boundary collapse, we can assume that the mere difference between known and unknown utility difference will also not prompt the use of constant boundaries.</p><p>Another prediction we tested from the <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fudenberg et al. (2018)</ref> theoretical framework was the specific computational effect of varying opportunity costs on the trade-off between response times and utility maximization. We examined whether participants could adapt decision strategies to varying opportunity costs imposed by a block time limit in sequential risky choices. We found that participants' individual decision quality was reduced at the benefit of making more choices. In particular, participants decreased their boundary separation and increased their decay rate in a collapsing boundary DDM at the same time as a response to the higher opportunity costs. This aligns with the optimal choice model and shows that participants adapted to the influence of opportunity costs on their expected overall reward.</p><p>This adaptation to increased opportunity costs also relates to more choice inconsistency found in risky choices made under strict individual-trial time limits or dual task demands <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Olschewski &amp; Rieskamp, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Olschewski et al., 2018)</ref>. The examined manipulation of a block time limit differs from strict individual-trial time limits in that it allows participants to vary their accumulation time between trials dependent on the difficulty of the task and their decision strategy. The block time limit just increases the overall cost of time, as time spent on one decision problem reduces the time available for making informed choices in later trials within the block. Previous studies found that participants spent too much time on very hard choice problems or choice problems in which the two options have similar utilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bogacz et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Oud et al., 2016)</ref>. Importantly, since we only examined the relative shift in boundary positions across task environments and did not measure absolute subjective costs of time, we cannot directly judge whether participants overall spent too much or too little time on the choice problems (however, see the analyses of the empirical relationship between RTs and expected rewards in the Supplementary Information for evidence that participants in our time limit conditions who spent more time per choice earned lower expected rewards).</p><p>It is an important question how people learn to set their boundary in adaptation to the context <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Hawkins et al., 2012A;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">2012B)</ref>. According to the DDM framework, the boundary separation as well as potential decay rates are set prior to the trial onset. Therefore, any adaptation to the context can only evolve across repeated trials. One way participants could adapt their boundaries to the context, despite the lack of explicit outcome or performance feedback, is through metacognitive awareness or perceived confidence in the accuracy of their decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bénon et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Brus et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Lee, Daunizeau, et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Olschewski &amp; Scheibehenne, 2024)</ref>. Depending on this assessment, participants could in principle learn where to set their boundaries to match their target accuracy while taking varying opportunity costs into account. In the current approach, we do not explicitly model this adaptation process, but rather rely on average boundary parameter estimates for trials in different conditions. Future research could incorporate this learning and adaptation process more explicitly.</p><p>We found an additional deviation from optimal time allocation according to the theoretical framework in <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Fudenberg et al. (2018)</ref>: participants decided faster and made more errors for lottery pairs with rare events compared to lottery pairs with common events in Study 2 controlling for subjective attractiveness ratings. This seems to indicate that participants used different mixtures of strategies when rare or common events were present or made more errors in the accumulation process when rare events were present. Heterogeneity in the accumulation process can also explain the occurrence of a negative relation between RT and error rate. Whereas under the assumption of a single accumulation process, a collapsing boundary DDM predicts a positive slope, heterogeneous accumulation processes can induce non-positive or even negative slopes in the RTerror-rate space. Future theories of risky choice could incorporate this by allowing for varying levels of bottom-up saliencies depending on types of information and context (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Lee, D'Alessandro, et al., 2023)</ref>. This explanation resembles dual-process DDMs <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Diederich &amp; Trueblood, 2018)</ref>, DDMs with varying attention search (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Roberts et al., 2022)</ref>, and mixture models with a fast-guessing process <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Ratcliff &amp; Kang, 2021)</ref>. More generally, this implies that more complex risky choice problems as well as choice problems in mixed or in the loss domain could also induce a heterogeneity of strategies with direct consequences for the observed relation between RTs and utility maximization.</p><p>Alternatively, a negative slope between RT and error rate could also be explained by noisiness in the starting point of evidence accumulation (so that the accumulation process does not always start in the middle of both decision boundaries; <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Ratcliff et al., 2016)</ref>. The starting point bias in the evidence accumulation could incorporate prior information about the likelihood ratio of the favorable option. Empirical studies have indeed found that decision makers change their starting point and that this can be optimal if the decision maker believes that the stimuli distribution follows a non-stationary or auto-correlated stochastic processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Glaze et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Gupta et al., 2024</ref>). Yet, in these studies participants received at least partly trial-by-trial feedback. In contrast, in our task there was no trial-by-trial feedback and no indication of non-stationarity in the process. Therefore, biasing the starting point of evidence accumulation toward the left or right option in our task is not optimal under the here assumed models. Yet, in principle participants could hold false beliefs about the underlying process of choice generation; hence, rigorously distinguishing between different explanations for the non-increasing relationship between RT and error rate in risky choice in Study 2even when boundaries are collapsing-is left to future research.</p><p>Recently, studies on perceptual and epistemic choice also reported empirical evidence for collapsing boundaries <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bhui, 2019B;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Churchland et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Cisek et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Drugowitsch et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Gluth et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Khodadadi et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Malhotra et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">van Maanen et al., 2016)</ref>. In many of these studies, information sampling was experimentally controlled by sequentially presenting cues, and participants' responses were shown to be based on less evidence as time passed. However, there are also studies of perceptual decision making with implicit information sampling, which have reported no evidence of collapsing boundaries through cognitive modeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Evans et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hawkins et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Voskuilen et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>In contrast to the literature cited in the previous paragraph, which examined decisions based on objective evidence, we studied the implicit accumulation of subjective utility including risk preferences (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Busemeyer &amp; Townsend, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Lee, D'Alessandro, et al., 2023)</ref>. Further, we experimentally implemented choice situations in which constant or collapsing boundaries were optimal. Finally, preferential decisions are characterized by a correlation between reward from a correct choice and the difficulty of making this choice that is usually absent in perceptual tasks. This means that in preferential decisions, options with very similar utility are harder to distinguish, while at the same time the reward from identifying the slightly better option is small. More generally, task differences may involve variations in the objective function that people aim to maximize, potentially leading to different theoretical conclusions about the optimal setting of boundaries <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Khodadadi et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Malhotra et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Tajima et al., 2016)</ref>. Thus, more research explicitly comparing perceptual/epistemic and preferential decisions is needed to precisely map the similarities and differences in the accumulation processes and decision boundaries between these two domains. Further, it is important to examine similarities and differences in the setting of the decision boundary under implicit and explicit accumulation processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Glickman &amp; Usher, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Glickman et al., 2022</ref>).</p><p>An important limitation of empirically examining preferential choices in general and the use of constant or collapsing boundaries in particular is that the subjective utility of a choice alternative is not directly observable. The measurement of this variable is always noisy and can lead to erroneous conclusions with respect to the data generating process when relying on behavioral data analysis alone as we showed with simulations. In the current studies, we tried to control this measurement noise as much as possible by implementing two types of lottery rating tasks with repeated measurement. This should reduce measurement noise compared to a common approach in risky choice, where preference orders are represented by additional free parameters and simultaneously estimated together with the other free parameters of a choice model. However, our approach assumes that participants hold the same subjective utility in ratings and choices for a given option. Empirically, this might not be possible to control perfectly as ratings and choices may also be affected by situation-specific characteristics such as attention lapses, imprecise perceptions, or fatigue (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Khodadadi et al., 2017)</ref>. We demonstrated that, in particular, behavioral analyses of the relation between RT and error rate are subject to this measurement noise. At the same time, our model recoveries showed that model comparison analyses to distinguish between decision processes originating from constant and collapsing boundary DDMs turned out to be relatively reliable even under measurement noise and with heterogenous strategies (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Evans et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hawkins et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Milosavljevic et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Voskuilen et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Another consequence of measurement noise for implementing the condition of known utility difference is that participants might not perceive the information about the utility difference as certain. This could be the case if they have metacognitive awareness of the noisiness in their previous ratings or, more generally, in their cognitive processes and preferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(De Martino et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Lee &amp; Daunizeau, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Olschewski &amp; Scheibehenne, 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Polanía et al., 2019)</ref>. Under these circumstances it would have still been optimal to use collapsing boundaries also in our "known difficulty" condition. This raises the fundamental questions whether we can ever be in a situation of known utility differences in preferential choices. If we answer this question negatively, then-although the constant boundary model is theoretically optimal in certain situations-we should not expect that participants use it as a decision strategy. Under these assumptions, people should always use collapsing boundaries, but-at least according to the function approximation of the optimal boundary in the model of high uncertainty about the utility differences-specifically, if the prior variance of the utility difference is large-then a given amount of evidence should not trigger a choice, as the large prior variance increases the likelihood that this evidence could still be outweighed by new information. In contrast, the same amount of evidence could be enough to trigger a choice if the prior variance is small. Hence, more uncertainty about the utility difference should lead to higher starting points of thresholds. In the case of our knowledge manipulation in Study 1, even if there are never situations with a priori known utility differences with certainty, there are still different degrees of uncertainty; participants should experience more uncertainty in the unknown than in the known utility difference condition. In that case, we would predict that boundaries should be wider under higher than under lower uncertainty; a result that is not fully supported by the data of Study 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>A cornerstone of adaptive behavior is the ability to know when to stop information search, decide, and move on to other choice problems. When making choices under risk repeatedly, the utility differences between two options are usually not known a priori. We found that, under these conditions, participants behaved qualitatively in line with optimal models of collapsing decision boundaries as they reduced their target level of evidence for the (seemingly) expected utility maximizing option as time elapsed. Importantly, we discovered an asymmetry in the participants' response to characteristics of the choice environment:</p><p>participants were better at adapting to opportunity costs increasing the cost of deliberation time than they were at adapting to prior knowledge of utility differences increasing the potential reward of continued deliberation time. They adapted to increased opportunity costs by moving boundaries inwards and increasing decay rates in line with predictions of optimal models. This means they spent less time maximizing utility in an individual choice in order to make other potentially rewarding choices. However, they did not adapt to the reward of deliberation time when utility differences were known, because they failed to use constant levels of evidence when they knew the utility difference and thus the reward of a utility maximizing choice in advance. This asymmetry in understanding the costs and rewards of deliberation time should be taken into account when planning interventions to improve decision making: it seems to be more promising to change behavior by appealing to the costs, rather than the rewards of deliberation time. In general, whereas many studies in risky choice are concerned with individual choice biases from expected utility theory, we point out that under opportunity costs the allocation of deliberation time to a given choice problem is an important characteristic of good decision making, too.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A: Illustration of the evidence accumulation process (blue line) in a drift diffusion model with upward drift, no starting point bias and constant (left) or collapsing (right) decision boundaries. Lower and upper boundaries represent choice options and a decision for the respective option is made as soon as evidence accumulation hits a boundary. Dotted lines represent an inward move of the respective decision boundaries. B -D: Error rate against RT for simulated data from different DDMs. Doubled costs mean that decision boundaries were moved inwards by 50% compared to the baseline condition. B: Simulated data from DDMs with the same drift in every drift rate condition (indicated by color). C: Simulated data from</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Stylized screenshots of the presentation of lotteries and the input screen for the ratings (left) and the choice part (right) with the different within-subject conditions for Study 1 (above) and Study 2 (below).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Results of Study 1. Error rate as a function of mean-standardized RT, split into bins of choices by the absolute rating difference between the choice option, and for the known and unknown difficulty condition. Rich colored points are the observed means for each of five bins of mean-standardized RT and rich colored lines are regression lines based on the observed data. Pale colored points and lines are average model predictions with parameters fitted to data individually for each participant and condition. Left panel: Predictions from the model with constant boundaries. Right panel: Predictions from the model with collapsing boundaries. Error bars are 95% confidence intervals.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3also presents the average predictions of the fitted DDMs with constant and collapsing boundaries for both conditions. It shows that the collapsing boundary DDM is able to capture the structure of the RT distribution, the effect of the rating differences, and the relation between RT and error rate from the data. We also examine individual-level results of the likelihood ratio tests, with 53 participants in the known difficulty condition and 62 participants in the unknown difficulty condition (each out of 119 participants) having a likelihood ratio test with p &lt; .050, providing individual-level evidence for collapsing boundaries.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The bar did not have pre-set values or distinct points, with participants able to click anywhere on the line, with only a zero point (indifference) marked with a black vertical line in the centre. The point-marker appeared only once the participants clicked on the bar and exactly at the position where the participant clicked. Participants confirmed their rating by clicking on a button that brought them to the next trial. Participants repeated the ratings of the 80 lotteries pairs twice in two consecutive blocks. The presentation order was randomized in each block and for each participant. Ratings were not incentivized and participants earned a fixed salary of £3.50.In the choice session, participants completed eight blocks. Participants saw the same lottery pairs as in the rating session (not mentioned to participants). In the four no-time-limit blocks, participants faced a fixed number of trials (20) and no time pressure. The 80 lottery pairs were randomly distributed among the four blocks. In the four time-limit blocks, participants had a time limit of 80s and there were up to 40 lottery pairs to decide upon. The first 20 lottery pairs consisted of the set of lotteries rated before, whereas the last 20 lottery pairs consist of different pairs with similar EV and SD properties. We chose the time limit to allow most participants to finish between 20 and 35 trials, so that we acquired enough data while having a constraining time limit. The block order alternated in pairs of two blocks and incentives were as in Study 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results of Study 2 including regression lines with individual mean standardized RTs (conditions and ratings were pooled for the standardization; data were afterwards separated by condition and four quartiles Q of rating strength). The error rate is presented on a log-odds scale. Error bars are 95% confidence intervals. A: Data are pooled across common and rare event lotteries and separated to show the effect of time limit on the relation between error rate and mean-standardized response time. B: Data are pooled across time limit and no time limit conditions and separated to show the effect of rare event lotteries on the relation between error rate and mean-standardized response time. Regression Results of the Effect of Mean-Stand. RT on Error Rates.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Note.</head><label></label><figDesc>Cells contain parameter estimates of a logistic regression of mean-standardized RT on error rate. The standardization was performed separately for each participant and pooled across all conditions. Models (1) -(4) show the effect of RT on the error rate separately for each of the four cells of the experimental design. Model (5) shows the effect of the time limit while pooling over rare and common events. Model (6) shows the effect of rare events while pooling over no and present time limit. 95% bootstrapped confidence intervals in brackets. Stars indicate bootstrapped p-values. * p &lt; .050 ** p &lt; .010 *** p &lt; .001</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>this prediction, parameter estimates for the reciprocal of the starting point of the boundary g in the collapsing boundary DDM were higher in the time limit (M = 0.034, Med = 0.027, SD = 0.028) than in the no time limit condition (M = 0.027, Med = 0.024, SD = 0.022); t(234) = 3.41, p &lt; .001). Further, estimates of the decay rate h were higher in the time limit (M = 0.030, Med = 0.024, SD = 0.024) than in the no time limit condition (M = 0.014, Med = 0.009, SD = 0.017); t(234) = 10.38, p &lt; .001. The condition differences in the parameter estimates of the boundaries are consistent with the response of the normative accumulation model when opportunity costs increase: decision boundaries were set further inwards and decreased faster for a block of trials in response to the time limit.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The mean average absolute deviation between the two repeated ratings was M = 0.71 (Mdn = 0.68, SD = 0.23), 95% CI [0.67; 0.75]. The average number of lotteries rated differently (1 or more rating levels apart on the 7-point scale) at the</figDesc><table /><note>two time points was 54.59%, 95% CI [52.52%; 56.67%]. The variability of the ratings at the two measurement points could mean that the measurement noise was high enough to create an artifactual connection between RT and error rate. We therefore now examine the model comparison as a more unambiguous inference method, having showen in Section 2.3. that a constant boundary DDM with measurement noise is only very rarely misidentified as a collapsing boundary DDM in a model comparison.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Study 1: Regression Results of the Effect of Mean-Stand. RT on Error Rates. Note. Cells contain parameter estimates of a logistic regression of mean-standardized RT on error rate. The standardization was performed separately for each participant and pooled</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Known difficulty</cell><cell>Unknown difficulty</cell><cell>Pooled</cell></row><row><cell>(Intercept)</cell><cell>-1.82***</cell><cell>-1.60***</cell><cell>-1.84</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-2.00, -1.65]</cell><cell>[-1.77, -1.45]</cell><cell>[-2.03, 1.67]</cell></row><row><cell>Stan.-RT</cell><cell>0.16***</cell><cell>0.14</cell><cell>0.16***</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[0.07, 0.27]</cell><cell>[-0.12, 0.38]</cell><cell>[0.07, 0.27]</cell></row><row><cell>Rating Diff</cell><cell>-0.91***</cell><cell>-0.73***</cell><cell>-0.91***</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[-1.05, -0.77]</cell><cell>[-0.83, -0.63]</cell><cell>[-1.06, -0.78]</cell></row><row><cell>Unknown</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.26***</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>[0.15, 0.36]</cell></row><row><cell>Stan.-RT ×</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.02</cell></row><row><cell>Unknown</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>[-0.28, 0.22]</cell></row></table><note>As our main method of inference, we fitted the free parameters of a DDM with constant and collapsing boundaries for each participant and for each condition separately. For this analysis we had to exclude seven additional participants because the fitting of their parameters did not converge. Since the constant boundary model is nested in the collapsing boundary model for a decay rate of h = 0, we can use a likelihood ratio test to examine whether the additional complexity of a collapsing boundary is warranted given the improvement in fit it offers. For the group level fit we summed up all log likelihoods from the individual participants (and thus calculated the overall likelihood across all participants), separately for both conditions, and for a constant and a collapsing boundary model. In the known difficulty condition, the likelihood ratio test statistic is χ 2 (119) = 394.70, p &lt; .001, and for the unknown difficulty condition, χ 2 (119) = 761.68, p &lt; .001. The significant test statistics of the likelihood ratio tests imply that for both conditions, the additional complexity of the collapsing DDM is justified by a sufficiently better fit of the model to the data compared to the constant boundary model.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>For the parameter estimates of the collapsing boundary DDM, we found no support</figDesc><table><row><cell>TIME ALLOCATION &amp; RISKY CHOICE</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Study 1: Parameter Estimates for the Constant and Collapsing Boundary DDM.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell>(4)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Constant</cell><cell>Constant</cell><cell>Collapsing</cell><cell>Collapsing</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>boundaries -</cell><cell>boundaries -</cell><cell>boundaries -</cell><cell>boundaries -</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>known difficulty</cell><cell>unknown</cell><cell>known</cell><cell>unknown</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>difficulty</cell><cell>difficulty</cell><cell>difficulty</cell></row><row><cell>Boundary b</cell><cell>6.26</cell><cell>4.84</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[3.66, 10.64]</cell><cell>[2.86, 11.15]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Boundary start g</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.081</cell><cell>0.086</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>[0.054, 0.095]</cell><cell>[0.062, 0.095]</cell></row><row><cell>Boundary decay</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.025</cell><cell>0.070</cell></row><row><cell>h</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>[0.009, 0.066]</cell><cell>[0.020, 0.097]</cell></row><row><cell>Accumulation</cell><cell>3.34</cell><cell>3.41</cell><cell>3.76</cell><cell>4.48</cell></row><row><cell>noise θ</cell><cell>[2.37, 5.95]</cell><cell>[2.34, 7.10]</cell><cell>[2.91, 5.71]</cell><cell>[3.13, 6.36]</cell></row><row><cell>Non-decision</cell><cell>0.73</cell><cell>0.75</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>0.21</cell></row><row><cell>time ndt</cell><cell>[0.48, 0.96]</cell><cell>[0.59, 0.94]</cell><cell>[0.04, 0.32]</cell><cell>[0.06, 0.52]</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Crossing all EV and SD levels led to 40 different lottery pairs per lottery condition (rare or common events). The lottery pairs were shuffled with respect to the position of the first and the second lottery (either left or right) and with respect to the position of the first and the second outcome of each lottery (either top or bottom). This shuffle was repeated until the smaller of the two outcomes appeared on top between 18 to 22 of the 40 trials in each condition (rare or common); and the less likely outcome appeared on top between 18 and 22</figDesc><table><row><cell>± 0.1 × SD</cell></row><row><cell>sampling tolerance.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Study 2: Parameter Estimates for Constant and Collapsing Boundary DDM Separated for</cell></row><row><cell>Time Limit and No Time Limit Condition.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Study 2: Parameter Estimations for Constant and Collapsing Boundary DDM Separated for</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Rare and Common Event Lotteries.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(1)</cell><cell>(2)</cell><cell>(3)</cell><cell>(4)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Constant</cell><cell>Constant</cell><cell>Collapsing</cell><cell>Collapsing</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>boundaries -</cell><cell>boundaries -</cell><cell>boundaries -</cell><cell>boundaries -</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>common event</cell><cell>rare event</cell><cell>common event</cell><cell>rare event</cell></row><row><cell>Boundary b</cell><cell>14.44</cell><cell>14.81</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[10.32, 20.25]</cell><cell>[11.44, 20.02]</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Boundary start g</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.041</cell><cell>0.037</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>[0.025, 0.062]</cell><cell>[0.022, 0.057]</cell></row><row><cell>Boundary decay</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.008</cell><cell>0.009</cell></row><row><cell>h</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>[0.002, 0.016]</cell><cell>[0.003, 0.015]</cell></row><row><cell>Accumulation</cell><cell>7.28</cell><cell>7.83</cell><cell>7.52</cell><cell>8.06</cell></row><row><cell>noise θ</cell><cell>[5.52, 10.15]</cell><cell>[6.38, 10.40]</cell><cell>[5.81, 9.77]</cell><cell>[6.81, 10.83]</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding the right fit: A comparison of process assumptions underlying popular drift-diffusion models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jekel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dickert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1982" to="1993" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual risk attitudes arise from noise in neurocognitive magnitude representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Barretto-García</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>De Hollander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grueschow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polanía</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1551" to="1567" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The online metacognitive control of decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bénon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hopper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Verdeil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pessiglione</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Vinckier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">23</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A statistical test for the optimality of deliberative time allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bhui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="855" to="867" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing optimal timing in value-linked decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bhui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Brain &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision by sampling implements efficient coding of psychoeconomic functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bhui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="985" to="1001" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The physics of optimal decision making: a formal analysis of models of performance in twoalternative forced-choice tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Moehlis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="700" to="765" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do humans produce the speedaccuracy trade-off that maximizes reward rate?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="863" to="891" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sources of confidence in value-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Aebersold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grueschow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polania</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7337</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Survey of decision field theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Diederich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical Social Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="370" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision field theory: a dynamic-cognitive approach to decision making in an uncertain environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Townsend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="432" to="459" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biased sequential sampling underlies the effects of time pressure and delay in social decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">oTree-An open-source platform for laboratory, online, and field experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schonger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wickens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="88" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A unified account of numerosity perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Cheyette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Piantadosi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1265" to="1272" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-making with multiple alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Churchland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="693" to="702" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions in changing conditions: the urgency-gating model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cisek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Puskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>El-Murr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11560" to="11571" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence in value-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">De</forename><surname>Martino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic stochastic models for decision making under time constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Diederich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="274" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic dual process model of risky decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Diederich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="270" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The cost of accumulating evidence in perceptual decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moreno-Bote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Churchland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pouget</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3612" to="3628" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk, ambiguity, and the Savage axioms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ellsberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="669" />
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of passing time in decisionmaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="316" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient coding and risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Frydman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="213" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Speed, accuracy, and the optimal timing of choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fudenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Strack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Strzalecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3651" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Normative evidence accumulation in unpredictable environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Glaze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Elife</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">8825</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integration to boundary in decisions between numerical sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence integration and decision confidence are modulated by stimulus consistency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value-based attention but not divisive normalization influences decisions with multiple alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kortmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Vitali</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="634" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deciding when to decide: time-variant sequential sampling models explain the emergence of value-based decisions in the human brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Büchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10686" to="10698" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic theory of choice and the preference reversal phenomenon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Grether</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Plott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="623" to="638" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trial-history biases in evidence accumulation can give rise to apparent lapses in decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Depasquale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kopec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brody</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">662</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transformation of stimulus value signals into motor commands during simple choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O'doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18120" to="18125" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An optimal adjustment procedure to minimize experiment time in decisions with multiple alternatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="348" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context effects in multi-alternative decision making: Empirical data and a Bayesian model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="498" to="516" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting the evidence for collapsing boundaries and urgency signals in perceptual decision-making</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2476" to="2484" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk aversion and incentive effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Holt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Laury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1644" to="1655" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hsiung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pearson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Poh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hakimi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Adcock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Huettel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Between heuristics and optimality: Flexible integration of cost and evidence during information sampling</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/2022.05.17.492355</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/2022.05.17.492355" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory: An analysis of decision under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to allocate limited time to decisions with different expected outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khodadadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Fakhari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="49" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of fast and slow decisions on risk taking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kirchler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Andersson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bonn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Johannesson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">Ø</forename><surname>Sørensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stefan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tinghög</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="59" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual fixations and the computation and comparison of value in simple choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1298" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking fast and slow based on a critique of reaction-time reverse inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bartling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risky decisions are influenced by individual attributes as a function of risk preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>D'alessandro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Iodice</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Calluso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rustichini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">101614</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trading mental effort for confidence in the metacognitive control of value-based decision-making. Elife</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63282</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence or confidence: What is really monitored during a decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daunizeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pezzulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1360" to="1379" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value certainty in drift-diffusion models of preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Usher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="790" to="806" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resource-rational analysis: Understanding human cognition as the optimal use of limited computational resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overrepresentation of extreme events in decision making reflects rational use of cognitive resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissociable mechanisms govern when and how strongly reward attributes affect decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Raja Beharelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polanía</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="949" to="963" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overcoming indecision by changing the decision boundary</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Malhotra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Leslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ludwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">146</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="776" to="805" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time-varying decision boundaries: insights from optimality analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Malhotra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Leslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ludwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="971" to="996" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Portfolio selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Markowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="1952" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The drift diffusion model can account for the accuracy and reaction time of value-based choices under high and low time pressure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milosavljevic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Malmaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Huth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="437" to="449" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gazedependent evidence accumulation predicts multi-alternative risky choice behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Molter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Huettel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Heekeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Mohr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1010283</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal decision making in heterogeneous and biased environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing three effects of time pressure on risk taking: Choice consistency, risk preference, and strategy selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Olschewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="541" to="554" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taxing cognitive capacities reduces choice consistency rather than preference: A model-based test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Olschewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Scheibehenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="462" to="484" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s in a sample? Epistemic uncertainty and metacognitive awareness in risk taking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Olschewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Scheibehenne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">101642</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions under risk are decisions under complexity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Oprea</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3789" to="3811" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Irrational time allocation in decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Oud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Cheong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">283</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1822" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral decision research: A constructive processing perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bettman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient coding of subjective value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Polanía</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Woodford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Qualitative speed-accuracy tradeoff effects can be explained by a diffusion/fast-guess mixture model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15169</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling response times for two-choice decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rouder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion decision model: Current issues and history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internal and external sources of variability in perceptual decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Voskuilen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time to pay attention? Information search explains amplified framing effects under time pressure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Teoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hutcherson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="104" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward rate optimization in two-alternative decision making: empirical tests of theoretical predictions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Simen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Contreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1865" to="1897" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preference reversals: A broader perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lichtenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="596" to="605" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age-related differences in diffusion model boundary optimality with both trial-limited and time-limited tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Starns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="145" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dietary self-control is related to the speed with which attributes of healthfulness and tastiness are processed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hutcherson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="134" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal policy for value-based decisionmaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tajima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Drugowitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pouget</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of four methods for simulating the diffusion process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tuerlinckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Maris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Boeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods, Instruments, &amp; Computers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="456" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Striatal activation reflects urgency in perceptual decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Van Maanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fontanesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="294" to="303" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing fixed and collapsing boundary versions of the diffusion model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Voskuilen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimum character of the sequential probability ratio test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wolfowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Annals of Mathematical Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="326" to="339" />
			<date type="published" when="1948" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
