<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emory</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
							<email>emory.richardson@yale.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">correspondence Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>Box 208205</postBox>
									<postCode>06520-8205</postCode>
									<settlement>New Haven</settlement>
									<region>CT</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:20+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>2</term>
					<term>686 (Main Text) 3</term>
					<term>950 (Methods &amp; Results) Version : 22.2.6_psyArXiv_v1.3</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Limits on mental speed entail speed-accuracy tradeoffs for problem-solving, but memory and perception are accurate on much faster timescales. While response times drive inference across the behavioral sciences, they may also help laypeople interpret each others&apos; everyday behavior. We examined children&apos;s (ages 5 to 10) use of agents&apos; response time to infer the source and quality of their knowledge. In each trial, children saw a pathfinding puzzle presented to an agent, who claimed to have solved it after either 3s or 20s. In Experiment 1 (n=135), children used agents&apos; response speed to distinguish between memory, perception, and novel inference. In Experiment 2 (n=135), children predicted that fast responses would be inaccurate, but were less skeptical of slow agents. In Experiment 3 (n=128), children inferred task complexity from agents&apos; speed. Our findings suggest that the simple intuition that thinking takes time may scaffold everyday social cognition.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>A colleague once posed a trick question to the polymath John von Neumann. von Neumann was famous for his quick mental calculations, but the solution to this particular problem could either be found by brute-force calculation, or by a rarely noticed shortcut. The question was "Two cyclists twenty miles apart are moving towards each other at 10 mph; a fly caught between them is moving at 15 mph, from wheel to wheel and back again, until it is crushed between the wheels of the bikes. How far will the fly travel?". The brute force approach is to sum the geometric series, adding up all of the fly's increasingly short trips between the wheels; alternatively, one could notice that the cyclists will meet in exactly one hour, when the fly will have travelled exactly fifteen miles. von Neumann answered immediately, and the colleague disappointedly replied "oh, you've heard about the trick". von Neumann retorted "what trick? I simply summed the geometric series!".</p><p>The logic of this exchange is intuitively obvious, which is remarkable given that it relies on fairly intricate series of counterfactuals and violations of expectation. Even a von Neumann could not sum an infinite series so quickly; but while both guessing and memory can be nearly instantaneous, correctly guessing an infinite sum is extremely improbable -so improbable that we jump to the conclusion that von Neumann must have simply recalled the trick. Discovering that von Neumann had summed the infinite series reveals a prodigious mental speed -and by extension, extraordinary competence with numbers. This interpretation is effortless because we intuitively understand the CHILDREN_RESPONSE_TIME of <ref type="bibr">4 36</ref> relative speed-accuracy tradeoffs of different cognitive processes and the significance of violating those tradeoffs.</p><p>Yet, despite the widespread use of response time as an inductive tool in the behavioral sciences, attention to laypeople's own inferences about each others' response times has been sporadic and unsystematic. Nevertheless, the few existing studies suggest that timing is a rich and flexible cue. For example, adults who respond more quickly to trivia questions are also rated as more charismatic by peers <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(von Hippel et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Conversely, adults interpret longer latencies as reluctance in response to requests <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Roberts, Francis, &amp; Morgan, 2006)</ref>, as memory failure in response to trivia questions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Brennan &amp; Williams, 1995)</ref>, and as indecision between equally desirable options in decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Frydman &amp; Krajbich, 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Gates et al., 2021</ref>. Moreover, in negotiation contexts, buyers' hesitation (or lack thereof) can reveal their price-point, allowing experienced sellers to adjust their selling strategy in response <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Konovalov &amp; Krajbich, 2017)</ref>. Inferences like these often feel effortless despite their sophistication; yet, we are also notoriously bad at estimating the time required to complete a given task.</p><p>Where do timing-based inferences come from, and how systematic are they? We suggest that even the most sophisticated inferences build on a simple intuition already present in early childhood: thinking takes time. On this account, seeing an agent spend more or less time on a task than expected demands explanation. Reasoning about the time costs agents incur to achieve their goals may enable the same kinds of sophisticated inferences about beliefs and desires that we make by reasoning about the costs agents incur while pursuing goals in spatial environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Baker, Jara-Ettinger, Saxe, &amp; Tenenbaum, 2017)</ref>. Indeed, timing may be such a flexible cue because faster or slower responses simply index more or less thought; the question of what the agent was thinking about must be determined by context. Our proposal suggests a developmental approach; while young children may expect thinking about unfamiliar problems to take more time than remembering the answer or seeing it directly, explaining why an agent took more or less time than expected in a specific context may be more difficult. We return to this point in the general discussion.</p><p>Timing-based inferences have at least three parts: (1) an observer's representation of an agent's actual response time, (2) the observer's expectations about how long a task will take to complete, and (3) a plausible explanation for any difference between the two times. While children's time perception is less precise than adults', the ability to represent and compare durations develops early: even three-year-olds judge a 3s interval between two stimuli as more similar to a 4s interval than to a 1s interval (Droit-Volet &amp; <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Wearden, 2001</ref>; see Wearden, 2016, for review).</p><p>Children can also identify plausible explanations for differences in response times between two agents, such as competence or task difficulty. However, conflicting heuristics based on effort, speed, and outcomes often confound younger children's competence judgments until late childhood unless task difficulty is transparent <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Nicholls, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr"></ref> Leonard, Bennett-Pierre, &amp; Gweon, 2019). For example, when experimenters explicitly described agents in a story as (A) finishing a puzzle quickly or slowly, (B) thinking it easy or difficult, and (C) trying hard or not, preschoolers integrated difficulty, effort, and speed <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Heyman &amp; Compton, 2006)</ref>. Of course, speed, effort, and task difficulty may rarely be explicitly described in the real world. Still, more recent work suggests children can also integrate these cues spontaneously under certain conditions: when presented with videos that varied agents' speed in building block towers and the relative difficulty of their task, preschoolers recognized the tradeoffs -but only when physical cues to difficulty were unambiguous (Leonard, Bennett-Pierre, &amp; Gweon, 2019).</p><p>However, cognitively challenging tasks frequently require no physical effort at all.</p><p>Nevertheless, the difficulty of cognitive processes themselves may be detectable for toddlers, even when the objective difficulty of the task is less certain.</p><p>Consider the case of speech disfluencies like uh and um: disfluencies occur more frequently under high cognitive load, such as might be imposed by recalling a rare word or weak memory, or by planning a complex utterance <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Clark &amp; Fox Tree, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr"></ref> Kidd, White, &amp; Aslin, 2011b). By 30 months, children appear to interpret speakers' speech disfluencies as resulting from processing difficulties: they predictively look at hard-to-describe or unfamiliar objects at the onset of the filled pause <ref type="bibr">(Arnold, Hudson Kam, &amp; Tanenhaus, 2007</ref>; Kidd, White, &amp; Aslin, 2011a; Orena &amp; White, 2015). Children's inference may reflect implicit causal reasoning: hard-to-describe objects cause processing difficulties, which in turn cause disfluencies; hence, a disfluency signals that the speaker is preparing to refer to an unfamiliar or hard-to-describe object. When given an alternative cause for a speaker's disfluency, participants' inference is blocked. For example, if a speaker frequently forgets the names of common objects, a speech disfluency may not imply that they are trying to recall a rare word in particular:</p><p>chronically forgetful speakers may just as disfluent in producing rare words as common words. On this account, the listener's reasoning begins not from beliefs about task difficulty per se, but from recognizing the signs of effortful cognitive processing. These cues then trigger a post-hoc search for an explanation of those difficulties.</p><p>To the extent that response time signals effortful cognitive processing, it could license a variety of inferences about everyday behaviors. However, psychological processes themselves vary in the time and effort involved. For example, perceptual processes tend to be fast and automatic. Seeing someone take several seconds to respond to a question like "is this ball red or pink?" may tell us that the color they're looking at is an ambiguous case, even if we can't see it ourselves; if it turns out to be fire-engine red, we might wonder whether the person is colorblind. Memory retrieval may be slower than perception, but someone who takes tens of seconds to respond when asked their spouse's birthday might still elicit doubt or consternation, even before they produce an answer. In contrast, longer pauses are to be expected for questions that require explicit thought about complex relations: thinking takes time, on a scale that memory and perception only require under unusual circumstances. In short, violating the expected timescale may be conspicuous: why did the person need to think about what color they were seeing? Why didn't the person need to think about the answer to a complex calculation? Our success as individuals and as a species depends on our ability to quickly and accurately assess the knowledge, intentions, and competence of other agents; a response that is "too quick" may suggest very different inferences than a response that is "too slow".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Method</head><p>Here, we examined the development of explicit timing-based inferences in childhood.</p><p>We initially focus on children ages 5-10 because younger children may struggle to evaluate time and difficulty simultaneously for cognitive tasks (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Nicholls, 1978)</ref>. In each experiment, participants were introduced to a pathfinding puzzle ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). After learning the rules, participants watched other agents play the game one by one. After either ~3 seconds or ~20 seconds, the agent signaled that he thought he knew the solution. Participants were then asked to make a judgment. In Experiment 1, participants saw a complex puzzle presented to the agent, and judged whether the agent was "figuring out the answer for the first time", or "remembering the answer from yesterday". We predicted that participants would categorize fast responses as memory, and slower responses as reasoning. Experiment 2 was identical, but participants judged whether the agent had "actually figured out" the answer or "made a mistake". We predicted that even the youngest children would expect fast responders to make mistakes, and to be more likely to make mistakes than slow responders. In Experiment 3, participants saw the agent draw a card with one of two puzzles (simple or complex), but the participants themselves could not see which; they were asked to guess which puzzle the agent was looking at, and then guess whether the agent's solution was accurate. We predicted that children would integrate response time and puzzle difficulty to infer which map the agent was looking at and whether their solution was accurate. Importantly, the puzzle difficulty and the agents' response time were never explicitly mentioned in any of the experiments; inferences based on time or difficulty were made spontaneously. All children participated through an online platform for developmental research <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Sheskin &amp; Keil, 2018)</ref>. Participants came from 39 US states, were 51.7% female, 65% white, and had a median household income of   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1)</ref>; presentation of these answer choices was counterbalanced (Color_CB). Adults answered using a scale slider. The order of the six maps was reversed for half the participants (MapOrder_CB). Finally, four counterbalances were created to vary the order of the agents' response times (TimeOrder_CB).</p><p>Procedure. Training Phase: Participants were told that they would play a racing game with Mario, and learned the object of the game and the rules. The experimenter described the task to the children over a video-chat; the same materials were presented to adults as a prerecorded voiceover slideshow. The experimenter told the participant that Mario wanted to collect all of the treasures on a map, and take the shortest road through the map that followed a rule. The rule was that Mario could "not pick up two treasures in a row that are the same color, or two in a row that are the same shape. But he has to pick up all of the treasures". Participants were then required to answer four comprehension questions correctly (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). These were as follows. (1) Which of two example roads is shorter, (2) Which of two example roads breaks a rule, (3) Why does that road break a rule, (4) Identify an item to pick up next in an example sequence.</p><p>Participants who answered each question correctly the first time proceeded to the test phase. Children's incorrect responses were gently corrected after each question, and they proceeded to the test phase only if they were able to answer all the comprehension questions correctly in two additional training rounds. Adults incorrect responses were not corrected, and adults proceeded to the test phase only if they correctly answered all the comprehension questions in the next round. After learning how to play the game, participants were told that they would watch other people playing the game, and that their job was to decide whether each person was (A) remembering the shortest road through the map from playing it the day before, or (B) figuring out the shortest road for the first time. At this point, MTurk participants also answered an attention check question in order to screen out participants who were skimming instructions.</p><p>First Task: Memory vs. Inference. For each test item <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig 1)</ref>, the experimenter presented a new silhouette sitting in front of a blank screen, saying "Here's the next person. We'll show him the map, and when he thinks he knows the shortest road that follows the rules, he'll start his engine", at which point the map appeared on the screen. After ~3s or ~20s, an engine sound played, and the experimenter said "now he's started his engine, so he thinks he knows the shortest route through the map", and participants decided whether the agent had been "remembering the answer from yesterday" or "figuring it out for the first time". Children first chose one of two alternatives (remembering or figuring out) and then were asked whether the agent was "probably" or "definitely" [remembering / figuring it out]; adults used a 4-point scale directly. Three maps were presented for ~3 seconds before the engine started, and three for ~20 seconds.</p><p>Second Task: Perception vs. Inference. Like memory, perceptual processes are nearly instantaneous, making direct perceptual access another potential explanation for fast responses. In a second task, the experimenter introduced two new cartoon agents, one of which was wearing opaque goggles. The experimenter specified that neither had played the game before (and so could not be remembering the maps), but that the silhouette with goggles "likes to cheat"; a computer in his goggles would show him the shortest road when he looked at the map, and so he would not have to figure out the answer himself. The other silhouette was described as playing fair. The experimenter presented a map to the two characters, and an engine sounded after ~3s. Participants were then asked who had started his engine: the one who "cheated with his special glasses and saw the answer", or the one who "played fair". We expected participants to infer that only a cheater would have responded so quickly to a complex puzzle, but did not preregister the hypothesis for the second task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The three responses at each response speed were averaged to create a single score for each ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref> year olds and 86.7% of 7 year olds, suggesting that even the youngest children recognized that three seconds is an impossibly fast latency to solve the puzzle for the Next, we explored whether children would rate the fast response as memory at younger ages than they rated slow responses as inference, but our prediction here was not supported. For each subject's average rating for fast and slow responses, we calculated the deviation from chance responding. We then regressed these values on age in years, using contrast coding to compare each level to chance. The 7, 9, and 10 year olds were more likely to rate the fast responses as memory (β 7 = .66, p&lt;.001, β 9 = .88, p&lt;. These results evince an early-developing commonsense intuition that "thinking takes time", while perception and memory -even memory for a solution to a complex problem -are expected to be much faster. In Experiments 2 and 3, we ask whether children can use this intuition to predict the accuracy of an agents' response, and whether they modulate their judgments according to the difficulty of the problem. Procedure. First Task: Speed-Accuracy Tradeoffs. We made one change to our materials from Experiment 1. Agents were now described as playing the game for the first time, and participants were asked to guess whether each agent had "actually figured out the shortest road, or if they made a mistake", again using a 4-point confidence scale. Second Task: Speed &amp; Competence. To compare our results to past work on children's timing-based inference, one trial at the end of the experiment asked participants to judge the relative competence of two agents who each accurately solved the same puzzle after either 3s or 20s. Because this task was included simply to compare our results with past work, the full method and results are described in the Supplemental Materials. In brief, younger children and adults were equally likely to judge the fast and slow agent as "better at this game", but older children believed the fast agent was better.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Results are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref>. The three responses at each response speed were averaged to create a single score for each. A repeated measures ANOVA revealed a significant effect of Speed (F(1,111)=72.16, p&lt;.0001, η² = .394) and an AgeGroup*Speed interaction (F(2,111)=10.69, p&lt;.0001, η² = .162), but no effect of AgeGroup (F(2,111)=1.50, p=.23, η² = .026). There were two unexpected order of presentation effects, both suggesting that the predicted effect was larger for one counterbalance than the others; however these effects were smaller than the main effect of Speed, and subsequent analyses suggested that they could not explain the focal findings (TimeOrder_CB:  </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">F(3,111)=5.</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3</head><p>If observers infer that "more time = more effort", then they may infer that agents who spend more time are solving more complex problems than agents who spend less time.</p><p>We predicted that children would infer that (A) fast agents were more likely to be looking at easy maps than hard maps, (B) fast agents were more likely than the slow agents to be looking the easy maps, and (C) fast agents' solutions were correct for the easy maps but incorrect for the hard maps. Because Experiments 1 and 2 suggested that timing-based inferences appear to emerge around age 6 or 7, we focused on ages 6-8 in Experiment 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants. We recruited 32 adults through MTurk, as well as 96 children <ref type="bibr">(</ref>  <ref type="formula">7</ref>, technical difficulties preventing videos from playing (5), and fussing out (1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials.</head><p>We generated a set of Easy puzzles by rearranging the treasures on the complex puzzles from Experiments 1 and 2 into a row of alternating colors and shapes, so that the shortest route passed directly through them. This produced pairs of maps which were identical in the number and kind of treasures, but were Easy or Hard to solve. In each trial, participants saw an agent draw a card with one of the two maps;</p><p>when the agent rang a bell to signal that they were ready, children guessed which map was on the card. As in previous experiments, neither time nor the difficulty of the maps was ever explicitly mentioned.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure. The training phase was the same as in Experiments 1 and 2. First Task:</head><p>Which Map? Agents were described as playing the game for the first time. The experimenter explained that each person would take a card with a map on it, and ring a bell when they thought they knew the shortest road. On each trial, the experimenter showed the participant a slide with an Easy map a Hard map, and a video embedded between them, and reminded the participant of the task: "this person might get the card with this map [points at simple map] or they might get the card with this map [points at hard map]. Your job is to guess which map was on their card". After the agent rang the bell, the experimenter said "They rang the bell, so that means that they think they've figured out the shortest road through the map. But which map was on the card they got?". Children first chose one of the two alternatives and then were asked whether the agent was "probably" or "definitely" looking at the map; adults used a 4-point scale directly. In two Fast trials, the agent rang the bell after 3s, and in two Slow trials the agent rang the bell after 20s. The order of the trials and the color of the answers was counterbalanced.</p><p>Second Task: Difficulty &amp; Accuracy. After the main task, participants completed two additional Fast trials. In one video, both cards had Hard maps. In the other, both had Easy maps. Participants were first asked which map the agent was looking at, but then also guessed whether the agent's solution was correct or not, on a 4-point scale. The order of the Easy and Hard trials was counterbalanced.</p><p>Results. The two ratings at each response speed were averaged to create a single score for each. The primary question of interest was whether children would infer that the  Violin plots and means with 95% CIs for two Fast trials in Experiment 3 in which participants first inferred which of two Hard or two Easy puzzles the agent was solving, and then predicted the agent's accuracy on a 4 point scale (1=Definitely incorrect, 2=Probably Incorrect, 3=Probably Correct, 4=Definitely Correct). Though participants were equally likely to guess either puzzle when the difficulty was equalized, they predicted that the fast agent's solution was correct for Easy puzzles and incorrect for Hard puzzles. Note that "Easy" and "Difficult" were implicit -map difficulty was never explicitly mentioned. Children's judgments thus appear to integrate both the complexity of the puzzle and the agent's response speed. This conclusion is further corroborated by the results of the second task, in which a Fast agent drew one of two Easy puzzles or one of two Hard puzzles: deprived of task difficulty as a cue, participants were no more likely to infer that the agent had drawn one than the other, in any age group (all p's=n.s.; see Supplemental Materials). However, all ages were more likely to say that the agent had solved the Easy puzzle than the Hard puzzle (Difference scores: M Age6 = 0.56, 95 CI: 0.03- </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Response time has been a powerful inductive tool in the behavioral sciences. It has been used to infer preference strength <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Konovalov &amp; Krajbich, 2019)</ref>, intelligence <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Salthouse, 1996)</ref>, the strength of memory traces <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Singer &amp; Tiede, 2008)</ref>, and of course, diligence in online surveys. Response times have even been argued to impose bottomup constraints on models of perception, by comparing the maximum transmission speed of a single neuron with the time typically sufficient for basic perceptual tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Feldman &amp; Ballard, 1982)</ref>. Less attention has been paid to how laypeople themselves interpret response times.</p><p>Our experiments provide evidence that from an early age, the commonsense intuition that "thinking takes time" may help us interpret everyday behaviors. Indeed, Experiment 3 suggests that children spontaneously integrate task difficulty to estimate how much time a task should take: all ages expected slower responses to harder problems than easier problems. These estimates may help children decide how fast is too fast for an agent solving a novel problem. Children appeared to recognize speed-accuracy tradeoffs and modulate their accuracy judgments according to task difficulty (Experiments 2 and 3). Moreover, when confronted with quick responses to hard problems, children believed that the agent must have recalled the answer from memory or seen it directly (Experiment 1). Given participants' propensity to explain away fast responses as inaccurate, memory-based, or simple, it may seem inconsistent that only 8-10-year-olds inferred that agents who quickly solved complex novel problems were more competent than slower agents (Experiment 2). However, given the complexity of the hard puzzles, adults' judgments may simply reflect the more sophisticated judgment that the fast agent had only "solved" the puzzle by a lucky guess.  <ref type="bibr">2003)</ref>. Much of this work has focused on the costs imposed by navigating complex spatial environments. As a fundamental constraint on every cognitive process and social interaction, time imposes costs that are even more ubiquitous, but may be more challenging to evaluate because of their sensitivity to context. Nevertheless, our results suggest that by age 6, the commonsense intuition that 'thinking takes time' -more time than perception and memory -may allow us to infer how another agent knows something as well as the quality and complexity of their knowledge. As children learn to integrate contextual information such as agents' expertise and the difficulty of a problem, this simple intuition could scaffold more sophisticated reasoning about agents' knowledge, intentions, and reliability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplemental Materials</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. Supplement Experiment 2: Methods &amp; Results for Competence Judgments</head><p>Method. Past work has suggested that children think that "fast = smart" <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Heyman &amp; Compton, 2006)</ref>; accordingly, younger children in particular could reason that "faster agents are smarter, and smarter agents are better at solving puzzles, so a faster response is more likely to be accurate". However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Heyman &amp; Compton (2006)</ref> verbally described agents' response time and task difficulty to children, leaving children no opportunity to decide how fast was too fast. When allowed to evaluate time and difficulty for themselves, children might show more skepticism. Thus, in order to compare our results to past work, we asked children to make a competence judgment at the end of the experiment. Children were shown two new figures and told that these agents would "each start their engines when they think they've figured out the shortest road that follows the rules". One agent started his engine at 3s, and the other at 20s. However, unlike in main task, we then told the children that both agents had answered correctly. Children were then asked which of the two agents was "better at this game".</p><p>If children have the "fast = better" bias observed in prior studies, then of two agents who both accurately solve a problem, children should believe that the faster agent is more competent.</p><p>Results. For the Ability question , younger children and adults did not differ from chance when asked whether the fast or slow agent was "better" at the game, but older children were more likely to choose the faster agent (Supplemental <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref>: M Younger =53.3%, binomial p=ns, M Older =71.1%, binomial p=.007, binomial M Adult =60.0%, p = ns).</p><p>Past research using vignettes about agents solving puzzles has suggested that while children have a "faster=better" bias, children under 7 also confound effort, ability, and outcome, while older children begin to attribute outcomes to some combination of effort and ability <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Heyman &amp; Compton, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Nicholls, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Stipek &amp; Iver, 1989</ref>).</p><p>Children's judgments in the second task were consistent with that developmental trajectory: when told that the outcome was the same for the fast and slow agent, the 5-7 year olds considered them equally competent, while older children appeared to infer <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Supplemental Fig 1.</ref> Percentage responding that the fast agent was better at solving puzzles than the slow agent. Error bars are 95% CI. that the difference in speed nevertheless implied a difference in competence. However, adults did not consider the faster agent more competent in the Ability task. Adults may have been rightly been skeptical of the fast agent's competence advantage. Puzzles as complex as the ones we used could only be "solved" in three seconds by a lucky guess.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. Supplement Experiment 2: Comparing responses on the 1st and 2nd task</head><p>If an agent's response speed triggers a joint inference about their competence, this could offer a competing account of children's accuracy judgments in the main task of Experiment 2. Comparing children's competence judgments in the 2nd task with their accuracy judgments in the first task offer could some evidence for or against this account. If participants thought that the slow agent in the main task was less competent than the fast agent, there are three patterns we might expect to observe in the data. First, they might expect the fast agent to be more accurate than the slow agent; however, our primary results directly contradict that prediction -indeed, the reverse is true. Second, participants who judged the fast agent as more competent than the slow agent in the 2nd task may also have expected the slow agent's solution to be less accurate (in an absolute sense) in the main task. However, we found no association between participants' average accuracy predictions for the slow agent in the first task and their relative competence judgments in the second task, for any age group or the sample as a whole (Models 1a-1c in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> below). Third, we might expect an association between the difference in average accuracy predictions for the fast and slow agents on the first task and children's competence judgments on the 2nd task. However, we again found no association here for any age group or the sample as a whole (Models 2a-2c in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> below).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. Supplement Experiment 3: Change to Materials</head><p>Materials. We made two changes to the materials in Experiment 3. In addition to generating a set of Easy maps, we used live videos of agents drawing one of two cards from a stack (instead of having a single map appearing on a screen before an animated 2D silhouette), looking at it, and ringing a bell to signal completion after either 3s or 20s.</p><p>This was done in order to clarify what the agent had visual access to and when, while simultaneously showing children the two possible maps on the powerpoint slide in <ref type="table">Table 1  Table 2</ref> which the video was embedded. Each map appeared on either a blue or green background, so that children could answer by simply saying a color. All materials, along with information about the videos and counterbalancing, can be found on the OSF repository.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. Supplement Experiment 3: Results for Second Task ("Which Map", when difficulty equalized)</head><p>In a second task at the end of the experiment, participants saw two additional trials, in which an agent drew a card with one of two Easy puzzles or one of two Hard puzzles and claimed to have solved the puzzle after 3s. Participants were then asked which map </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. Supplemental Analysis: Ordinal Regressions</head><p>The response variable for the main task in all three experiments was a 1-4 ordinal rating scale. Though we preregistered analyses based on standard regression techniques, which treat ordinal scales as metric data, some recent publications strongly recommend that ordinal data never be treated as metric due to the increased risk of both Type I and Type II errors (Liddell &amp; Kruschke, 2018) compared to alternative analyses.</p><p>Thus, we also also include an alternative analysis below which uses cumulative ordinal regressions with logit link functions. Instead of assuming that the distance between each level of the response to an ordinal scale (e.g., "definitely accurate" vs. "probably accurate") is equal, ordinal models assume that responses are mapped on to the ordered set of scale categories from an underlying continuous distribution, and search for the latent thresholds that "cut" the continuous distribution into response categories.</p><p>Intuitively, a ordinal regression can be thought of a set of logistic regressions moving in order from one cut threshold to the next. Thus, in addition to producing the odds ratios for each coefficient in the model, an ordinal regression produces k-1 thresholds, where k is the number of categories in the ordinal (e.g., Likert) scale. Importantly, while the standard coefficients reflect change across levels, the threshold cuts are the same for all levels of all variables. However, just as in logistic regression models, the thresholds and standard coefficients can be exponentiated to produce predicted probabilities.</p><p>We used the clmm function from the ordinal package in R, which has similar random effects syntax to the lme4 package. We conducted two kinds of ordinal regression for each Experiment, including by-participant random intercepts in each. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exp 2: Results of Ordinal Regression</head><p>The results of the ordinal regression were similar to those of the ANOVA. For older children, the model including random intercepts by-participant was singular;</p><p>when the by-participant intercepts were removed, the model suggested that 70.9% of responses from older children rated Slow responders as more likely accurate than inaccurate, a significant difference (z = 1.97, p = .0489). Thus, as in Experiment 1, the only difference between the ANOVA and ordinal regression was the inclusion of coefficients estimating the strength of the developmental shift across age groups. of 10 12</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exp 3: Results of Ordinal Regression</head><p>The results of the ordinal regression were similar to those of the ANOVA. We first asked whether the child sample would be more likely to infer that fast responses were easy maps than hard maps, using a model with random intercepts by participant, and age (centered on the mean of the child sample <ref type="formula">7</ref> 3.38, p &lt; .001; OR SlowAge8 = 6.54, SE = .40, z = 4.75, p &lt; .001; OR SlowAdult = 12.10, SE = 1.77, z = 4.86, p &lt; .001).</p><p>In the second task of Experiment 3, participants saw two trials in which an agent quickly responded to one of two hard maps or one of two easy maps and participants were asked to rate their accuracy on a 4-point scale after inferring which map was the agent's target (with no difference in the difficulty of the two maps, participants were equally likely to infer either as the agents' target; see main text). The fit of a model including random intercepts by-participant was singular, so we removed them; in the reduced model, a significant effect of difficulty level suggested that participants were more likely to infer that the agent's solution was accurate for the easy map than the hard map (Log-OR Item_Hard = - There was a significant interaction of age and difficulty for adults, but not for any other age group (Log-OR Adult*Item_Hard = -1.46, SE = .68, z = -2.12, p=.034). Running a separate model for the easy and hard maps for each age and exponentiating the 2|3 threshold coefficient to produce odds ratios suggested that, as with the ANOVA analysis in the main paper, absolute estimations of accuracy were less clear. Children ages 6 and 8, but not adults or 7-year-olds, believed that the agent's solution was inaccurate for the Hard puzzle (Log-OR Age6 = 3.00, SE = .41, z = 2.69, p = .007; Log-OR Age7 = 1.91, SE = .37, z =</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Training Procedure: Children had three chances to answer 3 of 3 training questions correctly: (1) "Which road is shorter, red or green? Yes, red, great job!", (2) "Which road breaks the rule? Yes, green! Great job! And why does it break the rule?", (3) "Let's say Mario drives on the red road instead. So first, he picks up the pink circle, and then he picks up the purple star. Which treasure should Mario pick up next, so that he's not breaking any rules? Example Trials: After a Hard map appeared on the screen (Exps 1 &amp; 2) or the agent drew a card with either an Easy or Hard map (Exp 3), the agent signaled that they had found the shortest road that followed the rules, after either 3s or 20s.$77,083, as estimated by US Census data for their reported postal code (US household median: $68,703). The pre-registrations, power analyses, data, and materials for each experiment are available on the first author's OSF repository. Though our preregistered analysis plan uses standard linear regressions and ANOVAs, we also provide analogous analyses using ordinal regressions, following recent recommendations against using standard regressions for ordinal data (Liddell &amp; Kruschke, 2018), which were brought to attention during the review process. Because both analyses produce nearly identical results in each experiment but ordinal regressions are still atypical in the field, we present our preregistered analyses in the main text and provide the ordinal regressions as a point of comparison in the supplementary materials. We recruited 45 adults through MTurk, as well as 90 children in two age groups (45 age 5-7, M=6.5, SD=.94; 45 age 8-10, M=9.45, SD=.90; 53% girls). An additional 8 children (3 age 5, 4 age 6, and 1 age 7) and 5 adults were excluded before data collection for answering training questions incorrectly; these were replaced with new participants.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Materials.</head><label></label><figDesc>We created six grid maps with simple geometric shapes of different colors scattered across them. Each map had 8 or 9 shapes of 3 or 4 different colors. A flag in the bottom left corner of the grid marked the finish line, and a MarioKart character at the top right marked the starting line. During the test phase, participants saw the maps appear in front of a cartoon silhouette facing a computer screen. Children answered by using color-coded cartoon figures on the left and right of the screen</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). A repeated measures ANOVA revealed a significant effect of Speed (F(1,132)=202.09, p&lt;.0001, η² = .605) and an AgeGroup*Speed interaction (F(2,132)=17.51, p&lt;.0001, η² = .210), but no effect of AgeGroup (F(2,132)=0.425, p=.65, η² = .006). As predicted, all age groups categorized the fast response as memory (M Young =2.13, t(44) = -3.23, p=.002, M Old =1.80, t(44) = -7.33, p&lt;.0001, M Adult =1.47, t(44) = -13.00, p&lt;.0001), and categorized the slow response as inference (M Young =2.75, t(44) = 2.63, p=.012, M Old =3.21, t(44) = 7.23, p&lt;.0001, M Adult =3.45, t(44) = 10.58, p&lt;.0001). All age groups also identified the fast responder as having cheated(Fig. 3), including 80% of 6</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Violin plots and means with 95% CIs for Fast and Slow trials in Experiment 1. Each dot is the average of each participant's 3 fast trials (Green) or 3 slow trials (Blue). Participants rated each agent on a 4-point scale (1=Definitely remembering, 2=Probably remembering, 3=Probably figuring out for the first time, 4=Definitely figuring out for the first time). first time, but is easily explained by having direct perceptual access (M Young =71.1%, binomial p=.003, M Old =84.4%, binomial p&lt;.0001, binomial M Adult =91.1%, p&lt;.0001).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Proportions inferring that a Fast (3s) agent had "cheated" by seeing the solution in their computerized goggles (brown) or "played fair" by solving the puzzle themselves (green). Error bars are 95% CIs. 001, β 10 = .95, p&lt;.001), but the 5, 6, and 8 year olds did not differ from chance (β 5 = .21, p=.226, β 6 = .23, p=.180, β 8 = .28, p=.111). The 7, 8, 9, and 10 year olds were more likely to rate the slow responses as inference (β 7 = .54, p&lt;.001, β 8 = .37, p=.020, β 9 = .70, p&lt;.001, β 10 = 1.06, p&lt;.001), but the 5 and 6 year olds did not differ from chance (β 5 = -0.08, p=.618, β 6 = .28, p=.075).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>We recruited 45 adults through MTurk, as well as 90 children in two age groups (45 age 5-7, M=6.79, SD=.82; 45 age 8-10, M=9.84, SD=.82; 51% girls). An additional twelve children and one adult were screened out and replaced before data collection for failing the training (6), losing internet connection (2), fussing out (2), parent interference (2), and colorblindness (1).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Violin plots and means with 95% CIs for Fast and Slow trials in Experiment 2. Each dot is the average of each participant's 3 fast trials (Green) or 3 slow trials (Blue). Participants rated each agent on a 4-point scale (1=Definitely incorrect, 2=Probably incorrect, 3=Probably correct, 4=Definitely correct).chance (M Young =2.49, t(44)=-0.12, p=.907, M Old =2.66, t(44)=2.<ref type="bibr" target="#b16">16</ref>, p=.036, M Adult =2.76, t(44) = 3.00, p=.004). Children may have been right to be skeptical of accuracy on the slow trials: given the computational complexity of these problems, even 20s is too fast to solve them except by luck. Indeed, given past work suggesting that even older children can be unreasonably credulous towards confident speakers(Kominsky, Langthorne, &amp;   Keil, 2015), even a skepticism on the fast trials that emerges around age 6 or 7 may be precocious. However, since the difference between the fast and slow trials was not significant in the younger age group, interpretations of the youngest children's responses as reflecting skepticism of the agents' accuracy should be taken with a grain of salt. In Experiment 3, we examine the possibility of an early-but-nuanced skepticism more closely, asking whether children's judgments integrate both response time and task difficulty.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Fast</head><label></label><figDesc>agent was looking at the Easy puzzle. To test this, we centered children's average ratings on the Fast trials on chance performance (2.5 on a 4-point scale), and centered children's age on the average age of the sample. This makes the intercept of the regression equivalent to a t.test for the whole sample, but allows us to simultaneously check for age effects, using age as a continuous variable. As predicted, children were more likely to infer that the Fast agent must have been looking at the Easy puzzle than the Hard puzzle (β Int = -0.68, SE = .076, p&lt;.0001); the age effect was also significant, though smaller (β Int = -0.21, SE = .093, p&lt;.026). To examine the developmental pattern more closely, we also conducted one-sample t.tests comparing each age to chanceseparately; all ages were significantly more likely to infer that the Fast agent was</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Fig 5 .Fig 6 .</head><label>56</label><figDesc>Violin plots and means with 95% CIs for Fast and Slow trials in Experiment 3. Each dot is the average of each participant's 2 fast trials (Green) or 2 slow trials (Blue). Participants guess which map each agent was looking at, on a 4-point scale (1=Definitely Easy, 2=Probably Easy, 3=Probably Hard 4=Definitely Hard). Note that "Easy" and "Difficult" were implicitmap difficulty was never explicitly mentioned.looking at the Easy puzzle than the Hard puzzle (M Age6 = -0.53, t(31)=-3.38, p=.002; M Age7 = -0.56, t(31)=-4.13, p=.00026; M Age8 = -0.95 t(31)=-10.2, p&lt;.0001). The effect was similar for adults (M Age8 = -1.38 t(31)=-25.0, p&lt;.0001). Next, we compared children's inferences for Fast and Slow agents, using AgeYears and Speed as predictors. A repeated measures ANOVA revealed a significant effect of Speed (F(1,93)=28.11, p&lt;.0001, η² = .232) but no effect of AgeYears or AgeYears*Speed interaction (AgeYears: F(2,93)=1.45, p=.24, η² = .03;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The possibility of 'lucky guesses' illustrates an interesting contrast between reasoning about agents' allocation of time and reasoning about their navigation of space: costs measured in time may be more malleable than costs in distance, making reasoning about the utility of agents' actions on the basis of time more challenging -but also potentially more informative about the agent themselves. An agent that prefers a reward that is spatially distal over one that is spatially proximal must pay a higher cost to obtain the more valuable reward every time they do so; in this sense, space imposes a fixed cost to any physical action (Baker, Jara-Ettinger, Saxe, &amp; Tenenbaum, 2017; Jara-Ettinger, Gweon, Schulz, &amp; Tenenbaum, 2016; Jara-Ettinger,<ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Gweon, Tenenbaum, &amp; Schulz, 2015)</ref>. For instance, if the toddler in the dining room prefers the cherries in the kitchen to the dinner on the table, the distance to the kitchen is fixed both for them and their parent: no walking, no cherries. The immutability of spatial costs may make them particularly useful for analyzing rational action even in early infancy<ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Gergely &amp; Csibra, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Liu et al., 2017)</ref>. In contrast, while it may take longer to count a bowl of 35 cherriesthan a bowl of 30 cherries, a lucky guess could get them the 35 cherries without having to count; moreover, developmental changes in counting skill and precision in approximate number estimation may lead to different expected values of each strategy for a toddler and their parent (Halberda &amp; Feigenson, 2008; Baer &amp; Odic, 2019). Analogously, if an expert gives a quick estimate instead of a time-consuming calculation, we might infer that an 'educated guess' is sufficiently precise; but a novice who gives a quick estimate may not even understand the parameters of the question. In other words, while guessing and reasoning have their characteristic time signatures, successfully reasoning about time-costs may require us to consider context-specific factors like the complexity of the problem, the methods available to solve it, and potentially the competence of the agent. Thus, even with hard constraints on mental speed, cost-based reasoning about time may require more sophisticated inferences than cost-based reasoning about space. Timing's sensitivity to context may also help explain why competence judgments show a protracted developmental trajectory in the existing literature (Nicholls, 1978; Stipek &amp; Mac Iver, 1989; Heyman &amp; Compton, 2006): integrating multiple cues can be challenging for children. Neither speed, effort, nor accuracy alone signals competence: a competent agent must outperform the expected speed-accuracy tradeoffs because of their abilities. When simple heuristics like "more effort = better outcomes", "better outcomes = more competent", and "faster = better" imply conflicting competence judgments, children may find it difficult to weigh the relative importance of each dimension. Accounting for differences in motivation and attention adds to the challenge: conscientiousness and distraction can both increase response time, just as genius and haste can decrease it. However, recent computational work has suggested that by adulthood, people can distinguish distraction from focused thought by integrating the response time and complexity of the most likely topic of focus (Berke &amp; Jara-Ettinger, 2021). Children's inferences in our experiments were less sophisticated than competence judgments, but also more general: thinking takes more time than remembering or seeing, more complex problems require more thinking, and some problems are impossible to solve immediately. However, while our aim was not to establish the earliest age at which children can reason about response time, task demands still limit our conclusions about younger children's abilities. Though the rules to the puzzle game we used were simple enough that most children had no trouble learning them, the game was novel to children, and the procedure provided little reinforcement of the rules after the training. While our participants displayed precocious skepticism and sensitivity to task difficulty, novelty and low incentives may have hindered younger children's performance. If children learn to simulate others' mental processes through experience of their own mental processes in similar contexts, our study may have underestimated their capacities simply by giving them little experience solving the maps themselves (Sommerville, Woodward, &amp; Needham, 2005; Meltzoff &amp; Brooks, 2008; Kano et al., 2019). While the task was also novel for older children and adults, they may have also found it easier to simulate solving the maps for themselves before answering. Future work could test children's performance in a more familiar context, or compare their performance with and without additional practice solving similar puzzles. Future work could explore the impact of inferences about time on children's learning strategies. Some of these inferences may come from monitoring their own response time. For example, children increasingly modulate the time spent on easy versus difficult items in the Raven's Progressive Matrices battery with age, and the degree of modulation is strongly correlated with performance (Perret &amp; Dauvier, 2018). By adulthood, people's problem-solving strategies not only weigh time costs in the hundreds of milliseconds, but may integrate both cognitive and physical costs (Gray, Sims, Fu &amp; Schoelles, 2006; Feghhi &amp; Rosenbaum, 2019). Choices between different strategies can be thought of in terms of opportunity costs: in addition to costs and benefits of each strategy individually, an individual who uses one strategy foregoes the opportunity to benefit from the other strategy (Boreau, Sokol-Hessner, &amp; Daw, 2015). Thus, an understanding of how children learn to allocate time effectively may need to consider the both effectiveness of the problem-solving strategies available to them and the cognitive and physical tradeoffs between those strategies. For instance, in contexts that provide immediate accuracy feedback and little penalty for mistakes, it may be more rational to learn by trial-and-error than attempting to solve a problem through thinking alone. Future work could explore how children allocate time when the costs of error are high or low. Future work could also explore the use of response time in combination with other common social learning strategies. For instance, novices may be generally slow; but delays from experts may indicate a complex problem, a valuable solution, or a gap in the field's knowledge. Thus, experts' time allocation in particular may help learners estimate the value of persistence, either generally or for a specific task or problem-solving method. Indeed, children persist longer at physical tasks after observing adults spend more time and effort, but only if the adult's persistence paid off (Leonard, Lee, &amp; Schulz, 2017; Leonard, Garcia, &amp; Schulz, 2019). Even in early childhood, the assumption that agents pursue goals efficiently by minimizing expected costs while maximizing expected rewards helps us reason about others' preferences, knowledge, and beliefs (Jara-Ettinger, Gweon, Tenenbaum, &amp; Schulz, 2015; Jara-Ettinger, Gweon, Schulz, &amp; Tenenbaum, 2016; Gergely &amp; Csibra,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Model 1 Exp 1 :</head><label>11</label><figDesc>looks for between condition differences; when Model 2 is run on each Age and RTSpeed separately, exponentiating the threshold cut between levels 2 and 3 of the 4point Likert scale compares ratings to chance. (Model 1): clmm(as.ordered(Ratings) ~ RTSpeed*AgeGroup + (1|subID), data=., link="logit") (Model 2): clmm(as.ordered(Ratings) ~ 1 + (1|subID), data=., link="logit") Results of Ordinal Regression The results of the ordinal regression were similar to those of the ANOVA. Model 1 suggested that the age groups as a whole were more likely to infer that slow responders were figuring the maps out for first time than fast responders (Log-OR SpeedSlow =1.16, SE = .23, z = 5.01, p=.001). Moreover, both older children and adults were more likely than younger children to infer that the fast responders were remembering than figuring out (Log-OR AgeOlder =-0.55, SE = .23, z = -2.39, p=.017; Log-OR AgeAdult =-1.20, SE = .24, z = -4.99, p=.001), with the difference between fast and slow agents also increasing across AgeGroups (Log-OR Older*Slow = 1.35, SE = .32, z = 4.20, p=.001; Log-OR Adult*Slow = 2.52, SE = .34, z = 7.51, p=.001). Exponentiating the 2|3 threshold coefficient from Model 2 produced similar results, suggesting that all age groups also inferred that Fast responders were more likely to be remembering answers than figuring out: the model predicts that 65.7% of younger children (z = 2.82, 95CI: 54.9-75.0), 83.2% of older children (z = 5.33, 95CI: 73.3-89.9), and 95.5% of adults (z = 5.92, 95CI: 88.5-98.3) would give a rating of 2 or less on the 4-point scale. The reverse was true for Slow responders: the model predicts that 67.3% of younger children (z = -3.58, 95CI: 58.1-75.3), 84.3% of older children (z = -4.84, 95CI: 73.1-91.39), and 90.9% of adults (z = -5.80, 95CI: 82.1-95.6) would give a rating of 3 or more on the 4-point scale. Thus, the only difference between the ANOVA and ordinal regression was the inclusion of coefficients estimating the strength of the developmental shift across age groups.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>) as a fixed effect. The effect of Ct_Age was significant (Log-OR Ct_Age =-0.48, SE = .24, z = -2.05, p=.041). Exponentiating the 2|3 threshold coefficient of Model 2 suggested that 82.9% of 6-year-olds (z = 2.88, 95CI: 62.4 -93.4), 78.3% of 7-year-olds (z = 3.25, 95CI: 62.4-88.6), and 91.8% of 8-year-olds (z = 97.0, 95CI: 79.5-97.0) would infer the fast agents to be solving easy maps rather than hard maps. Similarly, when both Ct_Age and RTSpeed were included as fixed effects, participants inferred that fast agents were more likely than slow agents to be solving easy maps (Log-OR SpeedSlow =1.27, SE = .20, z = 6.23, p &lt;.001), with a significant effect of age and a marginal interaction (Log-OR Ct_Age =-0.40, SE = .19, z = -2.05, p=.04; Log-OR Age*Speed =0.47, SE = .24, z = 1.96, p=.05). While neither the age effect nor the interaction reached significance in the analogous ANOVA presented in the main paper, these effects do not change the results: running a separate model of RTSpeed for each age as well as adults and exponentiating the 2|3 threshold coefficient to produce odds ratios suggested that the difference between fast and slow trials was significant for all age groups (OR SlowAge6 = 2.26, SE = .33, z = 2.45, p = .014; OR SlowAge7 = 3.24, SE = .35, z = of 11 12</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>1 . 28 ,</head><label>128</label><figDesc>SE = .49, z = -2.64, p=.008), with the inferred accuracy of the easy map increasing with age (Log-OR Age7 = 1.10, SE = .47, z = 2.35, p=.019; Log-OR Age8 = 1.01, SE = .48, z = 2.10, p=.036; Log-OR Adult = 2.30, SE = .51, z = 4.51, p &lt; .001).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>27, p=.002, η² = .125; MapOrder_CB*Speed: F(1,111)=3.97, p=.049, η² = .034). Post hoc comparisons of the Age*Speed interaction revealed that while the adults and older children distinguished between 3s and 20s responses as predicted, the difference for younger children was not significant (Young: M Fast =2.24, M Slow =2.49 t(111) = -2.18, p=.473; Older: M Fast =2.19, M Slow =2.66, t(111)=-4.02, p=.0016; Adult: M Fast =1.77, M Slow =2.76, t(111) = -8.49, p&lt;.0001, bonferroni corrected). However, all age groups predicted that fast responses were likely to be wrong (M Young =2.24, t(44)=-3.04, p=.004, M Old =2.19, t(44) = -3.55, p&lt;.001, M Adult =1.77, t(44) = -9.47, p&lt;.0001). While adults and older rated the slow responses as likely to be right, younger children did not differ from</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>32 age 6, M=6.46, SD=.31; 32 age 7 M=7.55, SD=.31; 32 age 8, M=8.59, SD=.30; 48 girls). An additional 13 children were screened out and replaced before data collection for failing the training</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>AgeYears*Speed: F(2,93)=1.31, p=.27, η² = .027). Paired-sample t.tests revealed that the effect was similar for all age groups individually, including adults (Age6: M Fast =1.97, M Slow =2.41, t(31) = 14.1, p&lt;.0001; Age7: M Fast =1.94, M Slow =2.58, t(31) = 14.2, p&lt;.0001; Age8: M Fast =1.55, M Slow =2.48, t(31) = 16.3, p&lt;.0001; Adults: M Fast =1.12, M Slow =3.88, t(31) = 70.5,</figDesc><table><row><cell>p&lt;.0001).</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>.61), suggesting that they recognized the relative difficulty of the two puzzles.Estimations of absolute difficulty were less clear. Adults and children ages 7 and 8, but not age 6, believed that the agent's solution was correct for the Easy puzzle (M Age6 = 2.56, 95 CI: 2.22-2.91; M Age7 = 3.12, 95 CI: 2.81-3.41; M Age8 = 3.03, 95 CI: 2.66-3.38; M Adult = 3.68, 95 CI: 3.52-3.84), while children ages 6 and 8, but not adults or 7-year-olds, believed that the agent's solution was incorrect for the Hard puzzle (M Age6 = 2.00, 95 CI: 1.66-2.38; M Age7 = 2.31, 95 CI: 1.97-2.69; M Age8 = 2.12, 95 CI: 1.91-2.38; M Adult = 2.28, 95 CI: 2.00-2.56).</figDesc><table><row><cell>1.09; M Age7 = 0.81, 95 CI: 0.25-1.31; M Age8 = 0.91, 95 CI: 0.50-1.31; M Adult = 1.35, 95 CI:</cell></row><row><cell>1.06-1</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>When the agent in Exp 3 might have drawn one of two Easy or one of two Hard maps, participants were equally like to choose either of the two possible options. the agent had been looking at. Deprived of task difficulty as a cue, participants were no more likely to infer that the agent had drawn one than the other (Age6: M Easy =46.9%, p=0.860., M Hard =53.1%, p=0.860; Age7: M Easy = 59.4%, p=0.377, M Hard =46.9%, p=0.860;Age8: M Easy = 46.9%, p=0.860, M Hard = 56.2%, p=0.597; Adults: M Easy = 32.3%, p=0.071, M Hard = 50.0%, p=1.00). Results are shown inSupplemental Fig 2, below.</figDesc><table /><note>Supplemental Fig 2.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Model 1    suggested that all age groups were more likely to infer that slow responders were accurate than inaccurate (Log-OR SpeedSlow =0.53, SE = .23, z = 2.25, p=.024). Additionally, adults were more likely than younger children to infer that the fast responders were inaccurate than accurate, though older children did not differ from younger children(Log-OR AgeOlder =-0.55, SE = .23, z = -2.39, p=.017; Log-OR AgeAdult =-1.20, SE = .24, z = -4.99, p=.001); similarly, while the difference between inferences for fast and slow ages was significantly greater for adults than younger children, the difference was no greater in older children than younger children (Log-OR Older*Slow = 1.35, SE = .32, z = 4.20, p=.001; Log-OR Adult*Slow = 2.52, SE = .34, z = 7.51, p=.001). Exponentiating the 2|3 threshold coefficient from Model 2 suggested that all age groups also inferred that Fast responders were more likely be inaccurate than accurate: Model 2 predicts that 62.2% of younger children (z = 2.81, 95CI: 54.9-70.0), 64.3% of older children (z = 2.98, 95CI: 55.0-72.6), and 86.9% of adults (z = 6.39, 95CI: 78.8-92.2) would give a rating of 2 or less on the 4point scale. However, while Model 2 predicts that 74.3% of adults (z = 2.89, 95CI: 58.4-8.56) inferred that Slow responders were more likely accurate than inaccurate, the difference for younger children was not significant (48.1%, z = 0.43, 95CI: 39.4-56.9).</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research was supported by NSF grant DRL 1561143 awarded to Frank C. Keil.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">If you say thee uh you are describing something hard: The on-line attribution of disfluency during reference comprehension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Arnold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L H</forename><surname>Kam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Tanenhaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0278-7393.33.5.914</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-7393.33.5.914" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="914" to="930" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rational quantitative attribution of beliefs, desires and percepts in human mentalizing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jara-Ettinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Saxe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-017-0064</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-017-0064" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Certainty in numerical judgments develops independently of the approximate number system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Baer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Odic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogdev.2019.100817</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogdev.2019.100817" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">100817</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thinking about thinking through inverse reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Berke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jara-Ettinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/r25qn</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/r25qn" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-05-20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deciding How To Decide: Self-Control and Meta-Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y.-L</forename><surname>Boureau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sokol-Hessner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2015.08.013</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2015.08.013" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="700" to="710" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The feeling of Another&apos;s Knowing: Prosody and filled pauses as cues to listeners about the metacognitive states of speakers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brennan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Memory and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="398" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using uh and um in spontaneous speaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fox Tree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0010-0277(02)00017-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0010-0277(02" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal Bisection in Children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Droit-Volet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wearden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1006/jecp.2001.2631</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1006/jecp.2001.2631" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Child Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judging the subjective difficulty of different kinds of tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Feghhi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rosenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xhp0000653</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/xhp0000653" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="983" to="994" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Connectionist Models and Their Properties</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ballard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15516709cog0603_1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15516709cog0603_1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="254" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using Response Times to Infer Others&apos; Beliefs: An Application to Information Cascades</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Frydman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.2817026</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2817026" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A rational model of people&apos;s inferences about others&apos; preferences based on response times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Gates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Callaway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/25zfx</idno>
		<ptr target="psyArXiv.10.31234/osf.io/25zfx" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reverse-engineering the process: Adults&apos; and preschoolers&apos; ability to infer the difficulty of novel tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Asaba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bennett-Pierre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teleological reasoning in infancy: The naı̈ve theory of rational action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gergely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Csibra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S1364-6613(03)00128-1</idno>
		<idno>1016/S1364-6613(03)00128-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The soft constraints hypothesis: A rational analysis approach to resource allocation for interactive behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sims</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W.-T</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schoelles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.113.3.461</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.113.3.461" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="482" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developmental change in the acuity of the &quot;number sense</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Halberda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Feigenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0012682</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0012682" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The approximate number system in 3-, 4-, 5-, and 6-year-olds and adults</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1457" to="1465" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context sensitivity in children&apos;s reasoning about ability across the elementary school years</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Heyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Compton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-7687.2006.00540.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-7687.2006.00540.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="616" to="627" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Naïve Utility Calculus: Computational Principles Underlying Commonsense Psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jara-Ettinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2016.05.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2016.05.011" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="589" to="604" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Children&apos;s understanding of the costs and rewards underlying rational action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jara-Ettinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2015.03.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2015.03.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">140</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Great apes use self-experience to anticipate an agent&apos;s action in a false-belief test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Kano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Krupenye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hirata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tomonaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Call</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1910095116</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1910095116" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20904" to="20909" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Um&quot;: Toddlers&apos; developing use of speech disfluencies as cues to</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kidd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Aslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>I. Arnon &amp; E. V</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Learning the Meaning of</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clark</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Experience, Variation, and Generalization: Learning a First Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">28</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toddlers use speech disfluencies to predict speakers&apos; referential intentions: Toddlers use disfluencies to predict referential intentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kidd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Aslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-7687.2011.01049.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-7687.2011.01049.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="925" to="934" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The better part of not knowing: Virtuous ignorance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Kominsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Langthorne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dev0000065</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/dev0000065" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Strategic Use of Response Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Konovalov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.3023640</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3023640" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SSRN Electronic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revealed strength of preference: Inference from response times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Konovalov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">14</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who is better? Preschoolers infer relative competence based on efficiency of process and quality of outcome</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Leonard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bennett-Pierre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page">7</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How Adults&apos; Actions, Outcomes, and Testimony Affect Preschoolers&apos; Persistence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Leonard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Garcia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/cdev.13305</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/cdev.13305" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Infants make more attempts to achieve a goal when they see adults persist</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Leonard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.aan2317</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aan2317" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">357</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6357</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1290" to="1294" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analyzing ordinal data with metric models: What could possibly go wrong</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Liddell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2018.08.009</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2018.08.009" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="328" to="348" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ten-month-old infants infer the value of goals from the costs of actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Ullman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Spelke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">358</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6366</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1038" to="1041" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.aag2132</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aag2132" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-experience as a mechanism for learning about others: A training study in social cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Meltzoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Brooks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0012888</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0012888" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1257" to="1265" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Development of the Concepts of Effort and Ability, Perception of Academic Attainment, and the Understanding That Difficult Tasks Require More Ability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Nicholls</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I Forget What That&apos;s Called! Children&apos;s Online Processing of Disfluencies Depends on Speaker Knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Orena</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/cdev.12421</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/cdev.12421" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1701" to="1709" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Summer Vision Project (Project Mac AI Memo 100)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Papert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://dspace.mit.edu/handle/1721.1/6125" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perret-Clermont (2004) A Socio-cognitive perspective on learning and cognitive development.pdf</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Perret-Clermont</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Cognitive and Language Development in Children</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The interaction of inter-turn silence with prosodic cues in listener perceptions of &quot;trouble&quot; in conversation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.specom.2006.02.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.specom.2006.02.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Speech Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1079" to="1093" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Processing-Speed Theory of Adult Age Differences in Cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Salthouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">TheChildLab.com A Video Chat Platform for Developmental Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sheskin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/rn7w5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/rn7w5" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feeling of knowing and duration of unsuccessful memory search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Tiede</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/MC.36.3.588</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/MC.36.3.588" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="588" to="597" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developmental Change in Children&apos;s Assessment of Intellectual Competence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Stipek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Iver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">19</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Action experience alters 3-month-old infants&apos; perception of others&apos; actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sommerville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Woodward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Needham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2004.07.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2004.07.004" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quick Thinkers Are Smooth Talkers: Mental Speed Facilitates Charisma</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Von Hippel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ronay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kjelsaas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797615616255</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797615616255" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="122" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Palgrave Macmillan 1.74, p = .082; Log-OR Age8 = 5.40, SE = .49, z = 3.46, p &lt; .001; Log-OR Adult = 1.58, SE = .37, z = 1.25, p = .213), while children ages 7 and 8, but not age 6, believed that the agent&apos;s solution was accurate for the Easy puzzle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wearden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page">724</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The psychology of time perception. Log-OR Age6 = 0.88, SE = .35, z = -0.35</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<idno>Log-OR Age7 = 0.28</idno>
		<title level="m">SE = .43, z = -2.98, p = .003; Log-OR Age8</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>= 0.39, SE = .39, z = -2.39, p =</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Similarly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>no adult rated accuracy on the Easy maps as less than 3 (&quot;probably</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
