<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Asymmetric Anticipatory Emotions Underlie Risk and Time Preferences Running Head: &quot;Asymmetric Anticipatory Emotions&quot;</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2024-06-27">June 27, 2024</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dawson</surname></persName>
							<email>c.g.dawson@bath.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>BA2 7AY</postCode>
									<settlement>Bath</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
							<email>samuel.johnson@uwaterloo.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>BA2 7AY</postCode>
									<settlement>Bath</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Waterloo</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>N2L 3G1</postCode>
									<settlement>Waterloo</settlement>
									<region>ON</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>CV4 7AL</postCode>
									<settlement>Coventry</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>De Meza</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lukasz</forename><surname>Walasek</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Asymmetric Anticipatory Emotions Underlie Risk and Time Preferences Running Head: &quot;Asymmetric Anticipatory Emotions&quot;</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2024-06-27">June 27, 2024</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Anticipatory emotions</term>
					<term>Intertemporal choice</term>
					<term>Risky choice</term>
					<term>Behavioral economics</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>, and Joël van der Weele, and audiences at the Universities of Bath and Warwick for helpful discussion. Note. This is a preprint and has not been peer reviewed. Any subsequent journal publication will supersede this preprint as the version of record.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>When deciding to bet at the roulette table, we are meant to assess the likelihood of losing alongside a subjective estimate of how bad that loss would feel. However, if we make the bet, and the roulette wheel starts spinning, anticipatory emotions such as dread arise as we focus on the potential loss. This feeling of dread is endured until the roulette wheel slows and the uncertainty is resolved. Countless decisions are like this-starting a business, choosing a spouse, even submitting a journal article: They involve both risk and delay, their uncertain consequences revealed only with time.</p><p>In this article, we study individual differences in anticipatory emotions and their link to risk and time preferences. First, we find that negative anticipation (dread) is more powerful than positive anticipation (savoring). Second, this asymmetry is associated with both risk-avoidance and impatience. To the extent dread is expected to outweigh savoring, this makes a gamble less attractive. And if the bet is placed, the gambler pleads for the roulette wheel to stop, to resolve the dread-inducing uncertainty. Thus, asymmetric anticipatory emotions provide the missing psychological link between risk and time preferences.</p><p>We distinguish three kinds of emotions that influence decision-making based on their temporal profile <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Baumgartner et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Loewenstein et al, 2001)</ref>. Consider a choice made at time ! which will deliver a good or bad outcome at " . First, we feel reactive emotions in response to resolved outcomes, such as the (dis)pleasure of experienced gains and losses. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, reactive emotions occur at " in response to outcomes (e.g., money gained or lost at roulette). Second, we feel anticipatory emotions before an outcome, generated from mental imagery of the decision's expected consequences-savoring or dread in anticipation of imagined good or bad " outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Loewenstein, 1987)</ref>. Anticipatory emotions occur at # in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> (e.g., while the roulette wheel is spinning). Third, we forecast our future emotions at ! (e.g., when placing bets); these are expected emotions. Since reactive and anticipatory emotions occur after the decision is made, these emotions influence choice only through how they are expected at ! <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Mellers, Schwartz, &amp; Ritov, 1999)</ref>.</p><p>Expected reactive emotions manifest in the avoidance, at ! , of options expected to lead to negative reactive emotions at " , such as regret or disappointment <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Loomes &amp; Sugden, 1982)</ref>.</p><p>Famously, people are loss averse <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979)</ref>-they assume (at ! ) that the displeasure of losses is greater than the pleasure of gains (at " ). Interestingly, loss aversion may be partially an affective-forecasting error: Forecasts of loss aversion are large, whereas the realized emotional impact of losses and gains are more symmetric <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Kermer et al., 2006</ref>).</p><p>Yet this forecast, even if erroneous, matters greatly for decision-making: At the time a decision is made ( ! ), we know only how we expect it will make us feel. Expected anticipatory emotions are known to influence intertemporal choice. Whereas most behavioral models aim to explain why people undervalue future outcomes <ref type="bibr">(Loewenstein &amp; Prelec, 1991)</ref>, at other times people value the future too highly. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Loewenstein (1987)</ref> showed that discount rates can be negative when future sources of (dis)utility are particularly vivid. For example, Loewenstein's participants were willing to pay more to receive a kiss from a movie star in 3 days than 1 day, and more to avoid an electric shock in 1 year than 3 days. Loewenstein assumed that this occurs because people gain or lose utility not only from consuming these events (associated with reactive emotions) but also from imagining them (associated with anticipatory emotions). Whereas consumption utility will only be attained in the future, and hence is steeply discounted, (dis)utility from savoring or dread is experienced continuously from the time of the decision until the event. Thus, experiencing the shock sooner avoids disutility from dread that more-than-offsets the discounting of its consumption disutility.</p><p>Subsequent studies confirm this basic picture <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Berns et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Harris, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Story et al., 2013</ref>).</p><p>However, dread and savoring are not equally powerful <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Molouki et al., 2019)</ref>. The disutility from imagining negative events is greater than the utility of imagining comparable positive events for two reasons <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 1)</ref>. First, since people are loss averse, anticipatory emotions at # should reflect the greater disutility of bad outcomes at " . Just as dread would be greater for a $200 than for a $100 loss, dread for a $100 loss (psychologically valued at $200 due to loss aversion) would be greater than savoring for a $100 gain (valued at $100). Second, dread itself could be a more powerful emotion than savoring-an asymmetry we dub dread aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Dawson &amp; de Meza, 2018)</ref>. Imagining a positive outcome is emotionally mixed, whereas imagining a negative outcome is purely negative <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Hardisty &amp; Weber, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Nowlis et al., 2004</ref>). Whereas we dread an upcoming electric shock, we experience both savoring and impatience over an upcoming vacation. For example, most people prefer to resolve lotteries sooner as the magnitude of the payoff increases, suggesting that savoring competes (and sometimes loses) to other emotions such as impatience <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Ganguly &amp; Tasoff, 2017)</ref>.</p><p>In this article, we argue that asymmetric anticipatory emotions explain a fundamental puzzle about economic preferences: Why risk and time preferences are strongly inter-related.</p><p>Standard models of risk and time preferences treat these as separate dimensions, yet several lines of thinking suggest they are related. First, theorists have noted that the future is inherently uncertain, suggesting that risk attitudes are likely to affect intertemporal choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Dasgupta &amp; Maskin, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Epper &amp; Fehr-Duda, 2018)</ref>. Second, risk and time preferences are subject to some of the same anomalies in experiments <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Epper &amp; Fehr-Duda, 2018)</ref> and time preferences shift when risk is introduced, undermining the idea that these preferences are independent <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Anderson &amp; Stafford, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Hardisty &amp; Pfeffer, 2017)</ref>. Third, studies of preference elicitation have found that eliciting risk and time preferences simultaneously leads to more plausible discount rates because of the link between impatience and risk-avoidance <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Andersen et al., 2008)</ref>. Finally, there is direct evidence that individuals higher in risk-avoidance are also more impatient (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Anderhub et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dean &amp; Ortoleva, 2019)</ref>, although some discrepant studies exist (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Sutter et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>But there is little empirical work examining why risk and time preferences are intertwined.</p><p>We propose that asymmetries in anticipatory emotions provide this missing link <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 1</ref>). In the real world, many decisions are both risky and the payoffs are delayed. For example, when we decide what job to take, where to live, or who to marry, we will not know the consequences for months or years; likewise, many (if not most) business decisions are both uncertain and delayed. When decisions involve both risk and delay, anticipatory emotions play a powerful role, as we are licensed to imagine both good and bad outcomes until the outcome is resolved <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Golman et al., 2020)</ref>. To the extent that anticipatory emotions are asymmetric, disutility from imagining the bad outcomes outweighs the utility from imagining the good outcomes. This implies a link between risk-avoidance and impatience. Those who experience more intense dread will experience more disutility from future uncertainty, and this disutility will be proportional to the time delay until the uncertainty is resolved. If people correctly forecast these anticipatory emotions, they will be more risk-avoidant and more impatient: More risk-avoidant because avoiding risks minimizes disutility from dread, and more impatient because resolving uncertainty faster minimizes the time spent experiencing disutility from dread. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Expected Emotions</head><p>Dread is more powerful than savoring because the object of dread is future displeasure Dread is itself a more powerful emotion than savoring</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Risk Preferences</head><p>Increases risk-avoidance: Eliminating downside risks more valuable when dread pertains to more intensely displeasing losses Increases risk-avoidance: Eliminating downside risk more valuable with more intense dread over potential loss</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time Preferences</head><p>Increases impatience: Eliminating delay more valuable when dread is accrued over more intensely displeasing losses</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Increases impatience:</head><p>Eliminating delay more valuable with more intense dread accruing over the delay Aspects of these predictions have accrued support. On the savoring side, although most people prefer to find out the outcome of a lottery immediately, a minority-who are especially optimistic about the outcome and are more prone to experiencing the "thrill" of waiting-prefer delayed resolution <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Kocher, Krawczyk, &amp; van Winden, 2014)</ref>. On the dread side, using emotion regulation strategies-such as reappraising emotions to manage their impact on decision-making-decreases risk-avoidance <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Heilman et al., 2010)</ref>, implicating a direct causal link between emotional cognition and risky choice. This fits the broader association between neuroticism (emotional instability) and risk-avoidance <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Borghans et al., 2009)</ref>.</p><p>However, the primary obstacle to amassing large-scale evidence relating anticipatory emotions to economic preferences is measuring anticipatory emotions in economic survey data.</p><p>Here, we develop a novel approach to jointly estimating anticipatory savoring and dread across a nationally representative sample from the UK. To our knowledge, this study is the first to elicit individual levels of dread and savoring and relate them to risk and time preferences. Since both loss aversion and dread aversion are expected to contribute to asymmetries in anticipatory emotions, we also estimate individual levels of loss aversion to tease apart these effects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model</head><p>Setting. We model a decision made at ! whether to accept a gamble that will be resolved after an interval T. We follow prior models <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Caplin &amp; Leahy, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Loewenstein, 1987)</ref>, in assuming that the agent aims to maximize expected psychological utility, = $ + % , where % is the expected consumption utility-expected pleasure or displeasure at the actual outcome at time = ! + -and $ is expected anticipatory utility-expected dread or savoring experienced during the interval [ ! , ! + ]. For example, if the agent is deciding whether to take a coin toss gamble where heads pays +$100 and tails costs -$100, we assume this will depend on the agent's forecasts about both the reactive emotions associated with each potential outcome and the anticipatory emotions associated with uncertainty while waiting for the resolution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consider a gamble offering the monetary payoffs (</head><formula xml:id="formula_0"># ,…, &amp; ) with probabilities ( # ,…, &amp; )</formula><p>that is resolved after an interval T. We make the standard assumption that expected consumption utility % is given by the psychological value of each payoff, % ( ' ), weighted by a function of its probability % ( ' ) and discounted by % ( ):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">(1) % = ∑ % ( ' ) % ( ' ) % ( ) ' .</formula><p>We assume that % ( ' ) is increasing, that % (0) = 0, and, following prospect theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kahneman and Tversky 1979)</ref>, that people are loss averse: if ' &lt; 0, then % ( ' ) = − % (− ' ) for loss aversion parameter &gt; 1.</p><p>We now add $ , the expected utility from anticipation. We allow the value function</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">$ ( % ( ' ), )</formula><p>, weighting function $ ( ' ), and discount function $ ( ) to differ for consumption and anticipatory utility. We simply add up these expected anticipatory utilities for each outcome i and integrate from 0 to , since anticipatory (dis)utility is accumulated continuously until the outcome:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">(2) $ = ∫ ∑ $ ( % ( ' ), ) $ ( ' ) ' $ ( ) ( ! .</formula><p>We make three assumptions about the anticipatory value function $ (•). First, we assume that it is an increasing function of % ( ' ), so that we forecast greater anticipatory (dis)utility when expected consumption (dis)utility is higher; that is, $ ( % ( ' ), ) ∝ % ( ' ) and $ (0) = 0. Second, we allow that $ (•) may be time-varying; for example, anticipatory emotions could be especially powerful immediately after a decision is made and immediately before the outcome is revealed <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Baucells &amp; Bellezza, 2017)</ref>. Finally, and crucially, we assume that people are dread averse:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">if % ( ' ) &lt; 0, then $ ( % ( ' ), ) = − $ ( % ( ' ), )</formula><p>for dread aversion parameter &gt; 1. This assumption means that, holding constant the magnitude of consumption (dis)utility (i.e., over-and-above loss aversion), negative anticipatory emotions are more powerful than positive ones.</p><p>This model reflects both rationales for asymmetric anticipatory emotions. First, even if we set = 1, then loss aversion ( &gt; 1) still implies</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">that | $ (− % ( ' ))| &gt; | $ ( % ( ' ))| since | % (− ' )| &gt; | % ( ' )|.</formula><p>That is, contemplating losses is more painful than contemplating gains is pleasurable in part because the expected reactive emotions associated with losses are stronger. This rationale does not assume that dread itself is a stronger emotion than savoring, but instead that the amount of dread over losing ' would be greater than the amount of savoring over gaining ' , since loss aversion says that the disutility of a ' loss is greater than the utility of a ' gain. Second, we additionally allow negative anticipatory emotions to be more powerful than positive ones ( &gt; 1), because anticipating negative events is purely aversive, whereas anticipating positive events mixes positive (savoring) and negative (impatience) emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Hardisty et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Nowlis et al. 2004)</ref>. We will now show how these forces impact risk and time preferences.</p><p>Risk preferences. Loss aversion and dread aversion both straightforwardly increase riskavoidance in our model. As both and increase, the utility of the gamble decreases at any given timepoint. Specifically, when at least one of the ' 's is negative, this implies that decreases as a function of and , since and only appear in the negative terms, ' &lt; 0, of the expressions for both $ and % in Equations <ref type="formula">1</ref>and <ref type="formula">2</ref>. Intuitively: To the extent that dread outweighs savoring, risky (mixed) gambles are unappealing because the dread of the possible downside increasingly outweighs the savoring of the possible upside.</p><p>To illustrate this, let's return to the coin flip example, with equal chances of gaining or losing $100, with the gamble resolved after 3 periods. To study risk preferences, we calculate the delayed certainty equivalent of this gamble. These isolate risk preferences (over-and-above time preferences) by specifying the sure-thing payoff-after the same 3-period delay-that would make one indifferent between that sure-thing payoff and the gamble. To simplify calculations and isolate the effects of anticipatory utility, we assume that: (i) consumption utility is linear and loss averse [ % ( ' ) = ' for positive ' and % ( ' ) = ' for negative ' ];</p><p>(ii) anticipatory utility is linear in % ( ' ) and dread averse [for a scaling constant , $ ( ' ) = % ( ' ) for positive ' and $ ( ' ) = % ( ' ) for negative ' ]; (iii) probability weighting is linear for consumption utility [ % ( ' ) = ' ] and for anticipatory utility except in the case of certainty [ $ ( ' ) = ' for ' &lt; 1 and $ (1) = 0]; and (iv) there is no discounting [ % ( ) = $ ( ) = 1]. Note that these are simplifying assumptions for the numeric example; our theoretical results depend only on the much more general assumptions mentioned in the previous section.</p><p>In <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>, we calculate the delayed certainty equivalent while varying three parameters.</p><p>We set to either 0 or 0.05 (to study the effect of anticipatory utility), to either 1 or 2 (to study the effect of loss aversion), and to either 1 or 3 (to study the effect of dread aversion).</p><p>More negative values reflect greater risk-avoidance, since one is willing to pay more to avoid the gamble. Note. Entries relate to a gamble to be resolved after 3 periods, with a 50% chance of gaining $100 and 50% chance of losing $100. This gamble is modeled under the assumptions that (i) anticipatory utility is either absent or accrues at 0.05 times consumption utility per period ( of 0 or 0.05); (ii) loss aversion is either absent or losses are twice as powerful as gains ( of 1 or 2); and (iii) dread aversion is either absent or dread is three times as powerful as savoring ( of 1 or 3). Consumption utility ( % ) and anticipatory utility ( $ ) are calculated separately for the $100 gain and $100 loss after the 3 periods; see main text for the assumptions underlying these calculations (importantly, there is no discounting). The delayed certainty equivalent is the sure-thing payoff after 3 periods which would make the decision-maker indifferent between that payoff and the gamble; thus, negative values reflect risk-avoidance and positive values reflect risk-seeking. The present gamble equivalent is the value of the upside in an immediate gamble with a $100 downside, which would make the decision-maker equivalent between that gamble and the delayed gamble; thus, values less than $100 indicate greater impatience.</p><p>When is set to 0, there is no anticipatory utility. Since dread aversion is only reflected through anticipatory utility, it has no effect under these conditions (rows 1 vs 3). However, loss aversion has the usual effect of increasing risk-avoidance, with lower delayed certainty equivalents when is higher (rows 1 vs 2). Introducing anticipatory utility by setting = 0.05 does not affect risk preferences if gains and losses are weighted symmetrically ( = = 1) (rows 1 vs 5). But asymmetries in gain/loss weighting affect anticipatory utility and hence riskavoidance. Greater loss aversion results in more negative consumption utility, and through this effect more anticipatory disutility (rows 5 vs 6). Greater dread aversion has no effect on consumption utility but a multiplicative effect with loss aversion on anticipatory disutility (rows 5-8). As a result, increasing both loss aversion (through both consumption and anticipatory utility) and dread aversion (through anticipatory utility only) lead the gamble to appear less attractive, making a decision-maker willing to pay increasingly more to avoid the risk. In this example, the effect of loss aversion on risk preferences is larger than the effect of dread aversion, because loss aversion affects both consumption and anticipatory utility, whereas dread aversion affects only anticipatory utility, and both contribute to risk preferences.</p><p>Finally, it is worth noting that higher values of k lead to both more anticipatory utility and disutility. Intuitively, this is because people with more vivid emotional imaginations tend to experience both dread and savoring more strongly.</p><p>Time preferences. In the case of impatience, the argument is slightly more complex. The model implies that utility declines more steeply with time for higher values of due to more negative anticipatory utility. To see this, consider the derivative of = $ + % (i.e., the sum of Equations (1) and (2)) with respect to time:</p><p>(3)</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">+, +-L -.( = ∑ $ ( % ( ' ), ) $ ( ' ) $ ( ) ' + ( ' ) ( ' ) % ′( ).</formula><p>Negative values of</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">+, +-L -.(</formula><p>correspond to greater impatience in the sense of preferring outcomes to occur sooner. The parameter only appears through $ ( % ( ' ), ) and only for terms where ' &lt; 0. These terms are all negative because $ and % are increasing functions, with % (0) = 0 and $ (0) = 0. Therefore, Loss aversion and dread aversion have no effect on time preferences when there is no anticipatory utility ( = 0) (rows 1-4), due to our simplifying assumption of no time discounting. However, anticipatory (dis)utility affects time preferences through a separate channel independent of discounting. With anticipatory utility ( = 0.05), there is still no effect on time preferences with symmetric weighting of gains and losses ( = = 1) (rows 1 vs 5).</p><p>But loss aversion and dread aversion both increase impatience through anticipatory utility (rows 5-8). This happens because greater attention to losses in anticipation (through both and ) increases the attractiveness of resolving the gamble sooner. In this example, the effect of dread aversion on time preferences is stronger than the effect of loss aversion because only anticipatory utility is relevant to time preferences and, given this combination of parameters, dread aversion has a larger effect on anticipatory utility than loss aversion.</p><p>Overall, the model formalizes three insights. First, anticipatory utility is likely to be asymmetric for dread versus savoring-through both a loss aversion and dread aversion mechanism-as explained informally in the Introduction. Second, asymmetric experiences of dread and savoring can lead to greater risk-avoidance through both loss aversion (because the object of dread is more potent) and dread aversion (because the emotion of dread itself is more potent); taking on downside risks introduces dread and this experience decreases the emotional utility of risk-taking. Third, these asymmetries also lead to greater impatience, once again due to both loss aversion and dread aversion; lengthening the interval between a decision and its resolution prolongs the period of dread and this experience decreases the emotional utility of patience. We now test these insights empirically. that is, psychological characteristics should influence risk and time preferences and not the reverse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Open Practices Statement. The data that support the findings of this study are publicly available from the UK Data Archive. The complete STATA analysis script to replicate the results is openly available in Open Science Framework (OSF) at:</p><p>https://osf.io/n4c6q/?view_only=48a73996c84f4fdb85e6f5c83d66f31a</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measuring Asymmetric Anticipatory Emotions and Asymmetric Reactive Emotions</head><p>To measure an individual's anticipatory emotions to contemplating losses (dread) and gains (savoring) and reactive emotions to experiencing losses (displeasure) and gains (pleasure), we use a simple approach which looks at how individuals' current financial realizations (relative to the past year) and expectations about the next year's financial circumstances (relative to the current time) affects their current psychological well-being. To the extent that dread outweighs savoring, forecasting financial losses should have a greater effect on current psychological well-being compared to forecasting gains. Similarly, to the extent that people are loss averse, current financial losses should have a greater effect on current psychological well-being than current financial gains.</p><p>To implement this strategy, we use data from the first 17 waves (Waves 1-17) of the BHPS.</p><p>This yields a sample size of 125,026 observations from 13,969 individuals. Therefore, intrinsic anticipatory and reactive emotions are constructed from an average of 9 observations per individual.</p><p>Financial expectations ("Looking ahead, how do you think you yourself will be financially a year from now; better than you are now, worse than you are now, or about the same?") and financial realizations ("Would you say that you yourself are better off, worse off or about the same financially than you were a year ago?") were measured in each wave. Psychological well-being was measured using the General Health Questionnaire (GHQ) measured in each wave, a 12-item scale measuring psychological distress or 'disutility' (e.g., "Have you recently lost much sleep over worry?' and 'Have you recently been feeling reasonably happy all things considered?" [reverse-coded]). Responses are coded on a 4-point scoring system (items scored 0-1-2-3) that ranges from "strongly disagree" to "strongly agree". Scores are then summed together, providing each respondent with a total GHQ score ranging from 0-36. We rescale the measure so that higher scores correspond to higher psychological well-being or higher 'utility'.</p><p>First, we calculate, for each individual, the effect on their current well-being of forecasting a better financial situation next year (savoring gains) or a worse financial situation next year (dreading losses). That is, we assess the relationship between financial expectations ( ) and utility ( ), by estimating the following linear random effects multilevel equation for the ℎ individual at :</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">(4) '-= ! + # '- / + " '- 0 + 1 W ' / + 2 W ' 0 + 3 '-+ 4 W ' + '! + '# '- / + '" '- 0 + '-.</formula><p>In Equation 4, '-/ is a dummy variable indicating a financial expectation of "better off"</p><p>(for + 1) at (i.e. '-/ = 1 if the respondent expects to be "better off", otherwise '-/ = 0). '-0 is a dummy variable indicating a financial expectation of "worse off" (i.e., '-0 = 1 if the respondent expects to be "worse off", otherwise '-0 = 0). Therefore, an expectation of "about the same" serves as a baseline category to which the other forecasts are compared.</p><p>We also include a vector of time-varying sociodemographic and socioeconomic control variables, '-. To constrain all the variation to within-person, we follow <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Mundlak (1978)</ref> by including the time means of all the time-varying independent variables-that is, W ' / , W ' 0 , and</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">W ' .</formula><p>Finally, to allow individuals to have different psychological responses to expected income, we include both a random effect ( '! ) attached to the intercept and a random effect ( '# and '" ) attached to the slopes. These random effects together allow us to estimate heterogeneity in the effect of '-/ and '-0 across individuals. Specifically, '# and '" reflects the difference between the average within-person effect of anticipatory emotions, # and " , and the effect for each individual. In reporting results below, we therefore use # and " as population-level estimates of anticipatory emotions (savoring and dread, respectively), and ( # + '# ) and</p><p>( " + '" ) as their individual-level estimates.</p><p>Next, in an identical fashion, Equation 5 repeats the analysis for financial realizations, :</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">(5) '-= ! + # '- / + " '- 0 + 1 W ' / + 2 W ' 0 + 3 '-+ 4 W ' + '! + '# '- / + '" '- 0 + '-.</formula><p>Directly analogous to our analysis of anticipatory emotions, we use # and " as populationlevel estimates of reactive emotions (pleasure and displeasure to gains and losses, respectively), and ( # + '# ) and ( " + '" ) as their individual-level estimates.</p><p>We estimate both Equation 4 and 5 with an unstructured covariance matrix to allow for correlation between the random effect attached to the intercept and the random effects attached to the within-person coefficients. The within-person errors are modelled using an autoregressive structure of order 2, which is confirmed by model selection criteria (in particular, the Akaike and Bayesian Information Criteria). We now use these estimates to answer five questions motivated by our theoretical framework.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Do anticipatory and realized gains and losses affect current (dis)utility? From</head><p>Equation 4, the average within-effect effects of expecting to be "worse off Anticipatory emotions, though statistically significantly different from zero, are less powerful than realized emotions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Does dread loom larger than savoring?</head><p>The average within-effect effects of expecting "worse off" and "better off" discussed above makes plain that dread is much more powerful than savoring. If we define asymmetric anticipatory emotions at the group level as the ratio of the average within-person coefficients associated with dread and savoring (i.e., " / # ), the ratio is 6.19. This accords with Hardisty and Weber's (2020) lab studies, which find substantial amounts of dread but little evidence of savoring. Similarly, if we define loss aversion at the group level as the ratio of the average within-person coefficients associated with realized financial loss and gain (i.e., " / # ), the ratio is 2.05. This is in line with the classic estimate of λ, which is approximately 2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979)</ref>. The very large ratio of dread to savoring suggests that asymmetric anticipatory emotions are not fully explained by the loss aversion mechanism (via λ). This suggests that dread aversion ( ) is also partly accounting for these results; i.e., if λ ≈ 6 and λ ≈ 2, then ≈ 3. That is, this suggests that not only do people experience greater dread than savoring because the object of dread is more psychologically potent than the object of savoring (i.e., losses loom larger than gains; λ &gt; 1), but also because dread is itself a more powerful emotion than savoring (i.e., &gt; 1).</p><p>How much heterogeneity in anticipatory and reactive emotions is there across individuals? From Equation 4 and 5, we can extract individual-level estimates of the asymmetries in anticipatory and reactive emotions. Specifically, from Equation 4, the asymmetry in anticipatory emotions (i.e., λ ) can for each individual be measured as</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">( " + '" ) − ( # + '# )</formula><p>, with coefficients rescaled so that measures of anticipatory reactions to future monetary losses and gains are increasing in disutility and utility, respectively. Higher asymmetric anticipatory emotion scores relate to higher 'disutility' from anticipating income losses (dread) relative to 'utility' from anticipating income gains (savoring). In the same way, from Equation 5, the asymmetry in reactive emotions (i.e., loss aversion λ) for each individual can be measured as</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">( " + '" ) − ( # + '# )</formula><p>, with coefficients rescaled so that measures of reactions to current monetary losses and gains are increasing in disutility and utility, respectively. Higher loss aversion scores relate to higher 'disutility' from income losses relative to 'utility' from income gains. We find substantial heterogeneity across all parameters, with the exception of the parameter '# , which is the measure of heterogeneity in how individuals react to financial gains. Reflecting this, individual loss aversion is measured as ( " + '" ) − ( # ). <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> depicts the heterogeneity in asymmetric anticipatory and reactive emotions across individuals. These individual effects provide estimates of asymmetric anticipatory and reactive emotions, net of any other environmental influences from location and time and any other changes to individual circumstance. We will use these estimates in the subsequent analysis as our key predictors of risk and time preferences. 1 <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Histogram of asymmetric anticipatory emotions and asymmetric reactive emotions based on a single estimate per individual ( = 13,969). A normal density is also plotted in each graph, with the same mean and variance as the estimated data. Higher asymmetric anticipatory emotion scores relate to higher 'disutility' from anticipating income losses (dread) relative to 'utility' from anticipating income gains (savoring). Higher asymmetric reactive emotion scores relate to higher 'disutility' from income losses relative to 'utility' from income gains.</p><p>Are people higher in negative anticipatory emotions (dread) also higher in positive anticipatory emotions (savoring)? If so, this would suggest that dread and savoring both emanate from the common psychological mechanism of vividly imagining the future as our theory postulates. Equation 4 estimates a negative correlation between the random effect parameters, '# and '" , = −0.428, &lt; .001, suggesting that individuals higher in savoring are also higher in dread. To our knowledge, this is the first evidence that individuals who are more sensitive to positive anticipatory emotions also tend to be more sensitive to negative ones.</p><p>Although our primary interest is in the asymmetry between dread and savoring-as this is what drives our theoretical results-it is useful to observe that some people appear to experience more vivid anticipatory emotions in general, perhaps due to higher levels of neuroticism, differences in emotion regulation skills, more vivid mental imagery, or greater preoccupation with the future (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Zabelina &amp; Condon, 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Do people with more asymmetric reactive emotions (loss aversion) also have more asymmetric anticipatory emotions? Theoretically, asymmetric anticipatory emotions exists in part because the object of dread is more psychologically potent than the object of savoring (i.e., losses loom larger than gains; λ &gt; 1), but also because dread is itself a more powerful emotion than savoring (i.e., &gt; 1). Therefore, we expect a moderate correlation between the psychological constructs, which correspond to λ and λ . Indeed, we estimate a moderate correlation between asymmetric anticipatory emotions and asymmetric reactive emotions (loss aversion), = 0.466, &lt; .001.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Asymmetric Anticipatory Emotions, Asymmetric Reactive Emotions and Economic Preferences</head><p>Next, we determine empirically whether individual differences in loss aversion and asymmetric anticipatory emotions may be linked to risk-avoidance and impatience, as our theory suggests.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Risk preferences.</head><p>In estimating the effect of asymmetric anticipatory and reactive emotions on risk preferences, we use the general risk question ("Are you generally a person who is fully prepared to take risks or do you try to avoid taking risks?" from 1 ("unwilling to take risks") to 10 ("fully prepared to take risks")), which was only asked in the final wave (Wave 18) of the BHPS. This measure of risk has been widely validated, with Dohmen et al.</p><p>(2011) suggesting it the best all-round predictor of risky behavior. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref> in the Supplementary Materials shows the distribution of general risk attitudes for our sample. It is worth noting that we do lose a significant proportion of individuals in our second-stage analysis owing to sample attrition. However, sample attrition rates in the BHPS are generally low and comparable to those achieved in other similar household panels. In common with nearly all previously published research using this data source, attrition is assumed to be a random event. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> reports the key results. As risk attitudes are ordinal, we use Ordered Logistic regression, with odds ratios reported for ease of interpretation. We standardize asymmetric anticipatory and reactive emotions and include controls for gender and an assortment of other personal characteristics and socioeconomic and sociodemographic variables, which are described in the table caption. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>, conditional on asymmetric reactive emotions and the control variables, higher asymmetric anticipatory emotions have a strong negative effect on risk preferences. Specifically, a 1 SD increase in asymmetric anticipatory emotions is associated with 0.904 lower proportional odds of being in the highest risk-taking category (versus the combined other categories). It is important to note, that as we control for asymmetric reactive emotions (i.e., loss aversion), the coefficient attached to asymmetric anticipatory emotions measures the effect of dread aversion on risk preferences. We also find higher loss aversion decreases people's willingness to take risks. Furthermore, mirroring prior work, women are more risk-avoidant than men <ref type="bibr">(Charness &amp; Gneezy, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Dohmen et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Eckel &amp; Grossman, 2002)</ref>. Using Shapley-based decompositions we also report the relative importance of asymmetric anticipatory emotions and loss aversion for risk preferences.</p><p>The Shapley-based decomposition method extracts the separate contribution to the explained variation in risk preferences of each included independent variable. From <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>, gender (an important predictor of risk preferences) explains 14.50% of the explained variation in risk,</p><p>whereas the respective contributions from asymmetric anticipatory emotions and loss aversion are 3.16% and 2.77%. These results suggest that, although moderately correlated, asymmetric anticipatory emotions and loss aversion capture different aspects of behaviour, and therefore have complementary predictive power for risk preferences. , current education level (highest academic qualification), current marital status, current housing tenure, current labor market status, logarithm of monthly household income (deflated) for the current year, current number of children under the age of 16 present in the household and square root of current household size. We also include a control for current level of psychological well-being, constructed as the individuals current self-reported GHQ score minus the individual's time-averaged GHQ score net of environmental influences from location and time and any other changes to individual circumstance. Full results are available in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table A3</ref> of the Supplementary Materials. = Odds ratio.</p><p>Time preferences. In estimating the effect of asymmetric anticipatory and reactive emotions on time preferences, we operationalize time preferences as an individual's tolerance for delayed gratification-to resist the temptation of an immediate reward in preference for a later reward. In Wave 5 of USoc (2013), all adults completed a 10-item delayed gratification scale (a=0.66), taken from a longer scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Hoerger et al., 2011)</ref>. Items include "I would have a hard time sticking with a special, healthy diet" [reverse-coded]; "I cannot motivate myself to accomplish long-term goals" [reverse-coded]; "I have given up physical pleasure or comfort to reach my goals"; and "I cannot be trusted with money" [reverse-coded], all on 0 ("strongly disagree") to 10 ("strongly agree") scales. <ref type="figure">Figure S2</ref> in the Supplementary Materials shows the distribution of time preferences for our sample. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref> reports the key results. As time preferences are approximately linear and normally distributed, we use Ordinary Least Squares (OLS) regression. We standardize our measure of time preferences and our measures of asymmetric anticipatory and reactive emotions and include the same set of controls used in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref>, conditional on asymmetric reactive emotions and the control variables, higher asymmetric anticipatory emotions have a strong negative effect on patience. Specifically, a 1 SD increase in asymmetric anticipatory emotions lowers patience by 0.081. Again, it is important to note, that as we control for asymmetric reactive emotions (i.e., loss aversion), the coefficient attached to asymmetric anticipatory emotions measures the effect of dread aversion on time preferences.</p><p>We also find higher loss aversion is associated with lower patience. More specifically, a 1 SD increase in loss aversion lowers patience by 0.043 SDs. Also, women tend to be more patient, as in prior work (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Dittrich and Leipold 2014)</ref>. From <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref>, using a Shapley-based decomposition method, gender explains 7.37% of the explained variation in patience, whereas the respective contributions from asymmetric anticipatory emotions and loss aversion are 10.02% and 5.98%. Thus, asymmetric anticipatory emotions explain more variance in time preferences than loss aversion. This may be because dread aversion reflects that anticipation of positive outcomes are mixtures of positive (savoring) and negative (impatience) emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Nowlis et al., 2004)</ref>-thus, dread aversion is conceptually linked to impatience. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>We gain utility not only from consuming experiences, but from anticipating our consumption. But all anticipatory emotions are not created equal. This article presents the first largescale econometric evidence that dread of imagined bad futures predominates over savoring of imagined good futures-most people are not just loss averse, but also dread averse.</p><p>We further show that asymmetric anticipatory emotions are linked to risk-avoidance and impatience. Our model explains why: When dread outweighs savoring, downside risks loom larger and delays are more aversive. Thus, we provide a unified explanation for why these economic preferences are correlated and suggestive evidence for this explanation.</p><p>Economic preferences have been criticized as lacking a grounding in deeper psychological processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Almlund et al. 2011)</ref>. We show that risk and time preferences are partly rooted in affective forecasts, grounding behavioral economics in affective and cognitive science (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Berns et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Johnson et al., 2023)</ref>. In forging this link, we motivate many directions for future research.</p><p>First-given that most decisions involve both risk and delay-our proposal for why asymmetric anticipatory emotions unify risk and time preferences suggests explanations for other phenomena. In ongoing work, we are extending this model into a broader account of risk and time preferences called Affective Information Theory. This theory aims to unify a number of hitherto disparate phenomena.</p><p>Sign effect. As Hardisty and Weber (2020; see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Molouki et al. 2019)</ref> argue, dread aversion explains why people discount gains at a faster rate than losses-the sign effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Thaler 1981</ref>). Since contemplating future losses produces negative affect, we are less prone to delay those losses than we would be without anticipation, decreasing the discount rate; the corresponding positive affect from contemplating gains is weaker, so discount rates remain high.</p><p>Certainty effect. People pay a premium to eliminate rather than reduce risks (the certainty effect; <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979)</ref>-for example, a much larger willingness to pay to reduce a risk from 1% to 0% than from 2% to 1%, or conversely a much larger willingness to pay to increase the chance of a benefit from 0% to 1% rather than 1% to 2%, despite these pairs of improvements having the same expected value. This follows immediately from the idea that even a small probability of a bad effect licenses savoring and dread, which are absent entirely when the event has a 0% probability. Decisions are often more sensitive to whether something is possible rather than its probability <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Loewenstein et al., 2001)</ref>. Our theory makes the further prediction that the certainty effect would be larger for losses than for gains, since the disutility associated with dread (and hence the utility of paying to reduce a risk to 0%) is higher than the corresponding utility for savoring. There is some support for this prediction <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Verschoor &amp; D'Exelle, 2020)</ref> but future research should target this question directly.</p><p>Present bias. People pay a premium to eliminate rather than reduce delay (present bias or hyperbolic discounting; <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Loewenstein &amp; Prelec, 1992)</ref>. Our theory provides an analysis of this bias in time preferences that is pleasingly parallel to the certainty effect for risk preferences.</p><p>As any delay will generate a license to engage in anticipatory emotions, delays are aversive if dread outweighs savoring. But just as our imaginations are often sensitive to possibilities rather than probabilities, we may be sensitive to the existence of a delay rather than its magnitudea prediction consistent with prior evidence of duration neglect in retrospective (rather than prospective) contexts (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Frederickson &amp; Kahneman, 1993)</ref>. Thus, we would be willing to pay more to eliminate dread-inducing delays rather than to reduce the duration of such a delay.</p><p>Second, our theory makes novel predictions and raises new research questions.</p><p>Risk-delay interactions. For mixed gambles (where both gains and losses are possible), delay should increase the premium paid to avoid potential losses, since the delay introduces disproportionately more disutility for losses. For risky choices about "pure" gains and losses, delay should actually neutralize risk relative to prospect theory predictions (i.e., make people less risk-avoidant for gains and less risk-seeking for losses) because the delay introduces another source of (dis)utility in the form of savoring (increasing the upside to a gamble in the gain zone and decreasing risk-avoidance) and dread (increasing the downside to a gamble in the loss zone and decreasing risk-seeking); the latter effect should be stronger than the former due to dread aversion.</p><p>Individual differences. The fact that people differ sharply in their anticipatory emotions leads to a rich variety of predictions to test about the magnitudes of intertemporal and risky choice phenomena. If the explanations above are correct, then dread-averse (vs. "dreadneutral") people will (i) show a larger discounting asymmetry between gains and losses (the sign effect), (ii) have more nonlinear probability weighting functions (the certainty effect), but only for losses, (iii) be more present-biased when losses are possible, (iv) be more loss-averse, but only for delayed prospects, and (v) have less elastic value functions (i.e., less concave for gains and less convex for losses), but only for delayed prospects.</p><p>Consumption versus anticipatory utility functions. Our formal model made very general assumptions about the shapes of the value, probability weighting, and discounting functions for consumption and anticipatory utility as our central goal was to show that a wide range of functional forms would lead to links between loss aversion, dread aversion, and risk and time</p><p>preferences. Yet little is known about these functions for anticipatory utility. Developing elicitation procedures to estimate these functions (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abdellaoui, 2000)</ref> would be a valuable contribution.</p><p>Predicted versus experienced emotions. Disentangling anticipatory from reactive emotions leads to interesting questions about affective forecasting. For example, people overestimate the extent of loss aversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Kermer et al., 2006)</ref> in the sense that they forecast, prior to a decision, that realized losses will be much more aversive than realized gains are pleasant, whereas the true asymmetry is smaller. Potentially, this could be due to participants' factoring in anticipatory (dis)utility experienced prior to the outcome being revealed. Since dread is stronger than savoring-specifically in this instance that &gt; 1-expected anticipatory emotions enhance forecasts about losses more than for gains. If so, then affective forecasting errors should be larger for vivid outcomes or over longer delays. A related question is whether dread aversion itself might be an affective forecasting error. Since decisions, including risk and time preferences, depend on expected emotions rather than experienced emotions, our model does not require that expectations about emotions be rational. However, since neural evidence points to the aversive experience of dread (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Berns et al., 2006)</ref>, some degree of expected dread aversion is probably rational, even if it proves exaggerated in forecasts.</p><p>Finally, these results have potential practical value. In health contexts, our results suggest that dread-averse people may be less willing to seek out information that is dread-inducing, leading to less preventative care and thus higher long-term costs-for example, would people with potential HIV exposure be likelier to get tested if results were instantaneous rather than requiring 3 weeks (cf. Ganguly and Tasoff 2017)? In marketing, dread aversion may help to explain the powerful effects of promotion-focus (motivation to bring about good outcomes) versus prevention-focus (motivation to avoid bad outcomes), which differ both across situations and individuals and have important consequences for the success of marketing appeals <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Avnet and Higgins 2006)</ref>. In finance, dread aversion likely pushes investors toward safer investments, which is one potential explanation for the equity premium puzzle <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Caplin and Leahy 2001)</ref> and suggests that dread-neutral investors can capitalize on this mispricing without the emotional cost taken by more dread-averse investors. Likewise, in labor markets, more dread-averse employees would favor payment structures with lower uncertainty. For strategic management and entrepreneurship, our results suggest that dread-averse decision-makers are likely to make more conservative decisions, which may be more or less desirable depending on the firm's industry, size, competitive positioning, and asset profile.</p><p>The anticipation of unpleasant events can have an equally, if not larger, impact on distress levels as the event itself <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Berns et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Lazarus, 1966)</ref>, and, unlike the event itself, can be experienced continuously from the time of the decision until the event occurs. Therefore, asymmetries in dread and savoring may be a fundamental individual determinant of economic preferences on par with loss aversion.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Distinctions among expected, anticipatory, and reactive emotions along the timecourse of decision-making.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Data and Sampling. We use data from the British Household Panel Survey (BHPS), a longitudinal survey measuring a wide variety of economic, social, and psychological variables among a nationally representative sample of over 5,000 UK households. The BHPS consists of 18 annual waves of data from 1991 to 2008. In addition, we use data from Understanding Society (USoc), a longitudinal survey of over 40,000 UK households which builds on the BHPS. USoc currently consists of 12 annual waves of data from 2009 to 2021. In Wave 2 (2010-2011) over 6,000 participants from the BHPS which ended in 2008 joined USoc. The BHPS and USoc data have been harmonized, which means we can track the original BHPS sample from 1991 to 2021. The sample used within this research is restricted to the original BHPS sample covering Great Britain. No other data restrictions were imposed. As we describe in more detail below, the longitudinal nature of the data allows us to elicit individual levels of anticipatory and reactive emotions over a number of years (Waves 1-17 of the BHPS) and prior to the elicitation of risk preferences (which was only asked in Wave 18 of the BHPS) and time preferences (which was only asked in Wave 5 of USoc). Thus, anticipatory and reactive emotions are expected to be exogenous with respect to individual risk and time preferences;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>026, −0.163], = 2.70, = .007) are both significantly different from zero and in the expected direction, providing evidence of both dread and savoring, consistent with Loewenstein (1987). Similarly, from Equation 5, the average within-effect effect of a current financial realization of "worse off" ( " = −1.063, 95% = [−0.988, −1.139], = −27.61, &lt; .001) and "better off" ( # = 0.519, 95% = [0.457, 0.581], = 16.37, &lt;.001) are both significantly different from zero and again in the expected direction.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Loss Aversion and Dread Aversion as Channels for Economic Preferences.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Effect</cell><cell>Loss Aversion</cell><cell>Dread Aversion</cell></row><row><cell>Reactive Emotions (Pleasure vs Displeasure)</cell><cell>Expected Emotions Risk Preferences</cell><cell>Displeasure after losses will be greater than pleasure after comparable gains. Increases risk-avoidance: displeasure over losses Eliminating downside risk more valuable with more intense</cell><cell>--</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Time Preferences</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>Anticipatory</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Emotions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>(Dread vs</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Savoring)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Examples of Risk and Time Preferences for Time-Delayed Gambles.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Assumptions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Utility</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Preferences</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Delayed</cell><cell>Present</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(</cell><cell>)</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>)</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>)</cell><cell>(</cell><cell>)</cell><cell>Certainty</cell><cell>Gamble</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Equivalent</cell><cell>Equivalent</cell></row><row><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>-50</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>$0</cell><cell>$100</cell></row><row><cell>0</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>-100</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>-$25</cell><cell>$100</cell></row><row><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>-50</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>$0</cell><cell>$100</cell></row><row><cell>0</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>-100</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell>-$25</cell><cell>$100</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">0.05 1</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>-50</cell><cell></cell><cell>7.5</cell><cell></cell><cell>-7.5</cell><cell></cell><cell>$0</cell><cell>$100</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">0.05 2</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>-100</cell><cell></cell><cell>7.5</cell><cell></cell><cell>-15</cell><cell></cell><cell>-$29</cell><cell>$85</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">0.05 1</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>-50</cell><cell></cell><cell>7.5</cell><cell></cell><cell>-22.5</cell><cell></cell><cell>-$15</cell><cell>$70</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">0.05 2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>-100</cell><cell></cell><cell>7.5</cell><cell></cell><cell>-45</cell><cell></cell><cell>-$44</cell><cell>$25</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>becomes more negative as increases, showing that dread aversion implies greater impatience. (In contrast, higher values of may or may not increase impatience, since appears in the terms for both anticipatory utility [where it unambiguously increases impatience] and consumption utility [where its effect is ambiguous because it depends on the sign of % ′( )].) Intuitively, this happens because greater corresponds to higher levels of anticipatory disutility, which accumulates as the interval increases in length .To illustrate this, let's return once again to the coin flip above. For each setting of , , and and using the same assumptions as above, we now calculate present gamble equivalents in the rightmost column ofTable 2. These isolate time preferences (over-and-above risk preferences) by specifying the upside of the gamble-resolved and paid out at the present time, with the same probabilities and same downside as the delayed gamble-that would make one indifferent between that present gamble and the delayed gamble. For instance, in our running example, a present gamble equivalent of $50 would mean that one would be indifferent between (i) a coin-flip, resolved immediately, with a $50 upside and $100 downside, and (ii) a coin-flip, resolved after 3 periods, with a $100 upside and $100 downside. Thus, lower values reflect greater impatience, since one is willing to accept a smaller gain to resolve the gamble sooner rather than later.</figDesc><table><row><cell>+, +-L -.(</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table S1</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>of the Supplementary Materials provides summary statistics of the variables used in the estimation of Equation 4 and</figDesc><table /><note>5, while Regression 1 and 2 in Table S2 of the Supplementary Materials reports the respective estimated results.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Predictors of Risk Preferences.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Dependent variable: Willingness to take risks in general</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">95% CI</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Predictors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Low</cell><cell cols="2">High Shapley %</cell></row><row><cell>Asymmetric anticipatory emotions</cell><cell>0.904***</cell><cell>-4.660</cell><cell>0.866</cell><cell>0.943</cell><cell>3.164</cell></row><row><cell>Asymmetric reactive emotions</cell><cell>0.920***</cell><cell>-3.660</cell><cell>0.880</cell><cell>0.962</cell><cell>2.773</cell></row><row><cell>Female</cell><cell>0.600***</cell><cell>-11.230</cell><cell>0.549</cell><cell>0.656</cell><cell>14.492</cell></row><row><cell>Pseudo R-squared</cell><cell>0.037</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Number of observations</cell><cell>6,839</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Number of individuals</cell><cell>6,839</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="6">Note. Entries are results of an Ordered Logit regression estimating the determinants of the</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">general risk question. The regression included the additional control variables: age (in</cell></row><row><cell>quadratic form)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Predictors of Time Preferences. Entries are results of an Ordinary Least Squares (OLS) regression estimating the determinants of delayed gratification (patience). See notes forTable 3. Full results are available inTable S4 of the Supplementary Materials.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Dependent variable: Standardized delayed gratification scale</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">95% CI</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Predictors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Low</cell><cell cols="2">High Shapley %</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Asymmetric anticipatory emotions -0.081***</cell><cell>-6.030</cell><cell>-0.107</cell><cell>-0.054</cell><cell>10.020</cell></row><row><cell>Asymmetric reactive emotions</cell><cell>-0.043***</cell><cell>-2.930</cell><cell>-0.072</cell><cell>-0.014</cell><cell>5.980</cell></row><row><cell>Female</cell><cell>0.199***</cell><cell>6.710</cell><cell>0.141</cell><cell>0.257</cell><cell>7.366</cell></row><row><cell>R-squared</cell><cell>0.096</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Number of observations</cell><cell>4,173</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Number of individuals</cell><cell>4,173</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Note.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">The reason we define asymmetric anticipatory emotions and asymmetric reactive emotions in terms of differences instead of ratios, at the individual level, is because the distributions of individual level dread and savoring for instance take both positive and negative values.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Materials</head><p>13,969 Note: Highest academic qualification dummy variables indicate the highest level of attainment. These educational dummy variables are: university/college degree -either at undergraduate or postgraduate level; other higher degree -which includes work-related, or vocational, higher education qualifications such as Higher National Diplomas (HND) and Higher National Certificates (HNC); A-level's -which are post-compulsory examinations taken at 18 to qualify for college or university entrance; GCSE's -which are schooling attainment qualifications taken at 16; Other qualifications -which includes school leaving exam certificate or matriculation; and lastly, no formal qualifications. 13,969 * &lt; .1. * * &lt; .05. * * * &lt; .01. Note: Entries are results of Multilevel regressions estimating asymmetric anticipatory emotions and asymmetric reactive emotions. Robust t-statistics in brackets. The multilevel regressions are estimated with an unstructured covariance matrix to allow for correlation between the random effect attached to the intercept and the random effects attached to the within-person coefficients. We assume the within-person errors follow an autoregressive structure of order 2. This assumption is confirmed by model selection criteria (in particular, the Akaike and Bayesian Information Criteria). The regressions include the individual time means of all the time-varying independent variables as well as forwarded control variables (i.e., + 1) and their respective individual time means. The random-effects parameters 5! , 5# and 5" are the estimates of the random coefficient standard deviation for the intercept and the within-person coefficients "Better off" and "Worse off," respectively; 5!,5# and 5!,5" are the correlations between the intercept and the within-person coefficients and 5#,5" is the correlation between the within-person coefficients. 6,839 * &lt; .1 * * &lt; .05 * * * &lt; .01 Note: Entries are results of an Ordered Logit regression estimating the determinants of the general risk question. The control variable "Current psychological well-being" is constructed as the individuals current self-reported GHQ score minus the individual's time-averaged GHQ score net of environmental influences from location and time and any other changes to individual circumstance. = Odds ratio.   </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parameter-free elicitation of utility and probability weighting functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Abdellaoui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1497" to="1512" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality psychology and economics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Almlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Duckworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Heckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kautz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of the economics of education</title>
		<editor>E. A. Hanushek, S. Machin, &amp; L. Woessmann</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam, Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="181" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the interaction of risk and time preferences: An experimental study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Anderhub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Güth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sonsino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">German Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="253" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eliciting risk and time preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rutström</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="583" to="618" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual decision-making experiments with risk and intertemporal choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stafford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How regulatory fit affects value in consumer choices and opinions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Avnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal profiles of instant utility during anticipation, event, and recall</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Baucells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bellezza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="729" to="748" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Future-oriented emotions: Conceptualization and behavioral effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Baumgartner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pieters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bagozzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="685" to="696" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neurobiological substrates of dread</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Berns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chappelow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cekic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Zink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pagnoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Martin-Skurski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">312</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="754" to="758" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender differences in risk aversion and ambiguity aversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Borghans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H H</forename><surname>Golsteyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Heckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Meijers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the European Economic Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="649" to="658" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological expected utility theory and anticipatory feelings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Caplin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leahy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Wishful thinking, prudent behavior: The evolutionary origin of optimism, loss aversion and disappointment aversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>De Meza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">SSRN Working Paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncertainty and hyperbolic discounting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dasgupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Maskin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1290" to="1299" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The empirical relationship between nonstandard economic behaviors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ortoleva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16262" to="16267" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender differences in time preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dittrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Leipold</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economics Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="413" to="415" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual risk attitudes: Measurement, determinants, and behavioral consequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Dohmen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Falk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Huffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Sunde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schupp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the European Economic Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="522" to="550" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The missing link: Unifying risk taking and time discounting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Epper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fehr-Duda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">SSRN Working Paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Duration neglect in retrospective evaluations of affective episodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Fredrickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">45</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fantasy and dread: The demand for information and the consumption utility of the future</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ganguly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tasoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4037" to="4060" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information gaps for risk and ambiguity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Golman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Gurney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Advance online publication</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intertemporal uncertainty avoidance: When the future is uncertain, people prefer the present, and when the present is uncertain, people prefer the future</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hardisty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pfeffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="519" to="527" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impatience and savoring vs. dread: Asymmetries in anticipation explain consumer time preferences for positive vs. negative events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hardisty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="598" to="613" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feelings of dread and intertemporal choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion regulation and decision making under risk and uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Heilman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Crisan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Houser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miclea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Miu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="265" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development and validation of the Delaying Gratification Inventory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hoerger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Quirk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Weed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="725" to="738" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conviction narrative theory: A theory of choice under radical uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tuckett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral &amp; Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory: An analysis of decision under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loss aversion is an affective forecasting error</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kermer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Driver-Linn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="649" to="653" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Let me dream on!&apos; Anticipatory emotions and preference for timing in lotteries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kocher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Krawczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Van Winden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Psychological stress and the coping process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lazarus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anticipation and the valuation of delayed consumption</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="666" to="684" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anomalies in intertemporal choice: Evidence and an interpretation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Prelec</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="573" to="597" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk as feelings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Welch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regret theory: An alternative theory of rational choice under uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loomes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sugden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="805" to="824" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion-based choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mellers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ritov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="332" to="345" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The sign effect in past and future discounting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Molouki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hardisty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Caruso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1674" to="1695" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the pooling of time series and cross section data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Mundlak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of a delay between choice and consumption on consumption enjoyment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Nowlis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mandel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mccabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="502" to="510" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dread and the disvalue of future pain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Story</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Vlaev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Seymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Winston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Darzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1003335</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impatience and uncertainty: Experimental decisions predict adolescents&apos; field behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sutter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kocher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Glätzle-Rützler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Trautmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="510" to="531" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some empirical evidence on dynamic inconsistency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economics Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="207" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probability weighting for losses and for gains among smallholder farmers in Uganda</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Verschoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>&amp; D'exelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theory and Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="258" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A meta-analysis of loss aversion in risky contexts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Walasek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mullett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">SSRN Working Paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Four-Factor Imagination Scale (FFIS): A measure for assessing frequency, complexity, emotional valence, and directedness of imagination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Zabelina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Condon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2287" to="2299" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Estimating Asymmetric Anticipatory Emotions and Asymmetric Reactive Emotions. Dependent Variable: General Health Questionnaire -36 and realizations: Expectation: Worse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S2</forename><surname>Table</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>off -0.582*** [-12.822</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Expectation: Better off 0.094*** [2.701] Realization: Worse off -1.063*** [-27.610] Realization: Better off</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
