<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The &quot;partial innocence&quot; effect: False guilty pleas to partially unethical behaviors</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Sanchez, P.Y</roleName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cardenas</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Williams College</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Williamstown</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kassin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Williams College</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Williamstown</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucrezia</forename><surname>Rizzeli</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angelo</forename><surname>Luongo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Devon</forename><surname>Kaat</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Korzun</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Christofi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><surname>Strolia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Athena</forename><surname>Sher</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Gavrilov</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rosalba</forename><surname>Linares</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">John Jay College of Criminal Justice</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">City University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The &quot;partial innocence&quot; effect: False guilty pleas to partially unethical behaviors</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/nr5bv</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:32+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>guilt</term>
					<term>shame</term>
					<term>anger</term>
					<term>emotion</term>
					<term>deservingness</term>
					<term>judgment</term>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>plea bargaining</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Draper, and Devika Goel-for their invaluable help with data collection.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The "partial innocence" effect: False guilty pleas to partially unethical behaviors According to combined data from the Innocence Project (2019) and the National Registry of Exonerations (2019), 18% of over 2900 exonerees to date pleaded guilty to crimes they did not commit. This "guilty plea problem" includes defendants who are partially innocent-that is, innocent of the specific crime to which they pleaded guilty but culpable of a lesser, related, or prior offense <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">(Zottoli et al., 2016)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> For example, a defendant might be guilty of some counts, but not others (e.g., possessing, but not selling marijuana). When partially innocent defendants waive their Sixth Amendment right to trial, they do so not for reduced charges and sentences but rather for punishment equal to what they might have received if convicted of their actual crimes <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">(Zottoli et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Cases of partial innocence pervade the American criminal justice system where over 95% of cases are resolved through guilty pleas <ref type="bibr">(United States Sentencing Commission, 2018)</ref>. For example, a field study of NYC residents convicted of a felony found that whereas 20% of defendants self-identified as completely innocent, twice as many (40.5%) self-identified as partially innocent (i.e., having committed a similar but different offense to the one charged) <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">(Zottoli et al., 2016)</ref>. Some legal scholars argue that some partially innocent people who are wrongfully convicted are likely known recidivists <ref type="bibr">(Bower, 2008)</ref>. This is because institutional biases make it more likely that police will stop and arrest the "usual suspects" and that prosecutors will charge them for crimes they did not commit that are consistent with their prior offenses. In other cases, an internal desire to take responsibility for analogous transgressions may motivate the accused's guilty plea. For example, Shanta Sweatt, an African American mother, pleaded guilty to possession of her ex-boyfriend's marijuana to "take ownership of what happens in the house" and to protect her children <ref type="bibr" target="#b78">(Yoffe, 2017)</ref>. As a result of this admission, she lost her public housing and had to pay costly court fines and fees. Perhaps, given more time and fewer pressures, Shanta would have kept silent until she could speak with her lawyer and explain her situation.</p><p>Considering the immense direct and collateral consequences resulting from guilty pleas, it is important to assess the role of the psychological state of partial innocence in plea decisions.</p><p>Such research can broaden our understanding of the psychological phenomenon of partial innocence, it's effect on plea decision-making, and inform policies designed to mitigate false guilty pleas.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Innocence and Plea Bargain Decision-Making</head><p>Theorizing on the phenomenology of innocence that can put innocents at risk, <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Kassin (2005)</ref> suggested that factors at the criminal investigation stage, such as the naïve illusion of transparency and belief in a just world can lead innocent suspects to waive their Miranda rights (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Kassin &amp; Norwick, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Scherr &amp; Franks, 2015)</ref>, to underreact, physiologically, to the accusation of guilt <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Guyll et al., 2013)</ref>, and even to confess under pressure expecting later to be exonerated <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Perillo &amp; Kassin, 2011)</ref>. Confessions increase the likelihood that even innocent defendants would accept a plea offer <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Perillo et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Redlich et al., 2017)</ref>. At the plea stage, innocents believe they will be viewed as such by attorneys and judges <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Kassin, 2005)</ref> and endorse more optimistic beliefs about their probability of acquittal <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Gregory et al., 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Tor et</ref> al., 2010)-even when both groups face objectively similar odds. This literature highlights the importance of examining to what extent a phenomenology of partial innocence may also uniquely characterize the behaviors, emotions, and cognitions of individuals guilty of wrongdoing different from the misconduct of which they have been accused.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Phenomenology of Partial Innocence</head><p>Research shows that people interacting with the criminal justice system desire a fair adjudication process, respectful treatment, and the opportunity to have their voices heard <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">(Tyler, 2000)</ref>. When considering plea offers, innocent and guilty defendants alike reject unfair offers framed as comparatively worse than those proffered to other similar defendants <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">(Tor et al., 2010)</ref>. This attention to fairness may be rooted in their belief in a just world <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Lerner, 1980)</ref> in which good actions deserve rewards and bad actions deserve punishment <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Feather, 1999)</ref>.</p><p>We propose that partially innocent defendants may believe that they deserve punishment for being "culpable of something" and that feelings of guilt may partly account for their disproportionately high plea rates. In support of this hypothesis, basic attribution research shows that people can attribute causality between their negative actions and punishment they receive even when no causal connection exists <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Callan, 2014)</ref>. Research on immanent justice reasoning suggests that the belief in a just world can lead people to draw incorrect causal connections between their unethical behaviors and subsequent random bad breaks <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Lerner, 1980)</ref>. Once punishment is perceived as deserved, it can trigger feelings of guilt and shame (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Feather et al. 2011</ref>)-non-mutually exclusive moral emotions that can motivate behaviors (or "action tendencies") intended to alleviate these feelings <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Callan, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Feather, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Feather et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Tangney et al., 2011)</ref> and which may represent different paths to guilty pleas. For example, whereas guilt-proneness and state feelings of guilt are associated with adaptive behaviors such as perspective-taking and empathizing, shame-proneness and feelings of shame instead tend to be associated with maladaptive behaviors such as externalizing blame, interpersonal distancing, defensiveness and expressions of self and other-oriented anger (e.g., 'humiliated fury'; <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Tangney et al., 2007)</ref>. These discrepant behaviors are the result of differences in the target of focus among people feeling guilty versus ashamed.</p><p>People feeling guilty tend to focus on the ways in which their 'bad behavior' negatively affects others. This empathic response then motivates them to "right the wrong[s]" of their transgression leading them to engage in reparative actions such as confessing, apologizing, and compensating for the consequences of their wrongdoing <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Cialdini et al., 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr">Tangney et al., 2007, p. 6)</ref>. Indeed, people feeling guilty also become more compliant, for example, by fulfilling the injured party's compensatory requests to donate time or money (for a meta-analysis, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Boster et al., 2016)</ref>. They may even comply with non-compensatory requests from individuals other than the injured party that mitigate guilty feelings while doing nothing to repair prior harms <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Carlsmith &amp; Gross, 1969;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Freedman et al., 1967)</ref>. In support of a similar role of guilt in plea contexts, real and mock defendants retrospectively attribute their guilty pleas to feelings of remorse and a desire to take responsibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bordens &amp; Bassett, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Redlich &amp; Shteynberg, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wilford et al. 2018)</ref>.</p><p>People feeling ashamed instead tend to have an egocentric focus on the 'bad self' (as opposed to their 'bad behaviors') and are thus less likely to reflect on the harmful consequences of their wrongdoings for others. This decreased empathic concern is joined by attempts to deny their wrongdoing and to escape from the shame-inducing situation. Research consistently links shame with a variety of risky, illegal, and problematic behaviors (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Tangney et al., 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Thus, while feeling guilty may predict increased responsibility-taking in the form of admissions of guilt, feeling ashamed may predict the opposite tendency (for a similar argument, see <ref type="bibr">Boster et al. 2016, p. 62)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview of the Current Study</head><p>Our goals were to understand the psychological state and effects on plea decisionmaking of individuals who are partially innocent of the crime for which they are charged. In Study 1 (N = 88), we employed a three-group between-subjects design using adapted versions of the cheating paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Russano et al., 2005)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Dervan and Edkin's (2013)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Perillo et al.'s (2014)</ref> high stakes deception-based plea simulation paradigms. Participants were experimentally induced to cheat (or not induced to cheat) on an academic task. To induce partial innocence, we randomly assigned half of participants who cheated to receive an accusation of having cheated on a separate, but comparable, task of which they were factually innocent. Guilty participants were instead accused of cheating on the same task on which they had cheated.</p><p>Following the accusation, a "project supervisor" offered all participants a plea deal in which they could avoid academic sanction in exchange for admitting guilt, agreeing to 40 hours of community service, and waiving their right to a hearing before an academic disciplinary committee. After rendering a plea decision, participants reported on their feelings of guilt and shame, and the decision-making experience, more broadly. In Studies 2 (N = 75) and 3 (N = 746), participants imagined themselves in an immersive role-playing version of the high-stakes paradigm of Study 1. To understand the phenomenology of partial innocence more fully, Study 3 distinguished between two novel manipulations of partial innocence-wherein participants were accused of a transgression that was either more or less severe than their actual misconduct.</p><p>Though the current work is primarily exploratory, we predicted that partially innocent (PI) participants would plead guilty at higher rates than innocent participants (Hypothesis 1), that they would self-report greater feelings of guilt (Hypothesis 2), and that feelings of guilt would be positively correlated with acceptance of the plea offer (Hypothesis 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>A total of 168 undergraduates from an urban commuter college in the northeast were recruited for a paid ($30) in-person laboratory experiment on "Social Perceptions." Students had to be registered for classes to enable the threat of academic sanction. To reduce the risk of enrolling students who might find the high-stakes paradigm too stressful <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Perillo et al. 2014)</ref>, participants were required to be 18 years or older, have a GPA above 2.0, and pass an online anxiety screener (N = 34 excluded; <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Beck et al., 1988)</ref>. Of the remaining 131 participants, we were able to schedule 107 for the laboratory phases: 19 were excluded from final analyses (2 innocent, 7 guilty, 10 PI) for failing to cheat (n = 9), cheating without inducement (n = 1), reporting suspicion prior to debriefing (n = 4), terminating the session due to significant distress (n = 4), and/or for failing to make a plea decision within the allotted time of 6 minutes (n = 6, evenly split across conditions).</p><p>After exclusions <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">, the final sample consisted of 88 participants: 28 Guilty, 31 Innocent,   and 29 PI (ages: 18</ref> to 32, M = 20.86, SD = 3.68; 73.9% females). Overall, 39.8% identified as Hispanic/Latino, 28.4% as Black/African American, 23.9% as Asian, 17% as White, and 3.4% as Other. We based our sample size primarily on resource constraints involved with designing a novel multi-part, cost and time-intensive paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Läkens, 2022)</ref>. We performed a sensitivity power analysis in G*Power 3.1 for feelings of guilt variable (H3), comparing the mean of the Accept vs. Reject group with an independent samples t-test, assuming a one-tailed test and an alpha of .05. A sample of this size (n = 83, as 5 participants did not provide emotion ratings) would provide 80% power to detect an effect of Cohen's d = .68 and 99% power to detect an effect of Cohen's d = .1.08. For reference, among eight studies that measuring state feelings of guilt, Boster et al.'s (2016) meta-analysis found an effect size of d = 1.06 for the association between feelings of guilt and increased compliance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and Procedure</head><p>All study materials and analysis code are available on the Open Science Framework: osf.io/v2r9e. Data for Study 1 (osf.io/7vjn4), Study 2 (osf.io/fdme4), and Study 3 (osf.io/tbz2p), as well as the corresponding codebook are available on OSF (osf.io/8uaz7). We report all manipulations, measures, and exclusions for all studies. For Study 3, all hypotheses, sample sizes, materials, procedures, inclusion and exclusion criteria, data preparation and statistical analysis code were pre-registered and are available at osf.io/7bn8 . We report all pre-registered analyses in the main body of the manuscript. There were no deviations from the pre-registered analysis plan.</p><p>Pre-experiment questionnaires. To examine the influence of partial innocence on plea decisions above and beyond the effect of individual differences across related constructs and to increase statistical power and precision in our models, we first administered measures to control for trait interrogative compliance, trait deservingness of bad outcomes, guilt and shame proneness, just world beliefs (general and personal), and self-esteem (αs = .62 -.83). However, because there were no bivariate correlations between these measures and plea decision, we do not discuss these further. See OSF (osf.io/uhq25) for a full description of each measure and means, standard deviations, and correlation matrices split by condition (Guilty: osf.io/y6js5; Innocent: osf.io/u9dzk; PI: osf.io/t9v2b. Cheating paradigm task. Next, participants were next scheduled for a laboratory session. Three trained research personnel helped run each session: an experimenter to guide participants through the tasks; a confederate to deliver the manipulation; and a "project supervisor" delivered the plea offer. 2 Each laboratory session took about one hour and comprised five highly-scripted phases: a rapport-building phase between participants and their confederate-partner, a culpability induction, an accusation, a plea offer, and post-decision questionnaires.</p><p>Laboratory phases were covertly video recorded. Sessions began with the Experimenter explaining to participants (one a confederate) that the researchers were interested in understanding how individuals and teams differ in their problem-solving abilities. As such, participants were given a few minutes to become acquainted with each other. This rapportbuilding phase was included to incentivize participants to comply with the confederate's requests for help in a subsequent task where collaboration was forbidden (described below). To further incentivize cheating, the experimenter noted the possibility of an additional performance-based compensation (up to $15) on two occasions. Next, participants solving two 2 Ten trained research assistants and the first and second authors (three female experimenters, four female confederate-partners, three male project supervisors) helped run sessions. RAs were trained by viewing recordings of pilot sessions and conducting mock sessions with each other under the supervision and guidance of the first and second authors. Pre-set randomizers were used to randomly assign Experiments to a type of accusation (Individual Task 1 vs. 2: see osf.io/js5tw), as well as Confederate-Partners to a cheating inducement (cheat vs. no cheat: osf.io/er7yf). All personnel were randomly assigned to sessions based on scheduling availability. However, to ensure that confederate behaviors were consistent across conditions, all interactions between participants and research personnel were scripted (for protocol and script, see osf.io/hjnw8). Participant evaluations of their partners and the experimenter provide indirect evidence of perceived consistency across research personnel (for information about these scales, see osf.io/uhq25). Specifically, participant ratings of the experimenter did not significantly differ based on experimenter, F(2, 82) = 1.42, p = .246, η2 = 0.04. Similarly, partner ratings did not differ based on partner, F(3, 81) = 0.56, p = .638, η2 = 0.02. Finally, there was no association between any partner (p =.07), experimenter (p =.06), or project supervisor (p =.93) and participant plea decision. problem sets individually and two collaboratively with a female confederate. In one third of conditions, the confederate complied with instructions to work alone on the both individual tasks (Innocent condition); in two-thirds of conditions, she induced participants to cheat by sharing and soliciting information on the second individual task (Guilty and PI conditions).</p><p>Participants then rated their impressions of their partner and the experimenter while the experimenter ostensibly scored their tests.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Accusation and manipulation.</head><p>After pretending to score their responses, the experimenter returned, stated there was a problem and removed the confederate to another room. Upon her return she accused the participant of cheating on either "Individual Task 1" (IT1) or "Individual Task 2" (IT2). Participants who were both induced and accused of cheating on IT2 comprised the Guilty group and those accused of cheating on IT1 but induced to cheat on IT2 comprised the PI group. To ensure that PI participants understood they were accused of IT1, not IT2, the experimenter demonstrated the problematic task on a blank copy of the worksheet. This precautionary measure was repeated twice (once by the laboratory supervisor) and two other times verbally. Participants not induced to cheat on any task were in the Innocent group regardless of accusation type. After the accusation, the experimenter left to ostensibly contact her superiors.</p><p>Plea deal and decision. Five minutes later, the "laboratory supervisor" arrived and informed participants that the professor considered cheating a form of academic dishonesty and planned to file charges with the college's "Academic Integrity Board." He then presented a deal: in exchange for pleading guilty and completing 40 hours of community service, which would appear in the student's internal record, the professor would not file charges. In contrast, refusal to accept the plea would lead to a hearing at which the participant would testify, the outcome of which was unknown (to allay fears of the most severe possible penalty, participants were told that they would not be expelled, regardless). Participants rendered a plea decision by signing the waiver form. The project supervisor exited the room ostensibly to speak with the experimenter.</p><p>Self-reports and debriefing. Next, the experimenter entered the room and probed participants for suspicion by asking the participant a series of questions: "How are you feeling?</p><p>What are you thinking? Why is that? Can you tell me a little more about that? What did you decide? Why did you accept/reject the offer?" The experimenter then assured participants that they were not in trouble, and promised to explain the study after participants completed a final (post-decision) questionnaire. Five participants had to be fully debriefed at this time (2 Innocent and 3 PI). Those who remained (n = 83) completed a post-decision questionnaire where they reported feelings of "guilt" and "shame" using 1 item each randomly presented as part of the 20item Positive and Negative Affect Scale (PANAS; <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Watson et al., 1988</ref>) on on 5-point Likert scales</p><p>(1 = Very slightly or not at all to 5 = Extremely), as well as other exploratory items reported in the Supplemental Materials. A subset of participants (n = 75) completed manipulation checks (explained below). All were then fully debriefed. A complete description of the experimental protocol and script followed by all research personnel is available at osf.io/hjnw8.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analytic Strategy</head><p>We present results from one-way ANOVAs with a Huber-White correction for unequal variances, Welch's t-tests for unequal variances results (Delacre et al., 2017), planned Games-Howell post-hoc comparisons, bias-corrected Cohen's d effect sizes according to <ref type="bibr">Hedges &amp; Olkin's (1985)</ref>, bias-adjusted pseudo R 2 Nagelkerke effect size, and 95% confidence intervals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preliminary Analyses</head><p>Participants did not significantly differ in age, GPA, anxiety, or any personality traits and beliefs across conditions (ps &gt; .36). Plea responses did not differ according to confederate, experimenter, or project supervisor (ps &gt; .07). Prior to a full debriefing, participants identified the individual task (IT1 or IT2) on which they were accused of cheating. Most participants (94.7%)-including all PI participants-reported the task accurately. When asked to identify the task on which they had actually cheated, 58.3% of Guilty participants, compared to only 20.7% of PI participants, accurately reported cheating on IT2. Across both groups, incorrect reporting consisted primarily of denials that they cheated on either task. Because we previously confirmed that all Guilty and PI participants had cheated, we interpret this inaccurate reporting as a reluctance on behalf of participants to incriminate themselves on paper, especially prior to a full debriefing. Further, PI participants reported ratings of self-perceived culpability (1 = completely innocent to 7 = completely guilty) that were not significantly different from those of Guilty participants, t(51.9) = -1.74, p = .199, dcohen = -0.48 [-1.14, 0.06]), but that were significantly greater than ratings in the Innocent condition (t(40.4) = 2.51, p = .041; dcohen = 0.65 [0.12, 1.21]).</p><p>Guilty participants reported feeling more culpable than those who were Innocent, t(80) = 4.42, p &lt; .001, dcohen = 1.22 [0.66, 1.9]). Collectively, these results demonstrates that PI participants understood they had been accused of cheating on a task different from the one they had actually cheated on and were more reluctant than Guilty participants to incriminate themselves again.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Confirmatory Analyses</head><p>H1: Culpability Predicts Plea Decision. Turning to our most critical dependent measure, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the plea rates broken down by condition. Results support our first hypothesis: in contrast to participants who were innocent, very few of whom agreed to plead guilty (6.5%), PI participants accepted the plea at a significantly higher rate-not different from those who were guilty (55.1% &amp; 53.5%, respectively). See <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> for logistic regression statistics.    Notably, among participants reporting emotions, 34.61% (n = 9 of 26) and 39.28% (n = 11 of 28) of PI and Guilty participants, respectively, reported feelings of guilt greater than 1 (not at all feeling this way) compared to just 3.44% (n = 1 of 29) in the Innocent condition; similarly, 35.71% (n = 7) and 26.92% (n = 10) of PI and Guilty participants, respectively, reported feelings of shame greater than 1 compared to just 6.8% (n = 2) of Innocent participants. 3</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2 Distribution of Mean Ratings of Guilt and Shame in Study 1</head><p>Note. Dot plot: Error bars represent 95% CIs. Feelings of guilt and of shame measured using a single-item each rated as part of the 20-item PANAS (1 = Very slightly or not at all to 5 = Extremely).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H3: Planned Mediation Paths to Guilty Pleas.</head><p>To examine the two routes by which moral emotions-feelings of guilt or shame-could predict plea decisions, we first confirmed the unconditional effect of each emotion on plea decision. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We then fit a parallel mediation model with the sem() function in the lavaan package for R (Rosseel, 2012). 5 This analytic plan allowed <ref type="bibr">3</ref> To ascribe any effects on plea decision to feelings of guilt and shame rather than negative affect more generally, we compared a composite score of general negative affect (e.g., fearful, upset, nervous) after plea decision and found no differences across conditions, F(2, 79) = 0.11, p = .89. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Feelings of guilt, b = 0.77, z = 11.4, p &lt; .001, OR = 2.16 [1.90, 2.48], and of shame, b = 0.38, z = 5.8, p &lt; .001, OR = 1.46 [1.28, 1.65], were independently strongly associated with plea decision. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The advantage of this analytic plan when compared to the parallel mediation procedure recommended by <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Hayes and Preacher (2014)</ref> is that it allowed us to retain the dichotomous dependent variable as OLS regressions employed by the SPSS PROCESS Macro require continuous dependent variables. We tested the statistical significance of the relative indirect and direct effects using the 95% bootstrap confidence us to control for the Innocent vs. Guilty dummy-coded contrast variable (X2) and feelings of shame-a related potential simultaneous mediator. To test the null hypothesis that the relative indirect effects through guilt and shame mediators do not significantly differ from each other, we specified a contrast for the two relative indirect effects, subtracted these from each other, and assessed whether the difference reached statistical significance. In sum, this analysis tentatively supports the idea that relative to being completely innocent, merely being culpable of something comparable-even when that something was not the target of the accusation-was associated with greater feelings of guilt and shame; and the more guilty, but perhaps not ashamed, individuals felt, the greater the frequency with which intervals. Relative here refers to the total, direct, and indirect effects in single and multiple mediation models containing multicategorical independent variables because it calculates the effect of being in one group relative to the reference group (Innocence). they accepted the plea offer. Of note, three reasons should give us pause when interpreting these results: (1) the indirect effects through feelings of guilt and shame did not significantly differ, <ref type="formula">2</ref>results are based on a small sample of participants (n = 83), and (3) emotion measures were collected after participants rendered a plea decision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3 Parallel Mediation Model of Culpability Predicting Plea Decision Mediated by Feelings of Guilt and Shame in Study 1</head><p>Note. Results of a parallel mediation analysis examining the relative indirect effects of condition contrasts (X1 and X2) on plea decision (Y) through state feelings of guilt (M1) and shame (M2). Unstandardized estimates are displayed with 95% confidence intervals. Reference Group: Innocent: = 1, All others = 0; Plea Decision: Accept = 1, Reject = 0. Estimated coefficients are based on bootstrapping procedure with 10,000 bootstrap samples. Bolded only, p &lt; .07; *p &lt; .05; **p &lt; .01; ***p &lt; .001; n = 83. See Supplemental <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> for the same model with Partially Innocent as the Reference Group.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion and Introduction to Study 2</head><p>PI participants-in stark contrast to innocent participants-pled guilty to an offense they did not commit and did so nearly as often as guilty participants. Results suggest that many partially innocent participants experienced moderate feelings of guilt-not unlike those felt by guilty participants, and significantly greater than those reported by innocent participants (d = 0.72 [0.27, 1.12]). Feeling guilty, in turn, was associated with pleading guilty. In Study 2, we sought to conceptually replicate our findings with an online student sample that was asked to imagine themselves facing similar circumstances to those encountered by Study 1 participants.</p><p>This conceptual replication served as a proof of concept for a larger, more immersive roleplaying replication and extension study. We also sought to examine whether judgments of deservingness would be more similar between PI and Guilty participants compared to Innocent participants (Hypothesis 4).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited a convenience sample of 79 students (Mage = 19.95 years, SD = 1.12; 30 male, 42 female, 3 non-binary) from the research participant pool at a small (&lt;2500) US liberal arts college for an online study on academic misconduct. After excluding participants who failed two or more attention checks, 75 remained. A sensitivity analysis indicated that an independent sample's t-test for pairwise comparisons with 25 participants per group (n= 50 per comparison pair) would be sensitive to reliably detect effects larger than or equal dcohen= 0.71 with 80% power (alpha = .05, one-tailed), sufficient to detect effects at least as large as those observed in </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and Procedure</head><p>Participants read a description of the scenario encountered in Study 1 and imagined themselves in that situation. After providing their first name at the beginning of the survey, their name was embedded throughout the scenario to increase realism and perspective taking.</p><p>Participants were randomly assigned to learn that they were Innocent (n = 24), PI (n = 26), or Guilty (n = 25) of academic misconduct and were presented with a plea offer resembling the one shown to participants in Study 1 on a letterhead pertaining to their institution. Prior to rendering a plea decision, participants were asked to describe how they might feel about their behavior during the research session, being accused of misconduct, and having to render a decision. Next, they completed the PANAS, rendered a plea decision, explained their decision, and then evaluated various attributes of the case-i.e., evidence strength, evidence influence on plea decision, estimated likelihood of conviction (see <ref type="table">Supplemental Table 4</ref> for exploratory analyses relating to plea judgments). Then, participants rated how deserving they were of their predicament and the fairness of the outcome (α = .89) and completed the General Just World Belief scale (GBJW: α = .79). See OSF for a correlation matrix of Study 2 variables split by condition (Guilty: osf.io/pmvjg; PI: osf.io/swxvm; Innocent: osf.io/j3b6q). <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows the distribution of emotion, deservingness, and evidence ratings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Confirmatory Analyses</head><p>H1: Culpability Predicts Plea Decision. As in Study 1, a binary logistic regression supported our first hypothesis: PI participants (61.53%) were significantly more likely to accept the plea deal than Innocent (12.5%) participants, but not more likely than Guilty participants (80%). See <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H2: Culpability Predicts</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4 Distribution of Mean Ratings of Emotions and Evidence Judgments by Condition in Study 2</head><p>Note. Dot plots: Error bars represent 95% CIs. Feelings of guilt and of shame measured using a singleitem each rated as part of the 20-item PANAS (1 = Very slightly or not at all to 5 = Extremely). Deservingness measured using 2-items (α = .89) in which labeled endpoints of Likert scales indicated that a rating of 1 was a low value (e.g., not at all deserving) and that a rating of 6 was a high value (very deserving). Labeled endpoints on Likert scales for evidence judgments ranged from 1 (not at all) to 7 (a great deal).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion and Introduction to Study 3</head><p>Study 2 replicated our initial laboratory experiment in a low-stakes, online role-playing paradigm. Partially Innocent participants reported feelings of guilt not unlike those of Guilty participants, but greater than those in the Innocent condition (d = 0.99 [0.49, 1.59]). Feeling guilty and ashamed was associated with pleading guilty, even when controlling for actual culpability. Interestingly, results suggest that students asked to imagine themselves as culpable of academic misconduct reported more extreme moral emotions than students who engaged in academic misconduct. Despite this discrepancy in levels of absolute reported emotions, a similar pattern of relative differences in moral emotions and plea decisions across culpability conditions emerged across Studies 1 and 2.</p><p>In Study 3, we sought to examine the boundary conditions of these effects. Previously, we operationalized "partial innocence" narrowly by inducing participants into an ethically comparable transgression. Study 3 advanced its predecessors in three ways. First, in addition to the Guilty, Innocent and PI conditions we added two variations of partial innocence-those accused of less severe transgressions and those accused of more severe transgressions. An individual accused of a less severe transgression than the one they committed should believe themselves deserving of punishment, feel guilty, and plead guilty at rates similar to those accused of comparable transgressions. Conversely, an individuals accused of a more severe transgression than the one they committed should, like innocent participants, should feel wrongfully accused, and therefore less deserving, less guilty, angrier (Hypothesis 5; DeCelles et al. 2021), and plead guilty at lower rates than those accused of comparable transgressions.</p><p>Second, we improved our measurement tools by using multi-item scales to measure guilt, shame, anger, as well as judgments of deservingness of punishment and fairness of the plea deal and by administering these scales prior to making a plea decision. Third, based on Study 1, we constructed immersive role-playing stimulus materials designed to elicit a stronger emotional reaction in a less cognitively-taxing manner than a typical vignette study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>This study used a one-way (Guilty, Innocent, Partial-Comparable, Partial-Less Severe, Partial-More Severe) between-subjects design. An a priori power simulation using the superpower package <ref type="bibr">(Lakens &amp; Caldwell, 2021)</ref> in R demonstrated that a total N of 750 participants was sufficient to detect a small-sized effect of condition on guilty feelings (omnibus test of H2; dcohen =.175) with .99 power (α = .05). The simulation using predicted means and SDs based on Study 2 and pre-testing is available on OSF (osf.io/8c79r).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 995 U.S., Canadian, and UK student participants through Prolific and Amazon's MechanicalTurk for a role-playing study. Participants were eligible adults who had a minimum 98% approval rate, were not a part of other crowd-sourcing platforms, had not (e.g., "I feel remorse, regret") and shame (e.g., "I feel humiliated, disgraced") using a 5-point Likert scale ranging from (1 = Not feeling this way at all, 3 = Feeling this way somewhat, 5 = Feeling this way very strongly). The average score for the guilt (α = .95 <ref type="bibr">[.95, .96]</ref>) and shame (α = .90 [.88, .91]) subscales were calculated. The SSGS has been used in prior studies assessing emotions relating to (un)ethical behaviors (e.g., Gino, Ayal, &amp; Ariely, 2013). To measure anger, we used the 6-item Hostility subscale from the PANAS-X, which comprises self-report ratings of state emotions of hostility (e.g."angry", "irritable") uses a five-point Likert scale (1 = Very slightly or not at all, 5 = Extremely) (α = .90 <ref type="bibr">[.89, .91]</ref>).</p><p>State Beliefs About Deservingness. To assess whether participants felt they deserved to be punished, we asked 6 questions adapted from Feather et al. (2011; α = .93) such</p><p>as "I deserve to be punished for my actions during the research session" (1 = strongly disagree, 5 = strongly agree; α = .97 [.97, .98]).</p><p>Fairness. We assessed how fair participants thought the plea deal was relative to their alleged misconduct, their actual misconduct, to the consequences of their alleged misconduct, and to the potential consequences of being found guilty by the AIB using a 3-item summed and averaged composite score (1 = not at all fair, 4 = neutral, 7 = very fair; α = .84 <ref type="bibr">[.82, .86]</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>After consenting and providing a nickname (which we then used to increase engagement with the materials), participants watched an immersive animated video (Minutes = 8' 29"-10') in which a narrator described the scenario to a gender-ambiguous avatar representing the participant. Voice actors representing Patty, the Experimenter, and the Project Supervisor guided participant-avatars through events like those experienced by participants in Study 1 7 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 5</ref>). Participants were then randomly assigned to learn that their avatar had either followed the experimenter's instructions (Innocent condition) or that they cheated on "Individual Task 2" (IT2) (all other conditions) (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). Then, Innocent and Guilty participants were accused of cheating and stealing research compensation on IT2, whereas participants assigned to the PI-Comparable Accusation and the More Severe Accusation condition were accused of cheating and stealing research compensation on "Individual Task 1" (IT1)-a comparable offense. To make the accusation more severe, those in the More Severe Accusation group were also accused of stealing a researcher assistants' wallet containing her personal belongings and roughly $80 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7)</ref>. To make the accusation less severe, those in the Accusation Less Severe condition were accused of speaking with Patty, against the experimenter's rules, but not of cheating or stealing research compensation during IT1. After participants responded to three attention checks assessing their recall for the Experimenter's instructions, the task they had cheated on (if any), and the task they had been accused of cheating on. Participants received immediate feedback on the accuracy of their response and were provided with the correct response if incorrect. Those who failed two or more attention checks were prevented from continuing the study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 5 Images Depicting the Experimenter Introducing the Rules of the Study Participants Must Follow</head><p>Note. All images were accompanied by audio of voice-actors speaking directly to the participant-avatar. See the online article for the color version of this figure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 6 Images Depicting Guilty and Partially Innocent Participants Cheating with Patty (Left Image) and A Recap of the Accusation of Misconduct (Right Image)</head><p>Note. Innocent participant-avatars see themselves obeying the instructors' participation rules instead (not pictured). Bottom panel depicts a recap of the participant-avatars' actual misconduct (Right side) and the Experimenters' accusation for the Partially Innocent -Accusation Less Severe condition (Left side). Recaps such as these were presented after audio descriptions to avoid cognitively-taxing simultaneous displays of text and audio. See the online article for the color version of this figure. whether to take their case to the AIB, and <ref type="formula">3</ref>what they might say, if anything, to the project supervisor. The latter also served as an exploratory measure, not analyzed here, to capture spontaneous confessions. Participants then completed the SSGS, the Hostility Subscale, and the deservingness scale.</p><p>Plea Decision and Attributes of the Plea Judgments. Next, participants were presented with the same Study 1 plea offer (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 8</ref>), decided to accept or reject the plea deal, were then asked to explain their choice and rated the perceived strength of the exculpatory and of the inculpatory evidence (1 = not at all strong to 7 = very strong), their estimated likelihood of being found guilty (0% to 100%), the severity of the misconduct they committed (if not innocent), and the severity of the misconduct of which they were accused (1 = not at all serious to 7 = very serious). Participants also rated the influence of three factors on their decision (1 = not at all to 7 = very), inculpatory evidence, the consequences of accepting the deal (community service), the consequences of rejecting the deal (being referred to the AIB), as well as the fairness of the plea deal (1 = not at all fair to 7 = very fair).</p><p>Demographics. Finally, participants indicated whether they had ever cheated (and if so, where they had been caught) in an academic context, their age, ethnicity, and gender, before being debriefed. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preliminary Analyses</head><p>Participants did not differ in age, gender, ethnicity, or past cheating by condition (ps &gt;  <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref> shows the distribution and 95% confidence intervals of emotion, deservingness, and judgments of the plea ratings by culpability condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Confirmatory Analyses</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 9 Distribution of Mean Ratings of Emotions and Judgments of Plea Attributes by Condition in Study 3</head><p>Note. (A) Bee swarm plot shows individual mean ratings on emotion (1 = Not feeling this way at all, 3 = Feeling this way somewhat, 5 = Feeling this way very strongly) and dessert scales (1 = strongly disagree to 5 = strongly agree). (B) = Jittered plot of single-item ratings (except for plea fairness scale). Labeled endpoints of Likert scales indicated that a rating of 1 was a low value (e.g., not at all) and that a rating of 7 was a high value (e.g., very). Higher density of ratings are represented by thicker areas of the plot. Error bars in (A) and (B) depict 95% CIs. PI-C = Partially Innocent -Comparable Accusation; PI-LSA = Partially Innocent -Less Severe Accusation; PI-MSA = Partially Innocent -More Severe Accusation. Supplemental <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> contains the ANOVA Results for these measures. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the plea rates broken down by condition. There was a significant difference in plea decision across conditions χ2(4) = 124.3, p &lt; .001. Consistent with Study 2, Guilty participants accepted the plea at higher rates (73.71%) than Comparable Accusation participants (59.74%) who in turn accepted the plea at higher rates than Innocent (5.73%) participants. Further supporting H1, participants in the Less Severe Accusation (57.34%) condition accepted the plea more often than those in the More Severe Accusation (31.62%) condition, but not significantly more often than those in the Comparable Accusation condition, and those in the Comparable Accusation condition accepted the plea more often than those in the More Severe Accusation condition. See <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> for the logistic regression results.   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref> shows the results of this model. Supplemental <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> shows the same model with PI-C as the Reference Group. Unsurprisingly, this latter model demonstrates that the relative indirect effect of guilt did not significantly differ in any contrast of <ref type="bibr">PI-C vs. Other Cheat Condition (Guilty, PI-LSA, or PI-MSA)</ref>, ps &gt; .078 -.039, as guilty feelings did not differ between these groups rendering the a paths non-significant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H1: Culpability Predicts Plea Decision.</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H2: Culpability Predicts</head><p>These finding suggest that compared to being entirely innocent, being responsible for some wrongdoing-even when that wrongdoing was less severe, the same, merely comparable, or more severe than the target of the accusation-is linked to increased feelings of guilt and shame; and the more guilty, but not ashamed, people felt, the more likely they were to accept the plea offer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 10 Study 3 Parallel Mediation Model of Culpability Predicting Plea Decision Mediated by Feelings of Guilt, But Not Shame</head><p>Note. Results of a parallel mediation analysis examining the relative indirect effects of condition contrasts (X1, X2, X3, and X4) on plea decision (Y) through state feelings of guilt (M1) and shame (M2) composite scales. Unstandardized estimates are displayed, with 95% confidence intervals; c' = direct effect of X contrast on Y. PI-C = Partially Innocent (Comparable Accusation); PI-LSA = Partially Innocent (Accusation Less Severe); PI-MSA = Partially Innocent (Accusation More Severe). Reference Group: Innocent: = 1, All others = 0; Plea Decision: Accept = 1, Reject = 0. Estimated coefficients are based on bootstrapping procedure with 10,000 bootstrap samples. *p &lt; .05; **p &lt; .01; ***p &lt; .001; n = 746.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory Serial</head><p>Mediation. Next, we tested an exploratory serial mediation model to assess whether the effect of culpability on plea decision is serially mediated by judgments about deservingness of punishment and feelings of guilt. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> We based our mediation model on <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Feather's (1999)</ref> theory of deservingness. According to this theory, an individual's evaluation of deservingness and the emotions associated with it depend on the consistency between their actions and the resulting outcomes. When a positive action leads to a positive outcome, it is judged as deserved, resulting in feelings of pride and pleasure. Similarly, a negative action that leads to a negative outcome is also judged as deserved but results instead in feelings of guilt and regret. <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Feather et al. (2011)</ref> found support for this model by demonstrating that participants' appraisals of deservingness mediated the relationship between negative actions resulting in negative outcomes, and emotions such as guilt, regret, resentment, and anger. Indeed, in the current work, participants' beliefs about deservingness were strongly To expand on this model, we investigated whether the serial indirect effect of each of four culpability contrast (X) on plea decision (Y) through deservingness (M1) and then guilt (M2) would be significant. To compute the serial indirect effect, we estimated three logistic regression models. In the first model, we regressed the first mediator (dessert) on the four culpability contrasts. In the second model, we regressed the second mediator (feelings of guilt) on the four culpability contrasts and the first mediator. In the third model, we regressed the dependent variable (plea decision) on the four culpability contrasts and the two mediators. Next, we computed the coefficient for the relative serial indirect effect of each culpability contrast through deservingness beliefs and guilty feelings as the product of these coefficients (e.g., Innocent vs. Cheat Condition → Deservingness, Deservingness → Guilty Feelings, Guilty Feelings → Plea Decision). We then used a bootstrapping procedure implemented with 10,000 samples in lavaan to assess whether these relative indirect effects were significant. The indirect effects of all culpability contrast on plea decision through deservingness beliefs and feelings of guilt were significant. Supplemental <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> shows the same model with PI-C as the Reference Group.</p><p>In sum, these findings suggest that when accused of wrongdoing they did not commit, participants who imagined having committed another wrongdoing believed themselves more deserving of punishment relative to innocent individuals, and that beliefs about deservingness of punishment were, in turn, associated with feeling guilty, which in turn was associated with pleading guilty more often.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures 9B and 12</ref> show the distribution mean ratings for judgments of the plea attributes by culpability condition. Visual inspection of mean ratings suggest that Partially Innocent groups provided more middling-range responses relative to completely Innocent or Guilty participants: for example, compared to Innocent participants, PI groups rated the inculpatory evidence as stronger, the exculpatory evidence as weaker, and estimated their likelihood of conviction as higher. Whereas compared to Guilty participants, PI participants rated the inculpatory evidence as weaker, the exculpatory evidence as stronger, and estimated their likelihood of conviction as lower. For ANOVA results, see Supplemental <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>. Bivariate correlations between judgments of the plea experience and plea decision split by condition are available on OSF (Guilty: osf.io/3d8cr; Innocent: osf.io/zmqts; PI-Comparable: osf.io/juf9t; Less Severe Accusation: osf.io/y4rg2; More Severe Accusation: osf.io/j4zmr. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory Judgments of Plea Attributes</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion of Study 3</head><p>The results of Study 3 replicated and extended those of Study 1 using more valid multiitem measurement tools. Consistent with our pre-registered hypotheses, Partially Innocent participants accused of comparable or less severe wrongdoing compared to their actual misconduct reported beliefs about deserving punishment, and, in turn, feelings of guilt that were not significantly different from those of Guilty participants, but greater than those of Innocent participants. Greater feelings of guilt-but not of shame-were, in turn, associated with increased plea acceptances. Additionally, PI participants accused of wrongdoing more severe than their actual misconduct reported feeling as angry as innocent participants and accepted the plea significantly less often than those accused of comparable wrongdoing. But those accused of less severe wrongdoing accepted the plea nearly as often as those accused of comparable misconduct.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>The goals of the current study were to investigate the phenomenology and decisionmaking of partially innocent individuals. Three experiments demonstrate that partially innocent participants-in sharp contrast to those who were completely innocent-pleaded guilty to an offense they did not commit and did so at comparable or slightly lower rates as participants who were in fact guilty of that offense. Consistent with <ref type="bibr">Zottoli et al.'s (2016)</ref> field study, partially innocent participants pled guilty despite the high-stakes negative consequences (Study 1) and despite being accused of a more severe or a less severe offense (Study 3). On the secondary goal of investigating the psychology of partially innocent defendants' plea decisions, we found support for our prediction that partially innocent individuals would feel more deserving of punishment (Studies 2 and 3) and experience greater feelings of guilt than innocent individuals.</p><p>Feeling guilty, in turn, was associated with a higher likelihood of accepting the plea deal even when controlling for state feelings of shame (Studies 1 and 3). Whereas beliefs about just deserts and guilty feelings were closely associated with plea decisions, dispositional beliefs about deserving negative outcomes and personality traits, like interrogative compliance, just world beliefs, and guilt and shame proneness, were not (Study 1).</p><p>Even so, partially innocent participants differed from guilty participants in three significant ways. First, whereas guilty participants reported being more culpable than innocent participants, partially innocent participants rated their own culpability between completely guilty and completely innocent participants. Second, when asked to report which task they had cheated on, partially innocent participants denied cheating far more often than guilty participants-by a margin of 20.7% to 58.3%. Third, compared to guilty participants, partially innocent participants regarded the evidence in their favor as stronger and the evidence against them as weaker, ultimately estimating a lower likelihood of conviction (Studies 2 &amp; 3). Partially innocent individuals seemingly calibrated their evaluation of the strength and influence of the evidence on their plea decisions in light of their own private knowledge of their partial culpability. This is important because evidence strength-via its influence on estimates of likelihood of being found guilty at trial-is a predominant factor in defendant decision making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Kramer et al., 2007;</ref>.</p><p>In summary, this study provides strong preliminary support for the notion that, at least behaviorally and emotionally, partially innocent individuals may resemble guilty individuals more than completely innocent individuals. Notably, however, partially innocent people maintained a private understanding of their own ambivalent state of culpability (particularly when accused of committing a worse transgression), where the opposition's evidence might fall short, and why ambiguity might benefit them in a final adjudication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Strengths, Limitations, and Future Directions</head><p>This work is the first to empirically demonstrate the effect partial innocence on responsibility-taking in both real and imagined plea contexts. However, there are limitations that bear discussing. For one, the elevated ratings of guilt and shame as well as increased plea acceptances across conditions in the role-playing studies suggest it may have been somewhat difficult for student-participants to imagine how they would feel and react in response to a genuine accusation of academic misconduct. Indeed, research consistently finds that people tend to overestimate the impact of events on their emotional states (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ayton et al. 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Kawakami et al. 2009)</ref>. However, this same body of work consistently finds that people can, at minimum, accurately predict the emotional valence resulting from events, as well as identify which events will have a greater impact on their emotions. In fact, some work suggests that results obtained from studies that use hypothetical scenarios align with those from studies that examine real emotional experiences <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Robinson &amp; Clore, 2001)</ref>. Considering that academic misconduct is not entirely uncommon among students (25% had previously cheated in Study 3), it is likely that predictions about the direction, if not the magnitude, of expected feelings and behaviors might be at least partially accurate. In support, the relative differences in feelings of guilt and plea decisions across conditions were consistent across three studies using varied methodologies, yielding large effect sizes.</p><p>Further, in line with <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ajzen's (1991)</ref> theory of planned behavior, prior work suggests that intentions to engage in a behavior can accurately predict actual behavior when certain conditions -all met in the current work -are present, such as the availability of variability in responses, compatibility between the intention and behavioral measure, and controllability of one's own behavior <ref type="bibr">(Ajzen, 2020, pps. 320 -321;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Sheeran, 2002)</ref>. Still, this work finds that people's intentions tend to become biased toward socially desirable responses when a behavior (such as behaving ethically and taking responsibility for one's wrongdoing) is deemed more socially normative <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Sheeran, 2002)</ref>. This social desirability bias may also explain the higher reported feelings of guilt and responsibility-taking in role-playing compared to real-world decision-making studies.</p><p>Beyond describing the phenomenology of partial innocence, this work's primary theoretical contribution lies in its consistent support of a novel moral emotional explanation of plea decision-making. Study 3 operationalized "partial innocence" broadly by accusing participants of transgressions that were either ethically comparable, less severe or more severe than their actual misconduct. This enabled us to assess whether the proposed emotional mechanism could explain the self-incriminatory plea decisions of various types of partially innocent persons. As expected, though the consequences for pleading guilty were held constant, partially innocent persons who were wrongfully accused of more severe wrongdoing than their actual misconduct, were nearly as angry as completely innocent participants and significantly angrier and less willing to plead guilty than those accused of comparable misconduct. The fact that more severe wrongful accusations caused otherwise guilty persons to enter this partial innocence state where they felt less deserving of punishment, less guilty, angrier, and less willing to take responsibility reveal an important boundary condition to the effects found here.</p><p>Indeed, this finding highlights the value of gaining insight into the experience of being overcharged. Overcharging occurs when prosecutors threaten defendants with excessively severe charges that carry disproportionately harsher punishment than is warranted by the defendants' alleged misconduct to dissuade them from exercising their right to trial <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Caldwell, 2011)</ref>. These findings may suggest that when making accusations, a failure to map the magnitude of the charges to the accusation could backfire, causing the accused to no longer desire to take responsibility for their actual wrongdoings. In the real world, increasing the severity of charges is typically associated with increased punishment which may also deter responsibility-taking. Conversely, other work finds that overcharging by threatening guilty mock defendants and their mock attorneys with excessively harsh (compared to more appropriate) sentences increases plea acceptance <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Cardenas, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr">c.f. Schneider &amp; Zottoli, 2019)</ref>. Given these apparent discrepancies, future work should investigate the unique and interactive effects of culpability and type of overcharging (qualitatively versus numerically severe) on responsibility taking.</p><p>Although most past research has examined defendant plea decisions using exclusively hypothetical vignettes or field study self-reports (c.f. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Cardenas, 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Dervan &amp; Edkins, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Hendersen &amp; Levett, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Perillo et al. 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Pardieck et al. 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wilford &amp; Wells, 2018;</ref>, the current work used a triangulation approach that combined a highstakes real-world decision-making laboratory paradigm that afforded greater experimental control and then replicated and extended findings in two immersive and interactive role-playing studies. Where results differed was in the more extreme responses of participants in the roleplaying compared to real-world experimental paradigms, who reported a lower likelihood of conviction, feeling less guilt, and ultimately pled guilty less often. The more pessimistic estimates of role-playing participants are consistent with research on the illusion of transparency, the belief that one's internal states, thoughts, and emotions are visible to others <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Gilovich et al. 1998)</ref>. Indeed, given that the methodology instructed them to reflect on their thoughts and emotions, role-playing participants may have implicitly believed that the truth of their transgressions would be evident to an external disciplinary committee. In contrast, the more optimistic judgments of participants making ostensibly real-world decisions are more consistent with the known tendency of individuals to make self-serving evaluations under conditions of uncertainty for example by viewing themselves more positively <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Dunning et al. 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Epley &amp; Dunning 2000)</ref>, behaving as if innocent when their culpability is ambiguous <ref type="bibr">(Tor et al. 2010, Studies 4-5)</ref>, and by denying case facts, their knowledge, culpability, or the amount of harm caused (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bibas, 2004)</ref>. Discrepant findings can cause concerns over the reliability of the findings. Yet despite vast methodological differences, including use of different accusations, measurement instruments, samples, consequentiality, format and more, results related to the moral emotional pathways to guilty pleas and relative differences between groups were highly consistent across studies. This consistency suggests that certain simulation studies may closely model the emotions, cognitions, and behaviors of student participants involved in more expensive, time-costly, high-stakes deceptive plea decision-making paradigms. To further investigate the utility of this triangulation approach for understanding plea decision-making, future work should continue to compare results from behavioral observations of situations requiring responsibility-taking against results from analogous hypothetical scenarios (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Baumert et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Understanding different types of partially innocent individuals think, feel, and behave in legal contexts is important as numerous structurally embedded charging practices, such as strategic overcharging, can give rise to partial innocence. Yet future research could also examine whether the current explanatory model explains the phenomenology of real and imagined partial innocence wrought from nonstructural factors. For example, a partially innocent defendant may be one who was ignorant of the law, or one who knowingly violated a law they judged to be unjust and unfair; a defendant may lack clarity over their culpability during the time of a crime (resulting from intoxication or some other compromised mental state); or judge themselves to be morally guilty, and therefore worthy of, punishment as in sudden infant death cases which have contributed to false confessions and subsequent wrongful conviction of numerous bereaved mothers such as Jacqueline Fletcher who falsely confessed under pressure that she drowned her infant son because she felt responsible for his well-being <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Gudjonsson, 2003)</ref>. The current work should examine whether people like Fletcher might be especially vulnerable to the confrontation-based Reid interrogation technique commonly used in the US and Canada <ref type="bibr">(Davis &amp; Donohue, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Inbau et al., 2013)</ref>. This interrogation tactic instructs law enforcement to exploit the "troubled conscience… and… moral guilt" of "emotional offenders" by introducing minimization themes that emphasize sympathy and understanding (p. 185).</p><p>Given the foundational nature of this work, one might reasonably wonder if there truly does exist a singular "phenomenology of partial innocence," or if the experience of partial innocence might systematically vary depending on factors such as the circumstances that resulted in one being partially innocent. 10 Perhaps like other well-studied psychological phenomenon (e.g., anchoring biases, <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Turner &amp; Schley, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">cognitive biases, Oeberst &amp; Imhoff, 2023)</ref>, partial innocence may encompass various phenomenological experiences characterized by similar outcomes (i.e., greater responsibility-taking relative to innocence). Future work should investigate whether other forms of partial innocence that result in different phenomenological experiences are the result of different non-mutually exclusive psychological causes (e.g., emotion-based, biased information processing).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>This work is the first to suggest that partially innocent individuals guilty of committing a transgression take responsibility for a transgression not committed to assuage feelings of guilt.</p><p>Given that the proportion of partially innocent defendants potentially dwarfs that of innocent <ref type="bibr">10</ref> We thank an anonymous reviewer for suggesting this point. defendants, it is critical that we continue to advance our understanding of the phenomenology of this group at various stages of their involvement with the criminal justice system.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Percentage of Participants who Rejected and Accepted the Plea Offer in Each ConditionNote. PI-C = Partially Innocent -Comparable Accusation; PI-LSA = Partially Innocent -Less Severe Accusation; PI-MSA = Partially Innocent -More Severe Accusation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>H2:</head><label></label><figDesc>Culpability Is Associated with Feelings of Guilt and Shame. On selfreported feelings of guilt, a one-way ANOVA revealed a significant effect of condition, F(2, 80) = 6.28, p = .003, η 2 = .10 [.00, .23]: feelings of guilt were significantly greater among PI participants compared to completely Innocent participants (Mdiff = 0.66; t(29.2) = 2.66, p = .033, d = 0.72 [0.27, 1.12]), and among Guilty compared to completely Innocent participants, (Mdiff = 0.43; t(39.3) = 2.75, p = .024, d = 0.72 [0.23, 1.29]), but did not significantly differ between PI and Guilty participants, Mdiff = .23 [-.44, .91]; t(40.8) = .83, p = .68, d = 0.23 [-0.38, 0.71]). Next, we examined whether self-reported feelings of shame differed across conditions. The ANOVA indicated a significant effect F(2, 80) = 5.23, p = .007, η 2 = .08 [.00, .21]: feelings of shame were not significantly different among PI participants compared to either Innocent (Mdiff = .35; t(28.7) = 1.93, p = .15, d = 0.53 [-0.07, 0.93]) or Guilty participants (Mdiff = -.22; t(51.6) = -0.82, p = .69, d = -0.22[-0.75 , 0.34]). Only those in the Guilty condition felt significantly more ashamed than those who were Innocent, Mdiff = .57; t(30.1) = 2.78, p = .024, d = 0.73 [0.39, 1.11].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>shows the distribution of reported feelings. Visual inspection of the distributions across conditions reveals greater dispersion in the Guilty and PI conditions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3shows the results of this model along all paths.As expected, increased feelings of guilt (b1 path: b = 0.15 [0.07, 0.25], p &lt; .001) andshame (b2 path: b = 0.13 [0.005, 0.23], p = .016) were each associated with increased plea acceptance, even controlling for culpability condition. As expected, the indirect effect of theInnocent vs. PI contrast through feelings of guilt was significant (a2*b1: b = 0.10 [0.02, 0.21], p = .037), whereas the indirect effect of the Innocent vs. PI contrast through feelings of shame was not (a4*b2: b = 0.05 [-0.001, 0.12], p = .134). To formally test which route better predicted plea decision, we compared the two indirect effects through guilt and shame and found that these did not significantly differ (b = 0.06 [-0.04, 0.18], p = .335). Unexpectedly, neither indirect effect of the Innocent vs. Guilty contrast through feelings of guilt (a1*b1: b = 0.066 [0.01, 0.07], p = .056) or shame (a3*b2: b = 0.075 [0.002, 0.16], p = .067) reached statistical significance. As expected based on other results reported above, testing the indirect effect of the Partially Innocent vs. Guilty contrast through feelings of guilt (b = -0.04[-0.13, 0.05], p = .433) and shame (b = 0.03[-0.04, 0.12], p = .460) in a model with PI as the reference group showed that neither effect reached statistical significance.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Feelings of Guilt and Shame. Replicating Study 1, a oneway ANOVA demonstrated a significant effect of condition on feelings of guilt, F(2, 72) = 10.32, p &lt; .001 η 2 = .16[.03, .31]: feelings of guilt were significantly greater among PI participants compared to completely Innocent participants (Mdiff = 1.08; t(35.9) = 3.58, p = .003, d = 0.99 [0.49, 1.59]), and among Guilty compared to Innocent participants (M diff = 1.02; t(36.2) = 3.61, p = .003, d = 1.01 [0.53, 1.6]), but did not significantly differ between PI and Guilty participants,Mdiff = -0.06; t(48.8) = 0.17, p = .99, d = 0.05 [-0.51, 0.59]. Replicating Study 1, an ANOVA demonstrated a significant effect of condition on feelings of shame, F(2, 72) = 7.51, p = .001 η 2 = .12 [.01, .26]: Innocent participants felt significantly less ashamed than those in the PI (Mdiff = 09.78; t(36.5) = -3.03, p = .012, d = -0.83 [-1.36, -0.32]) and Guilty conditions (Mdiff = -0.83; t(34.2) = -3.08, p = .011, d = -0.86 [-1.42 , -0.38]). Feelings of shame did not significantly differ between Partially Innocent and Guilty participants (Mdiff = -0.06; t(34.2) = 0.17, p = .99, d = -0.03 [-0.6 , 0.53]). H3: Feelings of Guilt and Shame are associated with Plea Decision. Consistent with Study 1, increased feelings of guilt (b = 0.72, SE = 0.24, p = .002) and shame (b = 0.72, SE = 0.26, p = .006) were associated with plea acceptance. Adding condition to each model-for feelings of guilt (χ2(2) = 17.94, p &lt; .001) and shame (χ2(2) = 19.48, p &lt; .001)-significantly improved model fit. H4: Culpability Predicts Judgments of Deservingness. A one-way ANOVA demonstrated a significant effect of condition on deservingness, F(2, 72) = 37.52, p &lt; .001 η 2 = .40 [.22, .53]: PI did not feel significantly more deserving than Guilty participants (Mdiff = 0.24; t(47.9) = 0.76, p = .730, d = 0.21 [-0.35, 0.78]). As expected, on average, PI (Mdiff = 1.77; t(6.76) = 33.1, p &lt; .001, d = 1.86 [1.34, 2.63]) and Guilty participants (Mdiff = 1.53; t(6.74) =34.7, p &lt; .001 , d = 1.88 [1.33, 2.73]) each felt more deserving of punishment than Innocent participants.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>participated in related pilot studies, and were paid $2.75 (median survey duration = 21.48 mins). Participants were excluded for failing to identify their condition (i.e., stimulus attention check, n = 83), failing an instructional attention check (n = 168), and failing a language proficiency check (n = 5). The final sample consisted of 746 participants (Innocent: n = 157; Guilty: n = 156; Partial-Comparable: n = 154; Partial-Accusation Less Severe: n = 143; Partial-Accusation More Severe: n = 136;): Mage = 28.93 years (SD = 8.39); 34.98% male, 61.53% female, 2.95% Other. Participants identified primarily as White (67.82%), followed by Asian (13.8%), Black/African American (5.63%), Hispanic/Latino (1.87%), and Other (10.8%). Most students (75.87%) reported having cheated in an academic context and having been accused of cheating (88.47%). Measures Emotional States. The shortened State Shame and Guilt Scale (SSGS-S: Tangney &amp; Dearing, 2002, α = .82-.89), a 11-item self-report questionnaire, assessed state feelings of guilt</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Image Depicting Partially Innocent Participants Accused of More Severe Misconduct by Stealing Alex's Wallet Note. See the online article for the color version of this figure. Emotion Induction and Measurement. To induce an emotional response, participants responded to three open ended questions about how they would feel and what they would think about (1) their behavior while completing the problem sets, (2) having to decide</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Project Supervisor Informs Describes the Academic Integrity Board (Left Image) and the Plea Deal (Right Image)Note. See the online article for the color version of this figure.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc>05). Consistent with pilot testing, participants in the Less Severe Accusation group rated the severity of their accusation as less severe (M = 3.17, SD = 1.65) than those in the Comparable Accusation group (M = 4.4, SD = 1.85, t(295) = 6.01, p &lt; .001, dcohen = -0.7 95% CI [-0.96, -0.44]) and those in the More Severe Accusation group (M = 5.05, SD = 1.63) rated their accusation as more severe than those in the Comparable Accusation group, t(285) = 6.77, p &lt; .001, dcohen = 0.79 [0.55, 1.05]. 8 There were no significant differences in accusation severity ratings between the Innocent (M = 4.64, SD = 1.6), Guilty (M = 4.38, SD = 1.73), and PI groups.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Feelings of Guilt. On self-reported feelings of guilt, a oneway ANOVA revealed a significant effect of condition, F(4, 741) = 112.37, p &lt; .001, η 2 = .29 [.24, .34]. Consistent with Study 1, feelings of guilt were significantly greater among Comparable Accusation participants compared to completely Innocent participants (Mdiff = 1.73; t(263) = 14.4, p &lt; .001, d = 1.64 [1.38, 1.90]), and among Guilty compared to Innocent participants (Mdiff = 1.98; t(278) = 17.4, p &lt; .001, d = 1.97 [1.70, 2.24]), but did not significantly differ between Comparable Accusation and Guilty participants, Mdiff = 0.25; t(306) = 1.82, p = .361, d = 0.21 [-0.02 , 0.43]. As expected, Less Severe Accusation did not report significantly greater feelings of guilt than Comparable Accusation (Mdiff = -0.12; t(295) = 0.91, p = .894, d = 0.10 [-0.13 , 0.33]) or Guilty participants (Mdiff = -0.37; t(295) = 2.74, p = .051, d = 0.32 [0.09 , 0.55]). In support of H 2 , More Severe Accusation reported feeling less guilty than Comparable Accusation (Mdiff = -0.27; t(286) = 1.87, p = .335, d = 0.22 [-0.01 , 0.45]) and significantly more guilty than Innocent participants (Mdiff = 1.46; t(234) = 12, p &lt; .001, d = -1.57 [-1.83 , -1.31]). H3: Culpability Predicts Feelings of Shame. On self-reported feelings of shame, a one-way ANOVA revealed a significant effect of condition, F(4, 741) = 4.77, p &lt; .001, η 2 = .03 [.00, .05]. Similar to Study 1, feelings of shame did not significantly differ between Comparable Accusation participants and either Innocent (Mdiff = 0.31; t(308) = 2.35, p = .133, d = -0.26 [-0.49 , -0.04]) or Guilty participants (Mdiff = -0.19; t(308) = 1.35, p = 659, d = 0.16 [-0.07 , 0.38]). Again, Guilty participants reported feeling more ashamed than Innocent participants (Mdiff = 0.50; t(310) = 3.75, p = .002, d = -0.42 [-0.65, -0.20]) and also, unexpectedly, more than Less Severe Accusation participants (Mdiff = 0.41; t(297) = 3.05, p = .021, d = -0.35 [-0.58, -0.12]. Comparable Accusation participants did not significantly differ in reported shame from Less Severe Accusation (Mdiff = 0.22; t(295) = 1.66, p = 461., d = -0.19 [-0.42, 0.04]) or More Severe Accusation participants (Mdiff = -0.07; t(285) = 0.51, p = .987, d = 0.06 [-0.17, 0.29]). H4: Culpability Predicts Feelings of Deservingness of Punishment. Next, an ANOVA indicated that feelings of deservingness differed across condition, F(4, 741) = 464.31, p &lt; .001, η 2 = .51 [.46, .55]. Results were consistent with H4: Comparable Accusation participants did not feel significantly more deserving of punishment than Less Severe Accusation (Mdiff = 0.15; t(290) = 1.12, p = .797, d = -0.13 [-0.35 , 0.10]) or Guilty participants (Mdiff = -0.33; t(308) = 2.66, p = .062, d = 0.31 [0.08 , 0.53]) who felt the most deserving. Despite engaging in similar misconduct, More Severe Accusation participants felt less deserving of punishment than Comparable Accusation (Mdiff = -0.59; t(279) = 4.54, p &lt; .001, d = 0.53 [0.30 , 0.77]), Less Severe Accusation (Mdiff = 0.45; t(276) = 3.30, p &lt; .001, d = 0.39 [0.16 , 0.63]), and Guilty (Mdiff = -0.92; t(278) = 7.09, p &lt; .001, d = 0.83 [0.60 , 1.07]) participants. As expected, Innocent participants felt the least deserving, even compared to More Severe Accusation participants who had also been wrongfully accused (Mdiff = -1.86; t(165) = 18, p &lt; .001, d = 0.94 [1.93 , 2.51]).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>H 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Culpability Predicts Feelings of Anger. An ANOVA indicated that feelings of anger were significantly different across condition, F(4, 741) = 16.13, p &lt; .001, η 2 = .08[.05, .12].Results were largely consistent with H5: In line with our predictions, reported feelings of anger did not significantly differ between the More Severe Accusation and Innocent participants who were both accused of severe misconduct they had not engaged in (Mdiff = -0.16; t(287) = 1.29, p = .699, d = 0.15[-0.08 , 0.38]). Also, as expected PI-LSA participants were significantly less angrythan More Severe Accusation participants (Mdiff = -0.54; t(266) =4.61, p &lt; .001, d = 0.55 [0.31 , 0.79]), but, contrary to H5, not less so that Comparable Accusation (Mdiff = -0.03; t(295) = 0.29, p = .999, d = 0.03 [-0.20 , 0.26]) or Guilty (Mdiff = -0.03; t(297) = 0.27, p = .999, d = 0.03 [-0.20 , 0.26]) participants . H6: Planned Mediation Paths to Guilty Pleas. We performed a pre-registered multiple mediation analysis (similar to the one tested in Study 1) to examine two emotional routes-guilt and shame-through which culpability could result in a guilty plea. We used dummy-coded culpability contrasts, each comparing the No Cheat condition (Ref: Innocent) against a Cheat condition: Innocent vs. PI-C, Innocent vs. Guilty, Innocent vs. PI-LSA, Innocent vs. PI-MSA. Results were consistent with our predictions (H6) and the pattern of results from Study 1. Increased feelings of guilt (b1 path: b = .12 [.08, .16], SE = .02, p &lt; .001) predicted plea decision, whereas shame did not (b2 path: b = -.02 [-.06, .02], SE = .02, p = .367), even when controlling for culpability. Feelings of guilt mediated the relationship between each culpability contrast and plea decision (ps &lt; .001), whereas feelings of shame did not (p &gt; .398). Specifically, whereas the indirect effect of feelings of guilt was significant in the Innocent vs. PI-C (X1) contrast (a1*b1: b = 0.20 [0.13, 0.29], p &lt; .001), the indirect effect through feelings of shame was not significant (a5*b2: b = -0.01 [-0.02, 0.01], p = .432). A comparison of the two relative indirect effects through guilt and shame demonstrated that these were significantly different, b = 0.21 [0.13, 0.31], p &lt; .001. Similarly, in the Innocent vs. Guilty (X2) contrast the indirect effect through feelings of guilt was also significant (a2*b1: b = 0.24 [0.15, 0.33], p &lt; .001), whereas the indirect effect through feelings of shame was not (a 6 *b 2 : b = -0.01 [-0.03, 0.01], p = .398). Here again, a comparison of the two relative indirect effects demonstrated that these were significantly different (b = 0.25 [0.14, 0.35], p &lt; .001). Results across other culpability contrasts were highly consistent: the comparison of the relative indirect effects of shame and guilt were significant in the Innocent vs. PI-LSA (X3), b = 0.19 [0.12, 0.28], p &lt; .001, and the Innocent vs. PI-MSA (X4) contrast, b = 0.18 [0.10, 0.27], p &lt; .001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>correlated with feelings of guilt, r(746) = .64 [.60, .68], p &lt;.001. The current analysis expanded Feather et al.'s (2011) deservingness model by incorporating a willingness to take responsibility measure.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc>shows the results of this model. Consistent with H 2 and H 4 , in the first and second mediator models, all coefficients were positive and significant indicating that all Cheating groups believed themselves more deserving of punishment and reported feeling more guilty than the Innocent group (p &lt; .001). Beliefs about deservingness were positively associated with feeling guilty (b = 0.50 [0.42, 0.58], p &lt; .001), even controlling for condition. In the third model, the effect of deservingness beliefs (b = 0.18 [0.14, 0.21], p &lt; .001) and feelings of guilt (b = 0.04 [0.01, 0.07], p = .018) on plea decision were significant. Additionally, whereas the Innocent vs. Guilty and Innocent vs. PI-MSA contrasts were significant, the Innocent vs. PI-C and Innocent vs. PI-LSA contrasts were not significant. The latter result may tentatively suggest that the mediators fully explain the variance in plea decision between Innocent vs. PI-C and between Innocent vs. PI-LSA conditions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Study 3 Serial Mediation Model of Culpability Predicting Plea Decision Mediated by Judgments of Deservingness of Punishment and Feelings of GuiltNote. Results of serial mediation analysis examining the relative indirect effect of condition contrasts (X1, X2, X3, and X4) on plea decision (Y) through judgments of deservingness of punishment (M1) and state feelings of guilt (M2). Unstandardized estimates are displayed, with 95% confidence intervals. PI-C = Partially Innocent (Comparable Accusation); PI-LSA = Partially Innocent (Accusation Less Severe); PI-MSA = Partially Innocent (Accusation More Severe). Reference Group: Innocent: = 1, All others = 0; Plea Decision: Accept = 1, Reject = 0. Estimated coefficients are based on bootstrapping procedure with 10,000 bootstrap samples. *p &lt; .05; **p &lt; .01; ***p &lt; .001; n = 746.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure 12</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Distribution of Estimates of Likelihood of Conviction Across All StudiesNote. Dot plot: Error bars represent 95% CIs. Labeled endpoints of Likert scales indicates that an estimate of 0% chance indicated a 'I would definitely be acquitted', a 50% chance indicated 'unsure', and a 100% chance indicated 'I would definitely be found guilty.' PI-C = Partially Innocent -Comparable Accusation; PI-LSA = Partially Innocent -Less Severe Accusation; PI-MSA = Partially Innocent -More Severe Accusation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Logistic Regressions Predicting Likelihood of Plea Decision by Culpability</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Wald z</cell><cell>p</cell><cell cols="2">Odds Ratio 95% C.I. for Odds Ratio</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>B</cell><cell>S.E.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Lower Upper</cell></row><row><cell>Study 1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell cols="2">0.14 0.38 0.38</cell><cell>.705</cell><cell>1.15</cell><cell>0.55 -2.46</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">PI-C vs. Innocent -2.82 0.82 -3.42 &lt;.001</cell><cell>0.06</cell><cell>0.01 -0.25</cell></row><row><cell>PI-C vs. Guilty</cell><cell cols="2">0.06 0.53 0.12</cell><cell>.903</cell><cell>1.07</cell><cell>0.37 -3.05</cell></row><row><cell>Study 2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell cols="2">0.47 0.40 1.66</cell><cell>.243</cell><cell>1.60</cell><cell>0.73 -3.65</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">PI-C vs. Innocent -2.42 0.74 -3.28</cell><cell>.001</cell><cell>0.09</cell><cell>0.02 -0.34</cell></row><row><cell>PI-C vs. Guilty</cell><cell cols="2">0.92 0.64 1.43</cell><cell>.153</cell><cell>2.50</cell><cell>0.73-9.44</cell></row><row><cell>Study 3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Constant</cell><cell cols="2">0.39 0.16 2.40</cell><cell>.016</cell><cell>1.48</cell><cell>1.08 -2.06</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">PI-C vs. Innocent -3.19 0.38 -9.86 &lt; .001</cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell>0.02 -0.08</cell></row><row><cell>PI-C vs. Guilty</cell><cell cols="2">0.64 0.25 -260</cell><cell>.009</cell><cell>1.89</cell><cell>1.17 -3.07</cell></row><row><cell>PI-C vs. PI-LSA</cell><cell cols="2">-0.10 0.24 -2.96</cell><cell>.675</cell><cell>0.91</cell><cell>0.57 -1.44</cell></row><row><cell>PI-C vs. PI-MSA</cell><cell cols="3">-1.17 0.25 -6.96 &lt; .001</cell><cell>0.31</cell><cell>0.19 -0.50</cell></row></table><note>Note. PI-C = Partially Innocent -Comparable Accusation; PI-LSA = Partially Innocent - Less Severe Accusation; PI-MSA = Partially Innocent -More Severe Accusation.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Study 1 for H2 (dcohen=0.76 [0.21, 1.30]) andH3 (dcohen=0.94 [0.51, 1.44]).6    </figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">The choice to refer to these individuals as partially innocent rather than partially guilty is in line with the US legal system's presumption of innocence until proven guilty. Though such individuals may consider themselves (or be perceived by others as) morally or ethically guilty of wrongdoing, because they are as a matter of legal fact innocent of the charges of which they have been accused, we refer to them as partially innocent.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">The H2 and H3 effect sizes correspond to the difference in feelings of guilt between Partially Innocent and Innocent participants and between those who accepted and those who rejected the plea, respectively.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">Video for each condition are available on OSF: Guilty (osf.io/k3bcg); Partially Innocent Comparable (osf.io/y5eua); More Severe Condition (osf.io/uwy3m); Less Severe (osf.io/dkpb7); Innocent (osf.io/r8tpq).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">Pre-testing (n = 64) demonstrated that participants regarded the Less Severe Accusation as less serious, less consequential for the researchers, and less worthy of punishment (Mcomposite = 3.9 of 7, SD = 1.69) compared to the Comparably Severe Accusation (Mcomposite = 5, SD = 1.18, t(63) = -5.63, p &lt; .001, d = 0.76 [0.40 , 1.11]). As expected, participants also regarded the More Severe Accusation as more serious, more consequential, and more worthy of punishment (Mcomposite = 5.76, SD = 0.97) compared to the Comparably Severe Accusation (t(63) = -5.41, p &lt; .001, d = -0.70 [-1.06 , -0.35]).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">We pre-registered that if beliefs about deservingness were independently associated with plea decision, we would add desert as a third indirect pathway to the parallel mediation model reported above. A logistic regression was significant-χ2(1) = 200.9, p &lt; .001, R 2 = .46-and indicated that deservingness is strongly independently associated with plea decision, b = 1.15, z = 14.17, p &lt; .001, OR = 3.16 [2.71, 3.72]. However, we report a serial mediation here instead as conceptually this model is more in line with prior theorizing and empirical work on the causal role of desert on affective responses to outcomes (e.g.,<ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Feather, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Feather et al., 2011)</ref>.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Affective forecasting: Why can&apos;t people predict their emotions? Thinking &amp; Reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ayton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Elwakili</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="80" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/13546780600872726</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/13546780600872726" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The theory of planned behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ajzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0749-5978(91)90020-T</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0749-5978(91)90020-T" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="211" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The theory of planned behavior: Frequently asked questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ajzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/hbe2.195</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/hbe2.195" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Behavior and Emerging Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="314" to="324" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interventions against norm violations: Dispositional determinants of self-reported and real moral courage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baumert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Halmburger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schmitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1053" to="1068" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An inventory for measuring clinical anxiety: Psychometric properties</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Steer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-006X.56.6.893</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-006X.56.6.893" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="893" to="897" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plea bargaining outside the shadow of trial</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bibas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Law Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2463</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The plea bargaining process from the defendant&apos;s perspective: A field investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bordens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bassett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15324834basp0602_1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15324834basp0602_1" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A meta-analytic review of the effect of guilt on compliance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Boster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cruz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Manata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Deangelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Influence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="67" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/15534510.2016.1142892</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/15534510.2016.1142892" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Felony defendants in large urban counties</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.bjs.gov/content/pub/pdf/fdluc09.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Bureau of Justice Statistics.</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Charged up and anchored down: A test of two pathways to judgmental and decisional anchoring biases in plea negotiations. Psychology, Public Policy, and Law</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cardenas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/law0000390</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<publisher>Advanced Online Publication</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/7s4vz</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/7s4vz" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coercive plea bargaining: The unrecognized scourge of the justice system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Caldwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Catholic University Law Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="96" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Immanent justice reasoning: Theory, research, and current directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Harvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dawtry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in experimental social psychology</title>
		<editor>M. Zanna &amp; J. Olson</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="161" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some effects of guilt on compliance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Carlsmith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0027039</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0027039" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transgression and altruism: A case for hedonism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cialdini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Darby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Vincent</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="502" to="516" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0022-1031(73)90031-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-1031" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90031" to="90031" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Handbook of forensic psychology: Resource for mental health and legal professionals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Donohue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">file://localhost/opt/grobid/grobid-home/tmp/Users/stephanie.a.cardenas/Dropbox%20(Personal)/Partial%20Innocence/PB1%20Manuscript/PSPB%20ms%202022%20resubmission/doi-org.10.1016/B978-012524196-0/50037-1</idno>
		<editor>W. T. O&apos;Donohue &amp; E. R. Levensky</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>Elsevier Science</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="897" to="996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The road to perdition: Extreme influence tactics in the interrogation room</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anger damns the innocent</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Decelles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Howe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1214" to="1226" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797621994770</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797621994770" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Innocent defendant&apos;s dilemma: An innovative empirical study of plea bargaining&apos;s innocence problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Dervan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Edkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal Criminal Law &amp; Criminology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ambiguity and self-evaluation: The role of idiosyncratic trait definitions in self-serving assessments of ability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dunning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Meyerowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Holzberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0022-3514.57.6.1082</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.57.6.1082" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1082" to="1090" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feeling &quot;holier than thou&quot;: Are self-serving assessments produced by errors in self-or social prediction?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Epley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dunning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0022-3514.79.6.861</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.79.6.861" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="861" to="875" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgments of deservingness: Studies in the psychology of justice and achievement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Feather</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="107" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15327957pspr0302_1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327957pspr0302_1" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deservingness and emotions: Applying the structural model of deservingness to the analysis of affective reactions to outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Feather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/10463280600662321</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/10463280600662321" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Review of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deservingness and emotions: Testing a structural model that relates discrete emotions to the perceived deservingness of positive or negative outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Feather</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mckee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bekker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Motivation and Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1007/s11031-011-9202-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11031-011-9202-4" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compliance without pressure: The effect of guilt</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Freedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wallington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bless</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0025009</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0025009" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The illusion of transparency: Biased assessments of others&apos; ability to read one&apos;s emotional states</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Savitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Medvec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.75.2.332</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//0022-3514.75.2.332" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="332" to="346" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social psychology and plea bargaining: Applications, methodology, and theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Gregory</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mowen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Linder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.36.12.1521</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.36.12.1521" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1521" to="1530" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The psychology of interrogations and confessions: A handbook</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Gudjonsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Innocence and resisting confession during interrogation: Effects on physiologic activity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Guyll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Madon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Lannin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Scherr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Greathouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000044</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000044" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="366" to="375" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical mediation analysis with a multicategorical independent variable</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Preacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/bmsp.12028</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/bmsp.12028" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Mathematical and Statistical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="470" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating predictors of true and false guilty pleas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Levett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb00%2000297</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000297" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Criminal interrogation and confessions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Inbau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Reid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Jayne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Jones &amp; Bartlett Publishers</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Cases</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.innocenceproject.org/all-cases/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the psychology of confessions: Does innocence put innocents at risk?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kassin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0003-066X.60.3.215</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.60.3.215" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why suspects waive their Miranda rights: The power of innocence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kassin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Norwick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/B:LAHU.0000022323.74584.f5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/B:LAHU.0000022323.74584.f5" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mispredicting affective and behavioral responses to racism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kawakami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Karmali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Dovidio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">323</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5911</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="276" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plea bargaining recommendations by criminal defense attorneys: Evidence strength, potential sentence, and defendant preference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wolbransky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Heilbrun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Sciences &amp; the Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="573" to="585" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bsl.759</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bsl.759" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sample size justification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Läkens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1525/collabra.33267</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1525/collabra.33267" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Collabra: Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The belief in a just world: A fundamental delusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<publisher>Plenum</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward Parsimony in Bias Research: A Proposed Common Framework of Belief-Consistent Information Processing for a Set of Biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oeberst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Imhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/17456916221148147</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/17456916221148147" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bargained justice: The rise of false testimony for false pleas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pardieck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Edkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Dervan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fordham International Law Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="469" to="528" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The effect of prior false confession on guilty plea decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Perillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Crozier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Pollick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kassin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<pubPlace>New Orleans, LA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Paper presented at the American Psychology-Law Society conference</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inside interrogation: The lie, the bluff, and false confessions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Perillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kassin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="337" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10979-010-9244-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10979-010-9244-2" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plea decision-making by attorneys and judges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Redlich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bushway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Norris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Criminology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="537" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11292-016-9264-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11292-016-9264-0" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">To plead or not to plead: A comparison of juvenile and adult true and false plea decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Redlich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Shteynberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000205</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000205" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="611" to="625" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of confessions on guilty pleas and plea discounts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Redlich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Norris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bushway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/law0000144</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/law0000144" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, Public Policy, and Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="157" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simulation, scenarios, and emotional appraisal: Testing the convergence of real and imagined reactions to emotional stimuli</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Clore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1520" to="1532" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/01461672012711012</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/01461672012711012" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating true and false confessions within a novel experimental paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Russano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Meissner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Narchet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kassin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.0956-7976.2005.01560.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0956-7976.2005.01560.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="486" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The world is not fair: An examination of innocent and guilty suspects&apos; waiver decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Scherr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Franks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000121</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000121" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intention-behavior relations: a conceptual and empirical review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sheeran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14792772143000003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14792772143000003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Review of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shame, guilt, and remorse: Implications for offender populations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Tangney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stuewig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hafez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Forensic Psychiatry &amp; Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="706" to="723" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14789949.2011.617541</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14789949.2011.617541" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral emotions and moral behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Tangney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stuewig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mashek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="372" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev.psych.56.091103.070145</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.56.091103.070145" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The National Registry of Exonerations</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.law.umich.edu/special/exoneration/Pages/detaillist.aspx" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Exoneration detail list</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fairness and the willingness to accept plea bargain offers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Gazal-Ayal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garcia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Empirical Legal Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1740-1461.2009.01171.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1740-1461.2009.01171.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The anchor integration model: A descriptive model of anchoring effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Schley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2016.07.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2016.07.003" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social justice: Outcome and procedure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Tyler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/002075900399411</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/002075900399411" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Figure C. in U.S. Sentencing Commission Sourcebook</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.ussc.gov/sites/default/files/pdf/research-and-publications/annual-reports-and-sourcebooks/2017/2017SB_Full.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>United States Sentencing Commission</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development and validation of brief measures of positive and negative affect: The PANAS scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tellegen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.54.6.1063</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.54.6.1063" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1063" to="1070" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plea-bargaining law: The impact of innocence, trial penalty, and conviction probability on plea outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wilford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Frazier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s12103-020-09564-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12103-020-09564-y" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Criminal Justice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="554" to="575" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guilt status influences plea outcomes beyond the shadow-of-the-trial in an interactive simulation of legal procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wilford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Sutherland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gonzales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabinovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/lhb0000450</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/lhb0000450" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Law and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact bias is alive and well</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/a0032662</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0032662" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="740" to="748" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Innocence is irrelevant</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Yoffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2017/09/innocence-is-irrelevant/534171/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plea discounts, time pressures, and false-guilty pleas in youth and adults who pleaded guilty to felonies in New York City</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Zottoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Daftary-Kapur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Winters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology, Public Policy, and Law</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="259" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/law0000095</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/law0000095" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
