<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Please refer to published version in Nature Communications</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominik</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
							<email>deffner@mpib-berlin.mpg.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Science of Intelligence Excellence Cluster</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mezey</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Science of Intelligence Excellence Cluster</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Theoretical Biology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Kahl</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Schakowski</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pawel</forename><surname>Romanczuk</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Science of Intelligence Excellence Cluster</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Theoretical Biology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charley</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tübingen</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tübingen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Max Planck Institute for Biological Cybernetics</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tübingen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><forename type="middle">H J M</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Science of Intelligence Excellence Cluster</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Please refer to published version in Nature Communications</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:35+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Social information use</term>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>collective dynamics</term>
					<term>Hidden Markov models</term>
					<term>social learning</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Collective dynamics emerge from countless individual decisions. Yet, we poorly understand the processes governing dynamically-interacting individuals in human collectives under realistic conditions. We present a naturalistic immersive-reality experiment where groups of participants searched for rewards in different environments, studying how individuals weigh personal and social information and how this shapes individual and collective outcomes. Capturing high-resolution visual-spatial data, behavioral analyses revealed individual-level gains-but group-level losses-of high social information use and spatial proximity in environments with concentrated (vs. distributed) resources. Incentivizing participants at the group (vs. individual) level facilitated adaptation to concentrated environments, buffering apparently excessive scrounging. To infer discrete choices from unconstrained interactions and uncover the underlying decision mechanisms, we developed an unsupervised Social Hidden Markov Decision model. Computational results showed that participants were more sensitive to social information in concentrated environments frequently switching to a social relocation state where they approach successful group members. Group-level incentives reduced participants&apos; overall responsiveness to social information and promoted higher selectivity over time. Finally, mapping group-level spatio-temporal dynamics through time-lagged regressions revealed a collective exploration-exploitation trade-off across different timescales. Our study unravels the processes linking individual-level strategies to emerging collective dynamics, and provides tools to investigate decision-making in freely-interacting collectives.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Collective behavior emerges from individual-level cognition, and the cognitive mechanisms driving social interactions strongly determine whether social influence promotes adaptive behavior or leads to maladaptive herding <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2]</ref>. Despite their crucial role in governing the outcomes of collective behaviors, the decisionmaking processes of human collectives under naturalistic conditions remain poorly understood <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref>.</p><p>One of the key trade-offs driving collective systems is between using personal versus social informa-tion. Relying too heavily on personal information prevents the spread of useful information, while relying too heavily on social information reduces exploration and generates over-exploitation of the environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr">[9]</ref>. Most experimental studies to date on social decision-making used static-and often simulated- <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">25</ref> sources of social information <ref type="bibr">[7]</ref> or let interacting participants choose among a small set of well-defined options at prespecified time points [e.g., <ref type="bibr">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr">[17]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[18]</ref>. To understand the mechanisms governing real-world human collective systems, we need paradigms that al-30 low complex social dynamics to unfold within natu-ralistic environments. Analyzing behavior in such complex systems requires novel computational models that describe how dynamically-interacting individuals make decisions while accounting for their unique (visual) per- <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">35</ref> spectives and spatial constraints <ref type="bibr">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr">19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">20]</ref>. Such constraints are unavoidable features of the real world and fundamentally shape the costs and benefits of social information use <ref type="bibr">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">21]</ref>; they are thus prerequisites for testing collective dynamics in more realistic settings and connecting abstract models to reality.</p><p>Here, we use an immersive-reality approach to study how groups of four participants search for resources ("coins") in a 3D virtual environment with different resource distributions and incentive structures.</p><p>Participants could observe each other in real time and decide to join players who successfully discovered a resource patch ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1a; Supplementary Movie 1)</ref>. The 3D environment imposes a limited, first-person, field of view as well as realistic spatial constraints creating a natural trade-off between individual exploration of the environment and social information use <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">22]</ref>. Participants completed four rounds of the task in a 2x2 design ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1c</ref>; see Methods). In half of the rounds, resource units were concentrated in relatively few-but richpatches. In the other rounds, the same number of units were distributed among many-but poorer-patches. Theory on producer-scrounger games [e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[23]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr">[26]</ref> and our own simulation results <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[27]</ref> predict that a "scrounging" strategy, where agents use social information to join resource patches discovered by others, increases in frequency (relative to individually-searching "producers") when patches are difficult to find but rich in resources. Therefore, we expected participants to rely more on social information and to be less selective in concentrated compared to distributed environments.</p><p>Across social systems, individual incentives do not always align with the interest of the collective and theory on producer-scrounger dynamics <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr">[26]</ref>, and the evolution of social learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">28]</ref> predicts that social information use can be individually beneficial while at the same time reducing collective performance or population fitness. To investigate how participants balance the pros and cons of social information use depending on their interdependence with others, half of the groups were incentivized on the group level (i.e., paid depending on group success), while the other half on the individual level (i.e., paid depending on personal success). Since scroungers capitalize on others' discoveries and compete for limited local resources, we expected participants to rely less on social information when incentivized on the group level reducing maladaptive over-exploitation of social information (see preregistration for the full set of predictions: https://osf.io/5r736/ <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>).</p><p>Our analyses leveraged high-resolution time-series data from each participant of their visual information and movement trajectories. Behavioral analyses revealed individual-level benefits of high social information use and spatial proximity in concentrated resource environments, which came at the expense of group performance. Crucially, group-level incentives alleviated the negative consequences of apparently excessive scrounging. We next developed an unsupervised Social Hidden Markov Decision model (inspired by animal movement models in ecology <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">31]</ref>) to simultaneously infer decision sequences between latent states and describe how resource distributions, incentives, and situational factors influence participants' decisions to use social information <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1d)</ref>. Quantifying such la-100 tent social decision-making, we uncovered the mechanisms underlying behavioral outcomes, demonstrating how participants strategically adjusted their social information use to both environmental demands and incentive structure. Group incentives facilitated adap-105 tive tuning of decision strategies over time, with increased selectivity acting as a safeguard against maladaptive over-reliance on social information. Finally, we mapped the emerging group-level spatio-temporal dynamics through time-lagged Gaussian process re-110 gressions and discovered consistent collective benefits of more individualistic search in distributed environments and a collective exploration-exploitation tradeoff in concentrated environments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>115</head><p>We start by examining participants' behavior before turning to computational analyses. Results are reported as population-level effects from hierarchical Bayesian models controlling for participant-and group-level variability in both intercepts and slopes (for frequen-120 tist analyses of main behavioral results producing identical conclusions, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Supplementary Tables 1 and 3-7)</ref>. Inferences are based on posterior contrasts between conditions (on the outcome scale for behavior, on a latent scale for computational results), reported as poste-125 rior means and 90% highest posterior density intervals (HPDIs). We also report evidence ratios (ERs), which are equivalent to (one-sided) Bayes factors, to quantify the relative posterior probability for a directed effect compared to its alternative <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[32]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>130</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Foraging performance and scrounging</head><p>Participants incentivized on the group level showed no difference in performance between environments (-0.05 [-8.9,8.1], ER = 1.05; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2a</ref>; <ref type="table">Supplementary Table 1</ref>), whereas participants incentivized on 135 the individual level performed worse in concentrated than distributed environments (-8.4 <ref type="bibr">[-16</ref>.7, -0.5], ER = 20.7). To quantify success differences among incentive conditions over time, we computed exploitation probabilities at one minute intervals in each 140 round ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2b; Supplementary Fig. 1</ref>). In concentrated environments, group-incentivized participants consistently outperformed those incentivized on the individual level after four minutes. In distributed environments, individually-incentivized participants initially 145 performed better before converging on the same probability of success. Investigating success conditional on prior experience <ref type="table">(Supplementary Table 2</ref>), we found that group-incentivized participants performed better than individually-incentivized participants when forag-   or when having previously foraged in distributed environments (0.01 <ref type="bibr">[-11.3, 11.4]</ref>, ER = 0.99).</p><p>The structure of the environment also induced different patterns of foraging behavior. In concentrated environments, participants discovered fewer new patches (group incentives: -5.   <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>), suggesting increased social atten-tion in concentrated environments (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Supplementary  Fig. 3</ref> for aggregated results).</p><p>To account for the influence of participants' unique visual perspectives, we next computed scrounging rates as conditional probabilities for players to join a patch where they had observed one (or more) exploiting group member(s). Scrounging rates were higher in con-180 centrated than in distributed environments (group incentives: 0.44 [0.37,0.50], ER &gt; 100; individual incentives: 0.48 [0.42,0.54], ER &gt; 100), with most scrounging behavior seeming to occur in participants incentivized on the individual level while foraging in con-havioral metrics to the number of collected coins, we used multilevel Poisson regressions accounting for baseline success differences between incentive conditions. In concentrated environments, individual participants benefited from high scrounging rates <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 2d</ref>, top) and close proximity to others ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2e, top</ref>). This suggests individual-level adaptive benefits of social information use in resource environments where the behavior of others provides valuable information. By contrast, collective performance was higher if, on average, fewer players exploited a patch <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 2d, bottom</ref>) and, to a lesser degree, if group members kept greater inter-individual distance <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 2e, bottom</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig. 4</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Solitary foragers</head><p>To compare group foragers to solitary ones, we recruited additional participants who searched for coins on their own (see Methods). Foraging in the same resource environments but without competition, individual foragers, on average, collected more coins than participants in groups. They performed similarly in both environments and discovered more patches in distributed environments (Supplementary <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Fig. 5</ref>; see Supplementary <ref type="figure">Fig. 6</ref> for movement metrics and discoveries).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social Hidden Markov Decision Model</head><p>Next, we use a computational approach to delineate the mechanisms underlying participants' decisions to respond to or ignore social information. A computational approach is necessary because observable metrics, such as patch joining events, are only indirect indicators of underlying strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[33]</ref>. Such latent strategies as well as the decisions to switch between them lie at the core of theoretical (producer-scrounger) models but cannot be directly observed. Imagine, for instance, that a player decides to use social information and moves towards an exploiting group member but does not arrive before all coins are collected; or, more luckily, this player might even independently discover a new patch while relocating. In both scenarios, we do not observe the player joining a patch, although they have actively decided to use social information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>250</head><p>Our model uses time series of three state-dependent variables (on a one-second resolution; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig.1d</ref> and Supplementary <ref type="figure">Fig. 7)</ref> to probabilistically assign participants to one of two latent states at each point in time: individual exploration or social relocation (see Meth-255 ods). Individual exploration is characterized by irregular movement not directed towards successful peers, whereas social relocation is characterized by consistent, directed movement towards exploiting group members. Note that the latent states are statistically inferred from 260 changes in movement and interaction patterns, not hardcoded based on arbitrary criteria; we only selected the number of latent states and provided the model with prior information about how the states are expected to differ (i.e., which state should have larger values in the 265 state-dependent variables). Reassuringly, the model estimated smaller turning angles, larger reduction in distance to exploiting players and smaller relative bearings for the social relocation state compared to the individual exploration state ( <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 8</ref>), confirm-270 ing that the identified latent states correspond to our target of inference ( <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 7</ref> shows an example of a recovered state sequence using the Viterbi algorithm).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>State predictors and their adaptive consequences 275</head><p>Our model simultaneously infers the time-dependent transition probabilities between latent states. This allows us to describe how incentive conditions i and resource distributions j along with currently available (visual) information influence the probability of switching 280 from individual exploration to social relocation at time t. Specifically, we estimated the condition-specific influence of exploitation visibility V, visible patch distance D, number of visible exploiting players N, and time since success T ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1d</ref>; see Methods) :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">285 P I−&gt;S t = logit −1 (α i j [t] + β V i j [t] V t + β D i j [t] V t D t + β N i j [t] V t N t + β T i j [t] T t ).<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Averaging over all situations when at least one exploiting player was visible (i.e., V = 1), participants were more likely to switch to social relocation and approach others in concentrated compared to distributed environments with both group <ref type="formula">(</ref>  decision mechanisms underlying the observed scroung-300 ing rates ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2c</ref>). Using individual decision-weight estimates (i.e., random effects of state predictors from the multilevel computational model) to predict success reveals that individuals benefited from more social information use in both environments <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3b</ref>, first row).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>305</head><p>Turning to the strategies participants used to integrate social information, we found that, across conditions, participants were more likely to use social information if observed successful group members were close rather than farther away, suggesting selective 310 rather than indiscriminate use of social information <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3a</ref>, second row). This selectivity with respect to distance proved adaptive in distributed, but not in concentrated environments <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3b</ref>, second row). Moreover, participants preferentially decided to join patches 315 where fewer group members were exploiting in the individual but not in the group incentive condition <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3a</ref>, third row). Being selective with respect to the number of others at a patch proved neutral in both environments ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 3b, third</ref>  same patch in only 14% of cases and three players in only 3% of cases (one player in 83%). As a last factor, we also investigated the influence of past personal success on the probability to respond to social information. Surprisingly, we found that participants did not become more likely to use social information if unsuccessful for a longer time and there was also no relationship between individual-level weights and foraging success <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3a,b</ref>, fourth row).</p><p>Investigating the role of latent decision weights on collective performance reveals the same pattern observed for behavioral outcomes ( <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 9</ref>). The average baseline probability to turn social for groups was negatively related to collective success in concentrated environments, again revealing a contrast to individual-level outcomes where high social information use proved beneficial. Other decision weights were unrelated to collective success.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Temporal dynamics in state predictors</head><p>Over time, group-incentivized participants outperformed those incentivized on the individual level in concentrated environments ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2b</ref>; Supplementary Table 2). Did participants adjust their decision-making over time or did they enter the experiment with fixed, unchanging strategies? <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref> shows the temporal dynamics in state predictors from the time-varying state predictors model (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Supplementary Fig. 10</ref> for similar linear trends).</p><p>We first focus on participants incentivized on the group level. Participants started with similar overall propensities for social information use in both environments but, over time, seemed to become more likely (partly) explain the emerging benefits of collectivelyincentivized participants <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 2b)</ref>. In distributed environments, decision weights stayed relatively constant and there were no clear trends in the influence of the time since the last success.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>370</head><p>In the individual incentive condition, baseline levels of social information use started at higher levels compared to the group incentive condition and seemed to increase even further in concentrated environments (0.18 [-0.03, 0.40], ER = 10.4). Unlike collectively-375 incentivized participants, there was no distinct development towards more selective social information use in either environment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Collective visual-spatial dynamics</head><p>Our behavioral results suggested that, averaging over the whole rounds, groups benefited from less social information use and lower proximity in both environments ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2d</ref>,e, bottom). However, collective outcomes dynamically unfold over time, calling for a deeper understanding of the timescales at which the costs and benefits of social information use occur.</p><p>To examine such fine-grained collective dynamics, we quantify the changing relationships between groups' visual-spatial organization and collective foraging success for different time lags ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Fig. 5</ref>; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Supplementary   Fig. 11</ref> shows results for up to 3-minute time lags in steps of 5 seconds). Positive (negative) regression weights for a given time lag τ mean that greater interindividual distance/visibility among group members at time t − τ increased (decreased) groups' current collective foraging success at time t.</p><p>In distributed environments, groups of individuals who stayed farther away from each other were indeed more successful irrespective of time interval and incentive condition. In concentrated environments, we observed more intricate temporal dynamics. At relatively short timescales (&lt;≈ 15s for group incentives, &lt;≈ 8s for individual incentives), smaller inter-individual distances were associated with greater collective success; being closer together allowed collectives to better exploit clustered resources discovered by group members. This beneficial effect of grouping was especially pronounced for groups incentivized on the collective level. On the flip side, at longer timescales, larger distances among group members were associated with greater foraging success. If groups disperse, they are better able to explore large parts of the environment and discover one of the few, rich patches, thereby, increasing their collective foraging success in the future. Individuallyincentivized groups benefited more strongly from spatial distancing, likely because their higher sensitivity to social information increased their risks for overexploitation and herding. At even longer timescales, there was no longer an association between group distance and foraging success ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Supplementary Fig. 11</ref>).</p><p>Turning to inter-individual visibility, we observe a negative effect at short timescales (&lt;≈ 20s) for both environments and incentive conditions. As players could not see others while exploiting a patch, low visibility often meant that a lot of players were currently collecting 425 coins. More substantially, the number of visual connections among group members was positively related to collective success longer into the future across all conditions, suggesting that groups paying more attention to others in this crucial time window of patch discovery 430 had greater success later on.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Discussion</head><p>Finding and collecting rewards in heterogeneous environments is key for adaptive collective behavior, yet it remains largely unknown how individuals in freely in-435 teracting groups make strategic choices in naturalistic environments and how these choices might shape individual and collective outcomes. We designed a 3D immersive-reality collective foraging paradigm to obtain fine-grained visual and spatial data from interact-440 ing groups and developed computational Social Hidden Markov Decision models to extract and understand strategic choices from naturalistic behavior. Collective foraging provides an ideal testbed to study social decision-making and collective adaptation in a con-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>445</head><p>trolled, yet ecologically-relevant, context <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">34]</ref>. Anthropologists have identified our unique abilities to collectively find and extract high-quality resources from diverse environments as a defining feature of human adaptability <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[35]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[36]</ref><ref type="bibr">[37]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[38]</ref>. Collective foraging further unites 450 several key ecological and social challenges, such as navigating uncertain environments, cooperating with others to achieve common goals, as well as competing to gain privileged access to resources <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">39]</ref>.</p><p>As predicted by game-theoretic models of collective foraging [e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">40]</ref>, participants systematically adjusted their social information use to the resource distribution relying more on the behavior of others when resources were difficult to find, but provided a large potential for exploitation (i.e., in concentrated compared to distributed environments). Our work not only translates and tests predictions from idealized producer-scrounger models in more realistic social scenarios but, thereby, also highlights the fundamental role space and perception play in modulating social decision-making. Moreover, we found that participants calibrated their strategies over time, becoming more (less) likely to use social information in concentrated (distributed) environments, extending previous research highlighting the importance of selective and strategic social learning rather than pure copying or innovation <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">20]</ref>.</p><p>In both environments, individuals benefited from high propensities to switch to social relocation, whereas actually capitalizing on social information and scrounging at patches discovered by others was only adaptive in concentrated environments but maladaptive in distributed environments. The reason for this apparent contradiction might be that participants could still discover new patches while approaching group members and more directed movement even generally increased their chances of patch discovery. Therefore, participants incurred little costs by frequently responding to social information even if resources were evenly distributed, thus generating divergent consequences for latent propensities to respond to social information compared to manifest outcomes. Moreover, in distributed environments, where far-away patches were likely depleted before arrival, participants collected more points if they tuned their propensity to switch to social relocation based on the distance of exploiting group members, supporting recent theoretical predictions on the importance of selective copying in collective search <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref>.</p><p>Large amounts of social information use proved adaptive for individuals (in concentrated environments) but maladaptive for collectives. Groups performed better in either environment if, on average, fewer players exploited a given patch and players stayed further away from each other; additionally, solitary foragers generally outperformed participants in groups.</p><p>Crucially, placing the incentives on the collective level alleviated the negative collective consequences of high social information use. In concentrated environments, where scrounging is individually beneficial, collectively-incentivized participants were less likely to respond to social information and exploit patches discovered by others, increasing their foraging success compared to participants incentivized on the individual level. Group incentives had a more reliable effect on latent switching probabilities compared to observed scrounging rates where the evidence was rather weak. This is likely because switching probabilities in the computational model directly reflect decisions to use social information and approach successful others, whereas scrounging rates are influenced by many other 515 factors beyond an individual's control such as the behavior of others, highlighting the need to model social information use at the level of latent decisions instead of noisy behavioral outcomes. Moreover, group incentives also facilitated adaptive tuning of latent de-520 cision strategies over time, with increased selectivity likely safeguarding against maladaptive over-use of social information. There was no change towards more selective social information use in the individual incentive condition, suggesting that participants consistently 525 aimed to maximize their own success which benefited from frequent scrounging. Previously, Hung and Plott showed that a "majority rule institution" where participants were rewarded depending on group accuracy, reduced information cascades <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>. Similarly, Bazazi and 530 colleagues showed that collective incentives reduced individuals' reliance on social information in an interactive group estimation task and, thereby, increased the diversity of opinions and group wisdom <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43]</ref>. The present findings extend such work demonstrating how 535 incentive structure together with environmental affordances influence social information use and its collective consequences in more unconstrained and spatially explicit scenarios.</p><p>At first glance, the collective drawbacks of high 540 social information use we observed seem to contradict models of collective search [e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">44]</ref> that have shown that high degrees of social information use can also be beneficial on a collective level in rich and clustered environments. However, in such models, in-545 dividual exploration is typically governed by a random walk or similar stochastic process and social information provides the only source of adaptive information. Human participants, in contrast, use rich internal models of the environment and the task, as well as mem-550 ory, to systematically search the arena. These enhanced individual exploration abilities likely shifted the relative collective benefits of personal and social information use compared to theoretical models. Moreover, our time-lagged dynamics analysis provided a subtler pic-555 ture of when and how it is beneficial for collectives to join forces. In distributed environments, collectives indeed consistently benefited from independent search. In concentrated environments, our results suggested that groups need to dynamically adjust their visual-spatial 560 organization over time and collectively strike the right balance between independent exploration and joint exploitation. Recently, we have introduced a mechanistic agent-based simulation framework for collective foraging which combines individual-level evidence accumu-565 lation of personal and social cues with particle-based movement <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[27]</ref>. So far, we have focused on the role of reward distribution and real-world constraints on social information use and foraging success <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[27]</ref>; exploring additional factors such as different individual search processes, cognitive abilities, or resource types will grant broader insights into the determinants of collective foraging success. A promising avenue for future experiments could be to investigate cases of collective foraging where social 575 information use does not create zero-sum scenarios, as in the present paradigm, but facilitates novel abilities to emerge on the group level such as collective tracking of mobile resources <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[45]</ref><ref type="bibr">[46]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[47]</ref>. Other interesting extensions of our paradigm would be to systematically 580 vary group size, which has been predicted to affect the rate of scrounging <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25]</ref>, and to include patches of different qualities forcing individuals to additionally decide when to leave a given patch [48]. As we found that the benefits of collective incentives increased over time 585 (both within and across rounds), researchers could also investigate in greater detail how individuals (and collectives) update their strategies as a function of their own and observed payoffs.</p><p>Moving forward, we want to emphasize that devel-590 oping more naturalistic experimental paradigms should not be a research goal in itself, unless the added complexity provides additional theoretical insights. By "naturalistic", we thus do not mean conditions that are simply more complex or appear more similar to the 595 real world, but heterogeneous environments which are shaped endogenously as a consequence of one's own and others' actions and which are marked by temporal and spatial autocorrelation <ref type="bibr">[49,</ref><ref type="bibr">50]</ref>. In our case, including perceptual and spatial constraints added key 600 features of real-world decision environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">25]</ref>, which, as we showed, fundamentally shape the costs and benefits of social information use. The cues that participants can base their decisions on (e.g., the distance to visible others) arise naturally as a consequence</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>605</head><p>of their choices and the behavior of others instead of being externally imposed by the experimenter. As the ecological validity of such cues (i.e., the degree to which they reflect statistical patterns in the world) also determines the ecological validity of the experiment itself</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>610</head><p>[51], naturalistic approaches in this stricter sense also help us to bridge the gap between the lab and the real world. Finally, to identify and model latent choices between different behavioral states ("Individual Explo-615 ration" and "Social Relocation"), we developed a bespoke Social Hidden Markov Decision model. Traditionally, cognitive and behavioral scientists have investigated choices in relatively static and highly standardized experimental situations. Although abstracting 620 away from real-world details and controlling the environment participants face can allow researchers to more accurately identify cognitive processes and strategies, ultimately, we aim to understand how people make unconstrained decisions in relevant real-world ecologies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>625</head><p>Technological advances now provide us with unprecedented access to the individual-level informational environments and constraints that guide strategic choices in humans and other animals <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr">52,</ref><ref type="bibr">53]</ref>. Such dy-namic data require dynamic statistical inference and</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>630</head><p>Hidden Markov models provide ideal tools to simultaneously extract meaningful patterns from multidimensional time-series data and use internal or external situational factors to predict switches between the identified hidden states. Although our model is tailored to 635 the present experimental paradigm (especially with respect to the state-dependent variables), our freely available modeling code and in-depth documentation set the scene for future research on the socioecological drivers of social decision-making in human and (non-640 human) animal collectives. In addition to other naturalistic behavioral experiments <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr">54,</ref><ref type="bibr">55]</ref> man behavior that goes beyond the often highly constrained experiments of psychology, economics, and cognitive science, moving towards a science of unconstrained behavior that dynamically unfolds in naturalistic and socially interactive environments. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Methods</head><p>The study was approved by the Institutional Review Board of the MPIB (number: A 2022-06). The preregistration document can be accessed here: https://osf.io/5r736/ <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants started with an in-game tutorial to familiarize themselves with the keys and virtual environment (see Supplementary Movie 2). Participants then completed the task in groups of four, interacting live in a 3D immersive game environment. Group members were seated in the same room; opaque desk divider panels ensured that they could not observe each other's screen and mice with silent buttons prevented them from hearing when others clicked on coins during the coin collection mini-game. Over four rounds lasting twelve minutes each, participants controlled avatars in the virtual world (a square 90m x 90m "castle courtyard") and searched for resources ("coins") hidden under ground ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1a; Supplementary Movie 1)</ref>. At the beginning of each round, a fixed number (see section below) of non-overlapping circular resource patches ("coin fields") with a radius of r = 3 meters was randomly placed across the arena. Participants used keyboard buttons to freely navigate through the virtual environment and detect resource patches with a metal detector. Participants could only move their avatar forward, turn right or turn left using the "W","A" and "D" keys, respectively. All other keys were deactivated.</p><p>When individuals encountered a patch, their metal detector lighted up and they could start collecting coins by clicking on coin symbols appearing at different locations on the screen <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1b)</ref>. New coins appeared at a fixed interval of two seconds and stayed on the screen until collected (this interval was chosen as pilots showed that all participants were able to collect coins within two seconds). This simple "mini game" ensured that participants stayed engaged throughout the experiment without introducing additional sources of variation in performance. Participants continued collecting coins at a patch (and, therefore, could not move) until it was depleted. After that, the patch disappeared and a new patch containing the same number of coins was generated at a random location in the environment (ensuring that it did not overlap with any existing patch or participant). This means the number of patches and, therefore, the task structure remained constant within each round avoiding any effects of resource depletion or diminishing returns.</p><p>In addition to individual exploration of the environment, participants could also observe the behavior of others and freely decide to join players who have successfully discovered a resource patch. Avatars in the virtual environment performed a digging movement using a shovel to indicate that they were currently extracting coins (right avatar in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1a</ref>). If multiple players simultaneously collected coins from the same patch, each player extracted coins at the same rate of one coin every two seconds and coins, therefore, disappeared from a patch at a rate proportional to the number of extracting players. This means there was exploitative, but not interference, competition among players. Participants were only informed about the total number of coins collected (individually or collectively, depending on condition) after each round, but did not receive any additional feedback during rounds. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental Design</head><p>The experiment followed a 2x2 design <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1c)</ref>. Groups of participants were either incentivized on the individual or group level (between-subjects factor). In the "Individual In-765 centives" condition, participants' reward payment depended solely on their own amount of coins collected. In the "Group Incentives" condition, participants were rewarded based on the average number of coins collected across all four group members. As a second (within-subjects) factor, we manipu-770 lated the resource distribution: The same number of coin resources was either concentrated in few but rich patches ("Concentrated" condition; 5 patches with 48 coins each) or distributed among many but poor patches ("Distributed" condition; 15 patches with 16 coins each). Participants experienced 775 each resource distribution twice and all possible permutations of presentation order were realized for both incentive conditions. The resource distribution for each round was announced prior to the start of each round and was also indicated by the color of the walls enclosing the arena. Participants in the in-780 dividual foraging condition searched for coins on their own with the same resource distributions and were paid depending on the number of coins collected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data</head><p>At a sampling interval of 25Hz, we recorded partici-785 pants' (1) X-and Y-coordinates, (2) orientation vector, (3) velocity, (4) coin count and (5) whether they were extracting or not. From this raw data, we constructed movement trajectories of all players and computed the full visual social information available at each point 790 in time through basic triangulation (Supplementary Movie 3; see GitHub repository for complete data-processing scripts: https://github.com/DominikDeffner/VirtualCollectiveForaging). Moreover, we recorded (1) when a player arrived at a patch, (2) when a player extracted a coin, (3) when a patch was depleted, and (4) when and where a new patch was generated. For each event involving a player, we recorded the time stamp and ID of the player. Data from 2 out of 160 total rounds were omitted due to technical error in analyses relying on fine-grained visibility and movement data (i.e., scrounging 800 analysis and Social Hidden Markov Decision Model).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Behavioral analyses</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Temporal dynamics of success</head><p>To quantify how participants' performance changes over time, we used a multilevel model with Bernoulli likelihood to pre-805 dict whether players are currently exploiting a patch on a onesecond resolution. In addition to intercepts for each experimental condition and individual-and group-specific offsets, we used time (minute in round) as an ordered categorical (or monotonic) predictor, which also varied by condition. Instead</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>810</head><p>of imposing a particular functional form (e.g., a line), this approach only assumes that performance changes monotonically over time (i.e. either constantly increases or decreases) and lets the model estimate the size of the steps in which success probabilities change <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">74]</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">815 P(E)˜t i j = logit −1 (α i j + β MAX i jt −1 m=0 δ m i j ).<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The probability that players are exploiting in a specific minute of a round, indicated byt, is composed of the intercept for each incentive condition i and environment j and the total effect of experimental time multiplied by a sum of δ-parameters which represent the additional effect of each increment in time</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>820</head><p>(all δs together sum to 1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Scrounging analysis</head><p>To infer behavioral scrounging rates, we computed conditional probabilities for players to join a patch where they observed at least one exploiting group member. We first com-825 puted at which patches players observed an exploiting group member and then modeled the proportion of those patches that players actually joined using a binomial likelihood function. In addition to condition-specific intercepts, we implemented individual-and group-level random effects. This also allowed 830 us to use estimated individual-level scrounging rates (compared to other group members) to predict success in both environments within the same model propagating the full range of uncertainty ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2d; top)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social Hidden Markov Decision Model</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>835</head><p>We used a computational approach to study how different social and asocial cues impact participants' decisions to use social information and switch between behavioral states across the different conditions. Inspired by tools and concepts from animal movement ecology <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">75]</ref>, we developed a Social</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>840</head><p>Hidden Markov Decision Model. A Hidden Markov model is a doubly-stochastic time-series model with an observation process and an underlying state process <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1d)</ref>. It resembles a finite mixture model with several outcome variables where the identity of the underlying distributions is controlled by probabilities between both latent behavioral states and we included time-dependent (social and asocial) "state predictors" that influence such transitions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>State-dependent Variables</head><p>We used three state-dependent variables to infer the latent 860 states from the data: (1) participants' turning angles (change in movement direction in radians between successive time points; social relocation is expected to be characterized by directed movement, i.e., small turning angles), (2) the (smallest) change in distance to visible exploiting player(s) (social relo-865 cation marked by large reduction in distance to observed exploiting players) and (3) the (smallest) relative bearing (angle between orientation vector and vector connecting focal player to each other player; social relocation marked by consistent orientation towards other player, i.e., small relative bearing).</p><p>870 <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 7</ref>, top three rows, illustrates the statedependent variables for one exemplary time series with orange bars representing periods identified by the model as social information use through the Viterbi algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[78,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">79]</ref>. To model the turning angles, we used the von Mises distribution 875 which is commonly used in directional statistics for continuous circular data. It is a (more tractable) close approximation of the Wrapped normal distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[80]</ref>. For change in distance and relative bearings, we used normal and log-normal likelihoods, respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>880</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>State Predictors</head><p>To quantify how experimental conditions and situational factors modify each participant's probability to stop exploring independently and switch to social relocation at each time point t, we used four state predictors ( <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 7</ref>, bot- represents the default where only one player is exploiting) and (4) the (z-standardized) time since the last coin extraction T . All state predictors were estimated for each incentive condition i and environment j (Eq. 1). Note that D t and N t are multiplied by V t in Eq. 1 to "switch on" the effects of 895 distance and player number only for times when participants actually observed (an) exploiting player(s), i.e., when V t = 1. All predictor weights were estimated in a fully hierarchical Bayesian framework with random-effect terms accounting for the covariance of decision weights among both individuals 900 and groups while also allowing those covariances to differ among experimental conditions (omitted from Eq. 1 for the sake of readability).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time-varying state predictors</head><p>Moreover, we augmented these multilevel models by esti- </p><formula xml:id="formula_2">β˜t D i j = β D MAX i jt −1 m=0 δ D m i j .<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Note we only included individual-and group-specific offsets for the average effect of each state predictor over time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Forward and Viterbi algorithms</head><p>To efficiently compute the (log) marginal likelihood, i.e., the joint distribution of each data sequence summing over all possible state sequences, we used the forward algorithm, which calculates this likelihood recursively [see <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">75,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">76,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">78</ref>, for more technical introductions]. After model fitting, we used the dynamic-programming Viterbi algorithm to obtain the most likely state sequence given the observations and estimated parameters <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">76,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">78]</ref>. This reconstruction of the underlying state sequence helps visualizing the results of the fitted models and ensuring that the state-dependent distributions can be connected to psychologically meaningful processes. We only explicitly modeled times at which players potentially could use social information, i.e., times when they were allowed to move and at least one group member was currently collecting coins (white segments in <ref type="figure">Supplementary  Fig. 7</ref>). This means we omitted all times (1) when players themselves were exploiting a patch (dark grey segments in <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 7</ref>) and (2) when no group member was exploiting (light grey segments in <ref type="figure">Supplementary Fig. 7</ref>), because in both cases we know the state of a player. To ensure a proper latent state sequence, we set a player's state to individual exploration after both types of omissions. As detailed in the preregistration from 12.07.2022 (https://osf.io/5r736/ <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>), we have tailored a general collective foraging agent-based model <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[27]</ref> to the precise design of this experiments; we used this mechanistic model to generate synthetic data of the same format as our experimental data with known sequences of latent states (individual exploration and social relocation). We then confirmed that a baseline version of our computational model was able to reliably infer latent-state sequences on the level of single rounds. The preregistration document also contains further explanations of our modeling approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Collective Visual-Spatial Dynamics Model</head><p>Lastly, we investigated how the visual-spatial organization of groups affected collective success across different timescales and how these dynamics differed among incentive conditions and environments. Specifically, we used a time-lagged Gaussian-process regression model with binomial likelihood to estimate how spatial and visual organization at different times in the past t − τ (in steps of 5 seconds for up to three minutes, i.e., t − 5s, t − 10s, ..., t − 180s, as well as for each second for up to half a minute, i.e., t−1s, t−2s, ..., t−30s) predicted collective success (proportion of players exploiting) at time t. Gaussian processes extend the multilevel approach to continuous categories and estimate a unique parameter value for each category, while still regarding time as a continuous dimension in which similar time lags are expected to generate similar estimates <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[74]</ref>. The regression weight for a given time lag t − τ (for incentive condition i and environment j) is composed of the average effect and a lag-specific offset for each experimental condition:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">β t−τ i j =β i j + d τ i j .<label>(4)</label></formula><p>The lag-specific offsets follow a multivariate Gaussian distribution, separately for experimental conditions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">970               d 1 i j d 2 i j ... d τmax i j               ∼ N                           0 0 ... 0              , K i j              .<label>(5)</label></formula><p>The vector of means is all zeros, so the average effect remains unchanged, and K i j is the covariance matrix among time lags. We estimated the parameters of a Radial basis function (or "squared-exponential") kernel that expresses how the covariance between different lags changes as the distance between 975 them increases:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">K τxτy i j = η i j exp(−ρ i j (τ y − τ x ) 2 τ 2 max ).<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The covariance between time lags τ x and τ y equals the maximum covariance η i j , which is reduced at rate ρ i j by the relative squared distance between τ x and τ y .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model fitting 980</head><p>All models were fitted using Stan as a Hamiltonian Monte Carlo engine for Bayesian inference <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[81]</ref>, implemented in R v.4.0.3 through cmdstanr version 0.5.3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[82]</ref>. We used within-chain parallelization with reduce_sum to substantially reduce model run times through parallel evaluation 985 of the likelihood. To reduce the risk of overfitting the data, we generally used weakly informative priors for all parameters. For state-dependent distributions in the Social Hidden Markov Decision Model, we used informative priors to incorporate knowledge about the nature of both states 990 which also helps avoid label-switching, a common issue in all mixture models <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">78]</ref>. To optimize convergence, we implemented the non-centered version of random effects using a Cholesky decomposition of the correlation matrix <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[74]</ref> with LKJ priors for correlations matrices <ref type="bibr">[83]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>995</head><p>Visual inspection of traceplots and rank histograms <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[84]</ref> suggested good model convergence and no other pathological chain behaviors, with convergence confirmed by the Gelman-Rubin criterion <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[85]</ref> Tagging basketball events with hmm in stan.</p><p>https://mc-stan.org/users/documentation/ case-studies/bball-hmm.html. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Collective foraging task and Social Hidden Markov Decision model. (a) Participants in groups of four searched for</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>150 ing in concentrated environments for a second consecutive time (15.0 [4.3, 26.2], ER = 76.7), but not in the first round of the experiment (3.1 [-8.6, 14.3], ER = 2.1)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Behavioral Results. (a) Coins collected per incentive condition and environment (concentrated in blue, distributed in green). Each circle represents one round per participant (n = 160 participants), larger filled dots represent posterior means (as well as 90% HPDIs) from a Bayesian multilevel Poisson model. (b) Performance differences between incentive conditions (positive values indicate an advantage for group incentives), computed as the probability of exploiting a patch in one minute intervals (posterior means and 90% HPDIs; n = 160). (c) Posterior scrounging rates (conditional probabilities that players join a patch where they had observed at least one exploiting group member) per incentive condition and environment. (d) Average number of coins collected per individual as a function of individual-specific scrounging rates (with 90% HPDIs; top; n = 160) and per group as a function of forager density (i.e., average number of players exploiting a given patch; bottom; n = 40). (e) (Average) number of coins per round per individual (top; n = 160) and group (bottom; n = 40) in concentrated and distributed environments as a function of distance (standardized average distance to other players). Lines and uncertainty intervals show effects from multilevel regressions accounting for baseline differences between incentive conditions and individual-and group-level variability in both intercepts and slopes (transparent text if 90% HPDI overlaps 0).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>2 [-5.7,-4.7], ER &gt; 100; individual incentives: -5.6 [-6.1,-5.1], ER &gt; 100; Supplementary</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>State predictors and their adaptive consequences (a) Full posterior distributions (transparent curves) and 90% HPDIs (darker areas) for the influence of different state predictors on the probability that participants switch from individual exploration to social relocation per environment (concentrated in blue, distributed in green) and incentive condition. The top row shows baseline switching probabilities across all situations in which participants observe (a) successful player(s), the other rows show deviations from this expectation on the logit scale. (b) Success (average number of coins collected per individual; n = 160) in concentrated (left) and distributed (right) environments as a function of individual-level decision weights. Lines and uncertainty intervals show effects from log-normal regression models accounting for baseline success differences between incentive conditions (reported above, transparent text if 90% HPDI overlaps 0).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Fig. 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>row), likely reflecting the fact 320 that participants observed two players exploiting the Temporal dynamics in state predictors. 100 random draws from the posterior distribution (transparent lines) as well as posterior means (solid lines) for the influence of different state predictors over time in each round per incentive condition and environment (concentrated in blue, distributed in green). The first column shows baseline switching probabilities across all situations in which participants observe (a) successful player(s), the following columns show deviations from this expectation on the logit scale.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>to use social information in concentrated (0.20 [-0.01, 0.42], ER = 12.8) and less likely to use social informa-355 tion in distributed environments (-0.11 [-0.27, 0.05], ER = 6.2), suggesting calibration of social decision-making over time. Participants in concentrated environments started as rather indiscriminate social learners but, over time, became more selective and began to strongly rely 360 on distance (-0.45 [-0.64, -0.26], ER &gt; 100) and the number of exploiting players (-0.55 [-0.88, -0.24], ER &gt; 100) as cues. This tuning of decision strategies towards more selectivity might act as a safeguard against the over-reliance on social information and, therefore,365</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Fig. 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Collective visual-spatial dynamics. Time-lagged Gaussian-process regression weights (including 90% HPDIs) predicting collective foraging success (number of players exploiting a patch) based on (a) distance (average pairwise distance among players) and (b) visibility (number of visual connections among group members, ranging from 0, where no one is looking at others, and 12, where everyone is looking at everyone else) across different time intervals per incentive condition and environment (concentrated in blue, distributed in green).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>670</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>recruited from the Max Planck Institute for Human Development (MPIB) recruitment pool and invited in anonymous groups of four to the behavioral laboratory at the MPIB in Berlin, Germany (63 identified as male, 97 as female; M age = 28.5, S D age = 6.4 years; all were proficient in German and most came from Western, educated, industrialized, rich, and democratic societies [70, 71]). 40 additional participants were recruited for an individual control condition (14 identified as male, 26 as female; M age = 29.8, S D age = 5.7 years). Participants signed an informed consent form prior to participation and received a base payment of e18 plus a bonus of e0.01 per coin (depending on incentive condition, see below), earning on average e23.09 ± 0.71 (S D) for a total time of about one hour. The experimenter was blinded to the aim of the study and the hypotheses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The 3D virtual environment imposed a limited, firstperson, field of view (108 • horizontal and 76 • vertical FOV) as well as realistic spatial constraints (maximum movement speed of 2 m/s) creating natural trade-offs between individual exploration of the environment and social information 750 use [20, 22]. The experiment was implemented using the Unity [72] game engine (version 2020.3.21 [73],IL2CPP backend, built-in rendering pipeline, post-Processing Stack v2 3.1.1) using the Netcode for GameObjects library (version 1.0.0) with a Unity Transport layer. The four instances for 755 participants were connected to a local Windows Server running a Server Build of the experiment with a tick rate of 25Hz. Player movement was handled client-side. The Unity source code as well as built executives necessary to reproduce and run the experiment are stored on GitHub: 760 https://github.com/DominikDeffner/VirtualCollectiveForaging.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>845a</head><label></label><figDesc>Markov chain<ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[76]</ref>. The model uses time series of "statedependent variables" (on a one-second resolution) to probabilistically assign each time point per participant to one of a fixed number of latent behavioral states. Participants can be in three different states: individual exploration, social relocation and exploitation[77]. Since exploitation is observed, our only hidden states are individual exploration and social relocation and the model estimates parameters of the distributions that characterize both states. Additionally, our Social Hidden Markov Decision Model simultaneously infers the transition 855</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>885</head><label></label><figDesc>tom four rows): (1) a binary visibility indicator (V = 1 if any exploiting player is currently in field of view, V = 0 otherwise), (2) the (z-standardized) distance to the closest visible exploiting player D, (3) the number of other players extracting at the closest visible patch N (coded such that N = 0 890</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>905</head><label></label><figDesc>mating time-varying parameters through ordered categorical (monotonic) effects and describe how social decision-making dynamics unfold over time. As one example (other state predictors are constructed equivalently), the effect of patch distance on the probability to switch to social relocation in a spe-910 cific minute of a roundt is composed of the total effect of time times the sum of δ-parameters which represent the additional effect of each increment in time:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Accessed: 2023-05-03 60. Ötting M, Langrock R, Deutscher C, Leos-Barajas V, 2020 The hot hand in professional darts. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society Series A: Statistics in Society 183, 565-580 61. Strandburg-Peshkin A, Farine DR, Couzin ID, Crofoot MC, 2015 Shared decision-making drives collective movement in wild baboons. Science 348, 1358-1361 62. Strandburg-Peshkin A, Papageorgiou D, Crofoot MC, Farine DR, 2018 Inferring influence and leadership in moving animal groups. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences 373, 20170006 63. Pacheco-Cobos L, Winterhalder B, Cuatianquiz-Lima C, Rosetti MF, Hudson R, Ross CT, 2019 Nahua mushroom gatherers use area-restricted search strategies that conform to marginal value theorem predictions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 116, 10339-10347 64. Wood BM, et al., 2021 Gendered movement ecology and landscape use in hadza hunter-gatherers. Nature Human Behaviour 5, 436-446 65. Ford JD, Tilleard SE, Berrang-Ford L, Araos M, Biesbroek R, Lesnikowski AC, MacDonald GK, Hsu A, Chen C, Bizikova L, 2016 Big data has big potential for applications to climate change adaptation. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 113, 10729-10732 66. Szocska M, et al., 2021 Countrywide population movement monitoring using mobile devices generated (big) data during the covid-19 crisis. Scientific Reports 11, 5943 67. Kays R, Crofoot MC, Jetz W, Wikelski M, 2015 Terrestrial animal tracking as an eye on life and planet. Science 348, aaa2478 68. Kays R, et al., 2022 The movebank system for studying global animal movement and demography. Methods in Ecology and Evolution 13, 419-431 69. Nathan R, et al., 2022 Big-data approaches lead to an increased understanding of the ecology of animal movement. Science 375, eabg1780 70. Henrich J, Heine SJ, Norenzayan A, 2010 Most people are not weird. Nature 466, 29-29</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>) but joined more patches discovered by oth-</cell></row><row><cell>ers (group incentives: 1.4 [0.7,2], ER &gt; 100; individual</cell></row><row><cell>incentives: 1.1 [0.4,1.8], ER &gt; 100; Supplementary Ta-</cell></row><row><cell>ble 4). Participants also stayed closer to group members</cell></row><row><cell>(average distance to the other three players when focal</cell></row><row><cell>player was not exploiting; group incentives: -6.4 [-7.6, -</cell></row><row><cell>5.3], ER &gt; 100; individual incentives: -8.8 [-10.1, -7.6],</cell></row><row><cell>ER &gt; 100; Supplementary Table 5) and looked more</cell></row><row><cell>at others (average number of players in field of view</cell></row><row><cell>when focal player was not exploiting; group incentives:</cell></row><row><cell>0.08 [0.05,0.1], ER &gt; 100; individual incentives: 0.14</cell></row><row><cell>[0.11,0.17], ER &gt; 100; see Supplementary Fig. 2; Sup-</cell></row><row><cell>plementary</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>0.03 [0.004, 0.06], ER = 26.4)</figDesc><table><row><cell>Avg. P(I−&gt;S) Vis. Patch Dist. Vis. Expl. Players Time since Success</cell><cell>a</cell><cell>Environment Concentrated Distributed 0.2 0.3 Group Incentives 0.1 0.4 −0.6 −0.3 0.0 0.3 0.6 −0.6 −0.3 0.0 0.3 0.6 −0.6 −0.3 0.0 0.3 0.6</cell><cell>0.1 Individual Incentives 0.2 0.3 0.4 dat_baseline$pred[dat_baseline$Environment == 1] 50 100 150 200 dat_baseline$coins[dat_baseline$Environment == 1] 0.59 [0.18,0.98] 0.1 0.25 0.4 Coins b dat_baseline$pred[dat_baseline$Environment == 2] 0.53 [0.08,1.01] Ind. Weights −&gt; Success Incentives Group Individual dat_baseline$coins[dat_baseline$Environment == 2] 0.1 0.25 0.4 −0.6 −0.3 0.0 0.3 0.6 50 100 150 200 dat_dist$pred[dat_dist$Environment == 1] dat_dist$coins[dat_dist$Environment == 1] −0.6 −0.2 0.2 −0.02 [−0.22,0.17] Coins dat_dist$pred[dat_dist$Environment == 2] −0.21 [−0.4,−0.01] dat_dist$coins[dat_dist$Environment == 2] −0.6 −0.2 0.2 −0.6 −0.3 0.0 0.3 0.6 50 100 150 200 dat_numb$pred[dat_numb$Environment == 1] dat_numb$coins[dat_numb$Environment == 1] −0.5 0.0 0.5 0.01 [−0.16,0.19] Coins dat_numb$pred[dat_numb$Environment == 2] 0.06 [−0.3,0.42] dat_numb$coins[dat_numb$Environment == 2] −0.5 0.0 0.5 −0.6 −0.3 0.0 0.3 0.6 50 100 150 200 dat_time$pred[dat_time$Environment == 1] dat_time$coins[dat_time$Environment == 1] −0.3 0 0.3 Coins 0.1 [−0.8,0.98] dat_time$pred[dat_time$Environment == 2] dat_time$coins[dat_time$Environment == 2] −0.3 0 0.3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>290</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>and individual (0.05 [0.02, 0.08], ER &gt; 100) incentives</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(Fig. 3a, first row). Moreover, individual incentives re-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>liably increased participants' propensity to use social</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>information in concentrated (0.04 [0.002, 0.07], ER =</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>21.7) but less so in distributed (0.01 [-0.01, 0.04], ER =</cell></row></table><note>295 5.8) environments. Thus, participants were more likely to switch to social relocation when prioritizing their in- dividual success, particularly in concentrated environ- ments where scrounging is beneficial, uncovering the0.25 [−0.18,0.66]</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>R ≤ 1.01. All inferences are based on several hundred effective samples from the 1000 posterior<ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[86]</ref>. Finally, we repeated our main behavioral analyses using frequentist methods and fitted generalized linear mixed models through lme4 version 1.1-34. See GitHub repository for full model code and analysis scripts: https://github.com/DominikDeffner/VirtualCollectiveForaging.48. Bidari S, ElHady A, Davidson JD, Kilpatrick ZP, 2022 Stochastic dynamics of social patch foraging decisions. Physical review research 4, 033128 49. Brunswik E, 1955 Representative design and probabilistic theory in a functional psychology. Psychological Review 62, 193-217. 50. Fawcett TW, Fallenstein B, Higginson AD, Houston AI, Mallpress DE, Trimmer PC, McNamara JM, 2014 The evolution of decision rules in complex environments. Trends in Cognitive Sciences 18, 153-161. 51. Kihlstrom JF, 2021 Ecological validity and "ecological validity". Perspectives on Psychological Science 16, 466-471 52. Adjerid I, Kelley K, 2018 Big data in psychology: A framework for research advancement. American Psychologist 73, 899 53. Couzin ID, Heins C, 2022 Emerging technologies for behavioral research in changing environments. Trends in Ecology &amp; Evolution 54. Garg K, Kello CT, 2021 Efficient lévy walks in virtual human foraging. Scientific reports 11, 1-12 55. Spiers HJ, Coutrot A, Hornberger M, 2023 Explaining worldwide variation in navigation ability from millions of people: citizen science project sea hero quest. Topics in cognitive science 15, 120-138 56. Moussaïd M, Perozo N, Garnier S, Helbing D, Theraulaz G, 2010 The walking behaviour of pedestrian social groups and its impact on crowd dynamics. PloS one 5, e10047 57. Moussaïd M, Helbing D, Theraulaz G, 2011 How simple rules determine pedestrian behavior and crowd disasters. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 108, 6884-6888 58. Keshri S, Oh Mh, Zhang S, Iyengar G, 2019 Automatic event detection in basketball using hmm with energy based defensive assignment. Journal of Quantitative Analysis in Sports 15, 141-153 59. Ali I, 2019.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Jann Wäscher for recruiting participants, Philip Jakob for technical support, and Pietro Nickl for helping with <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. This research has been supported by the Deutsche</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Availability</head><p>The full experimental data are available on GitHub: https://github.com/DominikDeffner/VirtualCollectiveForaging, and have been archived within the Zenodo repository: https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10650332 <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[87]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Code Availability</head><p>All relevant analysis code, the Unity source code as well as built executives necessary to reproduce and run the experiment are stored on GitHub: https://github.com/DominikDeffner/VirtualCollectiveForaging,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1015</head><p>and have been archived within the Zenodo repository: https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10650332. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contributions statement</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing interests</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A cognitive computational approach to social and collective decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Galesic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Royal Society Interface</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17456916231186964</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Perspectives on Psychological Science</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Romanczuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cracco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Arlidge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nassauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1025" />
			<pubPlace>Brass</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective rule-breaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1082" to="1095" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Group coordination catalyzes individual and cultural intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<publisher>PsyArXiv</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Potential disad-1030 vantages of using socially acquired information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Giraldeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Valone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Templeton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">357</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1559" to="1566" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Does biology constrain culture? American Anthropologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="819" to="831" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social learning strategies: Bridge-building between fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Kendal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Boogert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Rendell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Laland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Webster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="651" to="665" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social learning strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Laland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Learning &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolution of learning strategies in temporally and spatially variable environments: a review of theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Aoki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theoretical population biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social foraging theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Giraldeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Caraco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The cultural transmission of great basin projectile-point technology i: an experimental simulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mesoudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>O'brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Antiquity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An experimental simulation of the &quot;copysuccessful-individuals&quot; cultural learning strategy: Adaptive 1050 landscapes, producer-scrounger dynamics, and informational access costs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mesoudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolution and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="350" to="363" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Flexible learning, rather than inveterate innovation or copying, drives cumulative knowledge gain. Science advances 6, eaaz0286 1055 14</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Miu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Gulley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Laland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Rendell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcelreath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lubell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Richerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Waring</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Baum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Edsten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Efferson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Paciotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolution and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="483" to="508" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Applying evolutionary models to the laboratory study of social learning</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic social learn-1060 ing in temporally and spatially variable environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kleinow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcelreath</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Royal Society open science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social learning strategies regulate the wisdom and madness of interactive crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Toyokawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Whalen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Laland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Conformist social learning leads to self-organised prevention against adverse bias in risky decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Toyokawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gaissmaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">75308</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual sensory networks and effective information transfer in animal groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Witt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Toyokawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gaissmaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strandburg-Peshkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="709" to="711" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PsyArXiv</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Visual-spatial dynamics drive adaptive social learning in 1075 immersive environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Flocking in complex environments-attention trade-offs in collective information processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rahmani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Peruani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Romanczuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1007697</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of collective behavior 1080 based purely on vision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bastien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Romanczuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">792</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chapman CA, 1991 Producers, scroungers, and group foraging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Vickery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Giraldeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Templeton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Kramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The american naturalist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="847" to="863" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Geometry for a selfish 1085 foraging group: a genetic algorithm approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Barta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Giraldeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">264</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1233" to="1238" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A spatial model of producing and scrounging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Beauchamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1935" to="1942" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of exploration on the use of producer-scrounger tactics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hamblin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Giraldeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">49400</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Visual social information use in collective foraging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mezey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rhjm</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Romanczuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="page">1095</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When does selection favor learning from the old? social learning in age-structured populations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcelreath</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">267204</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Preregistration: Social information use in virtual collective foraging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.17605/OSF.IO/5R736</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/11005R736" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An introduction to animal movement modeling with hidden markov models using stan for bayesian inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Leos-Barajas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Michelot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1806.10639</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A guide to state-space modeling of 1105 ecological time series</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Auger-Méthé</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ecological Monographs</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1470</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the american statistical association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="795" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generative inference for cultural evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kandler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Powell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Bio-1110 logical Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">373</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Foraging cognition: reviving the ecological intelligence hypothesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rosati</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="702" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of human life history evolution: Diet, intelligence, and longevity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lancaster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hurtado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolutionary Anthropology: Issues, News, and Reviews: Issues, News, and Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="1115" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The evolution of cultural evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Henrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcelreath</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolutionary Anthropology: Issues, News, and Reviews: Issues, News, and Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The secret of our success: How culture is driving human evolution, domesticating our species, and making us smarter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Henrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to explain the unusually late age at skill competence among humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Schuppli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Isler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Van Schaik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal 1125 of human evolution</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="843" to="850" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference of ecological and social drivers of human brain-size evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>González-Forero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">557</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="554" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Monk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Barbier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Romanczuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Alós</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">1130</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nakayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Rubenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Arlinghaus R</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How ecology shapes exploitation: a framework to predict the behavioural response of human and animal foragers along exploration-exploitation trade-offs</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ecology letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="779" to="793" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual exploration 1135 and selective social learning: Balancing exploration-exploitation trade-offs in collective foraging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Garg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Smaldino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of The Royal Society Interface</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information cascades: Replication and an extension to majority rule and conformity-rewarding institu-1140 tions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Plott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1508" to="1520" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bazazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Von Zimmermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-serving incentives impair collective decisions by increasing conformity</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">224725</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The spatial dynamics of predators 1145 and the benefits and costs of sharing information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Barbier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1005147</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signalling and the evolution of cooperative foraging in dynamic environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Torney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Berdahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Couzin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1002194</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emergent sensing of complex environments by mobile animal groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Berdahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Torney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ioannou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Faria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Couzin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">339</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="574" to="576" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Berdahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pentland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Krafft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2212.00869</idno>
		<title level="m">Flexible social inference facilitates 1155 targeted social learning when rewards are not observable</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A causal framework for cross-cultural generalizability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rohrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcelreath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://docs.unity3d.com/2020.3/Documentation/Manual/index.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Methods and 1230 Practices in Psychological Science 5, 25152459221106366 72. Unity Technologies, 2021. Unity user manual</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2023" to="2028" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">McElreath R, 2020 Statistical rethinking: A Bayesian course with examples in R and Stan</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CRC press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mcclintock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Langrock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Gimenez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cam</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Borchers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">1240</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncovering ecological state dynamics with hidden markov models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Glennie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Patterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ecology letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1878" to="1903" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Foraging success under uncertainty: search tradeoffs and optimal space use</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bishop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Nasrabadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bartumeus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Campos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ryu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lloret-Cabot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Méndez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Catalan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Pattern recognition and machine learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1299" to="1313" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Hidden Markov models for time series: an introduction using R</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zucchini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Langrock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>CRC press 1250</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The viterbi algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Forney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the IEEE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="268" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Circular statistics in R</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pewsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Neuhäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Ruxton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stan: A probabilistic programming language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Be-1255 Tancourt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brubaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Riddell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of statistical soft</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">76</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">cmdstanr: R interface to&apos;cmdstan&apos;. See mc-stan. org/cmdstanr/reference/cmdstanr-package. html 1260 83</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gabry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R ;</forename><surname>Češnovar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lewandowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kurowicka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Joe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of multivariate analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Generating random correlation matrices based on vines and extended onion method</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rank-normalization, folding, and localization: An im-1265 provedR for assessing convergence of mcmc</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bürkner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1903.08008</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference from iterative simulation using multiple sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistical Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="472" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Carlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Dunson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Rubin 1270 DB</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Data for: Collective incentives reduce over-exploitation of social information in unconstrained human groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mezey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schakowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Romanczuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rhjm</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5281/zenodo.10650332</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5281/1275zenodo.10650332" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Research Foundation) under Germany&apos;s Excellence Strategy -EXC 2002/1 &quot;Science of Intelligence&quot; -project number 390523135. CMW is supported by the German Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF): Tübingen AI Center, FKZ: 1285 01IS18039A and funded by the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG, German Research Foundation) under Germany&apos;s Excellence Strategy-EXC2064/1-390727645. The funders had no role in study design, data collection and analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">(</forename><surname>Forschungsgemeinschaft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">German</forename><surname>Dfg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>decision to publish, or preparation of the manuscript</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
