<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Enforcement Policies: Inspection Frequency vs. Punishment Severity</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kinneret</forename><surname>Teodorescu¹</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">¹Technion -Israel Institute of Technology ² Interdisciplinary Center (IDC)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Herzliya</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ori</forename><surname>Plonsky¹</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">¹Technion -Israel Institute of Technology ² Interdisciplinary Center (IDC)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Herzliya</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shahar</forename><surname>Ayal²</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">¹Technion -Israel Institute of Technology ² Interdisciplinary Center (IDC)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Herzliya</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Barkan³</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">¹Technion -Israel Institute of Technology ² Interdisciplinary Center (IDC)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Herzliya</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">³</forename><surname>Ben-Gurion</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">¹Technion -Israel Institute of Technology ² Interdisciplinary Center (IDC)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Herzliya</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Enforcement Policies: Inspection Frequency vs. Punishment Severity</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:36+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Behavioral ethics</term>
					<term>enforcement</term>
					<term>decisions from experience</term>
					<term>behavioral economics</term>
					<term>policy making</term>
					<term>cheating</term>
					<term>learning Enforcement Policies: Inspection Frequency vs. Punishment Severity</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>External enforcement policies aimed to reduce violations differ on two key components: the probability of inspection and the severity of punishments. Different lines of research offer competing predictions regarding the relative importance of each component. In three incentive compatible studies, students and Prolific crowdsourcing participants (Ntotal=430) repeatedly faced temptations to commit violations under two enforcement policies. Controlling for expected value, the results indicated that a policy combining High probability of Inspection with Low Severity of fine (HILS) was more effective than a policy combining Low probability of Inspection with High Severity of fine (LIHS). Consistent with the prediction of Decisions from Experience research, this finding held even when the severity of the fine was stated in advance to boost deterrence. In addition, the advantage of HILS over LIHS was greater as participants&apos; baseline rate of violation (without enforcement) was higher, implying that HILS is more effective among frequent offenders.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Enforcement policies: Frequency of inspection is more important than the severity of punishment Texting while driving, jaywalking, littering, not wearing facemasks and neglecting to keep social distancing during the Covid-19 pandemic are but a few examples of seemingly negligible violations that accumulate fast, with potentially dire social consequences. The prevalence of these violations highlights the shortcomings of reasoning with, or appealing to, people's civic duty, and point to the need for regulation and enforcement. External enforcement is composed of the probability of inspection and the severity of the punishment delivered upon detection <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Becker, 1968)</ref>. Clearly, the combination of complete monitoring and severe punishments is the fastest way to shape behavior. However, due to the limited resources devolved to monitoring, and the negative consequences of severe punishment (e.g., reactance), policy makers usually resort to two main compensatory strategies. One solution opts for less frequent inspection but greater severity of punishment and counts on its potential for deterrence. The other solution opts for close monitoring, and assumes that when the inspection rate is high, minimal or even symbolic punishment will suffice. The current paper examined the effectiveness of these two enforcement strategies in reducing violations.</p><p>Several theoretical perspectives are relevant here. The economic perspective views people as rational agents, whose actions are governed by cost-benefit analysis. Accordingly, people will commit violations if their expected utility (accounting for potential gains and losses) is positive <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Becker, 1968)</ref>. Under the additional assumption that most people are not risk-seeking, Becker's model predicts that people will be more sensitive to the severity of punishment than to the probability of detection. Several studies in experimental economics support this notion (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Anderson &amp; Stafford, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Block &amp; Gerety, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Engel &amp; Nagin, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Friesen, 2012)</ref>. The economic perspective therefore implies that delivering severe punishments, even rarely, is the most effective enforcement strategy.</p><p>A psychological perspective pits the external gain associated with violations against the internal cost of damage to one's self-perception (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Shalvi et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abeler et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Self-maintenance theory <ref type="bibr">(Mazal et al., 2008)</ref> suggests that aiming to perceive oneself as highly moral creates a barrier to acts of violation. Specific mechanisms allow people to engage in some wrongdoing but at the same time keep their sense of morality intact <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Ayal &amp; Gino, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Barkan et al., 2015)</ref>. Supporting this notion, findings in behavioral ethics indicate that although participants commit violations, they do so to a limited extent rather than to the maximum possible (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Gino et al., 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gino et al., , 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gneezy et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Mazar et al., 2008)</ref>. This self-curbing tendency has frequently been documented in common experimental tasks that eliminate detection and fines <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Gerlach et al., 2019)</ref>. Certain findings show that violation rates are generally insensitive to external settings, and remain relatively stable regardless of significant changes in the potential profit (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Fischbacher, &amp; Föllmi-Heusi, 2013)</ref> or in the chances of being caught <ref type="bibr">(Mazar et al., 2008)</ref>. If people are indifferent to external settings as implied by self-maintenance theory, the effectiveness of either enforcement strategy should be similar and limited.</p><p>Findings in the field of behavioral ethics typically rely on a single, or a short sequence of choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Gerlach et al., 2019)</ref> and generally do not address the long-term effects of external enforcement. Extending experimental tasks to repeated settings, introduces learning as a third perspective to consider. Research on repeated decisions from experience indicates that choice behavior is more sensitive to the frequency of experienced outcomes than to their magnitude (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Teodorescu &amp; Erev, 2014 a&amp;b)</ref>. This line of research shows that when people learn from experience, they tend to behave as though they underweight small probability outcomes (e.g. <ref type="bibr">Barkan et al., 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr">Hertwig et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr">Camilleri &amp; Newell, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Teodorescu et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Plonsky &amp; Teodorescu, 2020)</ref>. Altogether, these findings hint that infrequent large fines may not have the intended outcome, and suggest instead that frequent small fines should be more effective at decreasing violations.</p><p>This implies three competing hypotheses with respect to the effectiveness of the two enforcement strategies: H1 -Economic perspective: Rare large fines should be more effective than frequent small fines in deterring violations. H2 -Self maintenance theory: Both rare large fines and frequent small fines should have a similar and limited impact on the deterrence of violations.</p><p>H3 -Decisions from experience: Frequent small fines should be more effective than rare large fines at deterring violations.</p><p>In three studies, we tested these competing hypotheses by assessing which enforcement strategy is more effective in settings where people can repeatedly engage in small violations. We utilized the dots task (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Gino et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Hochman et al., 2016)</ref>, a perceptual task that creates a conflict between accuracy and profit maximization (when incorrect responses yield higher payoffs than correct responses). This task has three advantages. It consists of many trials, thus permitting the examination of violation behavior over time. It allows for incorporation and systematic manipulation of the probability of inspection and the severity of fines, while also controlling for the expected value (EV) of violations. Finally, it constitutes a simplistic simulation of real-life settings where people know enforcement is possible, and can learn the likelihood of being caught from experience <ref type="bibr">(Harel &amp; Segal, 1999)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pilot study</head><p>The pilot study tested the three competing hypotheses by comparing violation rates under two partial enforcement conditions: rare large fines vs. frequent low fines. In both conditions, the EV of violations was identical. Two control conditions administered either no external enforcement or full external enforcement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants. Forty-two undergraduate students from a major university participated in a 1-hour lab study. Payment was contingent on performance (M = 46.0 NIS, SD = 4.0). Each participant played 768 repeated trials, half of which contained a monetary temptation to commit a violation (i.e., overall, we analyzed 32,256 observations).</p><p>Basic task. We utilized the dots task <ref type="bibr">(Gino et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Hochman et al., 2016)</ref> and presented 20 dots distributed unevenly between two adjacent rectangles. On each trial participants were asked to decide whether there are more dots on the right or left rectangle. One side always yielded 1 point (0.01 NIS) whereas selecting the other side always yielded 10 points (0.1 NIS), irrespective of the correct answer. Thus, the payoff rule motivated 'accuracy-violations' such that participants could profit by selecting the more rewarding side on tempting trials where the correct answer is the less rewarding side. The more rewarding side was counterbalanced across participants, and remained the same for each participant throughout the experiment. The experiment consisted of four "games" of 192 trials each. In each game, half of the trials presented more dots on the more rewarding side (non-tempting trials), and half presented more dots on the less rewarding side (tempting trials). Participants played the task continuously. The order of trials in each game was random. Each trial started with a 0.5 sec presentation of a fixation point, followed by a 1 sec dots screen. Next, participants were asked to indicate which side had more dots by clicking on one of two boxes on the screen. Last, a 1 sec. feedback screen presented the trial's payoff.</p><p>On top of this basic incentive structure, we modified the dots task to include conditions with and without inspection of the correctness of the answer. Without inspection, the feedback screen only presented the trial payoff. To signal inspection, the feedback screen turned red and if an incorrect answer was detected, a fine appeared on the screen and was subtracted from the trial's payoff. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> depicts two trials on the modified dots task: one without inspection and one with inspection. Experimental design. The games tested the four enforcement conditions which differed in the rate of inspection and the severity of the punishment. The No-Enforcement (NE) condition corresponded to the original cheating condition on the dots task without inspection and fines. In the Full-Enforcement (FE) condition, each trial was inspected and each incorrect answer was fined -18 points. In the two partial enforcement conditions the inspection rate and punishment severity varied. In the High-Inspection-Low-Severity (HILS) condition, 90% of the trials were inspected and each detected violation was fined -10 points. In the Low-Inspection-High-Severity (LIHS) condition, only 10% of the trials were inspected, but each detected violation was fined -90 points. Therefore, the EV for an accuracy violation was identical in the two partial enforcement conditions. In addition, within each of the two partial enforcement conditions, the EV of an accuracy violation was identical to the fixed payoff that resulted from reporting the correct answer. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> summarizes the experimental conditions. Utilizing a complete within-subject design participants engaged in all the conditions (i.e., 4 "games" presented in random order(. Procedure. Participants read the instructions, signed a consent form and engaged in the dots task. The participants were informed that inspection could occur, and that in case of inspection the feedback screen would turn red and that detection of an incorrect answer would be fined. However, we did not specify the enforcement policy; thus, participants had to infer the probability of inspection and the severity of punishment (i.e. the fine) based on their experience in each game. Participants were informed when one game was over and a new one began, and that in each game the possibility of inspection as well as the severity of the punishment could be different.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The rate of accuracy violations was calculated as the difference between the proportions of 'beneficial errors' (i.e., selection of the incorrect but more rewarding side) and 'detrimental errors' (i.e., selection of the incorrect but less rewarding side) <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Hochman et al., 2016)</ref>. The mean rate of accuracy violations was the highest without enforcement (47.5% in NE condition) and the lowest with full enforcement (3.0% in FE condition). This suggests that accuracy violations were mostly intended, and favored profit over accuracy. Without enforcement, participants tended, on average, to violate accuracy for profit on just under half of the tempting trials. Note that only half of the trials were tempting. Thus, the accuracy-violation rate was below 25% and far below the maximum rate of 50%, thus leaving room for moral justification, as suggested by selfmaintenance theory.</p><p>Not surprisingly, the two partial enforcement conditions were less effective in reducing violations than full enforcement. Importantly however, a clear advantage emerged for probability of inspection over severity of punishment (despite the control for expected values). Consistent with the decisions from experience hypothesis (H3), the rate of accuracy violations was low when the enforcement rule prioritized probability, and significantly higher when the enforcement rule prioritized severe punishment (8.53% vs. 27.69% in the HILS and LIHS conditions respectively t(41) = 5.9, p &lt; 0.001).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Main studies</head><p>The main studies compared the two partial enforcement policies directly in a betweensubject design. Due to COVID-19 restrictions, these studies were run online 1 . To increase power and reduce noise, we increased the number of tempting trials. In each study, participants engaged in two games. They first completed the original dots task without enforcement and then repeated the task under either the HILS or LIHS enforcement conditions. This design served to (1) measure the effectiveness of each enforcement policy in reducing accuracy violations, and (2) categorize participants according to their baseline tendencies without enforcement. Several studies that have examined individual differences suggest that certain people react to incentives to lie, whereas others do not (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gneezy et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Hilbig &amp; Zettler, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kajackaite &amp; Gneezy, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Feldman, 2018)</ref>. Establishing individuals' baseline thus made it possible to identify participants who rarely misreport, even without enforcement, and therefore examine the effectiveness of partial enforcement on those participants for whom enforcement mattered. The pre-registered hypotheses were: (1) HILS enforcement will reduce violations more than LIHS (in line with H3 and the pilot results) and (2), this effect will be most pronounced in participants with high baseline violation rates. Experimental Task. We employed the dots task from the pilot study, with several changes aimed to increase power and make accuracy violations at baseline more tempting so as to avoid a floor effect. First, we replaced the vertical line with a diagonal, and always presented 17 vs. 13 dots on each side on each trial (the location of the dots within each triangle was random, thus naturally creating varied difficulty levels but with reduced variance). Second, we increased the temptation for accuracy violations slightly: the payoff still rewarded a response to one side regardless of accuracy (10 points), but we omitted the reward for the alternative response (0 points). Third, to obtain more data points, each game now had 120 trials, out of which 80 trials were tempting (the incorrect answer was rewarding) and 40 trials were non-tempting (the correct answer was rewarding). Last, we adjusted the inspection to include green and red screens rather than only red. Specifically, under inspection, if the answer was incorrect, the feedback screen turned red (and a fine was subtracted from the trial payoff), but if the answer was correct, the inspection screen turned green. This differed from the pilot study where all inspected trials turned red, for both the correct and incorrect answers.</p><p>Experimental design. All participants started with a "No-Enforcement" (NE) game and were then randomly assigned to either the HILS or the LIHS condition. The High Inspection Low Severity (HILS) condition had a .90 probability of inspection and a fine of -11 points. The Low Inspection High Severity (LIHS) condition had a .10 probability of inspection and a fine of -99 points. We adjusted the fines to keep the Expected Value (EV) of accuracy violation on the tempting trials identical in the two conditions (i.e., EV=0.1, which is slightly larger than the zero points obtained from reporting the correct answer).</p><p>Procedure. Participants signed a consent form, read the instructions and then played two games. All the participants started with a "No-Enforcement" (NE) game. Next, the possibility of enforcement was explicitly introduced and participants played a second game according to the experimental condition. As in the pilot study, we informed participants that inspection is possible but did not specify the probability of inspection or the amount of the fine, which they had to infer through experience. Upon completion, we asked participants to guess the goal of the study, and whether they would have acted differently if they had to do the task again. Participants were then notified about their bonus payment and received their task-completion code.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analysis.</head><p>As in the pilot study, accuracy-violation rates were calculated as the difference between 'beneficial errors' (percentage of incorrect answers in tempting trials out of all tempting trials) and 'detrimental errors' (percentage of incorrect answers in non-tempting trials out of all non-tempting trials). Given the within-subject aspect of the experimental design, the dependent variable for the main analysis was the difference between accuracy-violation rates in the enforcement and baseline games where a larger difference indicated the greater effectiveness of enforcement (we expected both enforcement conditions to reduce accuracy violations as compared to their respective baselines). Based on the results of the pilot, and consistent with the decisions from experience hypothesis (H3), we expected a larger difference in the HILS enforcement condition and a smaller difference in the LIHS enforcement. Hence, we preregistered a one-sided Welch t-test to examine this main hypothesis and noted that if the Shapiro-Wilk test will have indicated a violation of the assumption of normality, we will use the Mann Whitney U test instead.</p><p>A secondary analysis further investigated the expected effect of enforcement on different types of participants. Using the accuracy-violation baseline rates in the first game (NE), three types of participants were preregistered. Participants whose baseline accuracy-violation rate was in the lowest quartile (Q1) were labelled Low Accuracy-violators. Participants whose baseline accuracy-violation rate was in the highest quartile (Q4) were labelled High Accuracy-violators.</p><p>Participants whose baseline accuracy-violation rate fell in the interquartile range (Q2 &amp; Q3) were labelled Medium Accuracy-violators. We calculated quartiles across all participants (since the baseline game was identical). Consistent with the pre-registration, we regressed the accuracyviolation rates in the second game on the enforcement condition (HILS/ LIHS), the type of participant (Low/Med/High Accuracy-violators), and their interaction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Testing the main hypothesis. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2a presents</ref>  explanation holds, there should be a greater improvement in accuracy between the first and the second block in the HILS condition compared to the LIHS condition. There was no evidence for this. Surprisingly, a Welch two sample t-test for the non-tempting trials revealed a significant difference between the two groups but in the opposite direction (M = 0.9%, SD = 6.0 vs. M = −2.4%, SD = 6.0 in the LIHS and HILS conditions respectively), t(173.5) = -2.87, p = .005. These results rule out the alternative explanation of simple feedback improvement.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">F(1,192)</ref> = 13.8, p &lt; .001, as well as a main effect for type, F(2,192) = 59.8, p &lt; .001. However, the interaction was not significant F(2, 192) = 0.94, p = .39; thus this analysis failed to find significant evidence for the hypothesis that High Accuracy Violators were more likely to be influenced by the enforcement condition.</p><p>The lack of evidence for the secondary hypothesis might reflect the loss of power involved with the categorization that reduced the continuous variable of accuracy-violation rates to a 3level variable. To test this possibility, we conducted a follow-up (unregistered) analysis repeating the regression above, but replacing the 3-level type with the individual accuracy-violation rate scores in the No-Enforcement game. This analysis yielded a significant interaction F(1,194) = 5.79, p = 0.017, b = 0.19, 95% CI [0.03, 0.35], partial f 2 = 0.03. The fitted regression lines for the two conditions <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 2b</ref>) showed that the difference between the two enforcement conditions was more pronounced when the accuracy-violation rates in the No-Enforcement game were higher. Specifically, the simple slopes for the accuracy-violation rates with enforcement on the accuracy-violation rates without enforcement were 0.41, 95% CI [0.31, 0.51] for HILS and 0.60, 95% CI [0.48, 0.72] for LIHS.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>In many real-life situations, the severity of sanctions is known ahead of time. That is, although the probability of inspection is unknown <ref type="bibr">(Harel &amp; Segal, 1999)</ref>, the magnitude of the fine is sometimes public knowledge (e.g., via traditional or social media platforms). Accordingly, arguments in favor of severe sanctions are rather common and usually emphasize the deterrence effect. Moreover, studies in behavioral economics suggest that the presentation of small sanctions might constitute too low a price which could legitimize violations (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Gneezy &amp; Rustichini, 2000)</ref>. Thus, knowing the severity of the punishment in advance might undermine the effectiveness of enforcement that prioritizes probability. Nevertheless, findings from the literature on decisions from experience suggest that repeated on-going experience with feedback quickly eliminates the initial effects of descriptive information (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Jessup et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Teodorescu et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Marchiori et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Erev et al., 2017)</ref>. We therefore hypothesized that the observed advantage of prioritizing probability (HILS) over severity of punishment (LIHS) would hold even with a-priori information about the magnitude of the fine.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Participants. 196 participants who did not participate in the previous study were recruited via the crowdsourcing platform Prolific to complete this follow-up study. They were paid £1.45 for participating and were given a bonus contingent on their accumulative points gained during the experiment (M = £1.02, SD = 0.29). Four participants were excluded based on the exclusion criterion of 35% 'detrimental errors' or more, resulting in 94 vs. 98 participants in the HILS and LIHS conditions respectively.</p><p>Task and procedure. We used the same task, design, and procedure with one exception:</p><p>the addition of information about the size of the fine (the probability of inspection remained unspecified). Participants now expected fines of -11 or -99 points in the HILS and LIHS conditions respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Testing the main hypothesis. The findings replicated the results of Study 1, although the effects were smaller. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3a</ref> presents the main result. In the HILS condition, the mean accuracy-violation rate decreased by 21.8% (SD = 28.6; from 35.4% in the No-Enforcement game to 13.6% in the with-enforcement game). In the LIHS condition, the accuracy-violation rates decreased by 14.5% (SD = 24.0; from 36.9% in the No-Enforcement game to 22.3% in the withenforcement game). Again, the Shapiro-Wilk test rejected the assumption of normality for the accuracy-violation rates (p &lt; .001). A Mann-Whitney U-test indicated that the reduction of accuracy-violation rates in the HILS condition (mdn = 18.1%, range <ref type="bibr">[-34, 109]</ref>) was greater than in the LIHS condition (mdn = 10%, range <ref type="bibr">[-29, 86]</ref>), U = 5291, p = .038, one-tailed test, effect size r = 0.128. This finding thus further supports our hypothesis that even when the severity of the fine is provided explicitly as means of deterrence, enforcement with a high probability of inspection and low fines is still more effective in reducing violation behavior than enforcement with severe fines but a low probability of inspection. Again, we found no evidence that the frequent inspections caused participants in the HILS condition to make fewer innocent mistakes than in the LIHS condition. A Welch two sample t-test revealed no difference between the two groups (M = 1.8%, SD = 7.2 vs. M = 1.3%, SD = 9.3 in the HILS and LIHS conditions respectively), t(182.5) = -0.36, p = 0.72. Thus, the increased effectivity of the HILS over the LIHS enforcement could not be attributed to feedback improving perceptual accuracy.</p><p>Testing the secondary hypothesis. A regression analysis using the continuous accuracyviolation rates in the No-Enforcement game indicated that the difference between the two enforcement conditions was more pronounced when the accuracy-violation rates in the No-Enforcement game were higher <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3b</ref>). The interaction with condition was significant, </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">F</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>What is the best way to reduce violations? The high cost of close monitoring and severe sanctions (e.g. more officers, negative mass reactance) render full enforcement impractical.</p><p>Instead, two common enforcement policies trade off the probability of inspection with the severity of punishment. Our findings suggest that in repeated settings, people are more sensitive to the probability of inspection than to the severity of the fine. In all three studies, the High Inspection Low Severity (HILS) policy was more effective at reducing violation rates than the Low Inspection High Severity (LIHS) policy, despite the equal EV. This finding was independent of potential improvement in perceptual skill, and held even when we increased deterrence by providing information about the magnitude of the fine in advance. Furthermore, the advantage of the HILS policy was more pronounced among participants who tended to commit more violations at baseline.</p><p>These findings are consistent with the decisions from experience hypothesis and specifically with the phenomenon of underweighting of rare events (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Newell &amp; Rakow, 2007)</ref>. According to this phenomenon, in repeated settings, rare severe punishments are underweighted, causing deterrence to lose its initial effect. Underweighting of rare events is often argued to be the outcome of a decision mechanism that relies on inference derived from small samples of past experiences (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Plonsky et al., 2015)</ref>. On each trial, decision makers only consider a small sample of previous experiences with each of the options, and choose the option with the higher sample mean. Since small samples usually include frequent outcomes and rare outcomes are under-represented, repeated choices are driven by the more frequent outcomes. In the current context, this mechanism explains why committing violations was more attractive when violations were rewarded most of the time (in LIHS) and less attractive when violations incurred a fine most of the time (in HILS). Interestingly, our findings are also consistent with empirical studies showing that crime rates are more strongly correlated with enforcement prevalence than with criminal sanctions <ref type="bibr">(Chalfin &amp; McCrary, 2017)</ref>. Our controlled experimental setting suggests a causal link between enforcement prevalence and violation rates for a general (non-criminal) population.</p><p>Our results run counter to the economic hypothesis, which posits that severe punishments are more effective than high monitoring in reducing violations in the general population <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Becker, 1968;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Anderson &amp; Stafford, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Block &amp; Gerety, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Friesen, 2012)</ref>. One plausible reason for this discrepancy is that experimental studies supporting the economic prediction tend to employ an explicit descriptive setting with very few opportunities for violation. The current studies employed an arguably more ecologically valid setting, where implicit opportunities to violate were repeated and the probability of inspection was not described a-priori. Hence, the difference could be the result of a description-experience gap in decisions to violate rules, similar to the gap found in risky choice <ref type="bibr">(Hertwig &amp; Erev, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>Our main result also diverges from the moral-self maintenance hypothesis, which emphasizes internal costs and implies that external enforcement has limited effectiveness.</p><p>Previous findings showing the insensitivity to the probability of getting caught (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Mazar et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Gamliel &amp; Peer, 2013)</ref> could be attributed to the focus on short-term effects. The current findings reveal a strong sensitivity to the external probability of getting caught and thus demonstrate the importance of investigating long-term learning effects in behavioral ethics.</p><p>However, the observation that under no external enforcement, most of the participants did not maximize profits is consistent with the suggested role of internal cost as a gatekeeper of morality.</p><p>From a practical standpoint, our findings suggest that policy-makers should prioritize high inspection rate over severe punishment. While increasing the magnitude of fines is often perceived as less costly <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Becker, 1968)</ref>, large fines could result in a perception of unfairness and consequently reduce the probability of detection <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Feess et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Polinsky &amp; Shavell, 2000)</ref>, which according to our results, is the key ingredient. Thus, while many regulators in the current Covid-19 pandemic have publicly called to increase the magnitude of fines, our findings clearly suggest that "gentle rule enforcement" that includes small punishments with high probability <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Erev et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Schurr et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Erev et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Roth et al., 2020)</ref> would be more effective in reducing violation rates, especially for high offenders, the target population of any enforcement policy.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Timeline example of two trials: the first trial without inspection and the second with inspection under an enforcement policy with severe punishment (fine= -90 points).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results of Study 1. Small dots depict individual participants. (a) Decrease in accuracyviolation rates from baseline to the enforcement block by condition. Error bars represent 95% bootstrapped CI for the mean. (b) Regression lines of the accuracy-violation rates in theenforcement blocks on the accuracy-violation rates in the No-Enforcement block, by condition. Shading around the lines are the 95% CIs.Testing the secondary hypothesis. As pre-registered, we categorized participants into three types according to their baseline accuracy-violation rates in the No-Enforcement baseline game. Low Accuracy-violators (Q1) were those with accuracy-violation rates below 12.5% at baseline, High Accuracy-violators (Q4) had accuracy-violation rates above 43.8% at baseline, and Medium Accuracy-violators (Q2 &amp; Q3) were those with accuracy-violation rates in between (12.5-43.8%). The three baseline types were consistently reflected in the second enforcement game. Specifically, the Low Accuracy-violators and the High Accuracy-violators consistently exhibited the lowest and the highest accuracy-violation rates respectively in the second game with enforcement. Importantly, all three types consistently manifested lower accuracy-violation rates when enforcement prioritized probability (HILS) compared to the accuracy-violation rates when enforcement prioritized severity of punishment (LIHS). The regression analysis indicated a main effect for condition,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Results of Study 2. Small dots depict individual participants. (a) Decrease in accuracyviolation rates from baseline to the enforcement block by condition. Error bars represent the 95% bootstrapped CI for the mean. (b) Regression lines of the accuracy-violation rates in the enforcement blocks on the accuracy-violation rates in the No-Enforcement block, by condition. Shading around the lines are the 95% CIs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Experimental conditions in the pilot study (EV=Expected Value).</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>EV (incorrect)*</cell></row><row><cell>Condition</cell><cell>P(inspection)</cell><cell>Fine</cell><cell>when reporting the incorrect</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>answer is tempting</cell></row><row><cell>No Enforcement (NE)</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>10</cell></row><row><cell>Low Inspection</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>High Severity</cell><cell>0.1</cell><cell>90</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>(LIHS)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>High Inspection</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Low Severity</cell><cell>0.9</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>(HILS)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Full Enforcement (FE)</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>18</cell><cell>-8</cell></row></table><note>* Compared with EV(correct)=1 for tempting trials in all conditions.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>MethodParticipants. 202 participants were recruited via the crowdsourcing platform Prolific to the study, which lasted about 17 minutes. Participants received a show-up payment of £1.45 and a bonus based on the number of points they earned during the task (M = £1, SD = 0.29). The number of participants was determined a-priori according to a power analysis based on a preliminary study (available in the supplemental material). The pre-registration (available at</figDesc><table><row><cell>Study 1</cell></row><row><cell>https://aspredicted.org/blind.php?x=4ux6ja) states: "The effect size d for the main effect between</cell></row><row><cell>groups in a pilot experiment was 0.395. With this effect size, and for 85% power and alpha of</cell></row><row><cell>0.05, we require at least 94 participants in each group, after exclusions. We will hence start with</cell></row></table><note>100 participants in each group, exclude any participants as necessary, and will complement the sample size to 94 in each group if necessary." We pre-registered an exclusion criterion, omitting participants who made more than 35% detrimental errors in the baseline no-enforcement game from the analysis. Six participants were excluded based on this criterion. The final sample was composed of 196 participants (104 in HILS, 94 in LIHS).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the main finding. On average, accuracyviolation rates decreased by 23.3% under the HILS enforcement that prioritized probability (SD = 25.7; from 33.6% in the No-Enforcement game to 12.2% in the with-enforcement game). In contrast, accuracy-violation rates decreased by only 10.3% under the LIHS enforcement that prioritized punishment severity (SD = 21.1; from 32.6% in the No-Enforcement game to 22.4%).</figDesc><table><row><cell>Because a Shapiro-Wilk test rejected the assumption of normality for the accuracy-violation rates</cell></row><row><cell>(p &lt; .001), and consistent with our pre-registration plan, we used a Mann-Whitney U-test to test</cell></row><row><cell>our hypothesis. Supporting our hypothesis (H3), the test indicated that compared to baseline the</cell></row><row><cell>reduction in accuracy-violation rates in the HILS condition (mdn = 15%, range [-18, 133]) was</cell></row><row><cell>greater than in the LIHS condition (mdn = 7.5%, range [-25, 90]), U = 6304, p &lt; .001, one-tailed</cell></row><row><cell>test, effect size r = 0.25.</cell></row></table><note>One possible concern was that the inspection screens could have confounded the experience of enforcement with simple accuracy feedback. That is, frequent inspection (HILS) could have improved participants' perceptual ability, which in turn could have led to fewer accuracy violations in both the tempting and non-tempting trials. To test for this possibility, we examined participants' accuracy in the non-tempting trials. If the feedback improvement</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">The transition to online participants was not straightforward. We ran three online studies to calibrate the online paradigm. The results of these studies are detailed in the supplemental material.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representative evidence on lying costs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Abeler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Falk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="104" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Punishment in a regulatory setting: experimental evidence from the VCM</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stafford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Regulatory Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The social psychology of morality: Exploring the causes of good and evil</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ayal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>M. Mikulincer &amp; P. R. Shaver</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>American Psychological Association</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="166" />
			<pubPlace>Washington, DC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Honest rationales for dishonest behavior</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ethical dissonance, justifications, and moral behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Barkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ayal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="157" to="161" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crime and punishment: An economic approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The economic dimensions of crime</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Palgrave Macmillan</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="68" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some experimental evidence on differences between student and prisoner reactions to monetary penalties and risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Block</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gerety</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Legal Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who is afraid of the stick? Experimentally testing the deterrent effect of sanction certainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nagin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of Behavioral Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="405" to="434" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Continuous punishment and the potential of gentle rule enforcement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ingram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Raz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shany</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioural Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="366" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Complacency, panic, and the value of gentle rule enforcement in addressing pandemics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Plonsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1095" to="1097" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of fine size and uncertainty on punishment and deterrence: Theory and evidence from the laboratory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Feess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schildberg-Hörisch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schramm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wohlschlegel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The law of good people: Challenging states&apos; ability to regulate human behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lies in disguise-an experimental study on cheating</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Fischbacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Föllmi-Heusi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the European Economic Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="525" to="547" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Certainty of punishment versus severity of punishment: An experimental investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Friesen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Southern Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explicit risk of getting caught does not affect unethical behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gamliel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Peer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1281" to="1288" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The truth about lies: A meta-analysis on dishonest behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Gerlach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">145</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-serving altruism? The lure of unethical actions that benefit others</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ayal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of economic behavior &amp; organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conscience accounting: Emotion dynamics and social behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Imas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Madarász</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2645" to="2658" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring lying aversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rockenbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Serra-Garcia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="300" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When the cat&apos;s away, some mice will play: A basic trait account of dishonest behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hilbig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Zettler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="88" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I can see it in your eyes&quot;: Biased Processing and Increased Arousal in Dishonest Responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hochman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fiedler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ayal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="322" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feedback produces divergence from prospect theory in descriptive choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Jessup</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bishara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1015" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incentives and cheating</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kajackaite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games and Economic Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="444" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noisy retrieval models of over-and undersensitivity to rare events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Marchiori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Di Guida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">82</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The fairness of sanctions: some implications for optimal enforcement policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitchell</forename><surname>Polinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shavell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Law and Economics Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="237" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of experience in decisions from description</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Rakow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1133" to="1139" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of biased exposure to forgone outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Plonsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reliance on small samples, the wavy recency effect, and similarity-based learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Plonsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">621</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Value of Alert Systems and Gentle Rule Enforcement in Addressing Pandemics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Plonsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shalev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">577743</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sinning saints and saintly sinners: The paradox of moral self-regulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sachdeva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Iliev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Medin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="523" to="528" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-serving justifications: Doing wrong and feeling moral</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shalvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Barkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ayal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of unpleasant experiences on evaluation and behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schurr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rodensky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the decision to explore new alternatives: The coexistence of under-and over-exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learned helplessness and learned prevalence: Exploring the causal relations among perceived controllability, reward prevalence, and exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1861" to="1869" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
