<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="fr">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">HOC Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université Grenoble Alpes</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>13 rue Hispano Suiza</addrLine>
									<postCode>92270</postCode>
									<settlement>Bois-Colombes</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">UMR CNRS 5525</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">TIMC-IMAG</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>ThEMAS team, Domaine de la Merci, 5 Avenue du Grand Sablon</addrLine>
									<postCode>38700</postCode>
									<settlement>La Tronche</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">AD-HOC Lab</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>13 rue Hispano Suiza</addrLine>
									<postCode>92270</postCode>
									<settlement>Bois-Colombes</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Univ. Grenoble Alpes, CNRS, UMR 5525, VetAgro Sup, Grenoble INP, TIMC</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>France 3 : Laboratoire Parisien de Psychologie Sociale, EA 4386 (équipe PS2C), 200 av. de la République</addrLine>
									<postCode>38000, 92001</postCode>
									<settlement>Grenoble, Nanterre Cedex</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Centre de Recherche sur les Fonctionnements et Dysfonctionnements Psychologiques (CRFDP</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Batiment Satie -Bureau S206</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Rouen Normandy</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>7475)</postCode>
									<region>EA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:40+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>raisonnement clinique</term>
					<term>intolérance à l&apos;incertitude</term>
					<term>validation psychométrique</term>
					<term>prise de décision</term>
					<term>évaluation</term>
					<term>mesure clinical reasoning</term>
					<term>intolerance of uncertainty</term>
					<term>psychometric validation</term>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>evaluation</term>
					<term>measurement</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>La littérature montre que l&apos;intolérance à l&apos;incertitude peut affecter négativement la prise de décision médicale des professionnels de santé. Cependant, il n&apos;existe pas d&apos;outils de mesure de l&apos;intolérance à l&apos;incertitude en français donc nous souhaitions valider l&apos;Intolerance of Uncertainty Scale-12 (IUS-12) en français, ainsi qu&apos;une version de l&apos;IUS-12 adaptée aux professionnels de santé (IUS-12-H). Nous avons demandé à des professionnels de santé de remplir nos deux échelles d&apos;intérêt, ainsi que des échelles connexes. Cinq cent seize professionnels de la santé ont rempli les versions françaises de l&apos;IUS-12 et de l&apos;IUS-12-H, et nos échelles additionnelles. Les analyses factorielles exploratoires ont montré que l&apos;IUS-12 et IUS-12-H avaient une structure à deux facteurs corrélés comme dans l&apos;article séminal de Carleton et al. (2007). Les versions françaises de l&apos;IUS-12 et de l&apos;IUS-11-H présentent des propriétés psychométriques comparables à la version originale, et peuvent donc être utilisées comme échelles de référence pour les professionnels de santé français.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="fr">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Declarations of interest: None.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgment:</head><p>We would like to thank Yannick Perdrix for his proofreading and his pertinent comments which contributed to the quality of this research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Availability Statement:</head><p>The data that support the findings of this study are available on request from the corresponding author.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Compliance with Ethical Standards</head><p>Competing interests: The author(s) declare none.</p><p>Ethical approval: The authors assert that all procedures contributing to this work comply with the ethical standards of the relevant national and institutional committees on human experimentation and with the Helsinki Declaration of 1975, as revised in 2008. We also received a favorable opinion from the CER-PN ethics committee of the University of Paris Nanterre (code: 2022-02-05).</p><p>Informed Consent: N.A.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DecidHealth : Psychometric validation of the IUS-12 and IUS-12-H on French healthcare professionals</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>With the COVID-19 pandemic, health care professionals (HCPs) have been brought to the forefront as central actors of our societies. Therefore, conducting studies on the medical practice of HCPs makes all the more sense as this topic deserves further investigation <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Abouzeid &amp; Sallam, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Guillou et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kazour et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Moghadami et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Payan-Carreira et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Pelaccia et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr">Vital et al., 2021)</ref>. Indeed, there is growing interest in medical practices and in finding factors that may impact the medical decision-making process. In this line, many recent studies have shown that medical errors are more frequent than previously thought, especially in stressful environments such as emergency rooms wherein 10% of cases patients are victims of medical errors <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Riou et al., 2019</ref>).</p><p>Intolerance of uncertainty (IU) is one of these factors of interest that is gaining attention but is still under-explored <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Begin et al. 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bhise et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Bloy, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Charrois, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Cranley et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Cristancho et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Farnan et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Han et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Ilgen et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Motte et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Quinlan et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Slade et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Vaismoradi et al., 2011)</ref>. We define IU as "the tendency of an individual to consider as unacceptable the possibility that a negative event will occur, regardless of the probability of its occurrence" <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Carleton et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr">Birrell et al., 2011)</ref>. In health contexts, uncertainty specifically refers to the state the HCP is in "when he or she is unsure of the etiological or syndromic diagnosis for a consultation, the therapy to be offered, or is unsure of his or her understanding of the patient and vice versa" <ref type="bibr">(Sandid, 2016, p. 5)</ref>. A significant body of empirical research has shown that uncertainty is part of medical practice, and can be encountered through different aspects such as diagnosis (i.e., "is it the right one?"), treatment (i.e., "should I prescribe this one?") or the nature of the condition itself (i.e., "am I sure I understand this condition?"; <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abecassis, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Begin et al. 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bhise et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Bloy, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Charrois, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Cranley et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Cristancho et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Farnan et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Han et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Ilgen et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Moffett et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Motte et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Quinlan et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Slade et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Vaismoradi et al., 2011)</ref>. IU is considered stable over time, but can be relatively modulated, particularly as it depends on situational and dispositional factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Begin et al. 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Strout et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>IU is of primary interest in the health field, as it can have negative consequences on the health decision-making process. Because highly uncertainty intolerant people may experience uncertain situations as stressful, they are bound to look for solutions to reduce this uncomfortable feeling or to get away from such situations. In particular, many studies have investigated the "premature closure" bias, which refers to promptly making a diagnosis (often based on pattern recognition), failing to consider other possible diagnoses, and prematurely stopping to gather data <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Pelaccia et al., 2014)</ref>. Premature closure may lead to ignoring certain data, which can obviously have an impact on the subsequent diagnosis, the chosen treatments, and therefore the patient's health condition <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Begin et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Begun &amp; Kaissi, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bhise et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dugas et al., 1997</ref><ref type="bibr">, as cited in Carleton et al., 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dugas et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">Grenier et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">Hicks &amp; Kluemper, 2011</ref><ref type="bibr">, Meyer et al., 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">Motte et al., 2020)</ref>. Indeed, this can decrease the patient's satisfaction and trust in the medical system and lead to negative emotional reactions that can negatively impact the response to treatment <ref type="bibr">(Meyer et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Strout et al., 2018</ref><ref type="bibr">, as cited in Moffett et al., 2021</ref>. For practitioners, the experience of this uncertainty can be stressful, while the stress factor already weighs heavily on HCPs. As stress is for instance one of the reasons why 30% of newly qualified nurses leave the profession within 5 years, it is clear that there is a need to further investigate factors such as uncertainty that contribute to the stress of HCPs. Furthermore, with the Ma santé 2022 1 plan and recent legislative and regulatory developments, France is seeking to reorganize its healthcare system with a greater sharing of medical tasks between the various professions. This requires professionals to take on tasks that were not previously devoted to them, increasing the uncertainty they may feel when caring for patients. In this context, it seems all the more important to study the parameter of IU among the French population.</p><p>Given the importance of this factor, research into the relationship between clinical reasoning and intolerance of uncertainty, including its impact on medical decisions, is essential. However, the implementation and evaluation of the relevance of the action plan to modify this parameter require reliable and valid tools to assess it. Researchers commonly use the Intolerance of Uncertainty Scale to assess intolerance of uncertainty <ref type="bibr">(Birrell et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Buhr &amp; Dugas, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Carleton et al., 2007)</ref>. A 27-item version (IUS-27) and a shorter 12-item version exist <ref type="bibr">(IUS-12, Birrell et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Buhr &amp; Dugas, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Carleton et al., 2007)</ref>. However, no reliable and valid version of this scale exists for measuring this parameter in HCPs in France. We wanted to conduct a French psychometric validation study of the IUS-12 scale as well as a validation of a version adapted to HCPs (called IUS-12-H).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Aim of the study</head><p>Our goal was to assess the validity of French versions of the IUS-12 and the IUS-12-H. Given that the IUS-12 has shown good psychometric qualities in English and that the IUS-12-H is partly based on the <ref type="bibr">IUS-12 (Birrell et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Buhr &amp; Dugas, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Carleton et al., 2007)</ref>, we hypothesized that both our French versions of the IUS-12 and the IUS-12-H would show good psychometric qualities and would correlate with each other.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>We conducted a validation study on HCPs using questionnaires including both our scales to be validated and additional scales.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>For this study, we focused on HCPs as defined by the french Public Health Code 2 . An HCP was considered to be any person practicing a medical profession (physician, midwife, or odontologist), a pharmacy profession (private or hospital pharmacists), or a medical auxiliary profession (nurse, physiotherapist, chiropodist, occupational therapist and psychomotor therapist, speech therapist and orthoptist, medical electroradiology manipulators and medical laboratory technician, audioprosthetist, optician, prosthetist and orthotist, dietician, caregiver, childcare assistants, paramedics, and dental assistants).</p><p>We interrogated a convenience sample recruited using two methods: email and social networks. For the email diffusion, the study was submitted to the e-mail network of a French university laboratory comprising HCPs. The email introduced the study as being about HCPs' decision-making. It included the estimated time to complete the study and the link to the study. Following a snowball sampling, these HCPs were invited to share the study with their HCPs peers. Diffusion via social networks was conducted on Facebook and Linkedin. The address of the online questionnaire was posted on Facebook groups for HCPs. Meanwhile, HCPs were contacted directly on Linkedin using private messages to invite them to participate in the study and to share it with their network. We ensured that the consent of the participants was obtained and that the study complied with the ethical standards of the relevant national and institutional committees on human experimentation and with the Helsinki Declaration of 1975, as revised in 2008.</p><p>For this study, we recruited 933 HCPs. Details on the professional activities of the 319 participants that filled them are provided in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Among the respondents, 417 were excluded because they did not meet our inclusion criteria (i.e., because they were underaged and/or not HCPs according to our definition and/or did not fully complete more than two scales). The final sample was composed of 516 individuals (M age = 36.72, SD age = 12. <ref type="bibr">22,</ref><ref type="bibr">197</ref> women, 120 men, 2 others, and 197 who did not specify their gender), of which 319 specified their field of professional activity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 1</head><p>Number of health professionals by discipline and status The IUS-12 is a 12-item scale that assesses intolerance of uncertainty. It is based on the original 27-item version developed by Freeston and colleagues (1994) for clinical assessment purposes. In this study, we will refer to the two correlated factor structure validated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Carleton et al. (2007)</ref> that includes both prospective (i.e., "propensity of individuals toward active information seeking as a way to reduce uncertainty/increase certainty", factor 1, Bottesi et al., 2019) and inhibitory IU (i.e.,"an inhibition of actions or experience which is caused by uncertainty", factor 2, <ref type="bibr">Bottesi et al., 2019</ref><ref type="bibr">, Jackson et al., 2016</ref>. Participants respond to the IUS-12 on a Likert scale ranging from "Not at all characteristic of me" (1), "A little characteristic of me" (2), "Somewhat characteristic of me"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Nombre de professionnels de santé par discipline et par statut</head><p>(3), "Very characteristic of me" (4), and "Entirely characteristic of me" (5). The IUS-12 theorized with a two correlated factor structure showed good psychometric qualities and correlates with the IUS-27 <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Carleton et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr">Jensen et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>To create the IUS-12-H, we took the IUS-12 items and adapted them to a medical context. Specifically, items begin with "When caring for my patients...". The IUS-12-H has the same instructions and rating system as the IUS-12.</p><p>As part of the validation process, the two scales were discussed with 7 HCPs during interviews to validate the wording of the items (i.e., 2 physiotherapists, 2 nurses, 2 general practitioners, and 1 pharmacist). One of these HCPs was a native English speaker.</p><p>Interviewed HCPs were to judge 1) the appropriateness of the translation (i.e., is the translation common French?), 2) the relevance of the translation in a medical context (i.e., do the terms reflect common medical practice?). We followed this process according to the guidelines of Bouletreau and colleagues <ref type="bibr">(1999)</ref>: "The translation of a questionnaire involves two essential steps: a literal translation and an adaptation to the cultural context, lifestyle, and idioms of the target population. This second step constitutes the cross-cultural validation of the document. It is essential for items dealing with social or psychological dimensions <ref type="bibr">[...]</ref> For questionnaires designed in another language and translated according to the methodology described above, the qualitative evaluation, even in the source language, is sufficient.</p><p>However, the quantitative evaluation of the questionnaire still has to be carried out in the target language.". The same process was done for both IUS-12 and IUS-12-H because IUS-12-H is largely based on IUS-12 and the interviews were on our target population, so we deemed the process adequate. We expected the IUS-12 and IUS-12-H to correlate positively and the association to be strong.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional scales</head><p>To assess the external validity of our two scales, we conducted a review to include scales measuring constructs close to intolerance of uncertainty.  Participants can answer on a Likert scale ranging from "Strongly disagree"</p><p>(1) to "Strongly agree" (6)</p><p>According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Sandid (2016)</ref>, the scale assesses four aspects of uncertainty: anxiety about uncertainty (factor 1), worry about adverse events (factor 2), reluctance to disclose uncertainty to patients (factor 3), and reluctance to disclose medical errors to other physicians (factor 4) Answers to this Likert scale can range from "Strongly agree" (1) to "Strongly disagree"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Convergent</head><p>The scale measures four lower-order factors ("Tolerance", "Absorption", "Appraisal", "Regulation") and one higher-order factor ("General distress tolerance") of tolerance to distress Responses range from "Not like me at all" (0) to "Exactly like me" (6).</p><p>The scale assesses two lower-order factors (factor 1:"Discomfort intolerance"and factor 2: "Discomfort avoidance") and one higher-order factor ("General discomfort intolerance")</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Divergent discomfort Perceived Stress Scale (PSS10)</formula><p>Lesage et al.</p><p>This scale estimates the amount of stress perceived by the respondent over the last two weeks, and thus the extent to which they feel that their environment was stressful during that time 10 Participants indicate the frequency experienced with the following response modalities: Never (0), Almost never (1), Sometimes (2), Quite often (3), Often <ref type="formula">4</ref>The PSS consists of two factors. Factor 1 includes negatively worded items (e.g., "Were you bothered by an unexpected event?"), and Factor 2 includes positively worded items (e.g., "Did you feel that you were in control of the situation?") Divergent Difficulties in Emotion Regulation Scale (DERS-16) French versions of Dan-Glauser and Scherer (2012) for the 16 items described in <ref type="bibr">Bjureberg and colleagues (2016)</ref> This scale assesses emotional regulation difficulties.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>16</head><p>Items are rated from "Almost never" (1), "Some of the time" (2), "Half of the time"</p><p>(3), "Most of the time" (4) to "Almost always" (5).</p><p>The scale consists of five factors: factor 1 includes items measuring lack of emotional clarity ("Clarity"), factor 2 includes items assessing difficulties in engaging in goal-oriented behaviors ("Goals"), factor 3 refers to difficulty in controlling impulses ("Impulses"), factor 4 includes items measuring rejection of emotional responses ("Nonacceptance") and factor 5 includes items referring to difficulties accessing emotional regulation strategies ("Strategies")</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Divergent</head><p>Questionnaire sur measures the perceived uncertainty in the professional environment modalities on a Likert scale are: "Strongly Disagree" (1), "Disagree" (2), "In-between" (3), "Agree" (4) and "Strongly Agree" <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">5</ref>perception of the wearing side of uncertainty, factor 2 to the perception of the constructive side of uncertainty, factor 3 to uncertainty management through control, factor 4 to uncertainty management through reassurance and factor 5 to uncertainty management through avoidance</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Need for Cognition Scale (NFCO)</head><p>Ginet and Py <ref type="formula">2000</ref>This scale measures the extent to which a person enjoys engaging in higher cognitive activities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>11</head><p>Participants respond on a Likert scale from "Completely false" (1), "Somewhat false" (2), "Somewhat true"</p><p>(3) to "Completely true" (4).</p><p>This scale has a unidimensional structure Divergent Need For Closure Scale (NFC) <ref type="bibr">Ginet and Py (2000)</ref> This scale measures the cognitive need to arrive at an answer, an end regarding a subject (i.e., "an individual's desire for a firm answer to a question and an aversion toward ambiguity,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>15</head><p>This Likert scale ranges from "Strongly Disagree" (1), "Disagree" (2), "Somewhat Disagree"</p><p>(3), "Somewhat Agree" (4)", "Agree"</p><p>(5) to "Strongly Agree" <ref type="formula">6</ref>This scale has a unidimensional structure Divergent <ref type="bibr">Kruglanski &amp; Webster 1996, p. 264</ref>, as cited in <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Rosen et al., 2014)</ref> Tolerance of Ambiguity in Medical Students and Doctors (TAMSAD)</p><p>Hancock et al. <ref type="formula">2015</ref>This scale assesses intolerance to ambiguity (IA), a construct close to but different from intolerance to uncertainty (IU, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Rosen et al., 2014)</ref> 29</p><p>Participants can answer on a Likert scale ranging from "Strongly disagree"</p><p>(1) to "Strongly agree" <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">5</ref>This scale has a unidimensional structure Divergent</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sociodemographic questionnaire</head><p>Participants were asked to indicate their gender. Participants could choose between "male", "female" and "other". If it was "other", a blank space allowed participants to fill in their gender. Participants ages were asked through an open-ended question that asked: "Please indicate your age in the box below (in numbers, e.g., 32)". The following question asked participants to indicate their status (i.e., student or not). If they were students, they were asked to specify their study discipline. Participants were to choose their discipline between six options: "nurse", "physiotherapist", "general practitioner", "osteopath", "pharmacist", or "other". If it was "other", a blank space allowed participants to fill in their study discipline. If they were already practicing, they were asked in what discipline and for how many years.</p><p>The response options for occupation discipline were the same as those for the study discipline question. Participants were asked to write the number of years of occupation in numbers,</p><p>through the following open-ended question: "Please indicate the number of years you have been practicing medicine (e.g., 32). This is the number of years since you graduated.".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>The first page of the questionnaire thanked the participants for their interest and presented the study as focusing on the parameters influencing health care decision-making to develop a tool to optimize decision-making based on their answers. They were reminded of the estimated time required to complete the study, were guaranteed anonymity, and had to create a pseudonymization code. They then completed all 11 scales displayed in a randomized order. Next, participants were asked to complete several socio-demographic questions (i.e., age, gender, occupation). They were also asked how they had found out about the study. The response options were the following: "by email", "on social networks", or "other". If it was "other", a blank space allowed participants to fill in how they came to know the study. Next, participants were asked to provide their email addresses. This was intended to send them the results of the study and to be able to contact them later for a future study.</p><p>The email addresses were collected through an embedded Framaform 3 question. Framaform is an online software that allows the collection of personal data without any third-party use.</p><p>The following instruction provided participants an explanation for using this tool: "The use of the framaforms.org tool allows us not to link your answers to your email address, which guarantees the strictest respect of your anonymity". The study ended with a final debriefing that thanked the HCPs for their participation, reminded them of the purpose of the study, and invited them to share the study with their peers. A contact email address was provided for any questions or comments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical analysis</head><p>We followed a three-stage analysis for all the scales in our study: 1) We ascertained the construct validity of all the scales by checking that the factorial structure observed corresponded to that described in the literature, 2) Then we tested the external validity of our scales by conducting correlational analyses, 3) And then we conducted new factor analyses with our scales and the additional scales in pairs to check the external validity (i.e. did the factor analyses show that the scales had different factor structures when taken in pairs). All these analyses were carried out for each scale, with the main objective of establishing the validity of the IUS-12 and the IUS-12-H.</p><p>We performed (i) exploratory factor analyses with a Promax rotation analysis. For each scale, items were reviewed. They were considered to belong to a factor when their loadings were at least 0.3 in one factor and no more than 0.2 in other factors. When an item saturated less than 0.2 in all factors, it was removed according to the step-by-step factor reduction method described by <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Samuels (2017)</ref>, and the analysis was performed again. Then (ii) we performed correlation matrices to establish Pearson correlation coefficients between our scales. Lastly, (iii) we conducted a new set of factorial analyses to confirm the external validity of our scales by ensuring that IUS-12 and IUS-12-H did not overlap with other scales. To do so, we conducted analyses with our scales (e.g., the IUS-12) and our additional scales (e.g., PRU). For the scales used to assess the divergent validity of our scales, we wanted to verify that when put together in a factorial analysis, the two factorial structures of the scales were indeed different. For the scales used to assess convergent validity, we wanted to check that the factorial structures overlapped strongly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Handling of missing data</head><p>We decided to use imputations to manage our missing data because it may be statistically preferable to deleting data of " incomplete " participants <ref type="bibr">(McNeish, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Stuart et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Xu et al., 2020)</ref>. The method we found most suitable was multiple imputations as it is preferable to other imputation techniques such as mean imputation or hot-deck <ref type="bibr">(Boussat et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Houghton et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Nassiri et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Peyre et al., 2011</ref><ref type="bibr">, Sun et al., 2017</ref><ref type="bibr">Xu et al., 2020)</ref>. In addition, multiple imputations are often used to process data in medical research (Jamaludin et al., 2021) and statistical analyses on imputed datasets often show results comparable to those on non-imputed datasets <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Cedars et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kolaja et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Lovik et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Sasaki et al., 2021)</ref>. Furthermore, we observed good psychometric qualities on tools validated with an imputed dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Cedars et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Moser et al., 2012)</ref>.</p><p>We used the Mice (Multiple Imputation with Chained Equations) packages on the R software. Multiple imputations are a statistical technique used to simulate missing data. The first step is the simulation of several datasets, usually 5, following an appropriate model.</p><p>Then, we averaged the imputed values to form a single final file on which we performed our statistical analyses <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Dray, &amp; Josse, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Josse &amp; Husson, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">McNeish, 2017)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Results of the factor analyses of the additional scales are available in Supplementary</p><p>Material.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assessing construct validity using exploratory factorial analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IUS-12</head><p>The seminal paper by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Carleton et al (2007)</ref> describes a two-factor structure. We found this structure to explain 53% of the variance (α = .90, M = 2.32, SD = .71). The factor loadings ranged from 0.46 to 0.95. However, item 3 was more saturated in the factor in which it was not supposed to be (0.49 vs. 0.33). We decided to retain this two correlated factor structure. Details of the factorial structure of the IUS-12 are available in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IUS-12-H</head><p>Again, we tested a two-factor model like <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Carleton et al (2007)</ref>. This model explained 50% of the variance and the factor loadings ranged from 0.43 to 0.87. However, item 3 was cross-loaded and did not seem to fall more into one factor than another (factor loadings were 0.39 and 0.38). We tested this two-factor model while removing item 3. The model accounted for 51% of the variance and the factor loadings ranged from 0.42 to 0.88 (α = .88, M = 2.31, SD = .67). We decided to keep this two correlated factor structure without item 3. Details of the factorial structure of the IUS-12-H are available in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>. .495</p><p>One should always look ahead so as to avoid surprises. Je pense qu'il faut tout anticiper pour éviter les surprises.</p><p>.803</p><p>A small unforeseen event can spoil everything, even with the best of planning. Je pense que même avec la meilleure des planifications, un léger imprévu peut tout gâcher.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>.562</head><p>When it's time to act, uncertainty paralyses me. Au moment de passer à l'action, l'incertitude me paralyse.</p><p>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assessing external validity using correlational analyses</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IUS-12 and IUS-12-H</head><p>The two IUS-12 factors and the two IUS-12 factors correlated positively and significantly. These correlations were very high. IUS-12 factor 1 correlated at r = .61 with IUS-12-H factor 1 and r = .41 with factor 2 (p &lt; .000). IUS-12 factor 2 correlated at r = .41</p><p>with IUS-12-H factor 1 and r = .62 with factor 2 (p &lt;.000). The main results of the correlational analyses for the IUS-12 and IUS-12-H are available in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 4</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PRU</head><p>All four PRU factors showed significant positive correlations with the two IUS-12 factors (ranging from r = .11 to r = .44, p &lt;.000). PRU factors 1 and 2 had higher correlations than factors 3 and 4 (ranging from r = .27 to r = .44 versus r = .11 to r = .19, p &lt;.000).</p><p>Similarly, all four PRU factors showed significant positive correlations with the two factors of the IUS-12-H (ranging from r = .06 to r = .53, p &lt;.000). Again, PRU factors 1 and 2 showed higher correlations than factors 3 and 4 (ranging from r = .38 to r = .53 versus r = .06 to r = .23, p &lt;.000).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DTS</head><p>The DTS correlated significantly negatively with factor 1 (r = -.40, p &lt; .000) and</p><p>factor 2 of the IUS-12 (r = -.43, p &lt; .000). Similarly, DTS correlated significantly negatively with factor 1 (r = -.33, p &lt; .000) and factor 2 of IUS-12-H (r = -.34, p &lt; .000).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DIS</head><p>Factor 1 of the DIS correlated positively with the two IUS-12 factors, but these associations were weak and nonsignificant (r = .06, p &lt;.164 and r = .08, p &lt; .075). In contrast, factor 2 of the DIS correlated positively and significantly with the IUS-12 factors (r = .19 and r = .18, p &lt;.000). A similar pattern was found with the IUS-12-H. The associations remained non-significant and weak. Factor 1 of the DIS correlated positively only with factor 2 of the IUS-12-H (r = .04, p &lt; .323) and did not correlate with factor 1 (r = .00, p &lt; .915).</p><p>But factor 2 of the DIS correlated positively and significantly with both factors of the IUS-12-H (r = .14, p &lt; .002 and r = .12, p &lt; .007).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PSS10</head><p>The two PSS10 factors correlated positively and significantly with the two IUS-12 factors. The correlations ranged from r = .32 to r = .40 (p &lt; .000). Similarly, the two PSS10 factors correlated positively and significantly with the two factors of the IUS-12-H (ranging from r = .24 to r = .36, p &lt; .000).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DERS-16</head><p>All </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NFC</head><p>The NFC showed positive and significant correlations with both IUS-12 factors (r = .64 and r = .41, p &lt; .000) and both IUS-12-H factors (r = .49 and r = .33, p &lt; .000).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>TAMSAD</head><p>TAMSAD was significantly negatively correlated with both factors of the IUS-12 (r = -.44 for both factors, p &lt;.000). These significant and high negative correlations were also found with the two IUS-12-H factors (r = -.49 and r = -.48, p &lt; .000)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assessing external validity using exploratory factorial analysis</head><p>Overall, the scales showed a factor structure quite distinct from that of the IUS-12 and IUS-12-H. Regarding convergent validity, the IUS-12 and the IUS-12-H cross-loaded on most items. Only factor 1 of the IUS-12 was in a separate factor from the other items. For the additional scales, only the QIT showed partial cross-loading with the IUS-12. Factor 1 of the IUS-12 cross-loaded with the items of factor 3 of the QIT model that we retained during our previous analyses. Factor 2 of the IUS-12 did not cross load with the QIT. The results of these analyses are summarised in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 5</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overall study results</head><p>Intolerance of uncertainty can have deleterious consequences on the medical decision-making process <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Begin et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Begun &amp; Kaissi, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bhise et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dugas et al., 1997</ref><ref type="bibr">, as cited in Carleton et al., 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dugas et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">Grenier et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">Hicks &amp; Kluemper, 2011</ref><ref type="bibr">, Meyer et al., 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">Moffett et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Motte et al., 2020)</ref>. More studies are needed to understand the link between IU and medical decisions <ref type="bibr">(Brun et al., 2022)</ref>. No valid and reliable scale exists to measure this parameter on French populations, and even more so on HCPs. Previous psychometric analyses were conducted on the English version of the IUS-12 (i.e., one of the main scales used to measure IU) and deemed the scale to have two factors: desire for predictability (i.e., needing to know what is going to happen) and uncertainty paralysis (i.e., inability to act due to uncertainty, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berenbaum et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Birrell et al., 2011)</ref>. But newer analysis suggested a two correlated factor structure composition of the IU including prospective IU (i.e., "propensity of individuals toward active information seeking as a way to reduce uncertainty/increase certainty", factor 1, Bottesi et al., 2019) and inhibitory IU (i.e.,"an inhibition of actions or experience which is caused by uncertainty", factor 2, <ref type="bibr">Bottesi et al., 2019</ref><ref type="bibr">, Jackson et al., 2016</ref>.</p><p>To overcome this lack of reliable tools and clarify the factor structure of the IUS-12, we submitted French versions of the IUS-12 and the IUS-12-H to HCPs to conduct a psychometric validation procedure on these two scales. We recruited HCPs to answer our questionnaire, which included the IUS-12, the IUS-12-H, and scales intended to be used to establish the convergent and divergent validity of our two scales. Our psychometric analyses of the responses of 516 HCPs suggest that both scales are psychometrically valid and can be used to measure IU (with the IUS-12) and IU in the medical context among HCPs (with the IUS-12-H). The two scales correlated highly and positively with each other but diverged from the additional scales that were used to establish their divergent validity. We conclude that both our scales have good psychometric qualities and are valid. The IUS-12 can be used to assess general IU, while the IUS-12-H can be used to measure IU in a medical professional context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Theoretical and practical implications</head><p>Several theoretical implications are to be considered in light of our results and the factor structures found. Both the IUS-12 and the IUS-12-H had a similar factor structure to that described in the seminal article by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Carleton et al (2007)</ref>. However, we note that item 3</p><p>was not placed in the factor described by Carleton for the IUS-12 and that a model without this item was more satisfactory for the IUS-12-H. Therefore, this item may be removed from the IUS-12-H to ensure more satisfactory psychometric properties in the future. Regarding our factorial analyses for external validity between these two scales, we noticed that factor 1 items were included in a separate factor that did not cross load with the rest of the IUS-12-H.</p><p>This could be explained by the content of the items in factor 1 which differ more from the IUS-12-H (a medical context bound measure) than the factor 2 items. Regarding the additional scales used in the study, we found the structures described in the literature for the PRU, DIS, NFCO, NFC, and TAMSAD. For the DTS, we did not find the lower order 4-factor structure described by Wagener and <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Blairy (2015)</ref>. This is potentially due to our sample size as well as the specific population we interviewed, which may have a different distress experience than the general population. We tested different models and identified a satisfactory two-factor model but this required the removal of 6 items (i.e., 40% of the scale), which did not seem acceptable to us and led us to retain the unidimensional model referring to the general factor described by Wagener and <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Blairy (2015)</ref>. For the PSS10, a model without item 7 seemed more satisfactory. This slight difference is probably due to our sample size and certainly does not question the structure of the scale. Similarly, for the DERS-16, the model described in the literature minus two items was more satisfactory, which in our view does not fundamentally question the validity of the structure originally described in the literature. For the QIT the mixing of some factors, the number of items that needed to be removed, and the number of models that we had to test suggest that more research is needed to determine whether this is due to our sample or whether the structure of the scale needs to be revised. Furthermore, we note that the items assessing avoidance and uncertainty of HCPs were grouped in our models, which may pave the way for a new factor structure where these items are grouped.</p><p>This study is also encouraging for many practical implications. Indeed, the IUS-12-H will now permit the measurement of IU among HCPs. In particular, this scale can be used in training courses involving HCPs with very different backgrounds and occupations. Beyond the prospects of comparison between professions, this scale offers the possibility of identifying HCPs with a high level of IU requiring remediation. This will also be an opportunity to develop and propose to HCPs pedagogical models adapted to their level of IU, without mixing in training individuals with very different levels of IU. In addition, we mentioned earlier the importance of comfort and well-being at work and how IU may impact these elements among HCPs. Following this validation, it is now possible to measure this construct and understand its impact, to determine whether it should be taken into account more fully in the professional practice of HCPs. As a result of this study, we now conceive IU, in the same way as anxiety, as a construct for which we all have a relatively modular baseline.</p><p>A more comprehensive consideration of this construct can hopefully have a positive impact on the care provided. Insofar as uncertainty can lead to inadequate care, we are pleased to know that with IU scales it is now possible to better understand how HCPs deal with uncertainty and thus be able to identify individuals at greater risk of sub-optimal treatment issues due to poor uncertainty management.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations</head><p>However, despite our encouraging results, we should not forget the limitations of our study. Firstly, the inclusion of students in our participants was arguably a choice that needed to be considered. Indeed, <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Stephens et al. (2022)</ref> noted that including students in a study on uncertainty tolerance may constitute a bias because their sources of uncertainty and the activities in which they occur are different. His results also show differences in the reliability of the measures between students and experts and suggest that the way these two populations conceptualize uncertainty tolerance differs. However, we found the expected structure for our scales of interest and with good reliability indicators. We can assume that this limitation had little influence on our results and that similar results would be found with a sample of confirmed HCPs only.</p><p>Another, obvious limitation in our study stems from the fact that we validated a health-oriented scale (i.e., IUS-12-H) and a generalist scale (i.e., IUS-12) on HCPs. This is quite relevant for the IUS-12-H, but implies that the IUS-12 has been validated on a population that is not general. It is possible that HCPs have a different level of tolerance to uncertainty and more generally a different way of dealing with uncertainty than the general population. Further studies should be conducted on a general population to confirm the psychometric qualities of the IUS-12.</p><p>Furthermore, our sampling method was based on the assumption that all HCPs should be comparable in terms of IU, so our analyses do not take into account the potential differences that may be observed in different types of HCPs. It is conceivable that IU has a different impact and implications for GPs and emergency physicians, for example (e.g., differing severity, life-threatening situations, or more trivial conditions). Future studies should compare IU scores of different medical professions to determine if there are inter-professional variations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Future research perspectives and conclusion</head><p>It seems clear that one avenue for further research lies in comparing different types of HCPs. We did not make any assumptions about possible differences in IU levels between different types of HCPs. Future research should compare different populations to identify whether there are any specificities among different HCP types.</p><p>Other avenues for future research can be distinguished. One interesting point lies in the richness of the constructs we evaluated. We assessed a large number of constructs alongside our scales of interest to determine their psychometric validity. <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 4 reveal</ref> correlations that warrant further investigation (e.g., high negative correlations between the IUS-12 and the TAMSAD, which measure constructs for which a distinction is not fully supported empirically and are considered similar or even interchangeable in the literature;</p><p>Hillen et al., 2017; <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Rosen et al., 2014)</ref> as well as unexpected factor structure differences (e.g., the PRU and the QIT, which have distinct factorial structures from the IUS-12). These points need to be clarified to better understand how these constructs relate to IU.</p><p>Lastly, we think that the most important new area of research involves the interpretation of the scores on our scales. We are aware that a framework for interpreting the score is needed and future studies will have to determine at what threshold of "score change" one can consider there has been a change in the IU of HCPs. More precisely, two questions need to be addressed: 1) At what level of "score change" between two administrations of the scales can we consider that a change has occurred for the IU construct of a given person and 2) What level of "score change" can be expected between two administrations of our scales.</p><p>To summarise, the most important area for future research is to determine the "minimal clinically important difference" (MCID; McGlothlin &amp; Lewis, 2014) that can be expected for our scales. Indeed, if we conceptualize IU as a relatively stable but changeable trait, we should expect the scores on our scales to be able to evolve and it is important to determine at what level of "score change" we can consider that a training intended to develop tolerance to uncertainty has influenced participants for instance. With our sample, we see that the average level that can be expected on these scales is around M = 2.30, with a standard deviation of about SD = .70. The averages give us an idea of the scores that individuals might get on these scales, while the standard deviations suggest the range of score changes that can be expected with these scales. To determine the exact "minimum clinically relevant difference" an interesting approach would be to assess IU in two different groups. One group would be characterized by a high level of IU and a low level of well-being, while another group would be characterized by a low level of IU and a normal (or high) level of well-being. By comparing the scores on the IU scales of these two groups, we could gauge the level of "score change" that can be expected (i.e., to what extent can IU decrease?). Alternatively, we could conduct a study on a group with high IU and a low level of well-being (time t1), then offer them training to improve their tolerance of uncertainty, and measure their IU level after the training (time t2). This would allow us to know precisely to what extent a "score change" can occur and to provide an accurate score interpretation grid for our scales. This would facilitate their use and promote the development of studies evaluating this construct in general contexts, and in medical practice. 1503-1511.http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12144-017-9712-7</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>5 factors of the DERS-16 were significantly positively correlated with the two factors of the IUS-12. Correlations with IUS-12 factor 1 ranged from r = .19 to r = .39, p &lt; .000. Correlations with IUS-12 factor 2 ranged from r = .24 to r = .41, p &lt; .000 The factor that had the strongest correlation with both IUS-12 factors was factor 5 ("Strategies", with r = .39 and r = .41, p &lt; .000). Similarly, all 5 factors of the DERS-16 correlated significantly and positively with both factors of the IUS-12-H. Correlations with IUS-12-H factor 1 ranged from r = .21 to r = .33, p &lt; .000. Correlations with IUS-12-H factor 2 ranged from r = .19 to r = .35, p &lt; .000. Again, the factor that correlated the most with both IUS-12H factors was factor 5, with r = .33 and r = .35, p &lt; .000.QITFactor 1, 3 and 4 of the QIT correlated significantly with both factors of the IUS-12 (respectively r = .64, r = .52 and r = .32 for factor 1 of the IUS-12 and r = .54, r = .21 and r = .38 for factor 2 of the IUS-12, p &lt; .000). Factor 2 of the QIT was significantly negatively correlated with both factors of the IUS-12 (r = -.36 and r = -.28, p &lt; .000). The same pattern was observed for the IUS-12-H in that QIT factors 1, 3 and 4 correlated significantly positively with both IUS-12-H factors (respectively r = .46, r = 39 and r = .36 for IUS-12-H factor 1 and r = .46, r = .16 and r = .31 for IUS-12-H factor 2, p &lt; .000). Again, QIT factor 2 correlated significantly negatively with both factors of the IUS-12-H (r = -.24 and r = -.25, p &lt; .000).NFCONFCO correlated negatively and significantly with both IUS-12 factors (r = -.24 and r = -.25, p &lt; .000) and both IUS-12-H factors (r = -.25 and r = -.39, p &lt; .000).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Bloy</head><label></label><figDesc>.http://dx.doi.org/10.3917/sss.261.0067Bjureberg, J., Ljótsson, B., Tull, M. T., Hedman, E., Sahlin, H., Lundh, L. G., ... &amp; Gratz, K.   L. (2016). Development and validation of a brief version of the difficulties in emotion regulation scale: the 38(2), 284-296.http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10862-015-9514-x Bouletreau, A., Chouanïère, D.,Wild, P., &amp; Fontana, J. M. (1999).Concevoir, traduire et valider un questionnaire. A propos d'un exemple, EUROQUEST (Doctoral dissertation, Institut National de Recherche et de Sécurité (INRS)).Boussat, B., François, O., Viotti, J., Seigneurin, A., Giai, J.,François, P., &amp; Labarere, J.   (2021). Managing missing data in the hospital survey on patient safety culture: .http://dx.doi.org/10.1097/PTS.0000000000000595   Bottesi, G., Noventa, S., Freeston, M. H., &amp; Ghisi, M. (2019. Seeking certainty about Intolerance of Uncertainty: Addressing old and new issues through the .http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0211929    Brun, C., Zerhouni, O., Akinyemi, A., Houtin, L.,Monvoisin, R., &amp; Pinsault, N. (2022).Impact of uncertainty intolerance on clinical reasoning: A scoping review of the 21st-century literature. Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice.http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jep.13756 Buhr, K., &amp; Dugas, M. J. (2002). The intolerance of uncertainty scale: Psychometric properties of the English version. Behaviour research and therapy, 40(8), 931-945.http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0005-7967(01)00092-4 Jensen, D., Kind, A. J., Morrison, A. S., &amp; Heimberg, R. G. (2014). Intolerance of uncertainty and immediate decision-making in high-risk situations. Journal of Experimental Psychopathology, 5(2), 178-190.http://dx.doi.org/10.5127/jep.035113 Josse, J., &amp; Husson, F. (2011). Multiple imputation in principal component analysis. .http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11634-011-0086-7 Kazour, F., Richa, S., Zoghbi, M., El-Hage, W., &amp; Haddad, F. G. (2017). Using the script concordance test to evaluate clinical reasoning skills in psychiatry. Academic Psychiatry, 41(1), 86-90.http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40596-016-0539-6 Kolaja, C. A., Porter, B., Powell, T. M., &amp; Rull, R. P. (2021). Multiple imputation validation study: addressing unmeasured survey data in a longitudinal design. BMC Medical Research Methodology, 21(1), 1-9.http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/s12874-020-01158-w Lapthorn, B., &amp; Hellemans, C. (2011). Construction et validation initiale d'une échelle d'incertitude au travail. Paris: L'Harmattan. Lesage, F. X., Berjot, S., &amp; Deschamps, F. (2012). Psychometric properties of the French versions of the Perceived Stress Scale. International journal of .http://dx.doi.org/10.2478/s13382-012-0024-8 Lovik, A., Nassiri, V., Verbeke, G., Molenberghs, G., &amp; Sodermans, A. K. (2017). Psychometric properties and comparison of different techniques for factor analysis on the Big Five Inventory from a Flemish sample. Personality and Individual Differences, 117, 122-129.http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.paid.2017.05.048 McGlothlin, A. E., &amp; Lewis, R. J. (2014). Minimal clinically important difference: defining what really matters to patients. Jama, 312(13), 1342-1343.http://dx.doi.org/10.1001/jama.2014.13128 McNeish, D. (2017). Exploratory factor analysis with small samples and missing data. .http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00223891.2016.1252382 Meyer, A. N., Giardina, T. D., Khawaja, L., &amp; Singh, H. (2021). Patient and clinician experiences of uncertainty in the diagnostic process: Current understanding and future directions. .http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2021.07.028 Moffett, J., Hammond, J., Murphy, P., &amp; Pawlikowska, T. (2021). The ubiquity of uncertainty-a scoping review on how undergraduate health professions' students engage with uncertainty. Advances in Health Sciences Education, 1-46. (1) Moghadami, M., Amini, M., Moghadami, M., Dalal, B., &amp; Charlin, B. (2021). Teaching clinical reasoning to undergraduate medical students by illness script method: a randomized controlled trial. BMC medical education, 21(1), 1-7. Moser, A., Stuck, A. E., Silliman, R. A., Ganz, P. A., &amp; Clough-Gorr, K. M. (2012). The eight-item modified Medical Outcomes Study Social Support Survey: psychometric evaluation showed excellent performance. Journal of clinical epidemiology, 65(10), 1107-1116.http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2012.04.007 Motte, B., Aiguier, G., Van Pee, D., &amp; Cobbaut, J. P. (2020). Mieux comprendre l'incertitude en médecine pour former les médecins. Pédagogie Médicale, 21(1), 39-51. Nassiri, V., Lovik, A., Molenberghs, G., &amp; Verbeke, G. (2018). On using multiple imputation for exploratory factor analysis of incomplete data. Behavior research methods, 1-15.http://dx.doi.org/10.3758/s13428-017-1013-4Payan-Carreira, R.,Cruz, G., Papathanasiou, I. V., Fradelos, E., &amp; Jiang, L. (2019). The (2017). Proposing a validated clinical app predicting hospitalization cost for extracranial).http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0186758   Vaismoradi, M., Salsali, M., &amp; Ahmadi, F. (2011. Nurses' experiences of uncertainty in clinical practice: a descriptive study. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 67(5),991-999.http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2648.2010.05547.x   Vital, S., Wulfman, C., Girard, F., Tamimi, F., Charlin, B., &amp; Ducret, M. (2021. Scriptconcordance tests: A call for action in dental education. European Journal of Dental Education. Wagener, A., &amp; Blairy, S. (2015). Version française de la Distress Tolerance Scale et de la Discomfort Intolerance Scale. Canadian Journal of Behavioural Science/://dx.doi.org/10.1037/cbs0000015 Westerlund, M., &amp; Santtila, P. (2018). A Finnish adaptation of the emotion regulation questionnaire (ERQ) and the difficulties in emotion regulation scale (DERS-16). Nordic Psychology, 70(4), 304-323.http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/19012276.2018.1443279 Xu, X., Xia, L., Zhang, Q., Wu, S., Wu, M., &amp; Liu, H. (2020). The ability of different imputation methods for missing values in mental measurement questionnaires. dx.doi.org/10.1186/s12874-020-00932-0 Yiğit, İ., &amp; Guzey Yiğit, M. (2019). Psychometric properties of Turkish version of difficulties in emotion regulation scale-brief form (DERS-16). Current Psychology, 38(6),</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="7">Name, authors, purpose, number of items, response modality, factorial structure and expected validity (i.e. convergent or divergent) of the</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">additional scales</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="7">Nom, auteurs, objectif, nombre d'items, modalité de réponse, structure factorielle et validité attendue (c'est-à-dire convergente ou divergente)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">des échelles supplémentaires.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Name of the</cell><cell>Validated</cell><cell>Purpose</cell><cell>Number</cell><cell>Response modality</cell><cell>Factorial Structure</cell><cell>Expected validity</cell></row><row><cell>scale</cell><cell>by/Version</cell><cell></cell><cell>of items</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>used</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Physicians'</cell><cell>Sandid</cell><cell>This scales</cell><cell>15</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Reactions to</cell><cell>(2016)</cell><cell>assesses four</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Uncertainty (PRU)</cell><cell></cell><cell>aspects of uncertainty in</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>physicians</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Factorial structure of the IUS-12 and the IUS-12-H</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Structure factorielle de l'IUS-12 et de l'IUS-12-H</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>IUS-12</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Item</cell><cell>Factor 1</cell><cell>Factor 2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(Prospective IU)</cell><cell>(Inhibitory IU)</cell></row><row><cell>Unforeseen events upset me greatly.</cell><cell>.585</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Les imprévus me dérangent énormément.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>It frustrates me not having all the information I</cell><cell>.462</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>need.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Cela me frustre de ne pas avoir toutes les</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>informations dont j'ai besoin.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Uncertainty keeps me from living a full life.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>L'incertitude m'empêche d'apprécier pleinement la</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>vie.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, je déteste être pris.e au dépourvu.</figDesc><table><row><cell>l'avance. surprises. taken by surprise.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>I must get away from all uncertain situations. Even with the most careful planning when caring for</cell><cell>.441</cell><cell>.607</cell></row><row><cell>J'ai besoin de me retirer de toute situation qui my patients, a small unforeseen event can spoil</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>devient trop incertaine. everything. When caring for my patients, the smallest doubt can</cell><cell></cell><cell>.882</cell></row><row><cell>Même avec la meilleure des planifications lors stop me from acting.</cell><cell></cell><cell>952</cell></row><row><cell>de la prise de charge de mes patient.e.s, un léger Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, le</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>imprévu peut tout gâcher. moindre doute peut m'empêcher d'agir.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>IUS-12-H</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>When I am uncertain I can't function very well. Item When caring for my patients calls for action, When caring for my patients, I would like to be able</cell><cell>Factor 1 .847</cell><cell>.782 Factor 2 .828</cell></row><row><cell>Lorsque je suis dans l'incertitude, je ne peux pas uncertainty paralyzes me. to organize everything in advance.</cell><cell>(Prospective IU)</cell><cell>(Inhibitory IU)</cell></row><row><cell>bien fonctionner. I always want to know what the future has in store When caring for my patients, unforeseen events Au moment où la prise en charge de mes Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, patient.e.s nécessite d'agir, l'incertitude me j'aimerais être en mesure de tout organiser à upset me greatly. Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, les paralyse. l'avance.</cell><cell>.648 .422</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>for me. imprévus me dérangent énormément.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Je voudrais toujours savoir ce que l'avenir me When I feel uncertainty regarding care of my When caring for my patients, I must get away from</cell><cell></cell><cell>.672 .727</cell></row><row><cell>réserve. I can't stand being taken by surprise. Je déteste être pris.e au dépourvu. When caring for my patients, it frustrates me not patients, I can't function very well. all uncertain situations. Lorsque je suis dans l'incertitude dans la prise en Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, j'ai having all the information I need. charge de mes patient.e.s, je ne peux pas bien besoin de me retirer de toute situation qui Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, cela me frustre de manquer d'informations dont fonctionner. devient trop incertaine.</cell><cell>.759 .619</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>j'ai besoin.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>When caring for my patients, I always want to</cell><cell>.744</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>The smallest doubt can stop me from acting. know what is going to happen.</cell><cell></cell><cell>.860</cell></row><row><cell>Le moindre doute peut m'empêcher d'agir. When caring for my patients, I think that everything should be anticipated to avoid surprises. Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, j'aimerais toujours savoir ce qui va se passer.</cell><cell>.637</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>I should be able to organize everything in advance. Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, je</cell><cell>.858</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>J'aimerais être en mesure de tout organiser à pense qu'il faudrait tout anticiper pour éviter les When caring for my patients, I can't stand being</cell><cell>.737</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>Note: Item 3 of the IUS-12-H, "When caring for my patients, uncertainty prevents me from fully enjoying my work"/ "Lors de la prise en charge de mes patient.e.s, l'incertitude m'empêche d'apprécier pleinement mon travail", is not presented in this table as it was removed from the final model Note: All loadings below .40 on secondary factors (i.e., factors on which the item is not theoretically supposed to saturate) have not been included in the table to facilitate reading.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="8">Results of correlational analyses for IUS-12 and IUS-12-H by factors</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="9">Résultats des analyses corrélationnelles pour l'IUS-12 et l'IUS-12-H par facteurs</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>PRU</cell><cell></cell><cell>DTS</cell><cell>DIS</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">PSS10</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>DERS-16</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>F2</cell><cell>F3</cell><cell>F4</cell><cell>U</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>F2</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>F2</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>F2</cell><cell>F3</cell><cell>F4</cell><cell>F5</cell></row><row><cell>IUS-12</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>.44**</cell><cell>.37**</cell><cell>.19**</cell><cell>.11**</cell><cell>-.40**</cell><cell>.06</cell><cell>.19**</cell><cell>.34**</cell><cell>.30**</cell><cell>.28**</cell><cell>.28**</cell><cell>.31**</cell><cell>.19**</cell><cell>.39**</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>F2</cell><cell>.42**</cell><cell>.27**</cell><cell>.19**</cell><cell>.18**</cell><cell>-.43**</cell><cell>.08</cell><cell>.18**</cell><cell>.32**</cell><cell>.40**</cell><cell>.25**</cell><cell>.34**</cell><cell>.24**</cell><cell>.24**</cell><cell>.41**</cell></row><row><cell>IUS-12-</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>.51**</cell><cell>.45**</cell><cell>.18**</cell><cell>.06**</cell><cell>-.33**</cell><cell>.00</cell><cell>.14*</cell><cell>.30**</cell><cell>.24**</cell><cell>.24**</cell><cell>.24**</cell><cell>.25**</cell><cell>.21**</cell><cell>.33**</cell></row><row><cell>H</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>F2</cell><cell>.53**</cell><cell>.38**</cell><cell>.22**</cell><cell>.23**</cell><cell>-.34**</cell><cell>.04</cell><cell>.12*</cell><cell>.34**</cell><cell>.36**</cell><cell>.22**</cell><cell>.32**</cell><cell>.25**</cell><cell>.19**</cell><cell>.35**</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Both scales have very distinct factor structures, Partial crossloading = Both scales have factor structures that crossload on some items</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="8">Results of the external validity factorial analyses of the IUS-12 and IUS-12-H</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="9">Résultats des analyses factorielles de validité externe de l'IUS-12 et de l'IUS-12-H</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>PRU</cell><cell>DTS</cell><cell>DIS</cell><cell>PSS10</cell><cell>DERS-1</cell><cell>QIT</cell><cell>NFCO</cell><cell>NFC</cell><cell>IUS-12</cell><cell>TAMSA</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>6</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>D</cell></row><row><cell>IUS-12</cell><cell>Distinc</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Partial</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>Distinct</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>t</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>crossloa</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ding</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Matches</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Partially</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>our</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>expectati</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>ons</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">IUS-12-H Distinc</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Distinct</cell><cell>Partial</cell><cell>Distinct</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>t</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>crossloa</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ding</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Matches</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>Partially</cell><cell>Yes</cell></row><row><cell>our</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>expectati</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>ons</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Note: Distinct =</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">https://solidarites-sante.gouv.fr/systeme-de-sante-et-medico-social/masante2022/</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">As defined here : https://www.vie-publique.fr/fiches/37855-categories-de-professionnels-de-sante-code-se-la-sante-publique</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">https://framaforms.org/abc/fr/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Journal</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Material</head><p>Results of factor analysis of the additional scales</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PRU</head><p>We tested the four-factor model of the Gerrity et al., (1995) PRU scale. We observed the same structure as theirs, with all factor loadings ranging between 0.49 and 1.00. This model explained 61% of the variance (α = .85). We chose to stick to this model for further analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DTS</head><p>We tested the model described by Wagener and Blairy (2015) comprising 4</p><p>lower-order factors comprised in one higher-order factor. First, we tested a four-factor model.</p><p>We found a somewhat similar structure, but many items were saturated in a different factor than the one Wagener and Blairy had described as their original factor. Firstly, the "Absorption" and "Appraisal" factors were partly mixed into one factor (with factor loadings ranging from 0.53 to 0.94). We found the "Tolerance" factor (with factor loadings ranging from 0.50 to 0.98), but item 5 was missing and saturated at 0.42 in the factor mixing the "Absorption" and "Appraisal" factors. Items 11 and 12 of the "Appraisal" factor constituted a new single factor (with factor loadings ranging from 0.68 to 1.00). We partially found the "Regulation" factor, with items 8 and 13-factor loadings ranging from 0.84 to 0.97, but item 14 only loading at 0.38. Furthermore, item 7 saturated similarly in several factors, and item 6 did not saturate in any factor. This model explained 54% of the variance. To test for a unidimensional structure corresponding to the general factor described by Wagener and Blairy, we calculated the cronbach's alpha of this scale. Its value was very high (α = .91). We, therefore, decided to retain the unidimensional structure of this scale.</p><p>For the unidimensional scales we calculated their Cronbach's alpha. All cronbach's alphas were satisfactory (NFCO: α = .85; NFC: α = .84; TAMSAD: α = .</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incertitude médicale et processus de décision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Abecassis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Communication aux Ateliers thématiques en économie de la santé: Rationalité et processus de décision. Dijon: Forum-Latec</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Individual versus Team-Based responses to Script Concordance Test in Teaching Clinical Reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Abouzeid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sallam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.21203/rs.3.rs-196274/v1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-196274/v1" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factors Associated with Physician Tolerance of Uncertainty: an Observational Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Begin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hidrue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lehrhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Del Carmen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Armstrong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wasfy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of General Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncertainty in health care environments: myth or reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Begun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kaissi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1097/00004010-200401000-00005</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1097/00004010-200401000-00005" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Health care management review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="39" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intolerance of uncertainty: Exploring its dimensionality and associations with need for cognitive closure, psychopathology, and personality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Berenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bredemeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.janxdis.2007.01.004</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.janxdis.2007.01.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of anxiety disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Bhise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Rajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Sittig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chaudhary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Defining and measuring diagnostic uncertainty in medicine: a systematic review</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Need for cognition scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Cacioppo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Petty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Kao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Measurement Instrument Database for Social Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fearing the unknown: A short version of the Intolerance of Uncertainty Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Carleton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P J</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Asmundson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.janxdis.2006.03.014</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.janxdis.2006.03.014" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of anxiety disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of a Novel Adult Congenital Heart Disease-Specific Patient Reported Outcome Metric</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cedars</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vittengl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Stefanescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Jarrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Spertus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1161/JAHA.119.015730</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.119.015730" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Heart Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Clinical Decision Making by Fourth-Year Pharmacy Students: Understanding Their Uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Charrois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nurses&apos; Uncertainty in Decision-Making-A Literature Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cranley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Doran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tourangeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kushniruk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Nagle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1741-6787.2008.00138.x</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1741-6787.2008.00138.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Worldviews on Evidence Based Nursing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding clinical uncertainty: what is going on when experienced surgeons are not sure what to do?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cristancho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Apramian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vanstone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lingard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Novick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Medical Colleges</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Academic medicine: journal of the Association of</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1097/ACM.0b013e3182a3116f</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1097/ACM.0b013e3182a3116f" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The difficulties in emotion regulation scale (DERS)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Dan-Glauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Scherer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1024/1421-0185/a000093</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1024/1421-0185/a000093" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Swiss Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Principal component analysis with missing values: a comparative survey of methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Josse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11258-014-0406-z</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11258-014-0406-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Plant Ecology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">216</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="657" to="667" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">effectiveness of critical thinking instructional strategies in health professions education: a systematic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dugas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hedayati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Karavidas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Buhr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Phillips</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/03075079.2019.1586330</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/03075079.2019.1586330" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in Higher Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="829" to="843" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How and when do expert emergency physicians generate and evaluate diagnostic hypotheses? A qualitative study using head-mounted video cued-recall interviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pelaccia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tardif</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Triby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ammirati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bertrand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Dory</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Charlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.annemergmed.2014.05.003</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.annemergmed.2014.05.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Emergency Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="585" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Missing data methods for dealing with missing items in quality of life questionnaires. A comparison by simulation of personal mean score, full information maximum likelihood, multiple imputation, and hot deck techniques applied to the SF-36 in the French 2003 decennial health survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Peyre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leplège</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Coste</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quality of Life Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="300" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">This wasn&apos;t in the manual&quot;: a qualitative exploration of tolerance of uncertainty in the practicing psychology context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Quinlan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schilder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Deane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Australian Psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Que peuvent apporter les sciences humaines et sociales à la recherche en médecine d&apos;urgence?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Riou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Feral-Pierssens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tourette-Turgis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tazarourte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Freund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pelaccia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Riou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3166/afmu-2018-0118</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.3166/afmu-2018-0118" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differentiating intolerance of uncertainty from three related but distinct constructs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Rosen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ivanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Knäuper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/10615806.2013.815743</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10615806.2013.815743" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Stress &amp; Coping</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Anxiety</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Advice on exploratory factor analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Samuels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Déterminants des réactions face à l&apos;incertitude des internes de médecine générale en France: l&apos;étude DERFI-IMG (Doctoral dissertation)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sandid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Performance of two prognostic scores that incorporate genetic information to predict long-term outcomes following resection of colorectal cancer liver metastases: An external validation of the MD Anderson and JHH MSK scores</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sasaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gagnière</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dupré</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Ardiles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>O'connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Margonis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/jhbp.963</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jhbp.963" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Hepato Biliary Pancreatic Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychometric properties of the brief persian version of the Difficulties in Emotion Regulation Scale (The DERS-16)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shahabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hasani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bjureberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1534508418800210</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1534508418800210" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Assessment for Effective Intervention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="143" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dilemma of diagnostic uncertainty when treating people with chronic low back pain: a qualitative study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Slade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Molloy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Keating</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0269215511420179</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0269215511420179" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinical rehabilitation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="558" to="569" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reliability of Uncertainty Tolerance Scales Implemented Among Physicians and Medical Students: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Stephens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Karim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sarkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lazarus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1097/ACM.0000000000004641</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1097/ACM.0000000000004641" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academic Medicine: Journal of the Association of American Medical Colleges</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple imputation with large data sets: a case study of the Children&apos;s Mental Health Initiative</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Stuart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Azur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Frangakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Leaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/aje/kwp026</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/aje/kwp026" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American journal of epidemiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">169</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1133" to="1139" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Strout</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hillen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gutheil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hutchinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tolerance of uncertainty: A systematic review of health and healthcare-related outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.pec.2018.03.030</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2018.03.030" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Patient Education and Counseling</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1518" to="1537" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">&amp; Nanda, A. DIS We tested a two-factor model to compare it to the model proposed by Wagener and</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kalakoti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Thakur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Dossani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Patra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">We observed the same two-factor structure that explained 47% of the variance (α = .62)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blairy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page">10</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>All factor loadings ranged between 0.35 and 0.94. We retained this model</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">We tested a two-factor model for comparisons with the Lesage et</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page">structure</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">We tested a second model without item 7. The factor loadings ranged from 0.48 to 0.73 and it explained 37% of variance (α = .79)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>But item 7 was cross-loaded with low values (0.31 in the factor where it should not be and 0.22 in its original factor). We retained this model. DERS-16</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">We tested the 5-factor model described in the literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bjureberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shahabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><surname>Westerlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Santtila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Goals&quot;) at 0.50. We found factor 2 (with factor loadings ranging from 0.71 to 0.94) plus item 16, and factor 4 (with factor loadings ranging from 0.93 to 0.94) minus item 10. This model explained 65% of the variance. We tested this 5-factor model again without items 10 and 16. The model explained 67% of the variance and we found all the factors described in the literature. The factor loadings were good</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiğit &amp; Guzey</forename><surname>Yiğit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>with factor loadings ranging from 0.48 to 1.05) and 3</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">with factor loadings ranging from 0.61 to 1.04)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>But item 10 from factor 4 (&quot;Nonacceptance&quot;) loaded at 0.38 into factor 5 and item 16 from factor 5 loaded into factor 2. ranging from 0.48 to 1.04 for factor 1, from 0.66 to 0.90 for factor 2, from 0.60 to 1.08 for factor 3, from 0.78 to 1.05 for factor 4 and from 0.41 to 0.92 for factor</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">We also found factor 2 (i.e., perception of the constructive side of uncertainty, with loading factors ranging from 0.49 to 0.75). However, item 27 is only saturated with a value of 0.30 and also saturated in factors 1 and 3 (at -0.23 and -0.21). As for factors 1 and 5, they were partly mixed. This grouping of items included all of the items in factor 5 (i.e., uncertainty management through avoidance) and all of the items in factor 1 (i.e., perception of the wearing side of uncertainty), minus items 1 and 11 (with loadings ranging from 0.42 to 0.84). the factor combining factors 1 and 5 and in the new factor combining items 1 and 11 (at 0.47 and 0.45). We decided to test a 4-factor model</title>
		<idno>α = .90</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">This model explained 45% of the variance. We found factor 3 (i.e., uncertainty management through control, with loadings ranging from 0.44 to 0.77) and factor 4 (i.e., uncertainty management through reinsurance, with loadings ranging from 0.49 to 1.06)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The remaining factor was a mixture it loaded similarly in all three factors (-0.25 for factor 1, 0.30 for factor 2, and -0.20 for factor 3). Thus, we reran our analysis using this model without item 27. We found the same structure with satisfactory saturations (between 0.47 and 0.76 for factor 1 (grouping of initial factors 1 and 5), 0.47 and 0.74 for factor 2, 0.46 and 0. 47 and 1.07 for factor 4) and the model still explained 44% of the variance (α = .82). We decided to keep this model for further analysis</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
