<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Electron Observer Theory: A Neuroscientific Approach to the Mind-Body Problem and Measurement Problem</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuqi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>yuqiect@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Electron Observer Theory: A Neuroscientific Approach to the Mind-Body Problem and Measurement Problem</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:41+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This manuscript is a preprint and has not yet been subjected to peer review. The author is actively engaged in further testing and refining the theories and methods outlined, particularly those mentioned in Section V. Comments, suggestions, and constructive criticism are welcomed. The author encourages independent verification or falsification of the theories presented herein.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>Associating consciousness with quantum mechanics has faced criticism in the past. Common arguments against it were either the body environment is hostile to quantum effects or the misunderstanding of "quantum mechanics is about microscopic objects." Recent experimental confirmations of quantum mechanics <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bild, et al. 2023)</ref> and the increasing relevance of its strangest predictions, such as superpositions and entanglement, which are theoretically possible even for macroscopic objects <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Schrödinger 1935)</ref>, have expanded our understanding of quantum principles, highlighting that quantum effects are not determined by scale but rather by information accessibility. In Electron Observer Theory (EOT), the electron is not isolated but rather interacts with each "environment fragment", a notion proposed in Quantum Darwinism <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Zurek 2009)</ref>, during the occurrence of neural signals. Therefore, it is not limited to environmental conditions.</p><p>Several researchers have discussed the notion of a single neuron being conscious <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bieberich 2002)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Edwards 2005)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Sevush 2006</ref>). Argonov discussed the idea of a single electron possessing consciousness (V. Y. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Argonov 2012)</ref>. Remarkably, EOT arrives at a similar conclusion as these papers, despite being developed independently and approaching the question from a different perspective.</p><p>EOT is based on two postulates: 1. Each particle (molecular or smaller particle) in your body is individually conscious. 2. Conscious decisions are affected by subjective feelings. To satisfy these two postulates, a new model is proposed to explain the mind-body problem, using a springpowered machine as an analogy: each particle in the spring is an individual observer and experiences the force around it as its subjective feelings; as the spring returns to its equilibrium position, it pushes the next gear to make the machine move; as the spring gets compressed, the machine stops moving. This spring is one of the neurons in the most integrated area of the brain, and it makes final conscious decisions based on the input it receives. And each particle in the spring is an electron that contributes to the membrane potential. The positive or negative electric force the electron experiences is consistent with the neuron's action.</p><p>Psychologically, this idea fits Freud's pleasure principle <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Freud 1920)</ref>. Philosophically, it fits determinism. And it's compatible with much experimental evidence of consciousness research in neuroscience <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Sevush 2006)</ref>. In quantum theory, an electron is not a tiny marble but rather an "elementary particle" characterized by a set of quantum properties, including mass, charge, spin, etc. One of its propertiesposition is determined by a probability distribution that is only resolved upon measurement. Meanwhile, according to EOT, subjective experience does not exist until brain signals reach the Dominant Neuron(DN), change its membrane potential, and cause the electrons to be detected and entangled with the environment fragment correlates with the input information. This process is guided by the principle of einselection <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Zurek 2009)</ref>. The brain creates the conscious experience at that moment, giving you a spatial location in the universe, which is the electron's location. Your subjective experience at that moment is the electron's subjective experience observing the quantum system it's in. This also provides a radical solution for the measurement problem in quantum mechanics.</p><p>EOT describes the model of the universe as follows:</p><p>1. The environment is not a whole but made of environment fragments(Ɛ) <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Zurek 2009)</ref>  <ref type="figure">(Fig.  6</ref>).</p><p>2. The universe is superdeterministic (Hossenfelder 2020).</p><p>3. The universe is a many-world.</p><p>4. Each observer(elementary particle) exists in Ɛ itself. The observer observes things in Ɛ in a measured state; things outside of Ɛ remain in a superposition <ref type="figure">(Fig.7)</ref>. Everything you are observing at this moment is in Ɛ.</p><p>5. Unlike the original Many-world Interpretation(MWI) <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Everett III 1957)</ref>, which posits that the world splits into branches upon each quantum measurement without explaining why an observer's subjective experience follows one specific branch rather than another, EOT offers a different perspective. In EOT, each branch of the world already exists and is entangled with at least one observer rather than splitting into branches. And the existing branches merge upon interaction. Though the concepts differ, EOT and MWI are mathematically equivalent. <ref type="figure">(Fig.8)</ref> The problem is how a human observer can be conceptualized as a single electron. In the following sections, EOT will detail the underlying mechanism, drawing upon the two postulates.</p><p>In summary, the Electron Observer Theory (EOT) presents a compelling new perspective on the relationship between observer and quantum measurement. If the two underlying postulates are valid, EOT could serve as a critical bridge to understanding the four biggest unsolved problems: the measurement problem in quantum mechanics, the hard problem of consciousness, the finetuning problem, and the paradox of free will and determinism.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. POSTULATE 1</head><p>Consider this question. Imagine if your body was split down the middle and each half was placed in separate rooms. Which half would you experiencethe left or the right? The feasibility of such a scenario raises questions: How would each half remain alive? And is half of your body still "you"?</p><p>To circumvent these issues, let's add something to the scenario. Suppose we use identical atoms from other sources to recreate the right half of your body and connect it to your existing left half, and vice versa for the other room. This ensures that both entities remain biologically viable with the same neuronal connections you originally had. From a third person's view, these two bodies would appear indistinguishable. Yet the intriguing question arises: From your perspective, which body would you be experiencing?" <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1</ref>).</p><p>To answer the question, let's consider another thought experiment. Suppose an alien places you in Room A and crafts an identical replica of you, right down to the molecular level, in Room B. This doppelganger possesses the exact neural composition as you and even shares the conviction that it is, in fact, you. To ensure identical neuronal structure, the alien designs both rooms to be identical to each other, keeping your experience the same as the doppelganger <ref type="figure">(Fig.  2)</ref>.</p><p>The experiment deepens. The alien meticulously swaps a single molecule from your body with the same molecule from your copy. This initial exchange goes unnoticed because you've essentially swapped like for like, maintaining your overall structures. But the experiment doesn't stop here. The alien proceeds to exchange every molecule between the two of you until a complete swap has occurred <ref type="figure">(Fig. 3)</ref>.</p><p>From an external observer's perspective, no change is discernible. Both entities remain identical. From your viewpoint, the initial exchanges seem inconsequential. Yet, by the end, every molecule constituting your original self has shifted to another room. In a purely materialist and monistic understanding-where the mind and body are inseparable-your subjective experience should now be tethered to where the entirety of your molecules are located. Therefore, if all your molecules have moved to Room B, then "you" should now experience the body in Room B. But when, during this molecular dance, did "you" shift rooms? Which molecule is exchanged? And if we were to run this experiment by exchanging cells, which cell marks the shift?</p><p>This leads to a thought-provoking hypothesis: Your consciousness might be pinned to a single, pivotal particle within you. Perhaps you are merely a "receptor", experiencing the vast data stored and transmitted by your brain's neural architecture.</p><p>While it might seem like a bold proposal, conducting this experiment on larger scales reveals intriguing insights. If we execute the swap at an organ level, it becomes immediately apparent that the brain acts as the critical determinant of consciousnessa conclusion widely recognized in the scientific community. Digging further into this concept, if we were to transition from swapping organs to exchanging specific clusters of cells, we're drawn to speculate that perhaps a particular region of the brain functions as the epicenter of one's self-awareness. This idea gained traction from numerous neuroscientific studies that have identified certain brain regions as more central to consciousness than others <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Crick and Koch 2005)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Koubeissi, et al. 2014)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Yin, et al. 2016)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Wong, Nair and Augustine 2021)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Nikolenko, et al. 2021)</ref>, and most of our mental processes are unconscious processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bargh and Morsella 2008)</ref>. Taking the granularity even further, if we entertain the idea of switching individual cells, it resonates with the single-neuron theory of consciousness <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Sevush 2006</ref>). Yet, the question remains: How can one neuron possess consciousness? Taking our molecule-swapping scenario, we propose that a molecule, maybe even something smaller, acts as an observer with subjective experience as its inherent quality. Consider your body's various components, including your brain's sections, as tools. They house your memories, enable your thinking, and shape your personality. Yet, at the core, you could be a tiny entity functioning as a "sentient receptor".</p><p>While the thought experiment may seem abstract, it parallels ongoing biological processes we experience daily. Millions of cells undergo programmed cell death every second. In seven years, while most of our cells get replaced at least once, many neurons in the central nervous system remain unaltered.</p><p>Therefore, we propose Postulate 1-each particle (molecular or smaller particle) in your body can be individually conscious based on this thought experiment. A previous paper also presented a similar idea (V. Y. Argonov 2012).</p><p>Note: In the thought experiment, within the identical confines of the rooms, neither you nor your doppelganger would recognize a change in location. Upon exiting, despite the distinct external environments hinting at a transfer, both versions would be equally convinced of their originality. You, having the memory of entering room A but exiting from Room B, would believe you've been transferred. However, your copy exiting from Room A, grounded in the same memories and experiences, would assert its originality. The experience of transfer might be real, but it will be unknowable to any observer. This thought experiment hinges on the monistic perspective that subjective experience is intrinsically tied to the matter within one's body. (For instance, if one's body resides in the kitchen, one's experience is anchored there.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. POSTULATE 2</head><p>If we categorize animal (including human) behaviors into two groups -those that give individuals pleasant feelings and those that evoke unpleasant feelings; and further categorize these behaviors into another two groups -those that benefit the survival of the individual's genes and those that jeopardize it, a significant overlap between these dichotomies emerges( <ref type="figure">Fig.  4)</ref>. As a biological machine, an animal's behaviors are supposed to be random. Behaviors in the first dichotomy might be expected to manifest randomly in the second. So, what accounts for this overlap?</p><p>The hypothetical explanation is that regardless of the complexity of an animal's nervous system, the guiding principle for animals to make decisions is to seek pleasant feelings and avoid unpleasant feelings <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Freud 1920</ref>) (Loonen and Ivanova 2015) (V. Y. Argonov 2014). An animal can execute a behavior to achieve great pleasure regardless of whether it harms survival <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Olds and Milner 1954)</ref>. Behaviors, whether beneficial to survival or not, were assigned randomly. However, animals that would receive pleasant feelings from behaviors that are harmful to the survival of their genes will have a lower chance of survival and reproduction. Eventually, millions of years of evolution calibrated these two dichotomies, resulting in overlapping the two dichotomies.</p><p>However, while there is a significant overlap between the two dichotomies, exceptions exist. Certain behaviors might be pleasurable but not necessarily beneficial for genetic survival, and vice versa. Such behaviors can be attributed to:</p><p>1. Environmental Change and Evolutionary Lag: Evolution operates over lengthy time scales. When the environment changes rapidly, the behaviors that were once advantageous might not align with what's beneficial in the current environment. There's a lag between environmental change and evolutionary adaptation. So, even if a behavior (e.g., consuming high-calorie foods) was beneficial in ancestral environments, it might not be in modern times, especially with issues like obesity. However, the pleasure derived from such behaviors remains.</p><p>2. Mutation: Random mutations are a driving force behind evolutionary change. Not all mutations are beneficial. Some might lead to pleasurable behaviors (e.g., an attraction to harmful substances like gasoline) that are not necessarily good for genetic survival. Over time, detrimental mutations would typically be weeded out by natural selection, but they can persist for some time.</p><p>While this hypothesis looks reasonable, one might argue against reducing all behaviors to the pleasure-pain dichotomy. There could be behaviors influenced by factors other than immediate subjective feelings, especially in humans, where culture, societal norms, and longterm planning play a role. Even Freud himself later developed his theory to include the idea of a "death drive" or "death instinct," which he believed could override the pleasure principle.</p><p>Freud's reality principle might overlook a critical aspect: the profound influence of the fear of death, a deeply rooted "unpleasant feeling." The reality principle may be reduced and fundamentally explained by the pleasure principle. Delving deeper into the definitions of "pleasant feelings" and "unpleasant feelings" provides clarity -they are not mere pleasure or pain. Pleasant feelings encapsulate a spectrum of positive sensations, such as pleasure, satisfaction, excitement, interest, impulse, even good smell, seeing beauty, etc. Unpleasant feelings include pain, fear, sadness, stress, anxiety, depression, bad smell, and even aversion to aesthetic displeasures. Notably, intricate emotions, such as anger, might involve a mix of both pleasant and unpleasant feelings.</p><p>Culture and societal norms shape the neural architecture of our brains, a dynamic learning process that influences our memory. Yet, at their core, decisions steered by these memories still operate on the pleasure-pain principle. For instance, in regions where consuming dog meat is normative, individuals derive pure gastronomic pleasure from it, unhindered by moral dilemmas. Conversely, in societies where dogs are cherished companions, the mere thought of consuming them can trigger aversion and guilt. This reaction doesn't stem from an abstract cultural perspective but from the tangible neural changes in the brain due to societal conditioning.</p><p>Though the nervous systems of advanced animals appear intricate, the underlying motivation for most behaviors revolves around either seeking positive feelings or evading negative ones. Consider a mother's selfless act to protect her child. If she has time to decide, the sheer emotional distress of envisioning harm befalling her offspring could surpass her apprehension of personal danger. In emergency scenarios, a mother might act on pure instinct, driven by deeply ingrained protective impulses, without thinking of the bad consequence, much like a deer confronting a predator to defend its young. Either way, the behavior is influenced by a balance between pleasant and unpleasant feelings.</p><p>Take another scenario: intentionally pricking your finger with a needle. This act, on the surface, contradicts the pleasure-pain paradigm. Yet, ask yourself, would you even consider such an act today if you've never read this text? There are always some positive feelings (such as feeling interested) that override the inherent negative sensations.</p><p>In summary, human choices, regardless of seeming cultural or societal influences, can be distilled down to the brain's foundational biological operations. Culture molds our neural pathways, which subsequently steer our experiences of pleasant and unpleasant, ultimately guiding our actions. Acts like eating dog meat may elicit varied responses across cultures, not due to intangible cultural norms, but because of distinct biological imprints left on individuals by their cultural environments.</p><p>A similar idea has been discussed in a previous paper (V. Y. Argonov 2014). While it's still a hypothesis, the overlap in the two dichotomies <ref type="figure">(Fig. 4</ref>) is undeniable and hard to explain by any other theory.</p><p>Thus, this is the second postulate for EOT: Every behavior of an animal that requires decision-making can be reduced to the pleasant-unpleasant principle regardless of the complexity of its nervous system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. THE SPRING ANALOGY AND THE MIND-BODY PROBLEM</head><p>The spring analogy</p><p>If both Postulate 1 and 2 are valid, how can they explain the mind-body problem? Postulate 2 states that subjective pleasant and unpleasant feelings can affect a physical body's motion. Then, according to Newton's first law of motion, they must be associated with a force. Combined with postulate 1, the particle must be able to generate a force to change the physical body's motion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fig. 5:</head><p>We can illustrate this mechanism through the analogy of a machine powered by a single spring. In this analogy, each particle in the spring represents an individual observer and experiences the surrounding force as its own subjective feelings. When the compressed spring returns to equilibrium, each particle "feels pleasant" and triggers a "chain reaction," initiating the machine's movement. Conversely, when the spring is compressed, each particle "feels unpleasant," the machine loses motivation. Thus, the influence of subjective feelings on the physical body also complies with the laws of physics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Neuronal Correlate</head><p>Where can we find such a spring-like structure in a human-machine? The structure must possess the following features:</p><p>1. Extensive connections for receiving input and transmitting output.</p><p>2. The capability to react quickly and repeatedly to neural signals in the brain.</p><p>Therefore, The neuronal membrane in a highly integrated brain region appears to be the only structure that fulfills these criteria. Each particle in the spring is an analogy to each charged particle contributing to the membrane potential. The neuronal membrane's activity will decide whether to stop or initiate a conscious action. When a conscious action is stopped, the spring(neuronal membrane) is compressed away from its equilibrium position, where the intracellular environment becomes more negatively charged. Thus, the particles in the spring analogy correspond to negatively charged particles in the neuron, such as amino acid residues or ions. And the negative charges come from the electrons. (They can be life-long or temporary residents depending on their location --whether they would be replaced by metabolism.)</p><p>We term this neuron the "Dominant Neuron" (DN) because of its extensive connection and the ability to impact numerous neural activities in the body. The predicted existence of the DN aligns with prior studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Edwards 2005)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Sevush 2006)</ref>. And its compatibility with neuroscience has been discussed well by them. However, the relationship between subjective feelings and decision-relative actions hasn't been assessed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The mind-body problem</head><p>If EOT is proven valid, it explains the mind-body problem as the following:</p><p>(1) Every electron is individually conscious. Only those contributing to DN's membrane potential are associated with human consciousness. It is unclear whether it's in the membrane of soma, dendrites near soma, or the axon, as the membrane potential varies in different parts <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Beaulieu-Laroche, et al. 2018</ref>).</p><p>(2) Human consciousness/subjective experience (e.g., color, shape, sound, taste) includes subjective feelings (pleasant and unpleasant feelings). Each electron observes the quantum system it's in as its subjective experience while experiencing positive and negative electric force as subjective feelings. The subjective feelings have a causal effect on the physical body because it's associated with a force.</p><p>(3) DN is constantly active whenever one is conscious, receiving neural signals from the brain. Micro-plans are made in the unconscious part of the brain <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Haggard and Eimer 1999)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Libet, et al. 1983</ref>) (Salvaris and Haggard 2014) (Bode and Haynes, Decoding sequential stages of task preparation in the human brain 2009) <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Bode, He, et al. 2011</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Soon, Brass, et al. 2008</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Soon, He, et al. 2013)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Perez, et al. 2015</ref>) (Fried, Mukamel and Kreiman 2011) and sent to DN for approval. While EOT partially agrees with the previous papers, it's more compatible with the other paper (Uri Maoz 2019), suggesting that conscious deliberation may play an important role in decision-making when the decisions matter.</p><p>(4) In daily life, most information you receive is associated with excitatory neurotransmitters released by the adjacent neurons of DN and received by DN whenever you are thinking or experiencing things that interest you even slightly. While you (the electron) experience positive electric force, DN repeatedly reaches action potential and sends signals to the next neuron, causing a "chain reaction" to execute the action or make you think of more related topics if the plan is not associated with motor function. The detail of the "chain" is unclear. Hypothetically, the neural impulses caused by DN may trigger the reward system, enhancing the micro-plan and causing the action to happen. Moreover, the reward pathway can also send signals to DN.</p><p>(5) Some information is associated with inhibitory neurotransmitters released by the adjacent neurons of DN and received by DN(e.g., images of snakes, trypophobia, repulsive smell, pain, expecting pain). While you( the electron) experience increasing negative electric force, the membrane potential in DN temporarily drops and denies the micro-plan. This mechanism protects you from potential danger, and some of the unpleasant feelings may involve the neural pathways in the amygdala.</p><p>(6) Each micro-plan is extremely short and takes milliseconds to hundreds of milliseconds. For a large plan, say, deciding whether to go to a certain restaurant, it'll be a combination of a large amount of micro-plans. (e.g., approve the micro-plan when thinking about the tasty food; deny the micro-plan when thinking about the price or bad service, etc.). When you decided not to go to the restaurant, DN either denied a micro-plan because of the negative feelings in the restaurant or approved a micro-plan that motivated you to drive away, such as thinking about another restaurant. And while you are driving away, other micro-plans may come to your mind to make you regret and change the previous decision.</p><p>(7) Your brain is constantly thinking and sending other micro-plans to DN, and each microplan is so short that denying a micro-plan doesn't completely stop the macroscopic body movement. Another micro-plan will instantly reach DN and motivate you to move or think. For example, milliseconds after unpleasant feelings about restaurant service, other things like food shows and work could come to your mind. However, constant pain and extreme fear can frequently and significantly drop DN's membrane potential to affect the thinking process.</p><p>(8) Hypothetically, DN is not merely a decision-making gate for action. It should also be a key for the cognitive thinking process to decide whether to believe information. For example, for someone without math training, it's hard to believe whether 27×28=756 is correct. For someone who has a certain training, by sending the long-term memory to DN one by one (e.g.,7×8=56; 2×8=16; 16 add 0→160; 27×2=54; 54 add 0→540.), because normal thinking processes are associated with excitatory neurotransmitters, DN will reach action potential when checking these micro-plans, approve them one by one and send feedback to the brain to create short-term memory of "56, 160, 540". Then, your brain uses the memory of addition to send more multiple micro-plans one by one(160+540=700; 700+56=756) to DN again. DN finally approved that "756" is a believable answer. (The micro-plans in different individuals' brains can differ based on their training.) For another piece of information like "2344325+2344213= 4688538", we can't believe it's correct because we don't have a memory of it. But one can use the memory that 'calculators are always right' to create a short-term memory by looking at the calculator's screen and then deciding to believe the answer. Thus, the brain's basic mechanics may not be determining "true or false" but rather "believable or not believable" based on whether it has the memories to trigger DN. When the brain thinks something is false, it needs a working memory to "believe it to be false." This could provide a neuroscientific explanation for why repeated exposure to something (leading to its long-term memory storage) makes the information seem more true <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Kahneman 2011)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Veritasium 2016</ref>).</p><p>(9) Micro-plan" and "memory" are synonyms in the context, as they can all be interpreted as specific neural pathways sending signals to DN. And "real-time experience" is just when sensory neurons are involved in the neural pathways.</p><p>(10) Different pleasant and unpleasant subjective feelings (e.g., pleasure, good taste, fear, sadness, etc. ) can be associated with the amplitude and frequency of the membrane potential of DN. And the electron's quantum state plays a role in distinguishing where the sensation comes from (e.g., eye, tongue, inner brain, etc.). They are the components that form complex emotions.</p><p>Although some of the explanations can be speculative, EOT is compatible with numerous scientific studies in neuroscience and psychology. Moreover, EOT explains the mechanism of the mind-body problem more explicitly and is very falsifiable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. COMPATIBILITY WITH QUANTUM MECHANICS</head><p>EOT and Quantum Darwinism(QD)</p><p>How should we interpret the idea that an electron is an observer? In quantum theory, an electron is not a tiny marble but rather an "elementary particle" characterized by a set of quantum properties, including mass, charge, spin, etc. One of the properties, position, is determined by a probability distribution that is only resolved upon measurement. Meanwhile, according to EOT, subjective experience does not exist until brain signals reach DN, change the membrane potential, and cause the electrons to be detected.</p><p>According to QD, the environment is not a whole but rather a collection of environment fragments(Ɛ), and each Ɛ is also a quantum system <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Zurek 2009)</ref>. It doesn't matter how fuzzy the body's environment is. Whenever brain signals reach DN, the electron in DN is always in an Ɛ. <ref type="figure">(Fig. 6)</ref> Take visual observation as an example. At this very moment, when you are looking at the screen, the photons reach the photoreceptors in the retinas, initiating a chain of neural signals. The neural signal propagates through a certain number of neurons to reach DN and interacts with the electrons in DN. The photons' information is deposited in these environment fragments along this neural pathway. The electron's quantum state becomes strongly correlated with the photons and every particle involved in this neural pathway for a brief moment until the next signal reaches DN.</p><p>From another perspective, if we regard the electron in DN as an observable and the photons as an observer, then when the signal reaches DN and interacts with the electron, the quantum state of the electron is einselected <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Zurek 2009)</ref> to fit the quantum state of the photons and the particles involved in this specific neural pathway. Thus, the state of consciousness is einselected to fit the environment.</p><p>For other sensory observations, the neural pathway will involve other sensory neurons rather than photoreceptors. For internal experiences such as memory and dreams, there won't be sensory neurons involved but only the neurons in the brain. Because the particles in the neural pathway in the brain always play a significant role in Ɛ, we often don't perceive reality as it is (Hoffman and Prakash 2014) (D. Hoffman 2019) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Adelson 1995)</ref>.</p><p>At any given moment, only a small portion of neurons are involved in creating the subjective experience. Although you have a life-long amount of memories stored in many places in your brain <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Huth, et al. 2016)</ref>, you can only experience a fragment in any given moment. For example, while reading this paper, you are not thinking about your best friend in childhood, your first pet, or your grandparents until I mention it, although these memories were encoded deeply in your brain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The measurement problem</head><p>If EOT can be proven, this view that we are an electron and everything we experience is in its Ɛ, along with QD, settles the measurement problem in quantum mechanics.</p><p>EOT can be seen as an observer-centric version of Many-world interpretation(MWI), and each electron in each branch of the wavefunction is an observer. It observes its Ɛ in a measured state, while things in other quantum systems are in a superposition. <ref type="figure">Fig. 7</ref>: For a quantum system(S1) made of two entangled electrons, each electron can "sense" the quantum state of the other electron and observe it in S1 in a measured state, while things outside of the quantum system remain a superposition. In another quantum system (S2) consisting of two entangled electrons, the electrons in S1 appear to be in a superposition, while they observe things in S2 to be in a measured state. So, whether a quantum observable is in a superposition or a measured state depends on different observers. Each electron in each branch of the wavefunction is an individual observer. <ref type="figure">Fig. 8</ref>: Using Wigner's friend thought experiment <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Wigner 1961)</ref> as an example. Suppose we let Wigner's friend (Jon) and Wigner each wear a gas mask and stay in each room with Schrödinger's cat <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Schrödinger 1935)</ref>. Before the door in the middle opens, there are already four branches of worlds, each observed by an observer.</p><p>Word 1: Jon's perspective. The white cat is dead; the orange cat is in a superposition.</p><p>Word 2: Jon's perspective. The white cat is alive; the orange cat is in a superposition.</p><p>Word 3: Wigner's perspective. The white cat is in a superposition; the orange cat is dead.</p><p>Word 4: Wigner's perspective. The white cat is in a superposition; the orange cat is alive.</p><p>When the door opens, World 1 or World 2 merges with World 3 or 4.</p><p>Suppose you were Jon and eventually found both cats alive when the door opened (World 2 and World 4 merge), then you have been in World 2 since the beginning and never interacted with World 1 or World 3.</p><p>This observer-centric version of MWI is mathematically the same as the original one but without the bizarre confusion of why an observer's subjective experience follows into one branch rather than the other.</p><p>Finally, EOT suggests that, for each branch of the world, its evolution is superdeterministic <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hossenfelder 2020)</ref>. According to EOT, the definition of a quantum measurement is the process by which information about an observable is transferred to Ɛ, where the particle-observer is. The eigenstate of an observable is einselected to fit the state of Ɛ. The randomness of the outcome of a quantum measurement may be because we never count the electron-observer's quantum state as a factor.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. FURTHER APPROACHES TO TEST EOT</head><p>There are three approaches we can work on to test EOT.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Examining the Existence of DN:</head><p>EOT predicts the existence of DN and its unique characteristics. Such a dominant neuron capable of significantly affecting many other neurons' activities is not easy to hide. It must have an extensive connection to various brain regions, including all four lobes in the cerebral cortex, ventral tegmental area, amygdala, and especially claustrum <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Crick and Koch 2005)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Koubeissi, et al. 2014)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Yin, et al. 2016</ref>) (Wong, Nair and Augustine 2021) <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Nikolenko, et al. 2021</ref>). Because of the hundreds of million years of calibration by evolution, DN's membrane activity becomes strongly correlated with the individual's conscious behaviors and subjective feelings. The membrane will drop for milliseconds whenever the individual feels unpleasant feelings, such as physical pain. However, performing such measurements in a living animal brain is challenging.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Simplified Simulation:</head><p>Another approach involves simulating simplified neurons and other cellular structures in a digital setting. The virtual neurons don't have to be exactly the same as the real neurons in structure but must maintain the basic mechanism, such as integrating dendritic input and sending axonal output. Let those individual virtual neurons and cells interact with each other, form colonies, and evolve in the virtual environment. EOT predicts that over time, the fittest colonies will inevitably develop a neuron resembling DN. The DN's activity (either inhibition or excitation) will align closely with the colony's macroscopic tendencies (avoiding danger or seeking beneficial elements). While this may not directly prove EOT, it will certainly make the theory more intuitive. Note that in large colonies composed of multiple neural circuits, some independent circuits may be associated with unconscious activities like the startle reflex, which are automatic reactions to avoid danger and may not necessarily be influenced by the DN of the colony. It can also be interpreted that each neural circuit possesses its own "DN".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Reconciling General Reality and Quantum Mechanics through EOT:</head><p>EOT serves as an observer-centric version of the Many-Worlds Interpretation (MWI). Each branch possesses its own space-time in this model, as observed by individual particle observers. How can we use this framework to reconcile General Relativity with Quantum Mechanics and address other conundrums?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VI. DISCUSSION</head><p>Consider this philosophical question: You experience your subjective reality from a location in space. But what's the precision of this location? Human size? Brain size?cm3?mm3? Does any scale make sense? If any, why such a size, and how does it explain the split-brain <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Sperry 1968)</ref> phenomenon?</p><p>EOT describes consciousness/subjective experience as a product selected by the information in the environment and the physical body. Its properties are given to fit the world. And one of the properties -position, is the electron's position. While subjective feelings are associated with electric force, the total subjective experience is associated with the electron's quantum state. It is consistent with QD that the electron's quantum state is einselected to fit the environment.</p><p>Everything you are seeing or experiencing at this moment is in Ɛ, observed from the location of an electron. Thus, consciousness/subjective experience can also be interpreted as "the world experiences itself from a location in space-time." And we shouldn't simply treat an electron as a tiny particle.</p><p>EOT proposes conceptualizing a multicellular organism as a colony of single-celled organisms rather than an entity when analyzing its subjective experience. Much like while viewing an ant colony as a single system may deepen our understanding of its collective behavior, when considering its subjective experience in this large system spread across two sides of a hill, applying the notion of subjective experience -"observe the world from a location" may be nonsensical or at least highly problematic. Although a human body is not as expanded as a hill, it still covers an enormous area relative to single-celled organisms. The tendency to view a multicellular organism as a single entity could be a result of evolutionary instincts that help us quickly identify friends or threats. While it helps us survive, it may also limit us from understanding the fundamental reality.</p><p>EOT also suggests that objective reality is a derivative phenomenon caused by the consensus of multiple observers when the information is shared. Fundamentally, reality is subjective. When the information is blocked, say, by Schrodinger's box, each observer can perceive their reality differently.</p><p>EOT is still a hypothesis based on two postulates. Despite being reasonable, there's no solid evidence to prove either of the postulates. Thus, further research needs to be done, as mentioned in section V. On the other hand, to falsify it, an alternative explanation is required. For example, when a researcher asks you to move your hand from right to left in a straight line as far as you can, normally, you would do it. But if a blade appears in the way, why would you stop before your hand gets cut? EOT's explanation is that DN gets inhibited by inhibitory neurotransmitters associated with negative feelings (e.g., expecting pain, imagining negative consequences after skin penetration). If EOT was wrong, what would be the alternative explanation, and how to prove it?</p><p>As speculative as EOT is, this does not stop us from thinking further while drawing upon it: if your subjective experience is determined by an electron's quantum state, which is a result of einselection to fit the external world, this correlation suggests that neither the world creates your consciousness nor your consciousness creates the world. Instead, they co-exist to fit each other. Information requires an observer to perceive, and they may be inseparable. This approach may help us understand the origin of the universe and the fine-tuning problem. The answer is speculativeevery possibility exists, and we simply exist in one of the universes that fit the existence of consciousness.</p><p>And other interesting questions arise, such as what's the subjective experience of a proton or positron, and how do they perceive the direction of time?</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Checker shadow illusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Adelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Checker_shadow_illusion" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Pleasure Principle as a Tool for Scientific Forecasting of Human Self-Evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Argonov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Evolution and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural Correlate of Consciousness in a Single electron</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Argonov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroQuantology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="276" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Unconscious Mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bargh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ezequiel</forename><surname>Morsella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhanced Dendritic Compartmentalization in Human Cortical Neurons</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Beaulieu-Laroche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">175</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="651" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recurrent fractal neural networks: a strategy for the exchange of local and global information processing in the brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erhard</forename><surname>Bieberich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biosystems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="164" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Schrödinger cat states of a 16-microgram mechanical oscillator</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Bild</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">380</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6642</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="274" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decoding sequential stages of task preparation in the human brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Bode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John-Dylan</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroimage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="606" to="613" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tracking the Unconscious Generation of Free Decisions Using UItra-High Field fMRI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Bode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">Hanxi</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chun</forename><forename type="middle">Siong</forename><surname>Soon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Trampel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John-Dylan</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">21612</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What is the function of the claustrum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francis</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Crick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">360</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1458</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1271" to="1279" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is consciousness only a property of individual cells?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">C W</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consciousness Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relative State Formulation of Quantum Mechanics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename><surname>Everett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hugh</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Reviews of Modern Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">454</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Beyond the Pleasure Principle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sigmund</forename><surname>Freud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1920" />
			<publisher>International Psycho-Analytical Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internally generated preactivation of single neurons in human medial</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Itzhak</forename><surname>Fried</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Mukamel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Kreiman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="548" to="562" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the relation between brain potentials and the awareness of voluntary movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Haggard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Eimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental Brain Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">126</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="128" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Objects of consciousness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Donald</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chetan</forename><surname>Prakash</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">577</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The case against reality: Why evolution hid the truth from our eyes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Donald</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>WW Norton &amp; Company</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking Superdeterminism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sabine</forename><surname>Hossenfelder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Physics (Frontiers in Physics)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">139</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural speech reveals the semantic maps that tile human cerebral cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Huth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wendy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>De Heer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frédéric</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jack</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Theunissen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gallant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">532</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="458" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Daniel Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electrical stimulation of a small brain area reversibly disrupts consciousness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohamad</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Koubeissi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabrice</forename><surname>Bartolomei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abdelrahman</forename><surname>Beltagy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabienne</forename><surname>Picard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Epilepsy &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TIME OF CONSCIOUS INTENTION TO ACT IN RELATION TO ONSET OF CEREBRAL ACTIVITY (READINESS-POTENTIAL): THE UNCONSCIOUS INITIATION OF A FREELY VOLUNTARY ACT</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Libet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Curtis</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elwood</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Gleason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dennis</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pearl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">brain</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">623</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Circuits regulating pleasure and happiness: the evolution of reward-seeking and misery-fleeing behavioral mechanisms in vertebrates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anton</forename><forename type="middle">J M</forename><surname>Loonen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svetlana</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ivanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The mystery of claustral neural circuits and recent updates on its role in neurodegenerative pathology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimir</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Nikolenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Functions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Positive reinforcement produced by electrical stimulation of septal area and other regions of rat brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Olds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Milner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of comparative and physiological psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">419</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preconscious Prediction of a Driver&apos;s Decision Using Intracranial Recordings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Omri</forename><surname>Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Mukamel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ariel</forename><surname>Tankus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rosenblatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1492" to="1502" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Yehezkel Yeshurun, and Itzhak Fried</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decoding intention at sensorimotor timescales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Salvaris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Haggard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">85100</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Die gegenw rtige Situation in der Quantenmechanik</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erwin</forename><surname>Schrödinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Naturwissenschaften (Naturwissenschaften)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="844" to="849" />
			<date type="published" when="1935" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single-neuron theory of consciousness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Sevush</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Theoretical Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">238</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="704" to="725" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting free choices for abstract intentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chun</forename><surname>Soon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">Hanxi</forename><surname>Siong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John-Dylan</forename><surname>Bode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PNAS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6217" to="6222" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chun</forename><surname>Soon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcel</forename><surname>Siong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans-Jochen</forename><surname>Brass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John-Dylan</forename><surname>Heinze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Chun Siong Soon, Marcel Brass, Hans-Jochen Heinze &amp; John-Dylan Haynes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="543" to="545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hemisphere deconnection and unity in conscious awareness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roger</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Sperry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">723</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Neural precursors of decisions that matter-an ERP study of deliberate and arbitrary choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uri</forename><surname>Maoz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gideon</forename><surname>Yaffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liad</forename><surname>Mudrik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">39787</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Illusion of Truth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Veritasium</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cebFWOlx848&amp;t=20s" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Remarks on the Mind-Body Question</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Wigner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Paul</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">the Scientist Speculates: An Anthology of Partly-Baked Ideas</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Changing the Cortical Conductor&apos;s Tempo: Neuromodulation of the Claustrum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kelly</forename><forename type="middle">L L</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aditya</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Augustine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Neural Circuits</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">658228</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Claustrum, consciousness, and time perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Devin</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Terhune</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Warren</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Smythies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Meck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="258" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum Darwinism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wojciech</forename><surname>Zurek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
