<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Ethical Choice Reversals</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenxu</forename><surname>Hao</surname></persName>
							<email>chenxu.hao@fau.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Chair of Autonomous Systems and Mechatronics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Friedrich-Alexander Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Weinberg Institute for Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Chair of Autonomous Systems and Mechatronics Department of Electrical Engineering Friedrich</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Alexander University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Erlangen-Nürnberg</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Ethical Choice Reversals</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:42+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>ethical decision</term>
					<term>preference reversals</term>
					<term>rationality</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Understanding the systematic ways that human decision making departs from normative principles has been important in the development of cognitive theory across multiple decision domains. We focus here on ethical decisions that impose difficult tradeoffs between the welfare and interests of different individuals or groups. Across three sets of experiments and in multiple decision scenarios, we provide the first clear evidence that contextual choice reversals arise in ethical choice settings, in just the way that they do in other domains ranging from economic gambles to perceptual judgments (Trueblood, Brown, Heathcote, &amp; Busemeyer, 2013; Wedell, 1991). Specifically, we find within-participant evidence for attraction effects in which choices between two options systematically vary as a function of features of a third dominated and unchosen option-a prima facie violation of rational choice axioms that demand consistency. Unlike economic gambles and most domains in which such effects have been studied, many of our ethical scenarios involve features for which there is no clear objective ranking. We provide empirical evidence and modeling analysis that shows that individual variation in these feature rankings partly explains observed variation in the attraction effects. We conclude by discussing how recent computational analyses of attraction effects may provide a basis for understanding how the observed patterns of choices reflect boundedly rational decision processes.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Understanding the systematic ways that human decision making departs from normative principles has been important in the development of cognitive theory across multiple decision domains <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Huber, Payne, &amp; Puto, 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">O'Curry &amp; Pitts, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Trueblood et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell, 1991)</ref>. Our focus in this work is on ethical or moral decisions-decisions concerned with the welfare of others <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Yu, Siegel, &amp; Crockett, 2019)</ref>. The primary contribution of our work is the first clear empirical evidence that systematic contextual choice reversals, or attraction effects, arise in ethical decisions. Such effects, arising in many choice domains and in many decision-making organisms, are among the most striking apparent violations of axioms of rational choice theory, which demand consistency. A secondary contribution of our work is a computational method for modeling individual differences in attribute rankings and deriving their implications for attraction effects. We show with this method that individually varying rankings partly explain observed variation in choice reversals across individuals and decision scenarios.</p><p>Ethical or moral decision making has been studied in a variety of ways. These include incentivized choices that involve harm or reward <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Crockett, Kurth-Nelson, Siegel, Dayan, &amp; Dolan, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Rand, Greene, &amp; Nowak, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">van Baar Jeroen, Chang, &amp; Sanfey, 2019</ref>) (e.g. decisions involving a trade-off between some monetary reward and the number of painful electric shocks directed to either self or another agent), and judgments about the moral appropriateness of actions involving the welfare of others (e.g., using hypothetical dilemmas such as the Trolley Problem; <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Awad, Dsouza, Shariff, Rahwan, &amp; Bonnefon, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barak-Corren, Tsay, Cushman, &amp; Bazerman, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Foot, 1967;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Kim et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Merlhiot, Mermillod, Jean-Luc, Dutheil, &amp; Mondillon, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Thomson, 1976)</ref>.</p><p>A common feature of these paradigms and much other work on ethical decisions is that the choices involve a tradeoff between the welfare or interests of different individuals or groups (often, but not always, including the decision maker). When these tradeoffs are particularly difficult, we refer to the choice problems as dilemmas.</p><p>Through careful experimental manipulation of features of these choice problems, behavioral scientists and moral philosophers have discovered many ways that ethical decisions depart from normative ethical theories or other normative decision and behavioral principles. A prominent example is moral luck <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Nagel, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Williams &amp; Bernard, 1981)</ref>, where judgments of moral blame or praise are based on consequences of actions where the consequences are out of the control of the actor (such judgments are thought to be inconsistent with a normative principle that morality should not be affected by luck; <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Kant, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Williams &amp; Bernard, 1981)</ref>. Another example is considering only a subset of the ethically-relevant attributes of a decision, or basing judgments or choices on non-relevant attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Nadurak, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Sinnott-Armstrong, Young, &amp; Cushman, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>One explanation for these and other departures from normative theory is that people use moral heuristics or "mental short-cuts" <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Sunstein, 2005)</ref> to make decisions. These heuristics may be understood as adaptive in that they strike a balance between cognitive effort and decision quality <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Gigerenzer, 2010)</ref>, but the practical concern is that they may also lead to undesirable consequences in law, politics, and other areas of public and private life <ref type="bibr">(Nadurak, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Sunstein, 2002)</ref>.</p><p>Our concern in this work is whether ethical decisions also exhibit violations of some of the most fundamental principles of axiomatic rational choice theory: consistency and independence. More specifically, our empirical question is whether contextual preference reversals arise in ethical choices, where a choice between two options or courses of action systematically varies as a function of properties of an unchosen option in the choice set. Such contextual preference reversals have been shown to arise in multiple choice domains, e.g. economic gambles, consumer goods, political candidates, perceptual size judgements <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Huber et al., 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">O'Curry &amp; Pitts, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Trueblood et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell, 1991)</ref> and in multiple decision making organisms, including humans, monkeys and slime molds <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Huber et al., 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Latty &amp; Beekman, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Parrish, Evans, &amp; Beran, 2015)</ref>. We will refer to these phenomena as contextual choice reversals rather than preference reversals, using a theoretically more neutral term that refers to the behavioral data rather than an internal cognitive construct (preferences).</p><p>In the remainder of the paper we first review the formal structure of decision problems that give rise to choice reversals, and summarize how we create ethical dilemmas with this formal structure. We then provide the details of our main experiments. Experiment 1 constructs ethical dilemmas that are isomorphic to a seminal study demonstrating choice reversals in economic gambles <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Wedell, 1991)</ref>, using variants of a single scenario (a choice among rescue plans after a natural disaster). This study yielded ethical choice reversals with a pattern nearly identical to the original economic experiment. Experiments 2 and 3 use a set of multiple distinct scenarios, including some that involve attributes without clear objective rankings. These scenarios also yield choice reversals, but to varying degrees. We show that variation among these scenarios and among individual decision makers can be explained in part by variation in individuals' subjective rankings of the choice attributes.</p><p>We conclude with a summary and a discussion of limitations of the studies. We also reconsider the question of rationality in light of new computational and mathematical models of multi-attribute decision-making that predict contextual choice reversals as a consequence of boundedly rational utility maximization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Contextual choice reversals and the attraction effect</head><p>Consider the following decision problem. You are choosing among three video games to purchase, and are weighing price against quality, here assessed as user experience of the game. The choices are a console-version video game that is very expensive and provides you with a great experience, a PC-version of the same video game that is cheaper but provides a lower-level experience, and a smartphone version that is the same price as the PC-version, but provides an even lower-level experience. Suppose that you opt here for the PC-version. But now consider a choice set with the same console-version and PC-version, but with a tablet version that provides the same great user experience as the console version but is more expensive. And suppose that faced with these options, you choose the console version.</p><p>You have exhibited a contextual choice reversal: you have switched your expressed preference between the console and PC-version of the game, dependent upon features of a third unchosen option. No matter how you tradeoff or weigh price and user experience, your choice behavior is inconsistent. Under a standard account, you either do not have stable preferences, or if you do, you did not choose rationally.</p><p>The structure of this example is a classic three-option two-attribute choice problem in which two options, termed target and competitor, are of roughly equal expected value but differ on both attributes: the target is superior to the competitor on one attribute but inferior on the other. The third option is a decoy and is dominated by the target, by being either inferior on both dimensions (2-dimensional dominance), or equal on one and inferior on the other (1-dimensional dominance). By changing the position of the decoy in attribute space, it is possible to change which of the other two options is the dominating option (and therefore the target). The empirical finding that moving the decoy in this way systematically changes preferences is known as the attraction effect, because the decoy positioning "attracts" additional choices. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> (a, left) shows possible placements of decoy options 1 using as an example choice among economic gambles <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Wedell, 1991)</ref>, where each option or gamble is a probability and value pair ⟨p, v⟩. Selecting option ⟨p, v⟩ means playing a gamble which pays out v with probability p and 0 with probability 1−p. The expected value of each option is thus pv. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> (b, middle) also shows the choice proportions reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> for both 1-dimensional (1D) and 2-dimensional (2D) variants of the decoy placement. Both the control and 1D and 2D problems involve the same set of A and B options; there is  <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> reversals in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> Figure 1: (a) Decoy placements illustrated with an example from <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>. When choosing among sets of gambles, the decision maker makes a trade off between two attributes: probability and the amount of money to win. Options A and B vary in both attributes but have the same expected value. As shown above, both A and C options have one-dimensional (1D) and two-dimensional (2D) decoys. When the third option, the decoy, is dominated by A, then A is the target and B is the competitor, and vice versa. (b) Choice proportions showing the attraction effect in both one-dimensional (1D) and two-dimensional (2D) dominance problems. The effect may be seen in the higher proportions of choices for the A options when the decoy is at A compared to when it is at B, and higher proportion of choices for the B options when the decoy is at B compared to when it is at A. There is an overall preference for option A. (c) Within-subject choice reversal rates in both 1D and 2D dominance problems reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>.</p><p>an overall preference for the A options (corresponding in the <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> stimuli to a risk-related preference for higher probability gambles). The decoy placement systematically yields the attraction effect for both A and B options, in both 1D and 2D decoy placements. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> (c, right) shows the within-subject choice reversal rates for pairs of decision problems reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> for 1D and 2D decoy placements. A pair of decision problems consist of identical A, B options, with the decoy separately dominated by A and B. If a participant always selects the target option in a pair, then there is a within-subject choice reversal. In most trials, participants choose consistently ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 15</ref>, Appendix B), and within-subject choice reversal rates are around 15% to 20%. To investigate contextual choice reversals in ethical decisions, we use three experiments that use ethical dilemmas that have the same formal structure as that shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. The challenge in designing such dilemmas is finding scenarios in which there is a trade-off between two attributes that impose the ethical dilemma, each of which admits three clearly distinct levels. Our first experiment addresses this challenge by creating ethical scenario isomorphs of the <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> stimuli, using the same probabilities and values as those stimuli.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials &amp; data availability</head><p>Experiment 1a &amp; 1b. All survey materials, data, and R analysis scripts are available from Open Science Framework: https://osf.io/9eqga/ Experiment 2 &amp; 3. All survey materials, data, and R analysis scripts are available from Open Science Framework: https://osf.io/w8nrm/?view only= 7a1d4608190742c6a188ce036e43d29d. Experiment 2 is pre-registered at https:// osf.io/4n9f7 and Experiment 3 is pre-registered at https://osf.io/7fdw8.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment 1</head><p>In Experiment 1a, we present a replication study of <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>, where participants made choices among sets of economic gambles. In Experiment 1b, we present a ethical decision study where participants made choices among disaster rescue plans isomorphic to the economic gambles in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Experiment 1a: Wedell (1991) replication</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">Method</head><p>Participants One hundred and fifty-five participants were recruited from undergraduate psychology subject pool at the University of Michigan. Five participants were excluded due to survey incompleteness. In total, 150 participants (104 female; age M(SD) = 19(0.76) years) were included in the data analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>We constructed a questionnaire that contained 40 pairs of questions (80 in total) with the original stimuli from <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991;</ref><ref type="bibr">Table 11</ref>, Appendix B). There were 10 pairs of questions for each type of decoy. Each pair contains two questions with the same A and B targets but different decoys: one dominated by A, and another dominated by B. Each participant completed a survey that contained 10 random pairs drawn from the 40 pairs of questions and all questions were displayed in a random order.</p><p>Here is one example of the question presented to the participants: Imagine you are presented with these three bets. Choose the bet you would most prefer to take.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>• .40, $25</head><p>• .40, $22</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>• .30, $33</head><p>All stimuli we used to construct the questionnaire are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 11</ref>, Appendix B, except for control decoys, which were constructed by altering the values of 1D decoys (R decoys) so that the control decoys were dominated by both targets <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>.</p><p>The goal of this experiment was to replicate <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>'s finding on how the type and position of decoy influence participants' choices on each pair. Thus, we were specifically interested in having decoy type and decoy position as the two predictors. In Wedell : Attraction effect across all trials, shown as choice proportions for A, B options in aggregate: (a). Attraction effect in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell(1991)</ref> with economic gambles; (b). Attraction effect in our <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> replication study with economic gambles (Experiment 1a); (c). Attraction effect in Wedell-isomorphic ethical dilemmas (Experiment 1b).</p><p>(1991), each participant completed 10 pairs of questions. Decoy position (atA, atB) was a within-subject variable. Decoy type (R, F, RF in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>'s Experiment 1 and R and control/R' in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>'s Experiment 2) and presentation order were between-subject variables. In our replication study, each person completed 10 pairs of questions. Both decoy position (atA, atB) and decoy type (R, F, RF, control/R') were within-subject variables.</p><p>Demographic information Participants answered a short demographic survey at the end. The questions include age, gender(male/female/other), age began to learn English, language used mostly at home, and highest grade completed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Descriptive analysis</head><p>We show the attraction effect 2 with choice proportions for the options across all trials below. Similar to what we see in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> results <ref type="figure">(Figure 2a</ref>), we observe attraction effects across trials in this experiment <ref type="figure">(Figure 2b</ref>). To gain insights on how participants choose the alternatives and to visualize the results, we analyzed the proportion of within-subject choice reversal for 1D and 2D decoy. To do this analysis, we categorized the response data into four types of response patterns for each pair of questions (e.g., <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 12</ref>, Appendix B): 1) choosing the same option for both questions in each pair (both As or both Bs), i.e., choosing consistently; 2) choosing targets for both questions in each pair (exhibiting a choice reversal); 3) choosing competitors for both questions in each pair (competitor reversal); 4) choosing decoy at least once.</p><p>As the majority participants had consistent choice within each pair regardless of decoy type, we focus on the target choice reversal rates and competitor reversal selection rates here ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>, full results see Appendix B).</p><p>In general, choice reversals occur around 20% of time within subjects <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 13</ref>, Appendix B) and proportions of choice patterns <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3c</ref>) are consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>'s original results <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3a</ref>) despite of the slightly high decoy selection rates (&gt; 10%) in our study. A clear choice reversal effect is observed for 1D decoys, whereas the choice reversal effect is weaker for the 2D decoy. In the control condition, least numbers of subjects exhibited choice reversal.</p><p>Bayesian statistical analysis Statistical analysis was conducted in R (R Core Team, 2013) using a Bayesian logistic regression model with RStan (Stan Development Team, 2017).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical models</head><p>We used a Bayesian multinomial logistic regression model to estimate the decoy type effect (1D, 2D, or control), the decoy position effect (atA, atB), and their interactions.</p><p>We set choosing B, decoy dominated by B, and decoy being one-dimensional (1D) as the reference category. Let m ∈ {1, 2, 3} denote the responses D, A, and B. Let P (Y ijk = m) denote the probability that the i-th participant's choice falls in the m-th category (i ∈ {1, 2, ..., N } is the index of subjects, j ∈ {0, 1} is the index of decoy positions. k ∈ {0, 1} is the index of decoy types). m P (Y ijk = m) = 1. The full model is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">categorical P (Y ijk = m) = β gm + β type m X ik + β decoy m X ij + β type * decoy m X ij X ik ,</formula><p>where categorical P (Y ijk = m) is the log probability of i-th participant choosing m, and β gm m estimates the log odds of choosing m to the baseline. When m = A, our main parameter of interest, β decoy A estimates the within-subject decoy position effect -the change in log odds of choosing A over B when decoy is moved from at B to at A. Parameter β type A estimates the effects of decoy types on the rate of choice reversals when it is considered together with the interaction term, β type * decoy A . More specifically, given our model baseline, parameter β type A , together with the interaction term, informs us whether there is a change in log odds of choosing m over B when decoy is 2D compared to 1D, as the decoy is changed from at B to at A. For example, a coefficient of log(1.3) for the combined two terms indicates a 30% increase in the log odds of choosing A over B.</p><p>Besides the full model, we also analyzed the data with a simple model excluding the control decoy or the interaction between decoy position and decoy type. This model is the Bayesian counterpart to the analysis used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref></p><formula xml:id="formula_1">'s original Experiment 1 (Appendix B).</formula><p>Priors Given that we do not have much prior information regarding our model parameters, we choose to select prior distributions that are neither fully informative nor flat. For the βs, we use weakly informative priors: normal(0, 5). shown in (a) for <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell(1991)</ref> original study with economic gambles, (c) for <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> replication study and (d) for ethical decisions. The posterior estimates for our main parameter of interest from the Bayesian logistic regression model, β decoy A , is shown in (b). When this parameter is above zero, it indicates that the logodds of choosing A to choosing B increases when decoy is changed to be dominated by A, suggesting a choice reversal effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chain convergence evaluation</head><p>For each model, we ran four independent chains and each of the four chains contains 2000 samples of each parameter. First 800 samples were part of the warmup (or burn-in period), which allows the sampling process to converge to the posterior distribution. We analyzed the samples after this period.</p><p>To interpret posterior distributions more cautiously and accurately, we first checked chain convergence through traceplots and Rhat <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Sorensen, Hohenstein, &amp; Vasishth, 2016)</ref>. The traceplots for parameters (not included) suggest that the chains have converged for all parameters the Rhat values from <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 15</ref>, Appendix B have shown convergence as well.</p><p>Posterior statistics The central tendencies and 95% credible intervals of the posterior distributions are reported in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 14</ref>, Appendix B. For the full model, the central tendencies and 95% credible intervals of the posterior distributions are shown in <ref type="figure">Figure  16</ref>, Appendix B. We will focus on parameters beta decoy A and types of decoy in our results. The mean estimate for our main parameter of interest, beta decoy A , is 0.34, showing a choice reversal effect. There is 40% increase in log odds of choosing A to B when decoy is moved from B to A. After adding the interaction, we can also see that when decoy is moved from B to A, compared to baseline category (1D decoy), 2D decoy has a weak positive effect (0.29 − 0.15 = 0.14, indicating 15% increase in log odds of choosing A to B). However, control decoy has a reversed effect (0.28 − 0.55 = −0.27, indicating 24% decrease in log odds of choosing A to B).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Experiment 1b: Ethical choice</head><p>Following our <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> replication, we created ethical dilemmas by transforming the tasks in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> into isomorphic problems. The isomorphs were created by preserving the numerical values of the ⟨p, v⟩ attributes of the original stimuli, but creating dilemmas from a forced choice among disaster rescue plans with different probabilistic outcomes for saving lives. The dilemma arises when one chooses between a plan with relatively moderately high probability of success but saving fewer lives, and a plan with a lower probability success but saving more lives. The tradeoff thus pits the lives of an imagined smaller group against the lives of a larger group.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Method</head><p>Participants Sixty participants were recruited from undergraduate psychology subject pool at the University of Michigan. Nine participants were excluded due to either: 1) not finishing the survey, or 2) failing the attention check question. In total, 51 participants (24 female; age M(SD) = 19(1.19) years) were included in the data analysis.</p><p>Materials In our experiment, decoy position (dominated by A/target versus dominated by B/competitor) and decoy type (1D, 2D, and control) were manipulated as withinsubject variables.</p><p>We constructed experimental materials that contains 40 pairs of ethical dilemmas (80 dilemmas in total), 10 pairs for each type of decoy. Each pair of dilemmas contained two questions with the same target and competitor choices but different decoys (dominated by A/at A and dominated by B/at B). Each participant completed a task that contains 10 random pairs of dilemmas and all questions were displayed in a random order. The task was implemented as a questionnaire using the Qualtrics software (Qualtrics, Provo, UT).</p><p>Since our ethical dilemmas are isomorphic to <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> tasks, all numerical values of the attributes are identical to <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>'s ⟨p, v⟩ attributes. The control decoys were created by altering the values of one of the 1D decoys so that the control decoys were dominated by both A and B.</p><p>An example of a pair of our task problems is shown in  Attention check. We gave participants one attention check question. This question was always presented at the end of the survey in order to avoid interference with other scenarios. The question stated that the participant can only have time to save people from one out of the three rooms in a burning house and asks the participant to choose from saving 1, 3, or 5 people.</p><p>Demographic survey. Participants answered a short demographic survey at the end. The questions included age, gender (male/female/other), age began to learn English, language used mostly at home, and highest grade completed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Descriptive analysis</head><p>The descriptive analysis was the same as that in Experiment 1a.</p><p>Similar to the results in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>  <ref type="figure">(Figure 2a</ref>) and in our replication study ( <ref type="figure">Figure  2b</ref>), attraction effects appear across trials in this experiment <ref type="figure">(Figure 2c</ref>). For the rest of the paper, we will include descriptive analyses of choice proportions across all trials in each experiment's corresponding Appendix. Generally, within-subject choice reversals occur around 10% to 15% (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 13</ref>, Appendix B). The proportions of choice reversals and choosing the competitor in both questions in a pair ("competitor reversal") in our ethical decision making study are very similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> original results ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3a)</ref>. A clear and strong choice reversal effect is observed for the 1D decoy type, whereas the choice reversal effect is less strong for the 2D decoy. In the control condition, we observe the lowest choice reversal rates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bayesian statistical analysis</head><p>We analyzed the data in the same way as we did in Experiment 1a. We first used a Bayesian multinomial logistic regression model to estimate the decoy type effect (1D, 2D, or control), the decoy position effect (atA, atB), and their interactions. Then, we also analyzed the data with the simple model excluding the control decoy or the interaction between decoy position and decoy type.</p><p>Priors For the βs, we used weakly informative priors: normal(0, 5).</p><p>Chain convergence evaluation For both models, we ran four independent chains and each of the four chains contains 2000 samples of each parameter. First 800 samples were part of the warmup (or burn-in period).The traceplots (not included) and Rhat values from  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3b</ref>). There is 111% increase in log odds of choosing A to B when the decoy is moved from B to A. By adding the interaction, we can also see that when the decoy is moved from B to A, compared to the reference category (1D), 2D decoy has a reversed effect (0.12 + (−0.31) = −0.19, i.e., log(.82) = log(1−0.18), indicating 18% decrease in log odds of choosing A to B). However, the control decoy has a reversed effect (0.27+(−1.01) = −0.74, i.e., log 0.48 = log(1−0.52), indicating a 52% decrease in log odds of choosing A to B). This result indicates that the 1D decoy has a stronger choice reversal effect than the 2D decoy, and the control decoy has a reversed effect. We will elaborate more on this in the discussion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">A comparison of performance and choice reversal rates between economic gambles (1a) and ethical choices (1b)</head><p>The economic gambles in our Wedell replication and the ethical isomorphs in Experiment 1 both allow us to assess behavioral choices in terms of expected value as an objective baseline. More specifically, the mean expected value of each participant's performance can be used as a measure that allows us to compare performance in the two experiments. We are also interested in comparing the rate of choice reversals in the two experiments, and understanding how the reversal rate might be related to performance across participants. We therefore conducted an exploratory Bayesian analysis with rstanarm (Goodrich, Gabry, Ali, &amp; Brilleman, 2020) to compare participants' performances and target reversal rates in the economic gambles (Experiment 1a) and in the ethical decisions (Experiment 1b). The statistical models are:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">performance =β 0 perf ormance + β 1 perf ormance economic gambles target reversal =β 0 targetreversal + β 1 targetreversal economic gambles,</formula><p>where the intercepts, β 0 s, estimate the mean performance and mean target reversal rates in ethical decisions (reference group); β 1 s estimate the mean difference in the performance and target reversal rates in ethical decisions and in economic gambles. All trials with control decoys were excluded from the analyses as these decoys were not expected to produce choice reversals in the first place. We used the default non-informative priors and ran four independent chains (4000 samples each, with the first 200 samples as the warmup).</p><p>In terms of performance, we found that participants in Experiment 1b (ethical decisions; N = 51, M = 9.96, SD = 0.06) performed better compared to participants in economic gambles (1a; N = 150, M = 9.83, SD = 0.22; β 1 perf ormance = −0.13, 95%  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 16</ref>. In terms of target reversal rates, participants in Experiment 1b (N = 51, M = 0.20,SD = 0.20) have slightly higher reversal rates than participants in economic gambles (1a; N = 150, M = 0.15,SD = 0.16; β 1 targetreversal = −0.04, 95% CI= [−0.10, 0.01]). However, note that the 95%CI includes 0. The distributions of target reversal rates in two are displayed in <ref type="figure">Figure 6b</ref>, and the full posteriors are reported in Appendix B, <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 17</ref>.</p><p>We also investigated the relationship between participants' performances and their within-subject target reversal rates in economic gambles and ethical decisions with a simple Bayesian regression model using rstanarm (Goodrich et al., 2020):</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">performance =β 0 + β 1 target reversal + β 2 ethical decisions + β 3 target reversal * ethical decisions,</formula><p>where "target reversal" is the centered values of an individual's target reversal rate and "ethical decisions" is a grouping variable, indicating whether the values correspond to Wedell 1991 replication study (reference group) or ethical decisions. We used the default non-informative priors and ran four independent chains (4000 samples each, with the first 200 samples as the warmup). We found that target reversal rates predict higher performance in economic gambles (β 1 = 0.60, 95%CI= [0.26, 0.93]), but not in ethical decisions (β 3 = −0.63, 95%CI= [−1.26, 0.01]; β 1 + β 3 &lt; 0)-plausibly because there is a ceiling effect in the ethical decisions (despite the higher reversal rate). The posterior estimates for model parameters and their 95% CIs are fully reported in Appendix B, <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 18</ref>. This relationship is interesting, because it suggests that higher reversal rates are not necessarily associated with lower performance-in fact the contrary, consistent with recent analyses suggesting that reversals are signatures of computationally rational choice strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Howes, Warren, Farmer, El-Deredy, &amp; Lewis, 2016)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Discussion</head><p>Our study is the first study that investigates and observes contextual choice reversals in the domain of ethical decision making by using tasks with the same structure as classic contextual choice reversal studies. By providing participants with ethical dilemmas that are isomorphic to the economic gambles in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>, we found evidence for choice reversals when the decoy was either one-dimensional or two-dimensional, with the former having a slightly stronger reversal effect. By comparing the data from Experiment 1a and 1b, we also found differences in performance and the relationship between performance and target reversal rates in data from economic gambles and ethical decisions: 1) the performance in ethical decisions is better; 2) higher target reversal rates predict better performance in economic gambles but not in ethical decisions, possibly due to a ceiling effect in ethical decisions.</p><p>Although we found evidence for contextual choice reversals in the ethical domain, we acknowledge several drawbacks of this Experiment. First, this task only involves two attributes (the probability of saving lives and numbers of lives that can be saved), both of which are measured on continuous scales, making it simple to compare the levels within each attribute (e.g., saving more lives is preferred and higher probability is preferred). Second, this task only involves one scenario-choosing a natural disaster rescue plan. In reality, people face ethical dilemmas in all kinds of scenarios-some could be high-level decisions such as determining rescue plans, but some could also be more immediate, personal decisions such as whether one should spend more money on a product that is fair-trade and environmental friendly. Based on our current task, we cannot directly generalize our findings to other ethical domains without further investigations, as ethical choices in other domains involve very different scenarios and attributes.</p><p>In the following experiments, we explore contextual choice reversals in ethical decisions further by creating tasks spanning various ethical domains, from personal choices involving weighing one's financial interest against fair trade practices, to choices connected to policies that influence the lives of groups of people.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiment 2</head><p>In our previous experiment, we found empirical evidence for contextual choice reversals in a domain that involves ethical decision making. However, the previous study only involved repeated tasks that contained the same two numerically-expressed attributes (probability of saving lives and numbers of lives saved) in a rescue-plan-selection scenario. Therefore, our new study aims to:</p><p>1. replicate our existing finding that contextual choice reversals can be observed in ethical decisions.</p><p>2. follow the design of the previous study and expand the decision tasks to various domains that involve ethical decisions.</p><p>One of the most challenging aspects of designing this experiment is to map the structure of contextual choice reversal tasks to ethical decisions in a greater variety of scenarios (rather than just the probability of saving lives and numbers of lives saved). To create the structure of contextual choice reversal tasks with a dominating target, a competitor, and a decoy option, we need three options with two attributes, and two to four levels in each attribute. This allows us to have the structure where the target and the competitor each is a dominating option on only one attribute, and the target dominates the decoy on both attributes ( <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>). If one of the two attributes have only two levels, then the target only dominates the decoy on one attribute. The target and competitor options also need to be approximately equally attractive. The ranking of the levels in each attribute needs to be clear (e.g., the fourth level is always preferred to the first level) among decision makers for the assumed dominance relationship in this structure to hold.</p><p>While number of lives saved have a clear objective rank as an attribute (i.e., larger numbers of lives saved are better), some specific ethical scenarios require us to use attributes whose levels do not have clear objective ranks. For example, in a dilemma, participants need to decide which prisoner to release while making a trade-off between the age of the victim and crime motivation. All prisoners in this dilemma robbed victims of different</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">level 1 level 2 level 3 level 4 level 1 level 2 level 3 level 4 attr 1 attr 2 target 2D decoy competitor level 1 level 2 level 3 level 4 level 1 level 2 level 3 level 4 attr 1 attr 2 competitor 2D decoy target 1D decoy 1D decoy 1D decoy</formula><p>1D decoy <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>: The structure for a pair of dilemmas that have the structure of a classic contextual choice reversal task. If both attributes have four levels, then we can create twodimensional decoys. If one of the attributes have two levels, we can create a pair of dilemmas with one-dimensional decoys. For example, if attr 1 only has level 2 and level 4, the required relationships among target, competitor, and decoy still hold, with the decoy being one-dimensional.</p><p>age and their crime motivations range from "to pay off gambling debt" to "to buy medication for their sick parent" or "to buy medication for their sick child". Although we may assume that it is more permissible to commit a robbery to save a loved one than to pay off gambling debt, there is no objective standard on which motivations are more permissible, especially considering that each decision maker has their own individual experience and ethical values. Thus, we need to gather data to know that, given the sample we have, how the levels in an attributes should be ranked. To find the majority-preferred rankings of levels in each attribute, we conducted a small study with 57 participants from the psychology undergraduate subject pool at the University of Michigan.</p><p>In this study, we investigated individuals' preferences among four levels of each attribute that we would use to construct ethical dilemmas subsequently. The attributes and each attribute's four levels are shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>We constructed six pairwise comparisons among the four levels of each attributes and all subjects were asked to make a choice in each pairwise comparison. An example of a set of questions that are pairwise comparisons among the four levels of the attribute "crime motivation" is included in Appendix C.2.</p><p>We found that there were consistent preferences among participants in some attributes use child labor, pay the workers poorly, pay the workers fairly, pay the workers well and provide health benefits Computer salary use child labor, pay the workers poorly, pay the workers fairly, pay the workers well and provide health benefits <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Experiment materials for constructing ethical dilemmas: attributes and their four levels.</p><p>(such as speed of delivery) but not in all attributes. There were individual variations in the preferences for ranking of the levels within an attribute. To create materials for our tasks, we kept the attribute for which more than half of the participants provided the same ranking orders. For example, for the "crime motivation" attribute, &gt; 50% participants ranked the levels as "stealing prescription drugs for a sick child" &gt; "stealing prescription drugs for a sick parent" &gt; "stealing prescription drugs for a friend's sick pet" &gt; "stealing prescription drugs to pay off gambling debt". With such information, we were able to construct tasks for Experiment 2. Experiment 2 involves three parts. Part 1 aims to check that participants' preferences are consistent with the rankings from the pilot study. Part 2 and Part 3 are the 9 ethical dilemmas with Wedell (1991)-like structures. Details of the three parts are provided below in the Method section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">Participants</head><p>After completing a power analysis (Appendix C.1), we recruited 502 U.S. participants (256 female; age M(SD) = 33(12.26) years) from Prolific (www.prolific.co) to complete this study in three sessions. We included the 475 participants (242 female; age M(SD) = 33(12.19) years) who completed all three parts in the data analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Design and materials</head><p>This experiment follows a 2×2 mixed design with one between-subject variable and one within-subject variable. The between-subject variable is decoy type (1D vs. 2D) and the within-subject variable is decoy position (atA, atB). We have 9 items/scenarios in total <ref type="table">(Table 3)</ref>. For the complete descriptions of the scenarios, see Appendix C.3.</p><p>Among all scenarios, 7 scenarios (emergency delivery, jail overcrowding, rescue plan, rescue a survivor, firing an employee, worker welfare, worker welfare 2) have both 1D and 2D decoys whereas 2 (jail overcrowding 2, inevitable injury) have only 1D decoys. Thus, as each participant sees all 9 items, decoy type is only between-subject for the 7 scenarios that have both 1D and 2D decoys. Each item is a pair of questions: in one question, decoy is at A, and in another, at B.</p><p>Each scenario poses a dilemma where the welfare of different sides is at stake. For a brief ethical content analysis of the scenarios explaining how each scenario poses a dilemma, see Appendix C.4.</p><p>Demographic survey. At the end of part 1 of this experiment, all participants also answered a short demographic survey at the end. The questions included age, gender (male/female/other), age they began to learn English, language used mostly at home, and highest grade completed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.3">Procedures</head><p>Participants completed part 1, part 2, and part 3 of the experiment in three separate sessions, each session activated on Prolific (www.prolific.co) the day after the previous session.</p><p>In Part 1, each participant completed 16 ethical decision tasks. In each task, each participant makes a choice among three multi-attribute options: one attribute is the same among the options and another attribute varies on three different levels. The 16 decision tasks correspond to the attributes in our ethical scenarios. An example of a question is in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>. In this example, the attribute pollution is the same among the options whereas the attribute speed varies. An example of the full set of questions corresponding to the speed and pollution attributes is given in Appendix C.5.</p><p>Each participant completes 9 decision tasks in each part of Part 2 and Part 3. The 9 decision tasks in each part correspond to the 9 ethical scenarios. To manipulate decoy position and decoy type of the decision tasks in each part, we have created four different versions of the tasks for Part 2 and 3, presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref>   <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: The nine scenarios we created for Experiment 2 and their two attributes/dimensions.</p><p>Each participant was randomly assigned one of the four versions of tasks. If a participant completed version 1 in Part 2, then they would also complete version 1 in Part 3. For each task version, Part 2 and Part 3 differ in decoy position, but not in decoy type.</p><p>All decision tasks were implemented in Qualtrics software (Qualtrics, Provo, UT). Four versions of the tasks were setup on Prolific (www.prolific.co) as four separate studies, thus the random assignment of the task version was done as participants signed up for the studies on Prolific.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decision problem:</head><p>You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner (who committed robbery). Which prisoner would you release? Options: Motive Probability of Recommitting To buy medication for his friend's sick pet</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>40%</head><p>To buy medication for his sick child 70% To payoff his gambling debt 40% <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: An example of a question with the attributes motivation for committing a robbery and probability of recommitting the same crime. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Type  2  1  atA  1D  2  atA  2D  3  atB  1D  4  atB  2D  3  1  atB  1D  2  atB  2D  3  atA  1D  4</ref> atA 2D </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Part Version Decoy Position Decoy</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">Descriptive analysis</head><p>Part 1 results showed that participants mostly made consistent choices when they were asked to choose among three options representing three of four levels in an attribute. If a participant did not choose the assumed best option in a decision problem corresponding to an attribute, we marked that participant-attribute pair as inconsistent. In SI, we included descriptive results after excluding trials corresponding to inconsistent participantattribute pairs (452 pairs, and the results did not change).</p><p>In the following analyses, we exclude the firing an employee item due to an experimental error and the rescue a survivor item due to its extremely high decoy selection rates (1D decoy: .45; 2D decoy: .42). The exclusion of the rescue a survivor item in statistical analyses does not change any of the following conclusions, and the full results with the rescue a survivor item are included in SI. We also focus on the aggregated data across items. For the complete descriptive results by each item, see Appendix C.6.</p><p>We present the choice proportions across all trials and all dilemmas in Appendix C.6. Here, we focus on analyzing the within-subject choice reversals. The response patterns within each pair of dilemmas are coded the same way as in Experiment 1. As expected, participants most frequently selected the option consistently (although less compared with the results in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell, 1991)</ref>. We present only response rates for decoy selection ("decoy selected"), choosing the competitors for both questions in a pair ("competitor reversal"), and within-subject choice reversals ("target reversal"). For complete proportions of choice patterns in Experiment 2, see <ref type="figure">Figure 19</ref>, Appendix C.6. As the aggregated data show, choice reversal rates (1D decoy: 0.22; 2D decoy: 0.23) in Experiment 2 are higher than those in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>. However, the rates for decoy selection (1D decoy: 0.07; 2D decoy: 0.04) and competitor reversals (1D decoy: 0.15; 2D decoy: 0.23) are slightly higher than those in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> as well. We do not observe any difference between 1D and 2D decoys.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Bayesian statistical analysis</head><p>Data analysis was conducted in R (R Core Team, 2013) using a Bayesian multinomial logistic regression model with RStan (Stan Development Team, 2017).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical models</head><p>We used a Bayesian multinomial logistic regression model to estimate the decoy type effect (1D vs. 2D), the decoy position effect (atA, atB), and their interactions. The model setup is the same as in Experiment 1.</p><p>The full model estimates the decoy position and type effects, the interaction between decoy type and position, as well as an item variance:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">categorical P (Y ijk = m) = β gm m + w item + β type m X ik + β decoy m X ij + β type * decoy m X ij X ik , (1) β ∼ N (0, 5), w ∼ N (0, σ w ),</formula><p>Besides the full model, we also ran a simple model without item variance on each of the item separately:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">categorical P (Y ijk = m) = β gm m + β type m X ik + β decoy m X ij + β type * decoy m X ij X ik β ∼ N (0, 5)</formula><p>Priors We used weakly informative priors for all βs: normal(0,5); the prior for item variance was normal(0,1).</p><p>Chain convergence evaluation For each model, we ran four independent chains and each of the four chains contains 4000 samples of each parameter. First 800 samples were part of the warmup (or burn-in period). The traceplots for parameters (not included) and the Rhat values <ref type="table" target="#tab_23">(Table 20</ref>, Appendix C.6) suggest that the chains have converged for all parameters.</p><p>Posterior statistics The posterior estimates for means and 95% credible intervals (CI) for the parameters in the full model are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_23">Table 20</ref> and <ref type="figure">Figure 22</ref> in Appendix C.6. Full results for the simple model applied to separate items are included in SI.</p><p>The posteriors for our main parameter of interest, β decoy A , for the aggregated data with the full model as well as for each scenario with the simple model are shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref>.</p><p>For the aggregated data, the estimated mean for the parameter β decoy A is 0.29 and its 95% CI is above 0 (95% CI = [0.16, 0.41]), suggesting that we have an overall choice reversal effect in aggregate. By adding an interaction between decoy position and decoy type, we also see that contrary to what we expected, when decoy is moved from B to A, compared to the baseline category (1D), 2D decoys have a slightly stronger effect (0.69−0.28 = 0.41).</p><p>Results from the simple model applied to individual items provide us with more insights on the variations among items. For items without 2D decoy, we simply applied the model to those individual items without β type m and interaction terms (i.e., categorical P (Y ijk = m) = β gm m + β decoy m X ij ). We can observe very clear choice reversals for four items: inevitable injury, jail overcrowding, rescue plan, and emergency delivery. , for the full model (aggregated data) and for each scenario analyzed with the simpler model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Discussion</head><p>This study focuses on exploring contextual choice reversals in decisions in various ethical domains. Similar to Experiment 1, our experiment follows the same structural design for the ethical dilemmas to create a choice environment commonly used in tasks that investigate contextual choice reversals. Different from Experiment 1, this study extends the ethical domains beyond where the decision maker needs to choose a rescue plan. We created various scenarios that touch on environmental concerns (e.g., emergency delivery) and human rights concerns (e.g., worker welfare). We also moved beyond using task stimuli that are isomorphic to <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> tasks. Instead, the attributes in these dilemmas are often qualitative-not all attributes are on a continuous scale-thus, the decision maker cannot calculate expected values directly by multiplying the attribute values together.</p><p>We found evidence for contextual choice reversals in aggregate, and we observed variations among individual items-we found very clear contextual choice reversals in some items, but not in all. First, we found clear choice reversals in the rescue plan item, an item taken directly from Experiment 1 and isomorphic to <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> tasks. This results replicates Experiment 1. Other items that produced clear contextual choice reversals include inevitable injury, jail overcrowding, emergency delivery. In the following discussion, we put focus on the items that did not produce contextual choice reversals and consider why they did not. The choice proportions for each option in each item <ref type="figure">(Figure 21</ref>, Appendix C.6) can provide us with insights.</p><p>The item jail overcrowding 2 had slightly high decoy selection rates and very consistent selection rates. In this item, the decision makers have to choose which prisoner to release-all prisoners committed robbery but for different reasons. There was an over-whelming preference for option B (one who robbed a teenager to buy medication for his sick child; <ref type="figure">Figure 21d</ref>, Appendix C.6). In other words, the two options are not equally attractive.</p><p>The unbalance could be explained on two levels. First, it is possible that one attributed is weighed more than the other during the decision making process-in this case, people could be generally more forgiving for those who try to save their child. Second, such unbalance is closely related to the challenges of mapping the structure of contextual choice reversal tasks to ethical decisions with attributes that have discrete levels. Although we did a pilot study to construct attributes with levels that have a majority-preferred ranking, we do not know if the difference between two levels are equal across attributes. This could suggest that the differences between target's and competitor's levels for victim age attribute (middle aged person, teenager) are not distinctive enough. Thus, the options may seem to be closer together on the victim age attribute, pushing people to focus more on the motivation attribute.</p><p>Similar unbalance is observed in worker welfare and worker welfare 2 <ref type="figure">(Figure 21</ref> c &amp; g, Appendix C.6). It is possible that the prices of the products are not distinguished enough, pushing people to focus more on the employee payment attribute.</p><p>Finding contextual choice reversals in aggregate and in some items in Experiment 2 suggests that there is potential to generalize our finding of contextual choice reversals to more ethical domains. However, we also face many challenges. The main challenges are: 1) despite finding attributes in various scenarios that have levels with a majoritypreferred ranking, not everyone have the same ranking in the given context; 2) we only have ordinal information on the discrete levels of an attribute, but we cannot know to what extent the levels differ from each other. Lastly, the items we used in our scenarios could be memorable. It is possible that people could remember the scenario even as they completed Part 2 and Part 3 one day apart.</p><p>In the following study, we revise the items accordingly to address these potential issues.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiment 3</head><p>Our Experiment 2 found empirical evidence for contextual choice reversals in a variety of ethical domains, providing us with potential to generalize our results in the ethical domain. However, we also found that item/scenario variations where some items produced contextual choice reversals and some did not.</p><p>In this experiment, we made four main changes to Experiment 2:</p><p>1. Item revisions. We excluded the previous rescue a survivor item due to its extremely high decoy selection rates. We included the firing an employee item correctly. We modified the three items worker welfare, worker welfare 2, and motivation &amp; victim age separately to make the differences among price attributes and victim age attribute larger.</p><p>2. Randomization for decoy types. Instead of having three sessions, we put previous Part 2 and Part 3 together into one session. We manipulated decoy type as a withinsubject variable. This allowed us to randomly present the 1D or 2D version of each item to each participant.</p><p>3. Manipulation of task instructions. We explored whether the knowledge of the existence of the dominance relationship between the target option and the decoy would increase contextual choice reversals by pushing the participants to look for the direct comparison between a dominating option (i.e., the target) and a dominated option (i.e., the decoy). Thus, we added the new between-subject manipulation of instruction, where participants will be randomly given an instruction that introduces the dominance of the target over the decoy.</p><p>4. Fillers. We introduced 16 fillers to make the critical items that we constructed less distinguishable.</p><p>This experiment involves two parts. As in Experiment 2, Part 1 aims to check that participants' preferences are consistent with ranks of various levels of the attributes that we used to construct the dilemmas. Part 2 contains the 8 critical items with Wedell (1991)like structures. Details of the two parts are provided below in the Method section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.1">Participants</head><p>We recruited 500 U.S. participants from Prolific (www.prolific.co) to complete this study in two sessions (demographic data were collected during the second session) and 480 participants (260 female; age M(SD) = 32(11.32) years) finished both sessions. We included the 456 participants (251 female; age M(SD) = 32(11.38) years) who passed the attention check in the data analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.2">Design and materials</head><p>This experiment follows a 2 × 2 × 2 mixed design with 1 between-subject variable and 2 within-subject variables. The between-subject variable is whether the participant receives the instruction explaining dominance or not. The within-subject variables are decoy type (1D vs. 2D) and decoy position (atA, atB). We have 8 critical items/scenarios <ref type="table">(Table 6)</ref> and 16 filler items/scenarios. The specific descriptions of the critical items can be found in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 19</ref>, Appendix C.3. Among the 8 critical items, 6 items (emergency delivery, jail overcrowding, rescue plan, firing an employee, worker welfare, worker welfare 2) have both 1D and 2D decoys whereas 2 items (jail overcrowding 2, inevitable injury) have only 1D decoys. Fillers do not have decoys, but they have a structure that imi tates that of critical items. In other words, each filler also has two versions where two out of the three options are the same and the third option varies in the two versions. All participants saw see all 24 items (48 questions). price of a pair of boots how well the company that sells the boots treats its workers <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: The eight critical scenarios in Experiment 3 and their two attributes/dimensions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Scenario</head><p>Attention check. To check whether participants read the scenarios carefully, we created eight multiple-choice questions asking about various details in the scenarios, such as "which of the following is not a motivation for committing a robbery in the decision problems". Each participant was randomly presented with five out of eight questions. If a participant answers at least three questions correctly, they pass the attention check.</p><p>Demographic survey. Between the two blocks in part 2 of the study, participants answered a short demographic survey at the end. The questions included age, gender (male/female/other), age they began to learn English, language used mostly at home, and highest grade completed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.3">Procedures</head><p>Participants completed Part 1 and Part 2 of the experiment in two separate sessions, each session activated on Prolific (www.prolific.co) the day after the previous session. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Fillers  1  1  atA  filler version 1  2  atB  filler version 2  2  1  atB  filler version 2  2  atA  filler version 1   Table 7</ref>: The two task versions in part 2 of Experiment 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Block Version Decoy Position</head><p>Part 1 of the experiment is the same as the Part 1 of Experiment 2. Each participant completed 30 ethical decision tasks. The tasks correspond to attributes that appear in critical items and attributes that appear in fillers.</p><p>Before participants started Part 2 of the experiment, they received an instruction about the decision tasks. The instruction is either a task instruction asking the participants to follow the instructions in the question carefully and choose the action they would be most likely to take in the given scenario or an instruction with additional explanations on what a dominating option and a dominated option is using an example from <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Huber et al. (1982)</ref>. In the latter instruction, participants were also be told that some of the scenarios they see in the task will have a dominating option and a dominated option. Each participant was randomly presented with either a task instruction only or with the instruction that has explanations on dominance.</p><p>Part 2 of the experiment contains 24 pairs of multiple-choice questions (48 questions in total). 8 pairs are critical items and the other 16 pairs are fillers. All 24 pairs of questions were presented in 2 blocks, with a demographic survey separating them. To manipulate decoy position, we have created two different versions of the tasks in part 2, presented in <ref type="table">Table 7</ref> below.</p><p>Each participant was randomly presented with one of the two versions of tasks. If a participant completed version 1 in block 1, then they would also complete version 1 in block 2. Each block contains 24 questions, presented in a random order. Block 1 and 2 differ in decoy position and filler versions. When each item is presented to a participant for the first time, its 1D or 2D decoy version is presented randomly. If an item's 1D decoy version is presented in block 1, then its 1D decoy version will be presented in block 2 as well.</p><p>At the end of Part 2, all participants completed a section of attention check questions, asking them details about the scenarios in the decision tasks.</p><p>All decision tasks were implemented and randomized in Qualtrics software (Qualtrics, Provo, UT).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1">Descriptive analysis</head><p>Part 1 results showed that participants were mostly consistent when they were asked to make a choice among three options representing three of four levels in an attribute. If a participant did not choose the assumed best option in a decision problem corresponding to an attribute, we marked that participant-attribute pair as inconsistent. In SI, we in- cluded descriptive results after excluding trials corresponding to inconsistent participantattribute pairs (391 pairs, and the results did not change).</p><p>In the following analyses, we exclude the firing an employee item due to its distinctively high decoy selection rate (1D decoy: .26; 2D decoy: .18). The exclusion of the firing an employee item does not change any of the following conclusions, and the full results with the firing an employee item are included in SI. We also focus on the aggregated data across items. The complete descriptive results by each item are in Appendix C.7.</p><p>Same as in previous experiments, we present the proportions of choice across all trials and all dilemmas in Appendix C.7. We focus on the proportions of choice patterns in Experiment 3 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 10</ref> below, excluding rates for consistent choices (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 24</ref>, Appendix C.7 for full results). The consistent-selection rates are extremely high (1D decoy: .78; 2D decoy: .82), indicating that participants mostly chose consistently between the pair of questions corresponding to the same item. The rates for contextual choice reversals (1D decoy: .10; 2D decoy: .09) and competitor reversal selections (1D decoy: .05 ; 2D decoy: .04) are fairly low from Experiment 3.  <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref>: Posterior estimates for means and 95% CIs of the main parameter of interest, β decoy A , for the full model (aggregated data) and for each scenario analyzed with the simple model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A G G R E G A T E D w o r k e r w e l f a r e i n e v i t a b l e i n j u r y j a i l o v e r c r o w d i n g 2 j a i l o v e r c r o w d i n g r e s c u e p l a n w o r k e r w e l f a r e 2 e m e r g e n c y d e l i v e r y scenario Posterior estimates with 95% CI</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Bayesian statistical analysis</head><p>Data analysis was conducted in R (R Core Team, 2013) using a Bayesian logistic regression model with RStan (Stan Development Team, 2017).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical models, &amp; priors: see Experiment 2.</head><p>We did not find any effect of whether subjects received instruction or not with the full analysis model (SI). Thus, we collapsed the with-instruction and no-instruction group together, and used the full model from Experiment 2. We have also applied the simple model from Experiment 2 to each item separately.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chain convergence evaluation</head><p>We ran four independent chains and each of the four chains contains 4000 samples of each parameter. First 800 samples were part of the warmup (or burn-in period). The traceplots for parameters (not included) and the Rhat values <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 21</ref>, Appendix C.7) suggest chain convergence for all parameters.</p><p>Posterior statistics The posterior estimates for mean and 95% CIs for the parameters in the full model and the simple model are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 21</ref> and <ref type="figure">Figure 27</ref> in Appendix C.7. Full results for the simple model applied to separate items are included in SI.</p><p>The posteriors for our main parameter of interest, β decoy A , for the aggregated data analyzed with the full model and for each item analyzed with the simple model are shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref> below.</p><p>For the aggregated data, the estimated mean for β decoy A is 0.19 and its 95% CI is entirely above 0 (95% CI = [0.07, 0.31]), suggesting that we have a clear overall within-subject choice reversal effect. By adding an interaction between decoy position and decoy type, we can also see that results suggest that when decoy is moved from B to A, compared to the baseline category (1D), 2D decoys have a slightly stronger effect (0.22 + 0.02 = 0.24). However, the effect of decoy type remains inconclusive as the 95% CI for the estimated interaction is ambiguous (β type * decoy A 95% CI = <ref type="bibr">[-0.19, 0.23]</ref>). Similar to Experiment 2, results for individual items <ref type="figure">(Figure 11)</ref> show that choice reversals are present for some items (worker welfare, worker welfare 2, inevitable injury, rescue plan, emergency delivery), but not present in jail overcrowding item and jail overcrowding 2 item.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Combined analyses for Experiments 2 and 3</head><p>To appropriately combine the items and compare results from Experiment 2 and Experiment 3, we present the following combined analyses. The results of choice proportions across all trials in identical dilemmas shared between Experiments 2 and 3, and the choice proportions across all trials in revised items in Experiments 2 and 3 can both be found in Appendix D.</p><p>Below we show the choice patterns (excluding consistent-selection rate) of the four identical items in aggregate (N=931) below in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 12a</ref>, where the rates of choice reversals in 1D and 2D decoy conditions are quite high. We ran the full model (Equation 1) on the combined data from the identical items in Experiment 2 and 3. The results suggest a clear aggregated choice reversal <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Figure 12b</ref>, β decoy A mean: 0.50, 95% CI = [0.38,0.62]). The estimate of the interaction between decoy type and decoy position is extremely small (β int A mean: -0.21, 95% CI = [-0.41, -0.01]). Combined with the estimate of decoy type, results show a slightly stronger effect for 2D decoy compared to baseline category (0.51-0.21=0.30). Full descriptive and statistical results for the aggregated data can be found in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 30</ref>, Appendix D.</p><p>We have also investigated how much time on average participants spent on a question during each session in Experiment 2 and Experiment 3 <ref type="table">(Table 8</ref>). On average, participants spent less time on a question (at least for critical items) in Experiment 3 than either session in Experiment 2. In both experiments, participants spent less time when they see the same item for the second time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Discussion</head><p>In this section, we briefly discuss the results of Experiment 3. We will discuss the comparison between Experiment 2 and Experiment 3 in the conclusion section.</p><p>Experiment 3 builds upon Experiment 2 to investigate whether contextual choice reversals arise in ethical domains. We also explored whether we observe stronger contextual choice reversal effects by providing participants additional information about the potential existence of the dominating and dominated options in the tasks. We improved the materials from Experiment 2 by revising the items, improving our randomization for , indicating the change in log odds of choosing A over B when decoy is changed from "atB" to "atA". Experiment 2 session 1 23.47s session 2 20.97s Experiment 3 critical items 20.59s first-seen critical 24.55s second-seen critical 16.58s <ref type="table">Table 8</ref>: Average time spent per item decoy types, and adding fillers as an attempt to make the critical items less distinctive and memorable.</p><p>Similar to Experiment 2, we found evidence for contextual choice reversals in aggregate, but we did not observe contextual choice reversals in all items. In addition, we also found very high consistent selection rates. This could be due to the fact that the participants did all pairs of questions within one session, making them more likely to remember their choices when they encountered the item for the first time in block 1. We also did not find any difference in the effects of 1D and 2D decoys on contextual choice reversals. Nor did we find any increased or decreased contextual choice reversals rates when participants were given additional information about the relationship between the dominating option and the dominated option.</p><p>We next explore how variation in reversal rates across items might be affected by individual participants' ranking of levels in the attributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Explaining variation in contextual choice reversals across ethical dilemmas</head><p>For attributes with qualitative rather than quantitative levels, different individuals may have different subjective rankings of the attribute levels. This poses challenges to the assumptions made for the task structure of the classical paradigm used to investigate choice reversals, which is that all decision makers have the same ranking of the features involved in the attributes. This assumption is not problematic for probability and value in economic gambles. But for the ethical dilemmas, this is not always the case. Consider the example below (illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 13</ref>). In a jail overcrowding 2 dilemma, the decision maker needs to make a trade off between victim's age and the crime motivation for committing a robbery. The victim age attribute has two levels: "child" and "middle-aged", and the crime motivation attribute has four levels: "to pay off gambling debt", "to help a friend's sick pet", "to help a sick parent", and "to help a sick child". Our original construction of the task assumes the ranking "robbing middle-aged person" &gt; (i.e., is more permissible than) "robbing a child" on the victim age attribute, and the ranking "help sick child" &gt; "help sick parent" &gt; "help friend's sick pet" &gt; "pay off gambling debt" on the crime motivation attribute. This assumption is based on our data investigating people's ranking for levels in various ethically-involved attributes and yields three options: a competitor, A ("robbing a middle-aged person to help a friend's sick pet"), a target, B ("robbing a child to help a sick child"), and a decoy, D ("robbing a child to help a sick parent").</p><p>However, as our data on individuals' ranking on levels in various attributes only indicate a majority preference, it is possible that some participants may have a different ranking for the same levels. One different yet possible ranking on the crime motivation attribute could be "help sick parent" &gt; "help sick child" &gt; "help friend's sick pet" &gt; "pay off gambling debt". If the participant has such a ranking, then our originally intended target, B ("robbing a child to help a sick child") becomes a decoy, and our originally intended decoy, D ("robbing a child to help a sick parent"), becomes the target for this participant. Thus, if this participant chooses the target option in their perspective, the choice would be reflected as a choice of decoy based on our original task structure. Thus, we believe that variation in choice reversal rates across scenarios could be systematically related to variations in people's ranking of the levels in the attributes.</p><p>To show how the individual differences in ranking of the levels in the attributes systematically affect the variation in choice reversal rates, we present a generative model that  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 13</ref>: Task structures for the jail overcrowding 2 dilemma according to our assumed ranking for levels in the crime motivation attribute (left) and according to a different yet possible ranking for levels in the crime motivation attribute (right).</p><p>takes into account the individual preferences of feature rankings in different attributes while generating choices for each ethical dilemmas. Our model predictions show that the variation among scenarios can be partly explained by the individual differences in the feature rankings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">A generative model of choices in ethical dilemmas</head><p>The model makes three assumptions: 1) individuals choose consistently within a pair (regardless of which option dominates the decoy) most of time; 2) there is noise in individual decisions, which causes individuals to choose the inferior options occasionally; 3) the distribution of the decision makers' feature rankings is based on the results from our study where we discovered the attributes for constructing ethical dilemmas. The model takes as input an individual's rankings for levels in all attributes and then simulate choices for all 16 ethical dilemmas from Experiment 3. Recall that the 16 dilemmas correspond to the 8 critical scenarios from Experiment 3 <ref type="table">(Table 6</ref>). Each scenario includes two questions. The difference between these two questions is decoy position.</p><p>Given the individual's ranking for levels in an attribute, the dominating and dominated relationship among the three options in a question may be different from our initial assumptions when we constructed the questions. An individual's ranking of attribute levels induces dominance relations that may differ from the assumptions we made when constructing the items. Consequently, what is intended to be a target may become a competitor or even a decoy given some individual's rankings. Thus, given an input of individual's rankings for levels in all attributes, the model re-creates the structural relationships among the options in each dilemma -in other words, the model identifies the target, competitor, and decoy in each dilemma given the individual's rankings. Then, the model generates choices based on that individual's rankings and the re-created structures of the decision problems.</p><p>The possible structures given all possible rankings of levels in attributes are summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 9</ref> below. Given the structures of dilemmas based on individual's rankings, the model generates choices for all ethical dilemmas in Experiment 3.</p><p>The model requires two parameters: an error rate, ϵ ∈ [0, 1], and a rate of choosing consistently, p consistent ∈ [0, 1]. When a question has a best option given some individual's rankings, the model selects randomly between the other two non-dominating options with p = ϵ. When a question has a worst option given some individual's rankings, the model selects the worst option with p = ϵ. When either question in a pair does not have an Attraction Configuration, the model selects the same options in the questions in that pair with p consistent .</p><p>After generating choices for all questions, for each question, we map the choice back to the option in the original Attraction Configuration of that same question. The original Attraction Configuration contains the target, the competitor, and the decoy that we initially constructed given our assumptions on the feature rankings.</p><p>We present the general algorithm for generating the decision problem's structure/configuration given a possible ranking and the method to generate choices given the problem structures in Appendix E.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Explaining variation in attraction effects across scenarios</head><p>We simulated 500 subjects in eight scenarios (with 1000 runs per subject). Each simulated subject had rankings for attributes that match a randomly sampled empirical subject in our study (N = 57) where we discovered the attributes for constructing ethical dilemmas. For each simulated subject, all 16 questions were generated in random order.</p><p>In the simulation, we set the decoy selection rate for questions with an Attraction Configuration as the same from our empirical data (mean decoy rate: .08). The error rate (ϵ) was set to a low and reasonable value (0.05) and the probability of choosing consistently (p consistent ) was set to 0.7, as people choose consistently in about 70% trials with an Attraction Configuration empirically.</p><p>The simulation reproduced the pattern of choice patterns from the empirical data (SI). However, our simulation generally predicted consistent choice rates lower than empirical data and competitor reversal choice rates higher than empirical data <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 31</ref>, Appendix E). The complete results including the firing an employee item can be found in SI. We focus on the results of simulated and empirical decoy selection rates and choice reversal rates in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 14</ref> below.</p><p>We observe that the simulations of choice patterns based on individual ranking for levels in attributes predict choice reversals not perfectly but quite well. The model predicts reversal rates better in dilemmas with 1D decoys than in dilemmas with 2D decoys. Besides reversal rates, the model also predicts decoy selection rates well for both dilemmas with 1D decoys and dilemmas with 2D decoys. This suggests that some item variations can indeed be accounted for by the variations of people's individually varying rankings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Structure/Configuration</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Illustrated example</head><p>Best Option Configuration: a best option dominates the other two options in both attributes  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Discussion</head><p>Our model explores the implications of individual differences in attribute rankings.</p><p>To make our model complete, we have made a few assumptions such as the distribu-  tion of the feature rankings among decision makers, and the inclusion of error rate and consistent-choice rate. The distribution is based on our study with a somewhat small sample size, and the other two parameters are reasonable values. These decisions could potentially contribute to the reason why our model results only partly account for the observed choice reversal pattern. One possible future direction is to implement higher-level subjective utility functions that capture how different individuals make tradeoffs among options that involve qualitative attributes. This, of course, requires deeper investigations of subjective utility functions in value-based decisions.</p><p>Finally, this generative model provides the foundation of a method to understand better context effects in domains with wide variation in attribute rankings, especially domains that involve qualitative attributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>This work provides the first clear evidence of within-participant contextual choice reversals in ethical domains, first with tasks isomorphic to economic gamble tasks, then with tasks spanning multiple ethical scenarios with qualitative attributes. By comparing choice reversals and performance-as measured by obtained expected value-between the economic (Experiment 1a) and isomorphic ethical decisions (Experiment 1b), we also found that performance in the ethical decisions was better than in the economic gambles, and that higher target reversal rates was associated with better performance in the economic gambles but not in the ethical decisions (we discuss this more below). In Experiment 2 and 3, we found choice reversals in aggregate among ethical dilemmas across various domains, some of which involve qualitative attributes without the clear objective rankings that come with quantitative attributes. In the further analyses comparing the results from Experiment 2 and 3, we observed smaller effects of choice reversals in Experiment 3 in aggregate, especially among the 4 identical items shared between the two experiments. This could largely be due to the fact that the participants in Experiment 3 completed the tasks in a single session and thus remembered the items well-an explanation consistent with the result that the rates of choosing consistently within a pair were extremely high. The time participants spent on these decisions may also provide some insight into the lowered choice reversal rates in Experiment 3, as the average time participants spent on critical items was shorter than that in Experiment 2, consistent with previous findings that choice reversals tend to diminish as time pressure increases <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Pettibone, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Choice reversals did not appear in all scenarios, suggesting significant item variation. We conjectured that at least some of this variation may be due to variation in individual subjective rankings of the attribute values in the scenarios-such variation could in effect change the location of the decoy so that it is no longer dominated by the intended target. We began to address this methodological challenge by developing a generative model that takes individual differences in feature rankings into account. We showed that this can indeed partly account for the variation of reversal rates among our scenarios.</p><p>Our primary aim in this work is not to demonstrate that human ethical decision making is irrational. Rather, it is to establish further empirical bridges between ethical decision making and general domain-independent theories of decision making, such as the multi-attribute choice models that can account for the contextual attraction effects we observed <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bhatia, Loomes, &amp; Read, 2021)</ref>. Our own preferred theoretical account does not treat contextual choice reversals as evidence for irrationality but rather as evidence for boundedly rational <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Simon, 1955)</ref> decision strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Howes et al., 2016</ref>)-more specifically, decision strategies that are well adapted to the cognitive and perceptual bounds of the decision maker. The <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Howes et al. (2016)</ref> model combines two sets of noisy observations: noisy ordinal observations comparing attribute values across pairs of options, and noisy calculations of subjective expected value. The model chooses the option with the highest expected value given these noisy observations, and the result is systematic contextual choice reversals. But under this account, such choice reversals are a signature of boundedly rational utility maximization. This account of contextual choice reversals is consistent with our exploratory finding in Experiment 1a where higher target reversal rates predicted better task performance in the economic gambles-a counter-intuitive finding under the assumption that choice reversals are irrational. Although we did not find this relationship between target reversals and performance in isomorphic ethical decisions, we observed that the overall reversal rates in ethical decisions are just as high-in fact, higher-as those in choices in economic gambles.</p><p>As with any study of moral or ethical decision making involving descriptions of fictional scenarios, our study is limited by the fact that our participants understood that no lives or welfare were actually at stake, and the decisions were made based on descriptions rather than actual experience with the choice setting. But modern ethical choices, especially in cases of policy-making, are also often marked by decisions based on descriptions and by a considerable psychological (and sometimes geographic) distance between the decision maker and the people affected by the decisions. We therefore think it is likely that such real-world decisions will also be subject to the kind of context effects that we demonstrated here. But we also caution against the view that the presence of such effects necessarily indicates irrational choice strategies; on the contrary, they may be signatures of adaptive, bounded rational decision making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendices A Background</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Behaviors</head><p>Heuristics/Effect Type Preference over government's policy to save more lives or more life-years depends on the framing when the expected utility is the same <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Sunstein, 2004)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Framing effect Substitution</head><p>People are willing to punish companies' ethical decisions that are based on cost-benefit analysis when the companies' liability is unclear under the law <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Viscusi, 2000)</ref> Rejecting costbenefit analysis in decisions affecting lives</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rules-of-thumb</head><p>Objections to emission trading led to the delay and reduction of the use of a pollution reduction tool that is, in many contexts, the best available <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Sunstein, 2002)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Do not allow moral wrongdoing for a fee</head><p>Rules-of-thumb People are averse to risks of death from products that are designed to promote safety, e.g., airbags <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Koehler &amp; Gershoff, 2003)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Betrayal risk aversion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Substitution</head><p>Punishment judgments towards corporations are a product of outrage and leads to decreased wages, increased prices, lost jobs <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Kahneman, Schkade, &amp; Sunstein, 1998)</ref> or less beneficial products such as vaccines and birth control pills on the market <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Baron &amp; Ritov, 1993)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Outrage</head><p>heuristic <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kahneman &amp; Frederick, 2002)</ref> Substitution People overestimate the carcinogenic risk from pesticides and underestimate the risks of natural carcinogens <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Rozin, 2001</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Do not tamper with nature</head><p>Rules-of-thumb Harmful acts are generally seen worse than harmful omissions <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Baron &amp; Ritov, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Rodriguez-Arias, Rodriguez Lopez, Monasterio-Astobiza, &amp; Hannikainen, 2020)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Omission bias Substitution</head><p>Most U.S. citizens say that they approve of postmortem organ donation, yet relatively few sign a donor card <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Johnson &amp; Goldstein, 2003)</ref>.   <ref type="bibr">.40,</ref><ref type="bibr">$25 .40,</ref><ref type="bibr">$20 .35,</ref><ref type="bibr">$25 .35,</ref><ref type="bibr">$20 .50,</ref><ref type="bibr">$20 .50,</ref><ref type="bibr">$18 .45,</ref><ref type="bibr">$20 .45,</ref><ref type="bibr">$18 .67,</ref><ref type="bibr">$15 .67,</ref><ref type="bibr">$13 .62,</ref><ref type="bibr">$15 .62,</ref><ref type="bibr">$13 .83,</ref><ref type="bibr">$12 .83,</ref><ref type="bibr">$10 .78,</ref><ref type="bibr">$12 .78,</ref><ref type="bibr">$10 Target B .30,</ref><ref type="bibr">$33 .25,</ref><ref type="bibr">$33 .30,</ref><ref type="bibr">$30 .25,</ref><ref type="bibr">$30 .40,</ref><ref type="bibr">$25 .35,</ref><ref type="bibr">$25 .40,</ref><ref type="bibr">$20 .35,</ref><ref type="bibr">$20 .50,</ref><ref type="bibr">$20 .45,</ref><ref type="bibr">$20 .50,</ref><ref type="bibr">$18 .45,</ref><ref type="bibr">$18 .67,</ref><ref type="bibr">$15 .62,</ref><ref type="bibr">$15 .67,</ref><ref type="bibr">$13</ref> .62, $13 <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 11</ref>: Gambles used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>'s original Experiment 1. R = range decoy; F = frequency decoy; RF = range-frequency decoy <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>. R and F are one-dimensional decoys (1D), and RF is two-dimensional decoy (2D).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B.2 Data structure and descriptive analysis</head><p>The    </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B.4 Additional Bayesian statistical analysis</head><p>We also analyzed the data with a simple model (see Eq (2) below) excluding the control decoy or the interaction between decoy position and decoy type. This model is the Bayesian counterpart of the analysis in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>'s original Experiment 1.     <ref type="figure">Figure 16</ref>: All posterior estimates for means and 95% CIs of all parameters specified in the logistic regression model in Experiment 1. β gm A describes the baseline situation -log odds of choosing A over B when decoy is "atB" and decoy type is 1D. The parameter β decoy A is our main parameter of interest, which indicate the change in logodds of choosing A to B when decoy is changed from "atB" to "atA". The parameters β control A and β 2D</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">categorical P (Y ijk = m) = β gm + β type m X ik + β decoy m X ij<label>(2</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">−10 −5 0 5 β A decoy β A gm β A control β A control*decoy β A 2D β A 2D*decoy β D decoy β D gm β D control β D control*decoy β D 2D β D 2D*</formula><p>A describe the effect of decoy type on choice proportions, i.e., the change in logodds of choosing A over B when decoy type is changed from 1D to control or 2D. The parameters β control * decoy A and β 2D * decoy A indicates the interaction between decoy position and decoy type effects when considered together with β R ′ A and β 2D A . For example, by combining β 2D A and β 2D * decoy A , we learn how logodds of choosing A to B change when decoy is changed from "atB" to "atA" and from 1D to 2D. Parameters β D s are interpreted similarly.    <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 18</ref>: Experiment 1 -posterior statistics for parameters in the regression model in equation 3.3. The reference group is <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> replication (i.e., economic gambles).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C Experiment 2 &amp; 3 C.1 Power analysis</head><p>We conducted a power analysis by simulating data and generate posteriors of simulated data with our full model (Equation <ref type="formula">1</ref>) so that we could collect data from a number of subjects that would let us achieve the following level of precision: the width of 95% credible interval (CI) of our main parameter of interest is less than 1. The 95% CI is the central portion of the posterior distribution that contains 95% of the probable effect values. Power Analysis <ref type="figure">Figure 17</ref>: Power analysis result: change of the width of 95% CI as subject number decreases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C.2 Example of questions for finding attributes to construct materials for Experiment 2 &amp; 3</head><p>Below we show a set of questions that are presented to participants for determining how participants' rank the levels in an attribute. The attribute is crime motivation and the levels are: stealing prescription drugs for a sick child, stealing prescription drugs for a sick parent, stealing prescription drugs for a friend's sick pet, and stealing prescription drugs to pay off gambling debt.</p><p>1. You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner. Which prisoner would you release?</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his sick child.</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his friend's sick pet.</p><p>2. You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner. Which prisoner would you release?</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his sick child.</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his sick parent.</p><p>3. You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner. Which prisoner would you release?</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his sick parent.</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his friend's sick pet.</p><p>4. You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner. Which prisoner would you release?</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his sick child.</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs to pay off his gambling debt.</p><p>5. You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner. Which prisoner would you release?</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his sick parent.</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs to pay off his gambling debt.</p><p>6. You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner. Which prisoner would you release?</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs for his friend's sick pet.</p><p>• A man who stole prescription drugs to pay off his gambling debt.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C.3 Scenarios in Experiment 2 &amp; 3 item scenario emergency delivery</head><p>You are responsible for an emergency delivery of medical supplies to a small village to prevent some serious illness. There are different vehicles that you may choose from. They all cost the same but vary in the delivery speed and the amount of pollutants produced. Which of the following vehicles do you choose?</p><p>jail overcrowding</p><p>You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner. Which prisoner would you release? (The prisoners' crime motivation and recidivism vary.) jail overcrowding 2</p><p>You are the sheriff of the jail in a small town. The jail is overcrowded and you have to release a prisoner. Which prisoner would you release? (The prisoners' crime motivation and victim's ages vary.) inevitable injury You work for a shipping company and your job is to monitor autonomous cars and control them in the case of an emergency. One day when you are working, one of the autonomous cars experiences a sudden brake failure. The car is approaching a busy intersection where there are pedestrians crossing the street. If you do nothing, the car will hit the nearby vehicle, killing all passengers inside the car and the nearby vehicle. By taking control of the car, you can navigate it to crash into one of the pedestrians crossing the street, but doing so may result in the injury of the pedestrians. Which of the following outcomes would you choose? rescue plan A hurricane hits a small town causing most houses to be destroyed. Three emergency rescue plans have been proposed. Assuming that the exact scientific estimates of the consequences of the plans are as follows, which plan would you choose? rescue a survivor <ref type="bibr">3</ref> A devastating hurricane that destroys most homes hits a small island. You are the lead expert on the emergency rescue team and you find three severely injured survivors buried underneath the rubble. A member of your team has evaluated the likelihood of successfully rescuing each survivor. After carefully examining the situation, you realize that this confined space is very fragile and you can try to rescue only one person before it collapses. The survivors you do not try to rescue will certainly die. Who would you try to rescue? (Likelihood of rescuing and age of survivors vary.) firing an employee You are the manager of a small group of people in a company. Due to low sales, you have to fire an employee. Who would you fire? (The employees' years of working experiences and their sense of responsibility vary.)</p><p>worker welfare</p><p>You are buying a laptop that is produced by different companies. Assuming that the products all have the same quality, which of the following companies would you choose to buy it from? (Price and how well the companies pay their workers vary.) worker welfare 2</p><p>You are buying a pair of boots that is produced by different companies. Assuming that the products all have the same quality, which of the following companies would you choose to buy it from? (Price and how well the companies pay their workers vary.) <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 19</ref>: Items (scenarios) appeared in Experiment 2 and Experiment 3. The rescue a survivor item only appeared in Experiment 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C.4 Ethical content analysis of the scenarios</head><p>Recall that we follow the definition in <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Yu et al (2019)</ref> that ethical decisions are decisions that affect others' welfare <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Yu et al., 2019)</ref>. In this section, we provide a content analysis of the scenario by explaining how each scenario poses a dilemma in which the welfare of different parties is at stake.</p><p>1. emergency delivery: In this scenario, the decision maker needs to select a vehicle to complete an emergency drug delivery to a remote village while making a tradeoff between the speed of the vehicle and the amount of pollutant that the vehicle produces. The speed of the vehicle directly affects the welfare of the villagers who are in need of the emergency medication, however, the faster vehicle also produces more pollutants, which would further threat the environment, posing a long-term threat to all people.</p><p>2. jail overcrowding: In this scenario, the decision maker needs to decide which prisoner to release due to overcrowding issue in a small town. The trade-off is between deciding based on the original motivation of the crime and the probability of the prisoner to recommit the same crime after being release. This poses a dilemma because even though it is more permissible for someone to commit robbery to buy drugs for their sick child (compared to the motivation of paying off gambling debt), this act is associated with higher probability of recommitting the same crimewhich damages the welfare of the robbery victim. Essentially, the welfare of the released prisoner or their family is pitted against the welfare of potential victims and the society in general.</p><p>3. jail overcrowding 2: In this scenario, the decision maker needs to decide which prisoner to release due to overcrowding issue in a small town. The trade-off is between deciding based on the original motivation of the crime and deciding based on the age of the victim. This poses a dilemma because even though it could be permissible for someone to commit robbery to buy drugs for their sick child, it could be less permissible to rob an old person or a child at the same time. Essentially, the welfare of the released prisoner or their family is pitted against the welfare of potential victims.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">inevitable injury:</head><p>In this scenario, the decision maker takes over the automatic car that is lost control and must make a decision of which pedestrian to run intootherwise all passengers in the car dies. Running into different pedestrians cause different injury to them with different probabilities -and weaker injury is associated with higher probabilities. This decision directly affects the welfare of the pedestrians involved.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">rescue plan:</head><p>This scenario is taken from Experiment 1, where the decision maker must decide on a rescue plan after a hurricane -each plan leads to saving different numbers of people, but saving more people is associated with lower probability of a successful rescue. In this decision, the survival of the few people is pitted against the survival of many people.</p><p>6. rescue a survivor: In this scenario, the decision maker also needs to decide on who to rescue after a hurricane -but this scenario focuses on the welfare of single survivors. The younger survivor is less likely to be successfully rescued. Here, the survival of individuals are pitted against the survival of each other.</p><p>7. firing an employee: In this scenario, the decision maker needs to decide which employee in a company to fire due to low sales. The employees involved in the decisions have worked at the company for different numbers of years (i.e., some employees have more experience), but the ones who have worked at the company for longer may have less sense of responsibility (e.g., they may often miss work or come to work late). This decision also directly impacts the welfare of the involved employees.</p><p>8. worker welfare and worker welfare 2: In these two scenarios, the decision maker decides on which product to buy. The scenarios involve different types of products. However, in both scenarios, some products are cheaper, but they may be produced by companies that do not treat their employees well (or use child labor); some products are more expensive, but they are produced by companies that pay their employees well and provide health benefits. In these scenarios, the welfare of the decision maker is directly involved -and it is pitted against the welfare of the companies' employees.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C.5 An example of a set of questions in part 1 of Experiment 2 and Experiment 3</head><p>Below is a set of questions corresponding to the item speed-pollution. In this set, pollution attribute says constant and speed attribute varies in each choice. Each participant was randomly presented one out of the four questions and three out of the four choices within in the question.</p><p>1. You are responsible for an emergency delivery of medical supplies to a small village to prevent some serious illness. There are different vehicles that you may choose from. They all cost the same and produce the same amount of pollutants but vary in the delivery speed (overnight, 3 days, 5 days, 7 days). Which of the following vehicles do you choose?</p><p>• A car that produces a low amount of pollutants and makes the delivery overnight.</p><p>• A car that produces a low amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 3 days.</p><p>• A car that produces a low amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 5 days.</p><p>• A car that produces a low amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 7 days.</p><p>2. You are responsible for an emergency delivery of medical supplies to a small village to prevent some serious illness. There are different vehicles that you may choose from. They all cost the same and produce the same amount of pollutants but vary in the delivery speed (overnight, 3 days, 5 days, 7 days). Which of the following vehicles do you choose?</p><p>• A car that produces a medium amount of pollutants and makes the delivery overnight.</p><p>• A car that produces a medium amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 3 days.</p><p>• A car that produces a medium amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 5 days.</p><p>• A car that produces a medium amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 7 days.</p><p>3. You are responsible for an emergency delivery of medical supplies to a small village to prevent some serious illness. There are different vehicles that you may choose from. They all cost the same and produce the same amount of pollutants but vary in the delivery speed (overnight, 3 days, 5 days, 7 days). Which of the following vehicles do you choose?</p><p>• A car that produces a high amount of pollutants and makes the delivery overnight.</p><p>• A car that produces a high amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 3 days.</p><p>• A car that produces a high amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 5 days.</p><p>• A car that produces a high amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 7 days.</p><p>4. You are responsible for an emergency delivery of medical supplies to a small village to prevent some serious illness. There are different vehicles that you may choose from. They all cost the same and produce the same amount of pollutants but vary in the delivery speed (overnight, 3 days, 5 days, 7 days). Which of the following vehicles do you choose?</p><p>• A car that produces a very high amount of pollutants and makes the delivery overnight.</p><p>• A car that produces a very high amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 3 days.</p><p>• A car that produces a very high amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 5 days.</p><p>• A car that produces a very high amount of pollutants and makes the delivery in 7 days.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C.6 Experiment 2 results</head><p>Choice proportions across trials. During the first session, participants saw all the scenarios for the first time. The choice proportions in the first occurrences of the scenarios allow us to explore the attraction effect exhibited in the data. If we see that the target is preferred over the competitor under the presence of the decoy, then we observe an attraction effect across participants. In this experiment, we observe an attraction effect at the first occurrences of scenarios ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 18)</ref>. However, the effect is not present in the second session, potentially due to memories of the scenarios from the first session, considering all scenarios are fairly distinctive.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C.6.1 Descriptive analysis by item</head><p>Here we present the descriptive results of choice patterns and choice proportions by item.    </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C.7 Experiment 3 results</head><p>Choice proportions across trials. We report below the attraction effect across all trials <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 23</ref>), i.e., the choice proportions for each option at each decoy position across all trials and all scenarios. Although participants completed the pairs of items in one session, they still saw the different versions of items (decoy-at-A and decoy-at-B for critical items) in two separate blocks. Similar to Experiment 2, we observe an attraction effect across subjects at the first occurrences of scenarios. The attraction effect is not present in the second block, potentially due to memories of the scenarios from the first block.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D Combined analyses for Experiments 2 and 3</head><p>Choice proportions across trials in identical dilemmas. <ref type="table">Table 28</ref> below contains the aggregated choice proportions for the first and second occurrences of the scenarios that are identical in experiment 2 &amp; 3 (emergency delivery, jail overcrowding, inevitable injury, rescue plan; the choice proportions for each scenario are provided in SI). Experiment 2 shows a stronger attraction effect across subjects among these items compared to Experiment 3 in both first and second occurrences. During the second occurrence, the effect is not present in Experiment 3.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 28</ref>: Attraction effect across subjects shown as aggregated choice proportions for first and second occurrences of identical items (emergency delivery, jail overcrowding, inevitable injury, rescue plan) in Experiment 2 (N=475) and 3 (N=456).</p><p>Choice proportions across trials in revised dilemmas. Below we include the results of attraction effects across subjects for the revised scenarios (worker welfare 2, worker welfare, jail overcrowding 2, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">Figure 29</ref>). We observe an attraction effect in Experiment 3 after the revision of items, especially in the first occurrences of items.  1. Each subject does 8 pairs of questions, corresponding to 8 scenarios. For each scenario, we look at the structure of the 2 questions in a pair.</p><p>2. If both questions have an Attraction Configuration, then we sample a choice pattern given the <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> data. We have chosen to use the distribution of response patterns <ref type="table" target="#tab_27">(Table 23)</ref> given <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> data as <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> tasks use gambles as decision problems, where both attributes involved in the decision -probability of winning and the amount of money to win have a clear ranking across individuals (i.e., higher probability and higher amount are desirable) -resulting in less noisy responses. However, we have adjusted the decoy selection rate to match the mean decoy selection rate from our empirical results (0.08) in Experiment 3 and renormalized the distributions.</p><p>3. If only one question has an Attraction Configuration, then for the single question with an Attraction Configuration, we sample a choice given the Wedell data (also adjusted the decoy selection rate, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_28">Table 24</ref>).</p><p>4. For the questions that do not have an Attraction Configuration, we sample 2 choices sequentially (given the randomly assigned order in which subject sees the question).</p><p>• If seeing a scenario for the first time:</p><p>a. this question has the Best Option Configuration: select best option with 1error ( ϵ) b. this question has the Worst Option Configuration: select worst option with error ϵ c. this question has the Similarity Configuration: sample a choice given the pattern in <ref type="bibr">Trueblood (2012)</ref> data <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">(Table 25)</ref>. d. this question has the Compromise Configuration: sample a choice given the pattern in <ref type="bibr">Trueblood (2012)</ref> data <ref type="table" target="#tab_29">(Table 26</ref>). Since we don't have decoy options in this case as defined in <ref type="bibr">Trueblood (2012)</ref>, both options other than the compromising option are considered as extreme options.</p><p>• If seeing a scenario for the second time: with p consistent , select the same option as before; with (1 − p consistent ), select an option that is not the same option as before.</p><p>Lastly, we map the choices back onto the original A, B, D in the decision problem.     Figure 31: Simulated and empirical "consistent choice" selection rates (left) and "competitor reversal" rates (right) for each scenario and decoy type. Generally, simulated same selection rates were lower than those in empirical data and simulated "competitor reversal" selection rates were higher than those in empirical data.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2: Attraction effect across all trials, shown as choice proportions for A, B options in aggregate: (a). Attraction effect in Wedell(1991) with economic gambles; (b). Attraction effect in our Wedell (1991) replication study with economic gambles (Experiment 1a); (c). Attraction effect in Wedell-isomorphic ethical dilemmas (Experiment 1b).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Within-subject response patterns (competitor reversals &amp; target choice reversals) are</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>The illustration of the task structures of<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> decision problem (left) and our ethical dilemmas (right).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Distributions of performances (mean EV) in economic gambles (Experiment 1a) and in ethical decisions (Experiment 1b) . CI= [−0.19, −0.07]). The distributions of performances in two are displayed in Figure 5, and the full posteriors are reported in Appendix B,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(a)  Relationship between performance and target reversal rate-each dot represents one subject. The light-color lines are constructed from 500 random samples from the total 15200 posterior samples and the dashed lines are medians from the posterior distributions of model parameters; (b) Distributions of target reversal rates in economic gambles (Experiment 1a) and ethical decisions (Experiment 1b). The lines show overall target reversal rates in two experiments, and the blue dashed line shows the overall target reversal rates in<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Response patterns (competitor reversals &amp; target/choice reversals) aggregated over all items in Experiment 2 (N=475).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>R E G A T E D w o r k e r w e l f a r e i n e v i t a b l e i n ju r y ja i l o v e r c r o w d i n g 2 ja i l o v e r c r o w d i n g r e s c u e p l a n w o r k e r w e l f a r e 2 e m e r g e n c y d e l i v e r y scenario Posterior estimates with 95% CI Figure 9: Posterior estimates for means and 95% CIs of the main parameter of interest, β decoy A</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Aggregated response patterns for all items (excluding firing an employee) in Experiment 3 (N = 456).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 12 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Descriptive and statistical results for shared items aggregated in Experiment 2 and 3 combined data (N=931): (a). Response patterns (excluding "consistent") aggregated over identical items from both Experiment 2 and 3. (b). Posteriors from the full model analysis of identical items from Experiment 2 and 3 for β decoy A</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Simulated and Experiment 3's empirical decoy selection rates (left) and choice reversal rates (right) for each scenario and decoy type.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure 15 :</head><label>15</label><figDesc>Descriptive results -full response patterns in: (a).<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell(1991)</ref>; (b).<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> replication; (c). Ethical decisions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. Attraction effect from data in the first session(b). No attraction effect from data in the second session</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>Figure 18 :Figure 19 :</head><label>1819</label><figDesc>Aggregated choice proportions during the first and second session in Experiment 2 (N=475). We observe a clear attraction effect across subjects in the first session, but the effect is not present in the second session. Full response patterns for data aggregated over all items in Experiment 2 (N=475).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>Figure 20 :Figure 22 :</head><label>2022</label><figDesc>Choice patterns for all 8 ethical dilemmas. Posteriors for the full model: β gm A and β gm D indicate the log odds of choosing A and D when decoy is "atB" and "1D".β decoy A and β decoy D indicate the change in log odds of choosing A &amp; D over B when decoy is changed from "atB" to "atA". β type A and β type D indicate the change in logodds of choosing A &amp; D over B when decoy is changed to 2D. β type * decoy A and β type * decoy D indicate the interaction of decoy position and type effect on the change in log odds of choosing A &amp; D over B. σ w estimates the sd of the item variations' distribution.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head>Figure 24 :Figure 27 :</head><label>2427</label><figDesc>. Attraction effect from data in the first block(b). No attraction effect from data in the second blockFigure 23: Aggregated choice proportions during the first and second blocks in Experiment 3 (N=456). We observe a clear attraction effect across subjects in the first block, but not in the second block. Aggregated response patterns for all items (excluding firing an employee) in Experiment 3 Posteriors for the full model: β gm A and β gm D indicate the log odds of choosing A and D when decoy is "atB" and "1D".β decoy A and β decoy D indicate the change in log odds of choosing A &amp; D over B when decoy is changed from "atB" to "atA". β type A and β type D indicate the change in logodds of choosing A &amp; D over B when decoy is changed to 2D. β type * decoy A and β type * decoy D indicate the interaction of decoy position and type effect on the change in log odds of choosing A &amp; D over B. σ w estimates the sd of the item variations' distribution.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>Figure 29 :</head><label>29</label><figDesc>Attraction effect shown as aggregated choice proportions for first and second occurrences of revised items (worker welfare 2, worker welfare, jail overcrowding 2) in Experiment 2 (N=475) and 3 (N=456). Full response patterns aggregated over identical items from both Experiment 2 and 3. Posteriors from the full model analysis of identical items from Experiment 2 and 3: β gm A and β gm D indicate the log odds of choosing A and D when decoy is "atB" and "1D".β decoy A and β decoy D indicate the change in log odds of choosing A &amp; D over B when decoy is changed from "atB" to "atA". β type A and β type D indicate the change in logodds of choosing A &amp; D over B when decoy is changed to 2D. β type * decoy A and β type * decoy D indicate the interaction of decoy position and type effect on the change in log odds of choosing A &amp; D over B. σ w estimates the sd of the item variations' distribution.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Figure 30 :</head><label>30</label><figDesc>Descriptive and statistical results for identical items aggregated in Experiment 2 and 3 combined data (N=931).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>An example of a question with the attributes motivation for committing a robbery and probability of recommitting the same crime.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 15 ,</head><label>15</label><figDesc>Appendix B have shown convergence for all four chains. statistics The posterior estimates for means and 95% credible intervals (CI) for the parameters in both models are shown inTable 15, Appendix B. For the full model, the central tendencies and 95% credible intervals of the posterior distributions are shown inFigure 16, Appendix B.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Posterior All estimates and 95% CIs for our parameter of interest, beta decoy A</cell><cell>, are positive, suggest-</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">ing a clear contextual choice reversal. Particularly, in the full model, the mean estimate</cell></row><row><cell>for beta decoy A</cell><cell>is 0.75, showing a choice reversal effect</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>The four task versions in part 2 and 3 of Experiment 2.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Possible structures/configurations given all possible feature rankings.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Summary of inconsistent behaviors and their underlying moral heuristics.</figDesc><table><row><cell>B Experiment 1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>B.1 Wedell (1991) stimuli</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Decoy bets</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Target bets</cell><cell>R</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>RF</cell></row><row><cell>Target A</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>table below shows an example of the data structure. Empirical data were organized as choice patterns for all subjects.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">subject pair decoy type pair choice pattern</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1D</cell><cell>consistent choice</cell></row><row><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>target reversal</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>1D</cell><cell>target reversal</cell></row><row><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>31</cell><cell>1D</cell><cell>decoy selected</cell></row><row><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell></row><row><cell>J</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>1D</cell><cell>target reversal</cell></row><row><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell><cell>...</cell></row><row><cell>J</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>competitor reversal</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>Table 12 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>An Example of the Data Coded as Choice Patterns for J Subjects.The table below shows the proportions of choice reversals in Experiment 1a and 1b, calculated from total number of pairs that exhibit a choice reversal (defined as subject choosing targets for this pair for both decoy positions) over total number of pairs done by all subjects for each decoy type.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Decoy Type</cell><cell cols="4">Subjects Total Pairs Done # of PR Proportions of PR</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment 1a</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1D (R)</cell><cell>142</cell><cell>382</cell><cell>82</cell><cell>0.21</cell></row><row><cell>1D (F)</cell><cell>137</cell><cell>367</cell><cell>83</cell><cell>0.23</cell></row><row><cell>2D</cell><cell>142</cell><cell>371</cell><cell>63</cell><cell>0.17</cell></row><row><cell>control</cell><cell>145</cell><cell>380</cell><cell>63</cell><cell>0.17</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment 1b</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1D (R)</cell><cell>47</cell><cell>129</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>0.11</cell></row><row><cell>1D (F)</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>150</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>0.13</cell></row><row><cell>2D</cell><cell>47</cell><cell>112</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>0.14</cell></row><row><cell>control</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>109</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>0.16</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Table 13</head><label>13</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>: Proportions of Within Subject Choice Reversals (PR) Occurrences in Experiment</cell></row><row><cell>1a and 1b.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head>Table 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Experiment 1a<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Wedell (1991)</ref> Replication) posterior statistics.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>Rhat n eff mean</cell><cell>sd</cell><cell cols="2">2.5% 50% 97.5%</cell></row><row><cell>Full Model β gm A β gm D β control A β 2D A β decoy A β control * decoy A β 2D * decoy A β control D β 2D D β decoy D β control * decoy D β 2D * decoy D Simple Model β gm A β gm D β 1D(R) A β 2D A β decoy A β 1D(R) D β 2D D β decoy D</cell><cell cols="3">1.00 3283 1.00 2025 -6.31 1.55 0.42 0.12 1.00 3137 0.27 0.23 1.00 3089 0.12 0.23 1.00 3090 0.75 0.19 1.00 2799 -1.01 0.33 1.00 2962 -0.31 0.35 1.00 2772 -3.45 3.34 -10.62 -3.17 0.17 0.41 -9.89 -6.09 -0.17 0.27 -0.32 0.12 0.38 0.75 -1.67 -1.00 -1.00 -0.31 1.00 2195 1.92 1.83 -1.60 1.84 1.00 2079 4.38 1.58 1.89 4.16 1.00 3435 -3.00 3.75 -10.84 -2.94 1.00 2230 -2.39 1.93 -6.38 -2.32 1.00 4800 0.34 0.14 0.06 0.34 1.00 1970 -5.89 1.18 -8.62 -5.75 1.00 3915 0.25 0.19 -0.11 0.26 1.00 4103 0.10 0.19 -0.29 0.10 1.00 4800 0.66 0.16 0.35 0.66 1.00 3466 1.23 0.73 -0.12 1.21 1.00 3456 0.64 0.81 -0.93 0.63 1.00 1906 3.14 1.11 1.47 2.99</cell><cell>0.66 -3.91 0.72 0.59 1.14 -0.34 0.38 2.37 5.66 8.01 4.07 1.31 0.63 -4.00 0.63 0.48 0.97 2.79 2.22 5.71</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16"><head>Table 15 :</head><label>15</label><figDesc>Experiment 1b (ethical decisions) posterior statistics.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_19"><head>Table 16 :</head><label>16</label><figDesc>Experiment 1 -posterior statistics for parameters in the model comparing performance in ethical decisions (reference group) and economic gambles.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell cols="2">Rhat n eff mean</cell><cell cols="2">sd 2.5% 50% 97.5%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">β 0 targetreversal (Intercept) 1.00 12055</cell><cell cols="2">0.20 0.02 0.15 0.20</cell><cell>0.24</cell></row><row><cell>β 1 targetreversal</cell><cell cols="3">1.00 11214 -0.04 0.03 -0.10 -0.04</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>sigma</cell><cell>1.00 12505</cell><cell cols="2">0.17 0.01 0.15 0.17</cell><cell>0.19</cell></row><row><cell>mean PPD</cell><cell>1.00 14261</cell><cell cols="2">0.16 0.02 0.13 0.16</cell><cell>0.20</cell></row><row><cell>log-posterior</cell><cell cols="4">1.00 6708 69.24 1.25 66.01 69.56 70.67</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_20"><head>Table 17 :</head><label>17</label><figDesc>Experiment 1 -posterior statistics for parameters in the model comparing target reversal rates in ethical decisions (reference group) and economic gambles.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell cols="2">Rhat n eff mean</cell><cell cols="2">sd 2.5%</cell><cell cols="2">50% 97.5%</cell></row><row><cell>β 0 (Intercept)</cell><cell>1.00 17139</cell><cell cols="2">9.78 0.02</cell><cell>9.73</cell><cell>9.78</cell><cell>9.82</cell></row><row><cell>β 1</cell><cell>1.00 11098</cell><cell cols="2">0.60 0.17</cell><cell>0.26</cell><cell>0.60</cell><cell>0.93</cell></row><row><cell>β 2</cell><cell>1.00 17954</cell><cell cols="2">0.20 0.05</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.19</cell><cell>0.29</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">β 3 (interaction) 1.00 12372 -0.63 0.32 -1.26 -0.63</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>mean PPD</cell><cell>1.00 17054</cell><cell cols="2">9.83 0.03</cell><cell>9.77</cell><cell>9.82</cell><cell>9.88</cell></row><row><cell>log-posterior</cell><cell cols="6">1.00 6523 -42.62 1.61 -46.59 -42.29 -40.49</cell></row><row><cell>σ</cell><cell>1.00 16642</cell><cell cols="2">0.29 0.01</cell><cell>0.27</cell><cell>0.29</cell><cell>0.32</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_23"><head>Table 20 :</head><label>20</label><figDesc>Posterior mean and 95% CIs for the full model parameters (Experiment 2).</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_25"><head>Table 21 :</head><label>21</label><figDesc>Posterior mean and 95% CIs for the full model parameters (Experiment 3).</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_27"><head>Table 23 :</head><label>23</label><figDesc>Distribution of Choice Patterns in<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> after re-normalizing.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">decoy position decoy type option prob</cell></row><row><cell>atA</cell><cell>1D</cell><cell>A</cell><cell>.65</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>B</cell><cell>.25</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>D</cell><cell>.08</cell></row><row><cell>atB</cell><cell>1D</cell><cell>A</cell><cell>.52</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>B</cell><cell>.38</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>D</cell><cell>.08</cell></row><row><cell>atA</cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>A</cell><cell>.66</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>B</cell><cell>.24</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>D</cell><cell>.08</cell></row><row><cell>atB</cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>A</cell><cell>.56</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>B</cell><cell>.34</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>D</cell><cell>.08</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_28"><head>Table 24 :</head><label>24</label><figDesc>Marginal Distributions of Choices<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> after re-normalizing.Table 25: Distribution of choices in Trueblood (2012) -similarity effect. Focal option refers to the option that is enhanced by the decoy.</figDesc><table><row><cell>option</cell><cell>prob</cell></row><row><cell>decoy</cell><cell>.2</cell></row><row><cell>focal option</cell><cell>.5</cell></row><row><cell>non-focal option</cell><cell>.3</cell></row><row><cell>option</cell><cell>prob</cell></row><row><cell>compromise</cell><cell>.48</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">extreme options .26</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_29"><head>Table 26 :</head><label>26</label><figDesc>Distribution of choices in Trueblood (2012) -compromise effect.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">For the purpose of our work, we distinguish the decoy types as one-dimensional (1D) or twodimensional (2D), and we consider the decoy dominated by both options a control decoy. To test specific hypotheses,<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref> positions the decoys as the Range decoy (R), the Frequency decoy (F), the Range-Frequency decoy (RF), and the Rprime decoy (R'). R and F decoys are 1D decoys, and RF decoys are 2D decoys.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">As we focus on the contrast between 1D and 2D decoy, we take the mean response rates for<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wedell (1991)</ref>'s R and F decoys as the response rates for 1D decoy in our analyses.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">The rescue a survivor item only appeared in Experiment 2.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Tyler Adkins, Logan Bickel, Pyeong Whan Cho, Ian Cook, Hannah Foster, Nicole Hamilton, Steven Langsford, Sarah Marks, Connor McMann, Logan Walls for helpful discussions and feedback over the many years.</p><p>This research was supported by University of Michigan College of Literature, Science and the Arts, and Templeton World Charity Foundation Grant #TWCF0205. Sponsors played no role in the conduct of the research or the preparation of the article or the decision to submit the article for publication.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E Explaining variation in contextual choice reversals across ethical dilemmas E.1 Algorithm for generating decision problems' structures given feature rankings</head><p>Here we describe a general algorithm to generate the decision problem's structure given any possible ranking. When we constructed decision problems in Experiment 3, we constructed options (A, B, D) whose rankings of levels in each attribute were our assumed rankings. However, in reality, decision makers do not have the same rankings of levels in each attribute.</p><p>Therefore, our first step is to generate all 24 possible rankings of four levels in an attribute <ref type="figure">(a 1 a 2 a 3 a 4 , a 1 a 2 a 4 a 3 , a 1 a 3 a 2 a 4 , a 1 a 3 a 4 a 2 , a 1 a 4 a 2 a 3 , a 1 a 4 a 3 a 2 , a 2 a 1 a 4 a 3 , a 2 a 1 a 3 a 4 ,  a 2 a 3 a 4 a 1 , a 2 a 3 a 1 a 4 , a 2 a 4 a 1 a 3 , a 2 a 4 a 3 a 1 , a 3 a 1 a 4 a 2 , a 3 a 1 a 2 a 4 , a 3 a 2 a 4 a 1 , a 3 a 2 a 1 a 4 , a 3 a 4 a 1 a 2 ,  a 3 a 4 a 2 a 1 , a 4 a 1 a 3 a 2 , a 4 a 1 a 2 a 3 , a 4 a 2 a 1 a 3 , a 4 a 2 a 3 a 1 , a 4 a 3 a 1 a 2 , a 4 a 3 a 2 a 1 )</ref>. These rankings are strict total order sets. We do not exclude the possibility that there are intransitive orders.</p><p>Second, given a ranking for one attribute and a ranking for another attribute, we reconstruct which of the original options (A, B, D) is the target, competitor, and decoy in the current decision problem. However, not all rankings allow us to yield a mapping between original options (A, B, D) and an Attraction Configuration (i.e., a target, a competitor, and a decoy). We describe how we discover all possible structures below.</p><p>For each question, we assume 2 attributes with four levels in each attributes and we are able to construct options with 2 attributes (16 possible options). To choose three options out of 16 possibilities without repetition, there are 560 sets given n k = n! k!(n−k)! . We plot each set of the three options in a 2D space and match them to the 5 possible configurations <ref type="table">(Table 9)</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.2 Generating choices given decision problems' structures</head><p>Recall that in Experiment 3, each subject sees all 8 scenarios, among which 6 scenarios have both 1D decoy and 2D decoy, and 2 scenarios only have 1D decoy. Thus, each subject randomly sees a total of 16 questions -the 1D-decoy or 2D-decoy version of the 6 scenarios and the other 2 scenarios, and the manipulation of decoy position (i.e., dominance) is within subject. We use the following choice function to generate choices for 16 ethical dilemmas in Experiment 3:</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universals and variations in moral decisions made in 42 countries by 70,000 participants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Awad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dsouza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shariff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rahwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-F</forename><surname>Bonnefon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1911517117</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2332" to="2337" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">If you&apos;re going to do wrong, at least do it right: Considering two moral dilemmas at the same time promotes moral consistency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Barak-Corren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C.-J</forename><surname>Tsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bazerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>1528-1540. doi: 10.1287/ mnsc.2016.2659</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Making decisions about liability and insurance: A special issue of the journal of risk and uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ritov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-94-011-2192-72</idno>
		<editor>C. Camerer &amp; H. Kunreuther</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="33" />
			<pubPlace>Dordrecht; Netherlands</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Intuitions about penalties and compensation in the context of tort law</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Omission bias, individual differences, and normality. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ritov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.obhdp.2004.03.003</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="74" to="85" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Establishing the laws of preferential choice behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loomes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment &amp; Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Harm to others outweighs harm to self in moral decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Kurth-Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Siegel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1408988111</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17320" to="17325" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The problem of abortion and the doctrine of double effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Foot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Oxford Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral satisficing: Rethinking moral behavior as bounded rationality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gabry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brilleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1756-8765.2010.01094</idno>
		<ptr target="https://mc-stan.org/rstanarm" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="528" to="554" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>rstanarm: Bayesian applied regression modeling via Stan. R package version 2.21.1)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why contextual preference reversals in humans maximize expected value</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Howes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Warren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Farmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>El-Deredy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0039996</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adding asymmetrically dominated alternatives: Violations of regularity and the similarity hypothesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Puto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do defaults save lives?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Goldstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1091721</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">302</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5649</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1338" to="1339" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Representativeness revisited: Attribute substitution in intuitive judgment. Heuristics and biases: The psychology of intuitive judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Frederick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/CBO9780511808098.004</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="81" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shared outrage and erratic awards: The psychology of punitive damages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schkade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1007710408413</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Kant: Religion within the boundaries of mere reason: And other writings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Kant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A computational model of commonsense moral decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kleiman-Weiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abeliuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Awad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dsouza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rahwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1801.04346</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Betrayal aversion: When agents of protection become agents of harm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Koehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gershoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0749-5978(02)00518-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0749-5978(02)00518-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="244" to="261" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Irrational decision-making in an amoeboid organism: transitivity and context-dependent preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Latty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Beekman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">278</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="1703" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence of uncertainty on framed decision-making with moral dilemma</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Merlhiot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mermillod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Jean-Luc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Dutheil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mondillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">05)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two types of heuristics in moral decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Nadurak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Filosifija sociologija</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why moral heuristics can lead to mistaken moral judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Nadurak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Kriterion (Austria)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2020, 01)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Mortal questions</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Canto edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The attraction effect and political choice in two elections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O'curry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pitts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15327663jcp040104</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327663jcp040104" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rhesus macaques (macaca mulatta) exhibit the decoy effect in a perceptual discrimination task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Parrish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Beran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception, &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1715" to="1725" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Attention</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing the effect of time pressure on asymmetric dominance and compromise decoys in choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Pettibone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">513</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Computer software manual</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spontaneous giving and calculated greed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nowak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7416</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="427" to="457" />
			<date type="published" when="2012-09-20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How do people use &apos;killing&apos;, &apos;letting die&apos; and related bioethical concepts? contrasting descriptive and normative hypotheses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rodriguez-Arias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rodriguez Lopez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Monasterio-Astobiza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hannikainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/bioe.12707</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bioethics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="509" to="518" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Technological stigma: Some perspectives from the study of contagion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rozin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Risk, media, and stigma: Understanding public challenges to modern science and technology</title>
		<editor>J. Flynn, P. Slovic, &amp; H. Kunreuther</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Earthscan</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Behavioral Model of Rational Choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1884852</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="118" />
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral intuitions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Sinnott-Armstrong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The moral psychology handbook</title>
		<editor>J. M. Doris</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="246" to="272" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian linear mixed models using stan: A tutorial for psychologists, linguists, and cognitive scientists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sorensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hohenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vasishth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.20982/tqmp.12.3.p175</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.tqmp.org/RegularArticles/vol12-3/p175/p175.pdfdoi:10.20982/tqmp.12.3.p175" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quantitative Methods for Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rstan: the r interface to stan</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stan</forename><surname>Development Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>r package version 2.16.2. [Computer software manual</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Risk and reason: safety, law, and the environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lives, life-years, and willingness to pay</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Columbia Law Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">moral heuristics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X05000099</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="542" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Killing, letting die, and the trolley problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Monist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="204" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not just for consumers: Context effects are fundamental to decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heathcote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797612464241</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="901" to="908" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The computational and neural substrates of moral strategies in social decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Van Baar Jeroen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Sanfey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Corporate risk analysis: A reckless act</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Viscusi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Stanford Law Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="547" to="597" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing among models of contextually induced preference reversals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wedell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="767" to="778" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Moral luck: Philosophical papers 1973-1980</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bernard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling morality in 3-d: Decision-making, judgment, and inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Siegel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>doi: 10.1111/ tops.12382</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="432" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
