<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Socioecology drives adaptive social foraging dynamics in the wild</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Schakowski</surname></persName>
							<email>schakowski@mpib-berlin.mpg.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominik</forename><surname>Deffner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Philipps-Universität Marburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Marburg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Science of Intelligence Excellence Cluster</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raine</forename><surname>Kortet</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Environmental and Biological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Eastern Finland</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Joensuu</settlement>
									<country key="FI">Finland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petri</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Niemelä</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Biological and Environmental Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Organismal and Evolutionary Biology Research Program</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Helsinki</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Helsinki</settlement>
									<country key="FI">Finland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marwa</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kavelaars</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Life Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Monk</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department">Marine Evolutionary Ecology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">GEOMAR Helmholtz Centre of Ocean Research Kiel</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kiel</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Pykälä</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff8">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Business and Economics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Lausanne</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Lausanne</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><forename type="middle">H J M</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Science of Intelligence Excellence Cluster</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff9">
								<orgName type="department">Leibniz-Institute of Freshwater Ecology and Inland Fisheries</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Socioecology drives adaptive social foraging dynamics in the wild</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:42+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Following the CRediT standard (54). Conceptualization: A.S., D.D., R.K., P.T.N., M.M.K., C.T.M., R.H.J.M.K.</term>
					<term>Data curation: A.S.</term>
					<term>Formal analysis: A.S., D.D.</term>
					<term>Funding acquisition: R.K., R.H.J.M.K.</term>
					<term>Investigation: A.S., D.D., R.K., P.T.N., M.M.K., M.P., R.H.J.M.K.</term>
					<term>Methodology: A.S., D.D., R.K., P.T.N., C.T.M., R.H.J.M.K.</term>
					<term>Project administration: A.S., R.K., R.H.J.M.K.</term>
					<term>Resources: R.K., R.H.M.J.K.</term>
					<term>Software: A.S.</term>
					<term>Supervision: D.D., R.K., R.H.J.M.K.</term>
					<term>Validation: A.S., D.D., R.H.J.M.K.</term>
					<term>Visualization: A.S.</term>
					<term>Writing -original draft:</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Foraging complexity and competitive social challenges are considered key drivers of human cognition. Yet, the decision-making mechanisms underlying social foraging in the real world remain unknown. Integrating high-precision GPS tracking and video footage from large-scale foraging competitions with with organizing the competitions, Deb Ain for copy-editing the manuscript, Charley M. Wu for helpful comments on an earlier version of this manuscript, Robert Arlinghaus for developing the surveys, and Félicie Dhellemmes for recording the drone footage.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The uniquely complex human foraging niche with its many ecological and social challenges is considered a main driver of the evolution of cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(4)</ref>. Diverse forms of human foragingincluding seal hunting in the Arctic, tuber digging in the tropics, wild berry picking, and recreational fishing-persist globally <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(5)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(7)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(8)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(9)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10)</ref>, testifying to a human adaptability that is unparalleled across animal taxa <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12)</ref>.</p><p>Foraging is, cross-culturally, considered a profoundly social activity <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14)</ref>. However, almost all existing field studies focused on solitary foraging, approaching foraging decisions as if they occurred in isolation from the social context <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(15)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(16)</ref>. Thus, it remains largely unknown how humans dynamically integrate personal and ecological with social information streams across diverse environments to inform fundamental foraging decisions, such as where to go and when to leave <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17)</ref>. Clarifying these mechanisms not only informs key parameters of social foraging theories and sheds light on flexible social decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18)</ref>, but also helps better predict collective human adaptation and mobility to changing climates and resource availability.</p><p>To study how social foragers weigh different streams of information in situ, we combined high-resolution tracking, computational and agent-based modeling techniques. Building on recent developments in biologging technology (19, 20), we equipped large groups of foragers competing for resources in ice-fishing competitions in Finland with GPS tracking devices and headcams recording spatial search and resource return (i.e., fish catches). To disentangle how personal, social, and ecological information are dynamically integrated to guide spatial search and patchleaving decisions at individual-level resolution, we developed generative computational models of decision-making and tested their predictions against observed behaviour. Tracking the same foragers across two years on different lakes also allowed us to quantify both the stability of interindividual differences in foraging strategies and adaptations to environmental gradients.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ice-fishing as a model for social foraging</head><p>Ice-fishing is a rich tradition in the Nordic countries (21, 22) that has evolved from subsistence foraging into regional and national competitions. Ice-fishing competitions offer a unique paradigm to study social foraging in a controlled yet natural setting involving mobile resources, complex and dynamically changing social information landscapes, and challenging physical and ecological conditions. In February 2022 and March 2023, we held a total of 10 ice-fishing competitions on 10 lakes across Northern Karelia, Eastern Finland (median lake size [min, max] = 2.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">see table S1</ref> for demographic details and figs. S12, S13, and S14 and Supplementary Text for details of participants' motives for participation and the cultural importance of ice-fishing competitions).</p><p>Participants were equipped with GPS devices and headcams providing high-resolution data on spatial search and fish catches <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 1C</ref>,D,F,G). For all lakes, we also obtained bathymetric data, which participants use to identify promising foraging locations <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 1D</ref>).</p><p>During the competitions, participants were free to relocate by foot within the competition area and to drill holes and angle using their personal fishing gear. Movie S1 shows a participant relocating, drilling, and angling during a competition; movie S2 shows an aerial view of typical relocation patterns; and movie S3 shows a 3D animation of a competition. Participants had to continuously make two key decisions: where to forage and when to leave for the next foraging location (23). To investigate the processes underlying both decisions, we discretized the highresolution spatiotemporal data by manually annotating foraging locations, fish catches, and spotleaving decisions from the videos and combined this with the timestamped GPS data <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 1F,G</ref>).</p><p>On average, participants covered 1,247m (SD across individuals = 780m; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig. S15</ref>) to visit 33.5 (SD across individuals = 15.5) angling spots (fig. S16) per competition, resulting in a total of <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr">055</ref> angling spots. During competitions, participants aggregated in locally dense but spatially dispersed clusters ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig. 1B; and fig. S1</ref>). Below, we use computational modeling to test whether these clusters were due to social information use (i.e., deciding to join others), converging personal information (i.e., independent detection of the same resource patches), or shared use of the same ecological information (i.e., bathymetric features).</p><p>Participants spent, on average, 200.4s (SD = 330.3s) at angling spots. The more fish they caught, the longer they stayed (standardized [95%CrI] = 0. <ref type="bibr">75 [0.74, 0.76]</ref>, N = 16,055; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. S2D</ref>).</p><p>Below, we use computational modeling to test the strategies and learning mechanisms underlying participants' leaving decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(17,</ref><ref type="bibr">24,</ref><ref type="bibr">25)</ref>. The 10 lakes strongly differed in resource abundance:</p><p>The average catch ranged from 279g (SD = 343g) to 2,012g (SD = 1,186g) and the percentage of successful angling spots (at least one fish catch) ranged from 3.9% to 32.0% ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. S2A,B</ref>).</p><p>Both average catch and percentage of successful angling spots strongly correlated across lakes </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Socioecology drives adaptive search</head><p>We begin with the decision of where to forage. To disentangle the effects of personal, social, and ecological information on spatial search, we developed a modeling framework inspired by step-selection models commonly used to understand animal movement decisions in complex environments (26-29). Within this framework, we estimated the relative importance of four spatial features for the decision of where to forage next: densities of successful and unsuccessful angling spots (personal information), density of other participants (social information), and distance to the closest depth curve as a measure of lake-bed roughness (ecological information; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 2A-D)</ref>.</p><p>Angling spots were considered successful if at least one fish had been caught there and unsuccessful if none had been caught. Areas closer to depth curves were considered rougher.</p><p>The model also contains two bandwidth parameters governing the degree to which personal and social information are spatially generalized. Low bandwidth estimates indicate that individuals expect that personal and social information is relevant for nearby areas only, whereas high bandwidth estimates indicate that individuals assume that personal and social information is also relevant for more distant areas. Spatial feature weights combined with bandwidth parameters thus capture participants' mental representations of the resource distribution across time and space (30-32).</p><p>To account for the nested hierarchical data structure (e.g., the same participants were followed on multiple lakes), feature weights were estimated for each foraging trip with random effects for foraging trip, lake, and participant. Bandwidth parameters were estimated for each lake. The full model specification is available in (33). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 2E</ref> shows that participants used all three sources of information-personal, social, and ecological-to select their next angling spot. They were more likely to select spots close to successful spots, close to other participants, in areas with steeper depth curve gradients, and they avoided unsuccessful spots. Systematic model comparisons showed that personal and social information were important for angling spot selection, whereas ecological information played only a minor role ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">fig. S3</ref>).</p><p>Individuals used these sources of information adaptively in a Brunswikian sense (34). Angling spots closer to successful spots and to other participants were indeed more likely to be successful, and angling spots closer to unsuccessful spots were less likely to be successful. Lake-bed roughness, however, did not predict success ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 2F</ref>). Participants exploited these features, relying mostly on personal and social information and only weakly on ecological information ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. 2E</ref>).</p><p>In line with theories of social learning (35, 36) and experimental evidence (31), we found evidence for conditional social information use: Participants became less (more) sensitive to social information when successful (unsuccessful; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 2G</ref>). Although small in effect size, such conditional social information usage may safeguard against maladaptive herding in clustered resource environments (37).</p><p>Participants integrated personal and social information at different spatial scales ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 2H, and</ref> fig. S4): Personal information was used more locally compared to social information. This suggests that personal information provided more precise-but also more costly to obtain-information about the location of successful angling spots, whereas social information was a less precise-but cheaper-source of information that facilitates exploration <ref type="bibr">(35,</ref><ref type="bibr">38,</ref><ref type="bibr">39)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Socially amplified search dynamics</head><p>To investigate how the estimated feature weights impacted the behavioural search dynamics, we employed an agent-based model to simulate synthetic foraging trajectories for all participants based on their estimated parameters in the spot-selection model. Our simulations recovered several key empirical search dynamics. In line with theories of area-restricted search (40, 41) and ample empirical findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">31)</ref>, we found that successful spot visits induced localized search by decreasing relocation distances <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Fig. 3A</ref>) and increasing turning angles <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Fig. 3B)</ref>. The longer the sequence of unsuccessful spots visits, the further participants relocated and at smaller turning angles. In contrast to a random walk, which would predict constant relocation distances and turning angles irrespective of foraging success, our model reproduced these patterns of localized search following patch discoveries <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Fig. 3A,B</ref>).</p><p>Using systematic parameter lesions to investigate the spatial features required to reproduce this pattern, we found that area-restricted search emerged from two processes: Participants sought out successful areas and avoided unsuccessful ones. Both processes are required to recover the gradually decaying effect of patch discoveries on movement behaviour ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">fig. S5</ref>). While many existing models of area-restricted search mathematically formalize search behaviour top-down, our results show how spatiotemporal dynamics emerge from basic decision-making processes. As a consequence of area-restricted search, successful participants explored less space (in both the empirical data and the simulations; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_28">fig. S6</ref>), suggesting that local aggregations of foragers are indeed a valid cue for the presence of resources.</p><p>When foraging in socially dense areas, area-restricted search was more pronounced; that is, individuals foraged more locally. This pattern was also reproduced by our model <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(Fig. 3C, D)</ref>. A parameter lesion analysis showed that social attraction in combination with attraction to successful areas and avoidance of unsuccessful areas was sufficient to reproduce this social phenomenon ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">fig. S5</ref>). Thus, encountering resources led to more localized search in the presence of others. This result demonstrates how individual-level tendencies can amplify in a social context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Incremental spot-leaving strategies</head><p>Next, we turn to the decision of when to leave an angling spot. In line with other foraging domains and theoretical assumptions of many optimal foraging models (42-44), fish catches at successful angling spots depleted at a constant rate (fig. S17, see (33) for specification of depletion models). To investigate the strategies individuals use to adapt to depleting resources, we tested the importance of eight cues for leaving decisions: time without fish catches as a measure of instantaneous reward rates, patch discoveries (i.e., whether a fish had already been caught there), global waiting times (i.e., average waiting time for fish catches across past angling spots), local waiting times (i.e., average waiting time for fish catches at the present angling spot), and the four spatial features known to guide spatial search (density of successful and unsuccessful spots, social density, and lake-bed roughness; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 2E</ref>). To estimate the role of learning mechanisms for leaving decisions, we assumed that global and local waiting times are updated at different rates through time and across successive spot visits inspired by reinforcement learning models. For the full model specification, see (33).</p><p>The longer participants caught no fish, the more likely they were to leave an angling spot ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Fig. 4A</ref>, upper half). Discovering a patch reduced the overall tendency to leave an angling spot ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Fig. 4A</ref>, lower half), suggesting that participants quickly inferred whether fish were present and only stayed longer if they learned that they were. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Fig. 4B</ref> illustrates how both cues jointly affected the probability to leave an angling spot over time. Overall, there was a reduced tendency to leave a spot after a first catch.</p><p>The probability to leave a spot was additionally modulated by local and global waiting times in opposite directions: In line with predictions from marginal value theorem (43), catching fish at a high rate decreased the probability to leave that spot, whereas high average catch rates across previous angling spots increased the probability to leave a spot <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig. 4C</ref>). However, these effects were small and model comparisons showed that including both cues did not improve predictive accuracy ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_29">fig. S7</ref>). This suggests that learning mechanisms within and across angling spots played only a minor role in spot-leaving decisions, likely due to strong prior beliefs about the foraging ecology (45).</p><p>Individuals were slightly less likely to leave a spot in areas of high social density, and slightly more likely to leave a spot in an unsuccessful area. There were no effects of the other spatial features on spot-leaving decisions <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig. 4D</ref>). Model comparisons showed that including spatial features only added little predictive accuracy ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_29">fig. S7</ref>), suggesting that spot-leaving decisions were less strongly influenced by social density than were spot-selection decisions. A potential explanation for this discrepancy is that social densities provide useful information in the absence of more reliable personal information when selecting a spot, but are overridden by more immediate personal experience when fishing at an angling spot <ref type="bibr">[cf. (35, 38, 46)</ref>].</p><p>In sum, and in line with experimental evidence from lab studies (24, 47) we found strong evidence for simple incremental spot-leaving strategies that are sensitive to instantaneous reward rates (i.e., time without catches), and patch discoveries. Learned reward rates and social densities played only a minor role in spot-leaving decisions, suggesting that individuals use a fixed-time rule for spot-leaving decisions (45) conditioned on patch discoveries. Additional model simulations showed that patch discoveries and time without fish catches indeed reproduced giving-up times similar to those produced by the full model containing all predictors (figs. S18, S19, S20, S21). Crucially, these two success-dependent cues alone (time without catches and patch discoveries) were sufficient to reproduce the empirical pattern that giving-up times at successful spots (time between the last fish catch and the decision to leave the spot) were substantially higher than those at unsuccessful spots (time between starting to fish and leaving the spot ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. S22</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Individual and ecological variation</head><p>What were the sources of variation in foraging strategies? A key challenge when encountering differences in behavioral strategies is determining whether they stem from interindividual differences or from differences between ecologies [e.g., Participants strongly and consistently differed in their use of social information and their avoidance of unsuccessful areas <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">(Fig. 5A, and fig. S8A</ref>), suggesting that social information use and exploratory tendencies constitute stable foraging strategies on the individual level. Variations in the use of ecological information and the attraction to successful areas, however, were primarily driven by between-lake differences. Women used more social information and were less likely to avoid unsuccessful areas compared to men <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">(Fig. 5C</ref>). Previous studies have found mixed evidence for the relationship between gender and social information use (49, 50), suggesting that this relationship is context-dependent. For example, in Hadza society, where foraging labour is divided by gender, women tend to stay closer to others and forage together (51). In ice-fishing, gendered social information use might be tied to cultural norms and expectations linked to, e.g., risk-taking.</p><p>Older participants were less likely than younger participants to avoid unsuccessful areas ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Fig. 5C</ref>), confirming previous experimental findings that exploratory tendencies decrease with age in favour of exploitation (52). Self-rated angling skill did not affect search strategies <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">(Fig. 5C</ref>). This contrasts social learning theores (35, 46), that would predict an decrease in social information use as a function of skill and may be due to our highly experienced participant sample.</p><p>Participants used more social information and were less strongly attracted to successful areas on lakes with high resource abundance <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">(Fig. 5E</ref>). This suggests that participants became more likely to engage in area-restricted search in response to a reduced likelihood to discover novel resource patches.</p><p>Participants strongly differed in their tendency to leave a spot as a function of time without fish catches, whereas the effect of patch discoveries was more influenced by between-lake variation ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Fig. 5B, and fig. S8B</ref>). Spot-leaving strategies did not vary with gender, age, or self-rated angling skill ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Fig. 5D</ref>), but individuals were more likely to leave a spot at lakes with high resource abundance ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Fig. 5F</ref>). Additional analyses confirmed that average giving-up times for successful and unsuccessful angling spots were higher on lakes with high resource abundance ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">fig. S10</ref>). As we found little evidence for learning mechanisms during foraging trips ( suggesting that foraging success is a stochastic outcome in these time-limited competitions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Although the unique complexity of human foraging is thought to be a main driver of the evolution of cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11)</ref>, there is no clear picture of the decision-making processes at work during foraging in the wild, in particular in social contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14,</ref><ref type="bibr">53)</ref>. Here, we demonstrated that the social context is crucial for understanding foraging decisions under natural conditions. To do so, we relied on icefishing competitions as a novel study system that facilitates large-scale experimentation in the field. This approach in combination with computational modeling techniques allowed us to investigate how personal, ecological and social information act together to shape dynamic decision-making in situ <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(18)</ref>. We provide evidence that humans trade off social and personal information, with social information being more important for patch choice, and personal information being more important for patch-leaving decisions. Using agent-based model simulations, we find that simple decision-making rules can generate complex search patterns, resembling real human behaviour. These results complement and extend existing research on foraging in particular and human decision-making in general. Our work will inform future theorizing and empirical testing of social foraging. More broadly, it provides a template for studying social decision-making outside the laboratory, and helps us predict how humans collectively adapt to changing climate conditions and resource availability.   <ref type="table">Table S2</ref> shows posterior estimates of main model parameters. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table S3</ref> shows posterior estimates for the feature validity analysis.   <ref type="table">Table S8</ref> shows posterior estimates of main model parameters.  Data and materials availability: All datasets and software code necessary to reproduce the results reported in this article can be accessed at https://github.com/aschakowski/Social-Foraging.</p><p>Raw GPS and video data can be obtained from the authors upon request after publication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary materials</head><p>Materials and Methods</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Text</head><p>Figs. S1 to S28</p><p>Tables S1 to S17</p><p>Movies S1-S3 Tables S1 to S17</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Materials for</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Socioecology drives adaptive social foraging dynamics in the wild</head><p>Captions for Movies S1 to S3</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Other Supplementary Materials for this manuscript:</head><p>Movies S1 to S3</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data collection</head><p>Data were collected over two consecutive weeks in February-March in 2022, and two consecutive weeks in March-April in 2023. Multiple-day tournaments are common in Finnish ice-fishing competitions and most participants competed on multiple days ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. S23</ref>). Invitations to participate in ice-fishing competitions were sent to two social media groups, each with more than 100 members of the competitive ice-fishing community, stating that the invitation could be shared with other competitive ice-fishers. Selected well-known ice-fishers who were not in these groups were contacted directly. We organized a total of 20 competitions. Of these, 10 were for individuals and 10 were for teams (i.e., groups of three). In both years, we organized five competitions of each incentive condition. This study reports data from the individual incentive condition only (i.e. At the end of a competition, participants had 30 minutes to return to the starting location. Each participant's total catch of Eurasian perch was weighed (to the nearest gram) and participants were ranked based on the weight of their catch. First prize was = C500, second prize was = C300, third prize was = C200 and 4th-18th prize was = C100.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GPS accuracy</head><p>To estimate the accuracy of GPS recordings during relocation, one study author (A.S.) wore four GPS watches on the same arm while walking in one of the competition areas prior to the first competition for 2 hours. GPS error was calculated as the pairwise spatial distance between GPS fixes obtained from each watch. To estimate GPS accuracy while being stationary, we computed the distance of recorded GPS locations from the average location during those times individuals were known to be angling based on the video recordings. During relocation, GPS errors ranged from 0m to 12.56m with 95% of all fixes having an error below 4.17m, and 50% of all fixes an error below 1.54m ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. S25A, B</ref>). While stationary, GPS errors ranged from 0m to 30.38m with 95% of all fixes having an error below 1.76m, and 50% an error below 0.47m ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. S25C, D)</ref>. When averaging GPS positions at angling spots (as we did for data analysis), we find that errors range from 0m to 17.10m with errors being below 1.40m in 95% of cases and errors being below 0.59m in 50% of cases when averaging GPS positions at angling spots ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. S25E, F)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Video coding</head><p>Video data was manually annotated by the first author (A.S.) extracting the time individuals started angling at a novel patch, caught a fish, and left a patch, using the software Boris (55). The start of angling was defined as the moment at which the lure first entered the water. Fish catches were defined as the moment at which the fish came out of the water. Spot-leaving time was defined as the moment at which the lure was taken out of the water for the last time at that spot. In 1. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bathymetric data</head><p>Depth curves for each lake were obtained from the Finnish Land Survey (https://asiointi. maanmittauslaitos.fi/karttapaikka/tiedostopalvelu/maastotietokanta?lang=en), the Finnish Environment Institute (https://www.syke.fi/fi-FI/Avoin_tieto/Paikkatietoaineistot), and the Finnish Transport and Communications Agency (https://julkinen.traficom.fi/oskari/?lang= en; all last accessed February 4th, 2025). Depth curves were provided to participants before the start of the competitions (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">fig. S24</ref> for examples). Depth curves were analysed at the same spatial resolution as the depth curves that were made available to participants. Participants were allowed to use GPS devices during the competitions to locate themselves on the bathymetric map, and were regularly observed using these maps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>S4</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Missing data</head><p>We excluded foraging locations from our analysis based on five criteria ensuring data quality.</p><p>First, we excluded locations where the video recording was obstructed during the start or end of angling for more than 20s such that the onset (or end) of angling could not be determined with 10s accuracy. Second, we excluded foraging locations when the video recording was obstructed for more than 10% of the total angling time for that location. Third, we excluded foraging locations where the standard deviation of GPS fixes exceeded 5m or where GPS fixes were missing for more than 10% of the angling time. Fourth, we excluded foraging locations, where the amount of missing GPS fixes during angling exceed 10% of the total angling time. Fifth, we excluded foraging locations where the lure was not visible after reeling in because in these cases it could not be determined whether a fish was caught or not. In addition, because the models reported in the main text rely on temporally-updated predictors, all subsequent spots after the first spot meeting any of the aforementioned criteria were excluded. Additionally, foraging trips where only one location remained were excluded from analysis, because model fitting required at least two locations for each foraging trip. Applying these criteria, lead to the exclusion of N = 2,831 (15.0%) locations from main analyses. Table S11 presents a detailed overview of excluded data and missing values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spot-selection model</head><p>To model angling spot choices, we applied a hierarchical Bayesian multinomial regression model. The model dynamically predicts the choice of each foraging location (except the starting location), 1 , ..., , ... , inspired by methods from movement ecology (26, 56). We modeled the probability that location ∈ Ω is chosen over alternative locations * ∈ Ω available to the decision-maker at </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(x s , x i ) = exp − ||x s , x i || 2 2 2</formula><p>, where ||x s , x i || refers to the Euclidian distance between x s and x i , and the bandwidth governs the degree to which feature indicators generalize to nearby locations.</p><p>We assumed that personal information consists of information on previous successful angling spot visits (at least one fish catch) and previous unsuccessful spot visits (no fish catch). That is, Personal , Social , we estimated a separate bandwidth parameter Personal , Social . To account for the fact, that participants could not choose locations that were already occupied by another individual, we added an offset to the social feature, such that the social feature was assumed to be 0 within a 5m radius around another individual. This was achieved by multiplying the radial basis kernel function with a noise term:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Personal = { Successful , Unsuccessful }.</formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">* (x s , x i ) = (x s , x i ) × (1 + exp (−20||x s , x i || − 5)) .</formula><p>For simplicity, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figs. 2 and fig. S4</ref> show , not * .</p><p>The feature dimensions differ in the degree to which they vary in time. Keeping the location at which the feature is evaluated constant, the successful and unsuccessful features change with every new spot being visited, whereas the social feature changes continuously through time.</p><p>For computational efficiency, we selected the * = 15 feature indicators that were closest to from the available feature indicators in order to compute feature values. We found that for * = 15 feature values correlate highly with feature values obtained using . We used unstandardized kernel density estimates, such that for time-varying feature values, each feature indicator had the same effect on the feature value. This ensured that feature weights for earlier choices could be compared to feature weights for later choices. Given equal spatial distance, this assumes a linear effect of the number of feature indicators on attraction to a location.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>S7</head><p>Finally, the roughness feature Roughness was computed as the distance to the closest depth curve in m. Negative values on the respective feature weight thus indicate that individuals are attracted to areas close to depth curves.</p><p>To account for the nested data structure, feature weights were estimated with random offsets for each individual, lake, and foraging trip. Offsets were estimated using a partial pooling method accounting for potential intercorrelations. Bandwidth parameters were estimated with hierarchical offsets for each lake.</p><p>We chose weakly informative priors <ref type="formula">61</ref> In the main text ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 2E, G, H)</ref>, we report main effects and lake-level effects for main feature weights as well as kernel parameters for each lake. <ref type="table">Table S2</ref> shows model parameter estimates, individual and trip level offsets, and convergence diagnostics.</p><p>To evaluate the importance of the different model parameters for predicting spot-leaving decisions, we relied on systematic model comparisons. We evaluated widely applicable information criterion computed based on expected log posterior predictive densities (ELPD) as implemented in the R package loo (68). We followed <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(69)</ref> in interpreting models as performing on par if</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Δ ELPD &lt; 4 × Δ ELPD .</formula><p>The same methods were used for systematic comparisons of the spot-leaving decision model and the resource depletion models described below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Prior Specification Spot-Selection Model</head><p>For the spot-selection model, the following prior specifications were implemented. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>S9</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feature validity</head><p>To estimate how the four features used by the participants related to foraging success, we simulated spatial features for each chosen angling location using the mean posterior estimates of the respective bandwidth parameters. Spatial features were then used to predict patch discoveries using a binary logistic regression model with random slopes and intercepts for each lake using the R package brms (70), using the default flat priors. In the main text, we report the main effects and lake-level estimates <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">(Fig. 2f)</ref>; <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table S3</ref> shows the full parameter estimates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Agent-based model simulations</head><p>We employed agent-based model simulations, using posterior estimates of the spot-selection model, to test whether our model predictions could recover the observed spatial search dynamics. We computed the posterior mean feature weights for each foraging trip, accounting for individual and lake-level variation and the mean posterior bandwidth estimates for each lake. For each sequence of observed angling spots, we simulated = 50 synthetic sequences, keeping the time at which spatial features were computed equivalent and the sequence of successessful and unsuccessful spot visits constant. We also kept the first spot equivalent between data and simulations. To obtain model predictions, we simulated alternative locations following the empirical distribution of relocation distances and turning angles, selecting locations based on the softmax choice rule. Based on this choice, spatial features were recomputed and the softmax rule was applied again to select the next location. This was repeated until the synthetic sequence contained as many choices as the empirical sequence. For simplicity, the social feature was computed from the empirical distribution of participants at each time step, and not from simulated locations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Patch depletion</head><p>Following (44), we fitted a series of resource acquisition functions capturing different patterns of depleting or non-depleting fish catches over time. First, we fitted a linear model assuming nondepleting rewards with time where the cumulative number of fish caught at time t, , is given</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">by S10 = * ,</formula><p>where is a free parameter governing the resource density. Second, we fitted a sigmoidal curve (Holling model), where rewards deplete after an initial phase of non-depletion:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">= 1 * 2 2 + 2 .</formula><p>1 , and 2 are free parameters governing the shape of the acquisition function. Third, we fit an asymptotic exponential function,</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">= 1 * (1 − exp(− 2 * )).</formula><p>1 and 2 are free parameters governing the asymptotic value and the rate with which the asymptotic value is reached. Following the formulation of (42), 1 is an estimate for the patch size and 2 estimates the rate with which extracted resources trend towards 1 .</p><p>Fourth, we fit an asymptotic Michaelis-Menten function,</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">= 1 * 2 + .</formula><p>This function makes similar predictions to the asymptotic exponential function with resources depleting more slowly, but reaching the asymptotic value earlier. For computational efficiency, parameters were estimated for each angling spot with a no-pooling method <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(64)</ref>. Results can be found in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">fig. S17</ref> and table S12.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spot-leaving model</head><p>To gain insights into the mechanisms underlying intertemporal decision-making, we extended on a logistic regression framework testing the influence of different time-varying cues on the tendency to leave an angling spot (24, 25). We predicted the probability that an individual leaves the current location = 1 at time as a weighted additive function of four sets of cues: number of time units without fish catches, * ; patch discoveries (i.e., whether or not at least one fish has been caught at a spot already), &gt;0 (1 if fish has been caught, 0 if not); global and local waiting times that are learned across (global) and within spots (local), and , respectively; and spatial features guiding S11 spatial search, Social , Roughness , Successful , Unsuccessful . Since these cues are on different scales, we relied on systematic model comparisons to gauge the importance of each set of predictors. To do so, we first fit a baseline model assuming a constant spot-leaving probability, 0 . We then fit a model including only * in addition to the intercept term 0 , a model including * and &gt;0 and the intercept term, a model including * , &gt;0 , and , and the intercept term, and finally a full model including * , &gt;0 , , , Social , Roughness , Successful and Unsuccessful . The full model is thus given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">( = 1) = logit −1 ( ),</formula><p>where ( = 1) is the probability that an individual leaves an angling spot at time , =</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">( 0 , * , &gt;0 , , , Social , Roughness , Successful , Unsuccessful ) T ,</formula><p>and is a vector of cue weights indicating the strength and direction of each predictor (with the first entry set to 1).</p><p>We assumed that both and are updated across time according to novel information. That is, within spots, we assumed that local reward rates are updated with each fish catch according to a delta learning rule. Delta Learning is commonly applied as a model of human learning, in particular in foraging tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(71,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">72)</ref>. In our case, we assume that For the spot-leaving decision-making model, we estimated all model parameters hierarchically, with population-level fixed effects and random offsets accounting for individual-level, lake-level, and trip-level variation in behaviour. We chose weakly informative priors (61) for feature weights and informative priors for bandwidth parameters (see Supplementary Material for a detailed description of model specification and prior choices). In the main text, we report main and lake-level effects for main cue weights <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Fig. 4A, C, D)</ref>. <ref type="table">Table S8</ref> shows model parameter estimates, individual-and trip-level offsets, and convergence diagnostics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>S13</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Prior Specification Patch-Leaving Model</head><p>For the spot-leaving model, the following prior specifications were implemented. We assumed that Variances were assumed to follow ∼ exponential(1) S14</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">main</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Giving-up time simulations</head><p>To compare predictions of the spot-leaving model to empirical data, we simulated synthetic leaving times for each angling spot. We computed leaving probabilities for each time bin based on the mean posterior estimate from the different spot-leaving model versions, accounting for individual-, lake-, and trip-level variation. For each time bin, we then sampled from the posterior leaving probability and recorded giving-up times as the first time bin with a sampled leaving event. Leaving probabilities were informed by empirical fish catches. We assumed, if no leaving events were sampled at the empirical giving-up time, that no fish catches would occur afterwards. Spatial features were held constant in these cases. For each foraging trip, we simulated N = 50 synthetic foraging trips. The obtained giving-up times were compared to empirical giving-up times to gauge model performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Quantifying interindividual and ecological variation</head><p>Given the hierarchical data structure, with many individuals being observed repeatedly across .</p><p>To further illustrate the relative contribution of interindividual and ecological variation to variation in foraging strategies, we computed correlations between individual-level parameter estimates across all lakes. We obtained individual-level estimates for each lake by computing the full effect for each foraging trip (i.e., trip-level residual + individual-level random effect + lake-level random effect) for each posterior draw, and the respective measure by computing the average full effect across S15 the remaining lakes on which the individual took part. We then computed a Pearson correlation coefficient to obtain a posterior distribution of correlation coefficients for each lake.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predicting interindividual variation</head><p>We predicted interindividual variation in parameter estimates based on three characteristics: age, gender, and self-rated angling skill. Self-rated angling skill was assessed using six questions on </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Predicting ecological variation</head><p>To quantify ecological variation, we computed, for each lake, the percentage of successful angling spots over all spot visits and the average amount of fish caught (in kg) as different, but correlated, measures of overall resource abundance. To investigate how this ecological variation influenced foraging strategies, we correlated these measures with the estimated lake-level offsets (N = 10) from the spot-selection and spot-leaving models. To obtain a posterior distribution for each regression coefficient, we computed the maximum likelihood solution for the regression equation predicting each posterior draw from the lake-level predictors as outlined above. As there were only 10 lakes, we conducted separate regression analyses for each predictor.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Text Participants and Study System</head><p>A total of 74 unique participants took part in our study. Of those, 31 participated in all ten competitions analyzed here and 55 participants took part in at least five competitions. See table S1</p><p>for   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">S12</ref> shows that among the most important motives for participation are to be with other individuals who share similar interests and enjoy similar things, but also to develop skills related to ice-fishing competitions and to test one's abilities in a competitive context. Individuals indicate that social recognition, the desire that others think highly of oneself and to show one's skills are less S17 important to participants. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig. S13</ref> further shows that fitness and nature experience are among the most important motivations to participate, in particular, the desire to keep physically fit, be close to nature, get fresh air and exercise. Interestingly, catching as much fish as possible or catching fish for consumption was less important to participants, while experiencing challenges and competition were rated as moderately to very important. None of the dimensions were, however, rated as less than moderately important on average suggesting that all dimensions play an important role for participants. Turning to the reasons why participants are involved with this particular leisure activity ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">fig. S14</ref>), we find that, again, social components are among the most important drivers. That is, icefishing competitions provide important opportunities to meet friends, identify with people sharing similar values and discuss competitions with like-minded individuals. Finally, participants see icefishing competitions as a means of identity affirmation, but less as a means of identity expression.</p><p>Interestingly, males and females are highly similar in their responses across almost all dimensions.                                   Note. * Results after exclusion of missing data.      </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>cognitive-computational modeling and agent-based simulations, we show how foragers adaptively integrate socioecological information streams for resource location and patch leaving. Contrasting earlier work, the social context emerges as a key driver of foraging decisions. Foragers use others for locating resources, especially when being unsuccessful, increase giving-up-times and engage in arearestricted search when foraging at high social densities. Our work uncovers the importance of sociality in human foraging decisions, and provides a template for harnessing high-resolution tracking data to study human cognition in the real world.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>38km 2 [1.08km 2 , 3.56km 2 ]; Fig. 1; for locations, see fig. S11). Following the typical setup of many regional ice-fishing competitions, competitions lasted 3 hours and participants were reimbursed individually based on the total weight of Eurasian perch (Perca fluviatilis) they caught. In each competition, 45 to 56 highly experienced (mean years of experience [SD] = 43.5 [14.3]) ice-fishers participated, resulting in 477 foraging trips by 74 unique individuals (mean age [SD] = 60.4 years [13.9 years], 23.1% female;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>standardized [95%CI] = 0.84 [0.36, 1.30], N = 10; fig. S2C). Below, we examine how this environmental heterogeneity-in combination with interindividual differences-shaped foraging strategies.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(48)]. Tracking the same foragers across different environments enabled us to disentangle these two sources of variation [see (33)] and explain variation in foraging strategies as a function of individual characteristics (i.e., age, gender, angling skill) and lake characteristics (i.e., resource abundance, operationalized as the average catch weight and the percentage of successful angling spots).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 4C) this suggests that prior ecological expectations play a major role in shaping individuals' giving-up times.In terms of adaptive consequences, we found no relationships between individuals' spatial search strategies and their foraging success (fig. S9A), and only small effects of patch-leaving strategies on foraging success, with successful individuals being slightly less sensitive to time without catches (fig. S9B). More generally, we found a relatively low repeatability of foraging success (fig. S9C),</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Ice-fishing as a model for social foraging. (A) Snapshot of a scene during a competition. Participants could freely relocate within the competition area, drill holes, and angle. (B) Aerial snapshot showing distribution of foragers; one group of foragers is densely packed together (topright corner). (C) Close-up of a participant fishing. All participants were equipped with headcams (here in white) that provided continuous data on behavioural states and fish catches and GPS smartwatches that logged their position at 1Hz. (D) Movement trajectories of participants (exemplified by 5 colored participant icons, left half) during three out of 10 of the competitions (right half, in blue, green, and teal) and trajectory of a single individual highlighted (in black). Ecological information was quantified based on the depth profiles (thin grey lines). Foragers participated multiple times across different ecologies (gray lines and arrows), making it possible to separate variation in foraging strategies into individual and lake variation (displayed is simulated data) using hierarchical Bayesian methods (E). (F) A processed movement trajectory: Video recordings were used to discretize participants' movement trajectories into angling and relocation events (small image insets) and to quantify each fish catch at each location (light blue circles indicate at least one fish catch, dark green circles none). (G) An angling spot visit, starting at t = 0, when an individual starts angling (S), containing six fish catches (fish icons) and ending with the individual leaving (L).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Spot-selection model. (A-D) Six angling spots, chronologically visited by one participant from bottom right to top left (green dots, black asterixes, and black squares). To predict the next spot choice (red cross), 50 counterfactual spots were simulated (grey dots) and compared to the chosen spot along four feature dimensions. (A, B) Personal information: (A) distance to last successful spots (asterisks) and (B) distance to the last unsuccessful spots (squares). (C) Social information: distance to competitors (triangles). (D) Ecological information: distance to bathymetric features (grey lines). (E) Standardized effects of the four feature weights on spatial spot choices. (F) Feature validity, showing the likelihood that an angling spot was successful given an increase in spatial features by one standard deviation. (G) Interaction effect between personal and social features on spatial spot choices. (H) Bandwidth parameters governing the degree to which personal and social features are generalized across space. For (E-H), vertical solid lines show posterior means of conditional effects; light green (dark green) shaded areas show 95% (66%) credible posterior intervals. Grey dots and intervals show point estimates and 95% posterior credible intervals, respectively, of hierarchical offsets for each of the 10 lakes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Spatiotemporal search dynamics. (A, B) Area-restricted search following successful spot visits. (A) Median relocation distances and (B) median turning angles for individuals that were successful at the n-to last spot. 0 indicates that participants were successful at the last visited spot. Grey lines show the data; error bars indicate ± 2×the standard error of the median. Shaded circles are proportional to the sample size for each data bin; numbers indicate sample sizes. Solid lines indicate the median and shaded areas indicate the 95% interval across all simulation runs for the full model (green) and a random walk model (blue). (C, D) Effect of social density on area-restricted search following successful spot visits. Panels show the same information as (A, B) but split by high and low social density, based on a median split of empirical social densities. Solid lines and shaded areas show simulated trajectories from the spot-selection model; 95% of all simulation results fall within the shaded areas.Tables S4, S5, and Tables S6, S7show posterior estimates of regression analyses based on empirical data for non-social and social area-restricted search.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Spot-leaving dynamics. (A) Posterior estimates for the effect of time without fish catches and patch discoveries on the probability to leave an angling spot. (B) Joint effect of time without catches and patch discoveries on probability to leave an angling spot. The bright green line shows the mean posterior estimate of the baseline probability to leave a spot as a function of whether a patch has been discovered (time after the first fish icon) or not (time before the first fish icon). (C) Conditional effects of the average time intervals between fish catches experienced at an angling spot (i.e., local waiting time) and across previous angling spots (i.e., global waiting time) on the probability to leave a spot. (D) Conditional effects of the spatial features on the probability to leave an angling spot. Spatial features were obtained using the mean posterior bandwidth estimates estimated in the spot-selection model. For (A-D), black solid lines show posterior means; light green (dark green) shaded areas show 95% (66%) credible posterior intervals. For (A, B, D), black dots and intervals show point estimates and 95% credible intervals, respectively, of hierarchical offsets for each of the 10 lakes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Interindividual and ecological variation of foraging strategies. (A), (B) Variance components contributing to variation in trip-level parameter estimates for (A) the spot-selection model and (B) the spot-leaving model. For each parameter, variance components sum to 1 − residual (trip-level) variance. (C, D) Posterior estimates predicting individual-level variation in main parameter estimates of the (C) spot-selection model and (D) spot-leaving model from individual level predictors. All individual-level data was available for N = 71 unique participants. (E, F) Posterior estimates predicting lake-level variation in main parameter estimates of the (E) spotselection model and (F) spot-leaving model from lake level predictors. Competitions were held on 19. C. C. Wilmers, et al., The golden age of bio-logging: how animal-borne sensors are advancing the frontiers of ecology. Ecology 96, 1741-1753 (2015), 10.1890/14-1401.1. 20. P. He, et al., A guide to sampling design for GPS-based studies of animal societies. Methods in Ecology and Evolution 00, 1-19 (2022), 10.1111/2041-210X.13999. 21. J. Suni, R. Komppula, R. Kortet, Experiential value of participation in angling competitiona study from Finland. European Journal of Tourism Research 32, 3213 (2022), 10.54055/ ejtr.v32i.2519. 22. B. A. Tolonen, J. Lappalainen, Origin of the large burbot (Lota lota (L.)) caught in an Arctic ice-fishing competition: a case study. Journal of Applied Ichthyology 15 (3), 122-126 (1999), 10.1046/j.1439-0426.1999.00133.x. 23. K. Garg, W. Deng, D. Mobbs, Beyond the individual: A social foraging framework to study decisions in groups (2024), 10.31219/osf.io/rmqyb. 24. A. Wilke, J. M. C. Hutchinson, P. M. Todd, U. Czienskowski, Fishing for the Right Words: Decision Rules for Human Foraging Behavior in Internal Search Tasks. Cognitive Science 33 (3), 497-529 (2009), 10.1111/j.1551-6709.2009.01020.x. 25. S. Hall-McMaster, P. Dayan, N. W. Schuck, Control over patch encounters changes foraging behavior. iScience 24 (9), 103005 (2021), 10.1016/j.isci.2021.103005. 26. A. Strandburg-Peshkin, D. R. Farine, M. C. Crofoot, I. D. Couzin, Habitat and social factors shape individual decisions and emergent group structure during baboon collective movement. eLife 6, r19505 (2017), 10.7554/eLife.19505. 27. T. Avgar, J. R. Potts, M. A. Lewis, M. S. Boyce, Integrated step selection analysis: Bridging the gap between resource selection and animal movement. Methods in Ecology and Evolution 7, 619-630 (2016), 10.1111/2041-210X.12528. 28. J. R. Potts, L. Börger, B. K. Strickland, G. M. Street, Assessing the predictive power of step selection functions: How social and environmental interactions affect animal space use. Methods in Ecology and Evolution 13 (8), 1805-1818 (2022), 10.1111/2041-210X.13904. 29. J. Fieberg, J. Signer, B. Smith, T. Avgar, A 'How to' guide for interpreting parameters in habitat-selection analyses. Journal of Animal Ecology 90 (5), 1027-1043 (2021), 10.1111/ 1365-2656.13441. 30. C. M. Wu, E. Schulz, M. Speekenbrink, J. D. Nelson, B. Meder, Generalization guides human exploration in vast decision spaces. Nature Human Behaviour 2 (12), 915-924 (2018), 10. 1038/s41562-018-0467-4. 31. C. M. Wu, et al., Visual-spatial dynamics drive adaptive social learning in immersive environments (2023), 10.1101/2023.06.28.546887. 32. C. M. Wu, B. Meder, E. Schulz, Unifying principles of generalization: past, present, and future (2024), 10.31234/osf.io/6uz9q. 33. Materials and methods are available as supplementary material. 34. E. Brunswik, Representative design and probabilistic theory in a functional psychology. Psychological Review 62 (3), 193-217 (1955), 10.1037/h0047470. 35. R. L. Kendal, et al., Social Learning Strategies: Bridge-Building between Fields. Trends in Cognitive Sciences 22 (7), 651-665 (2018), 10.1016/j.tics.2018.04.003. 36. M. Enquist, K. Eriksson, S. Ghirlanda, Critical social learning: A solution to Rogers's paradox of nonadaptive culture. American Anthropologist 109 (4), 727-734 (2007), 10.1525/aa. 2007.109.4.727. 37. W. Toyokawa, A. Whalen, K. N. Laland, Social learning strategies regulate the wisdom and madness of interactive crowds. Nature Human Behaviour 3 (2), 183-193 (2019), 10.1038/ s41562-018-0518-x.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>38. A. Witt, W. Toyokawa, K. N. Lala, W. Gaissmaier, C. M. Wu, Humans flexibly integrate social information despite interindividual differences in reward. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 121 (39), e2404928121 (2024), doi:10.1073/pnas.2404928121, https: //pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2404928121. 39. U. Toelch, M. J. Bruce, L. Newson, P. J. Richerson, S. M. Reader, Individual consistency and flexibility in human social information use. Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences 281 (1776), 20132864 (2014), 10.1098/rspb.2013.2864. 40. A. Dorfman, T. T. Hills, I. Scharf, A guide to area-restricted search: a foundational foraging behaviour. Biological Reviews 97 (6), 2076-2089 (2022), 10.1111/brv.12883. 41. C. Ross, L. Pacheco-Cobos, B. Winterhalder, A general model of forager search: Adaptive encounter-conditional heuristics outperform Lévy flights in the search for patchily distributed prey. Journal of Theoretical Biology 455, 357-369 (2018), 10.1016/j.jtbi.2018.07.031. 42. E. L. Charnov, G. A. Parker, Dimensionless invariants from foraging theory's marginal value theorem. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 92 (5), 1446-1450 (1995), 10. 1073/pnas.92.5.1446. 43. E. L. Charnov, Optimal foraging, the marginal value theorem. Theoretical Population Biology 9 (2), 129-136 (1976), 10.1016/0040-5809(76)90040-X. 44. V. V. Venkataraman, T. S. Kraft, N. J. Dominy, K. M. Endicott, Hunter-gatherer residential mobility and the marginal value of rainforest patches. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 114 (12), 3097-3102 (2017), 10.1073/pnas.1617542114. 45. H. H. Marshall, A. J. Carter, A. Ashford, J. M. Rowcliffe, G. Cowlishaw, How do foragers decide when to leave a patch? A test of alternative models under natural and experimental conditions. Journal of Animal Ecology 82 (4), 894-902 (2013), 10.1111/1365-2656.12089. 46. K. N. Laland, Social learning strategies. Learning &amp; Behavior 32 (1), 4-14 (2004), 10.3758/ BF03196002. 47. J. M. Hutchinson, A. Wilke, P. M. Todd, Patch leaving in humans: can a generalist adapt its rules to dispersal of items across patches? Animal Behaviour 75 (4), 1331-1349 (2008), 10.1016/j.anbehav.2007.09.006. 48. D. Nettle, M. A. Gibson, D. W. Lawson, R. Sear, Human behavioral ecology: current research and future prospects. Behavioral Ecology 24 (5), 1031-1040 (2013), 10.1093/beheco/ ars222. 49. L. Molleman, R. H. Kurvers, W. Van Den Bos, Unleashing the BEAST: a brief measure of human social information use. Evolution and Human Behavior 40 (5), 492-499, 10.1016/j. evolhumbehav.2019.06.005. 50. C. O. Brand, G. R. Brown, C. P. Cross, Sex differences in the use of social information emerge under conditions of risk. PeerJ 6, e4190, 10.7717/peerj.4190. 51. B. M. Wood, et al., Gendered movement ecology and landscape use in Hadza hunter-gatherers. Nature Human Behaviour 5 (4), 436-446 (2021), 10.1038/s41562-020-01002-7. 52. R. N. Spreng, G. R. Turner, From exploration to exploitation: a shifting mental mode in late life development. Trends in Cognitive Sciences 25 (12), 1058-1071 (2021), 10.1016/j.tics. 2021.09.001. 53. T. W. Fawcett, S. Hamblin, L.-A. Giraldeau, Exposing the behavioral gambit: the evolution of learning and decision rules. Behavioral Ecology 24 (1), 2-11 (2013), 10.1093/beheco/ ars085. 54. A. O. Holcombe, M. Kovacs, F. Aust, B. Aczel, Documenting contributions to scholarly articles using CRediT and tenzing. PLOS ONE 15 (12), e0244611 (2020), 10.1371/journal.pone. 0244611. 55. O. Friard, M. Gamba, BORIS: A free, versatile open-source event-logging software for video/autio coding and live observations. Methods in Ecology and Evolution 7 (11), 1325-1330 (2016), 10.1111/2041-210X.12584. 56. T. Michelot, N. J. Klappstein, J. R. Potts, J. Fieberg, Understanding step selection analysis through numerical integration. Methods in Ecology and Evolution 15 (1), 24-35 (2024), 10. 1111/2041-210X.14248. 57. T. Duchesne, D. Fortin, L.-P. Rivest, Equivalence between Step Selection Functions and Biased Correlated Random Walks for Statistical Inference on Animal Movement. PLOS ONE 10 (4), e0122947 (2015), 10.1371/journal.pone.0122947.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, 5 competitions in 2022 and 5 competitions in 2023 on a total of ten different lakes). Approximately a third of participants were from the local area of Northern Karelia. To minimize prior experience with lakes, we selected relatively unknown areas for our competitions. The exact location of the competitions was announced two weeks prior to the start of the first competition, at which point the lakes were closed to participants and maps with detailed depth curves were provided (fig. S24). On each competition day, participants were asked whether they had previously fished on the respective lake. In 2022, on average 44.4% of participants reported they had angled in one of the areas before; in 2023, 78.3% of participants reported they had angled in one of the areas before. See table S1 for details of demographic variables. On their first day, participants provided written informed consent and answered a survey containing demographic questions, a personality questionnaire, and questions regarding their motivation to participate in ice-fishing competitions. At the beginning of each competition, the study authors and trained field assistants equipped participants with headcams (Drift Ghost XL) and GPS watches (Garmin Forerunner 245). To ensure synchronicity, cameras were used to film the GPS time on the watches to later assign standardized timestamps. Competitions ran from 11 a.m. to 2 p.m. local time. Participants entered the competition area at 10:45 a.m., giving them 15 minutes to select an initial angling location. Participants could only use manual drills and the lures and fishing techniques included in the official competition rules of the Finnish Federation for Recreational Fishing. Hook S2 size was not regulated. Anglers typically select hooks (commonly between 14mm and 18mm for perch) depending on the size of the targeted fish. Chumming was not allowed.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>0% of cases (N = 182 of 18,886 sequences), individuals drilled new holes or relocated while leaving the lure in the old hole and returned to the old spot afterwards. In these cases, relocation time was counted as angling time since, in principle, fish could have been caught at the old location despite participants S3 being elsewhere. Videos were annotated by fast forwarding recordings up to 5 times the original speed, pausing, and using frame-by-frame mode to identify the exact timing of events. Coding one 3-hour video took approximately 1 hour. On average, participants spent 62.5% (SD across foraging trips = 13.0%) of their time angling; the bulk of their remaining time was spent relocating or drilling (fig. S26). A random subset of two to three videos per day (N = 26 of 510; 5.1%) were additionally annotated by a trained research assistant to estimate interrater agreement. We assessed the differences between raters in the number of annotated angling spots per video, the number of fish caught at each angling spot, the angling time at each angling spot, and the time of fish catches to estimate interrater agreement. fig. S27 shows the results of this analysis. In 24 videos, both raters agreed on the number of angling spots; in two videos, they disagreed by one spot (fig. S27A). One case was due to a technical error, resulting in the first minutes of the recording not being labeled by the second rater. The other case was due to disagreement over whether a participant had returned to the same angling spot after drilling a new hole during angling. Both raters also strongly agreed on the total number of fish caught at angling spots (fig. S27B) and the time spent fishing on these locations (fig. S27C). After removing three catches (out of 1,260; 0.2%) with a temporal deviation of more than 20s (working under the assumption that these were different fish catches), the mean difference in the timing of fish catches was 0.83s (median = 1s, range = [0s, 8s]); 95% of cases were below 3s (fig. S27D).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>time according to the softmax choice rule ( ) = exp( ) sampling locations with a distance and turning angle from the last known location −1 . To model realistic constraints on behaviour, and are sampled from the empirical distribution of distances and turning angles obtained from the whole dataset (see fig. S28 for the distributions of relocation distances and turning angles used to simulate synthetic angling spots). For the simulation, both variables were sampled independently. To control for systematic differences in relocation distances between individuals and lakes, we added Locality to the model equation, where = 1000 for each location. To model potential effects of available time in the competition on movement behaviour that are independent of personal, social, or ecological information use, we added Locality × to the model equation, where measures the available time in the competition when leaving the last known location −1 . Here, was normalized between 0 and 1 by dividing the time already spent in the competition by the competition duration of 3 hours. Conceptually, this model is related to a biased random walk, where relocation distances are not drawn from a normal distribution, but from an empirical distribution (57, 58). Similar models are routinely applied in the field of animal ecology, where they are known as resource, step, or habitat selection models (26, 56). Note that such models are typically applied to situations in which is measured in temporal units, whereas in our case is measured in ordinal units representing the number of spot choices. For each feature dimension, we computed feature values for both chosen locations , and all available locations * ∈ Ω , with the respective Euclidian coordinates x s t and x s * t . Feature values for spatial features representing personal and social information were then obtained by evaluating the kernel density of multiple spatially and temporally distributed feature indicators x i at both x s t and x s * t , where the feature value of at time , , is given by = ∑︁ =1 (x s , x i ), where denotes the number of observable feature indicators (x 1 , ..., x N s t ) at the time when was chosen. Analogically, we obtained the feature values of * ∈ Ω at time t, * , as * = ∑︁ =1 (x s * , x i ). is a kernel function governing the functional form of the spatial decay. In line with results from different decision domains, including spatial decision-making (30, 38, 59, 60), we chose a Gaussian kernel function (radial basis kernel) such that</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Feature indicators for the</head><label></label><figDesc>success feature consisted of the locations of spot visits with one or more fish catches, feature indicators for the loss feature consisted of the locations of spot visits with no catches, and feature indicators for the social feature consisted of the spatial location of other competitors at the time that participants started angling at spot . For each feature dimension,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>for feature weights and informative priors for bandwidth parameters (see Supplementary Material for a detailed description of model specification and prior choices). The model was fitted using Stan as a Hamiltonian Monte Carlo engine for Bayesian inference (62), implemented in R through cmdstanr (63). We used within-chain parallelization with reduce sum to reduce model run times through parallel evaluation of the likelihood. To optimize convergence, we implemented the non-centred version of random effects using a Cholesky decomposition of the correlation matrix (64) with LKJ priors for correlations matrices (65). Model convergence was assessed using the Gelman-Rubin criterion (66)ˆ≤ 1.01. Furthermore, all inferences are based on several hundred effective samples from the posterior (67). The same fitting procedures were applied to the spot-leaving decision model and the resource depletion models.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>∼ N ( 3 , 1 ) 65 )</head><label>3165</label><figDesc>For kernel bandwidth parameters Social and Personal , we assumed S8 For main effects of feature weights, , we assumed that ∼ N (0, 2) For each hierarchical level (trips, lakes, individuals), we assumed that offsets for all feature weights, , follow ∼ MVNormal (0, S) with entries S , = × signifying covariances between offsets at the same level (and variances for diagonal entries). The variance-covariance matrix S is obtained from its diagonal matrix D = diag(S 1/2 ) and the correlation matrix R as S = DRD R with entries R , = , signifying intercorrelations between parameters and was assumed to follow the LKJ-correlation prior (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>= ( 1 −</head><label>1</label><figDesc>) −1 + * if fish has been caught at time and = −1 otherwise. is initialized as at the time of the first fish catch. &gt;0 and contain information on local patch quality, such that &gt;0 captures any change in behaviour that occurs due to individuals making a distinction between successful and unsuccessful spots (i.e., patch discoveries), whereas captures change in behaviour that occurs within successful spots due to a change in catch rate. Across angling spots, we assumed that global rewards are updated at the time of leaving spots according to a delta learning rule such that = (1 − ) −1 + + 1 if the current spot is left at time , with measuring the number of fish catches at the spot until time . The fraction +1 quantifies the average waiting time for each fish catch at the angling spot. S12 If no fish had been caught at the time of leaving a patch (i.e., = 0), we assumed that = (1 − ) −1 + if exceeds the global reward, &gt; −1 , and = −1 otherwise. Doing so captures the asymmetric informational content of waiting times: If time spent waiting for a catch is longer than the current expectation, waiting times provide information that is likely to be too low. As such, captures a lower bound for the time intervals between subsequent fish catches. was initialized as +1 at the time of leaving the first spot if &gt; 0; otherwise, it was initialized as . For both local and global waiting times, learning rates and govern the speed of updating. Values close to 1 indicate that foragers only take into account the most recent information when deciding to leave a patch, whereas values closer to 0 indicate that foragers average these quantities across a larger range of time. For computational efficiency, time was binned in intervals of Δ = 10 , such that the models predicted a participant's likelihood to leave the spot within the next interval of Δ . Spatial features Social , Successful , Unsuccessful were computed based on the mean posterior bandwidth estimates Social , Personal estimated in the spot-selection model. Successful and Unsuccessfulwere fixed for each angling spot. In contrast to the spot-selection model, Social was not fixed for each angling spot, but was instead computed for each time bin. Roughness was calculated as the distance to the closest depth curve in km.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>effects of regression weights on the logit scale follow ∼ N (0, 1) and learning rate on the logit scale follows ∼ N (0, 1) As for the spot-selection model, for each hierarchical level (trips, lakes, individuals), we assumed that offsets for all feature weights, , follow ∼ MVNormal (0, S) with entries S , = × signifying covariances between offsets at the same level (and variances for diagonal entries). The variance-covariance matrix S is obtained from its diagonal matrix D = diag(S 1/2 ) and the correlation matrix R as S = DRD R with entries R , = , signifying intercorrelations between parameters and was assumed to follow the LKJ-correlation prior (65) R ∼ LKJ(4)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head>2 ( ) 2 + ( ) 2 + ( ) 2 and</head><label>222</label><figDesc>different lakes, we were able to express each feature weight or cue weight as a linear function of trip-level offsets, individual-level offsets, and lake-level offsets. For each model parameter-from the spot-selection and the spot-leaving models-we obtained posterior estimates for the variance in parameter estimates across foraging trips ( ) 2 , individuals, ( ) 2 , and lakes, ( ) 2 . ( ) 2 thus represents the residual variance in that is not explained by stable differences in individual-or lake-level variation. The relative contribution of individual-level variance to the total variation in , can thus be expressed as = ( ) the relative contribution of lake-level variance to the total variation in , as</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>self-perceived angling skills (all on a 5-point Likert scale). Participants were asked to compare their fishing abilities with other anglers in ice-fishing perch, ice-fishing other predators (e.g., pike and pike perch), ice-fishing cyprinides, ice-fishing competitions, all hook and line fishing, and all fishing other than hook and line fishing (Cronbach's [95%CI] = .76 [.66, .84]). These items were averaged to obtain a composite score ranging from 1 to 5. We computed posterior distributions for regression coefficients by computing the maximum likelihood solution of the linear regression formula predicting each posterior draw, , from the weighted sum of the three predictors, , using the following equation:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a detailed overview of sample size and participant characteristics for each day and fig. S23 for an overview of study participation. Ice-fishing has a long tradition in the Nordic countries, plays an important part in Finnish culture and traditions and has provided an important local source of subsistence until the Modern Era. Ice-fishing competitions are held on a national level in Finland since the second world war officially; though it is likely that competitions were arranged locally before that period. We relied on traditional competitive rules emphasizing physical strength (i.e., relocating without assistance of, e.g., kicksleds or motorized devices) and simple tools (i.e., manual drills, simple rods consisting of a thin line attached to a stick-like construction). These competitions require individals to endure harsh wheather conditions (i.e., low temperatures, heavy snowfall) for a long period of time, which is reflective of sisu, a cultural term descriptive of the Finnish national character, loosely translated as "determination and resoluteness in the face of adversity" (73). To assess the motives for participating in ice-fishing competitions, we administered a survey adapted from (74) designed to assess motives for participation in recreational angling competitions on six distinct dimensions (Being with Similar People, Skill Development, Autonomy, Independence, Observing other People, Social Recognition and Fitness, Nature Experience, Challenge, Exploration, Catch/Consumption, Trophy).Fig. S12shows the results of this survey. In addition, we adapted surveys from<ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(74,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">75)</ref> assessing the reasons why individuals engage in a fishing-related leisure activity on six dimensions (Fitness, Nature Experience, Challenge, Exploration, Catch/Consumption, Trophy) and from<ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(76)</ref> to measure how involved individuals are in a particular leisure activity in general on five dimensions (Social Bonding, Identity Affirmation, Attraction, Centrality, Identity Expression). Figs. S13 and S14 show the results of these surveys.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Fig.</head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. S12 shows that among the most important motives for participation are to be with other</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head>Figure S1 :</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Nonrandom clustering. To investigate the spatial clustering of ice-fishers, we applied a chain rule algorithm (77), which assigns individuals , to the same community if their pairwise distance is below a critical threshold . GPS locations were averaged in time bins of 60s and for each time step, we varied from 0m to 500m in steps of 5m and recorded the average community size relative to the total number of participants on that day. A spatially dispersed but locally dense network structure would be indicated by an initially faster increase of with increasing relative to a uniform distribution of locations that reaches its peak later than a network structure obtained from a random distribution of locations. Dots represent averaged results across all time steps (in 60s intervals) across all competitions. The blue line shows the results of a simulation assuming random distribution of the same number of individuals in the same area sizes. The vertical dotted line marks the intersection between both curves. Below the intersection, the data points are above the blue line, indicating that locally, individuals are clustered in dense network communities. Above the intersection, the blue line exceeds the data points, indicating that the locally dense clusters are spatially dispersed.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head>Figure S2 :</head><label>S2</label><figDesc>Variation in foraging success within and across lakes. (A) Distribution of individuallevel catch success across the 10 lakes. Dots show the total amount of Eurasian perch caught per individual on that lake. (B) Distribution of individual-level success in discovering resource patches. Dots show the proportion of successful spots per individual on that lake. For (A,B), horizontal lines depict 25%, 50% and 75% percentiles; whiskers range from 25%-1.5IQR to 75%+1.5IQR. (C) Both measures strongly correlate across the 10 lakes: Lakes with a high average catch also have a high proportion of successful spots. Whiskers indicate ± 2×the standard error of the mean in both directions. (D) There was a strong positive association between participants' number of fish caught and their angling time. Each dot shows an angling spot; the black line (shaded region) shows the posterior predictions (95%CrI) of a Bayesian linear regression model. (E) There was a strong positive correlation between the total number of fish caught and the total catch weight at the level of the foraging trip. Each dot represents a unique foraging trip; the black line (shaded region) shows the posterior predictions (95%CrI) of a Bayesian linear regression model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_25"><head>Figure S3 :Figure S4 :</head><label>S3S4</label><figDesc>Systematic comparison of spot-selection models. Comparison of versions of the spot-selection model with an increasing number of feature weights. Displayed are differences in widely applicable information criteria based on the pointwise expected log predictive densities (ΔELPD) relative to the best-fitting model. Values closer to 0 indicate better model performance relative to the best-fitting model. The worst-fitting model assumes random selection of locations ("Random"). "Locality" additionally includes the Locality and Locality × parameters. "Ecological" additionally contains the Roughness weight. "Personal" additionally contains Successful , Unsuccessful weights. "Social" additionally contains the Social weight. "Conditional social info" additionally contains the interaction terms between personal and social information. The importance of each set of features can be assessed by comparing model performance to the most complex model not containing that set of cues. Error bars indicate ± 4×the standard error of the difference. Numerical results can be found in Table S14 Spatial generalization. Posterior predictions of spatial feature generalization for personal and social information. Solid lines indicate mean posterior estimates; shaded regions indicate 95%CrI. Distance indicates the Euclidian distance in m to the closest feature indicator (i.e., a successful/unsuccessful spot or competitor). Feature values are assumed to decrease exponentially with the squared distance.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_26"><head>Figure S5 :</head><label>S5</label><figDesc>Parameter lesions. Figure caption on next page.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_27"><head>Figure S5 :</head><label>S5</label><figDesc>Parameter lesions. Results of a model simulation where feature weights are lesioned (i.e., set to 0). As in Fig. 3, the x-axis shows the successive number of unsuccessful spots since the last successful spot visit. 0 indicates that the last visited spot was successful (i.e., more than one fish catch). (A,C,E) Median relocation distances in m. (B,D,F) Median turning angles in degrees. For (A-D) data is indicated by the solid grey line; circles are proportional to the number of observations in each data bin. Model simulations with the respective feature weight set to 0 are shown in dark green (median across all simulation runs) and shaded green areas (95% of all simulation runs fall within this region). For comparison, the blue line and shaded region show results from a random walk model. Both success and unsuccessful feature weights are necessary to reproduce the empirical data. (E, F) The median relocation distances and turning angles split by high and low social densities at the respective angling spots according to a median split of the observed social densities. Solid lines show median estimates of simulation runs with social feature weights set to 0. Results of simulation runs fell within the shaded region in 95% of cases.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_28"><head>Figure S6 :</head><label>S6</label><figDesc>Foraging success and exploration behaviour. (A) When individuals experienced a higher percentage of successful spots during a foraging trip, they explored a smaller area ( [95%CrI] = -5.31 [-7.33, -3.65], N = 462 foraging trips, trips with less than 4 spots had to be excluded to compute the explored area, main effect from a hierarchical log-normal regression model with random offsets for lakes). This is a consequence of area-restricted search (i.e., shorter displacement and higher turning angles) following a successful patch discovery. Data is shown as grey circles; circle size is proportional to the sample size (black numbers) in each data bin; error bars indicate ± 2× the standard error of the median. This pattern is reproduced by the spot-selection model (green), but not by a random walk (blue). Simulated medians (solid lines) lie within the shaded areas in 95% of cases. (B) Simulation results when the success feature weight is lesioned. (C) Simulation results when the unsuccessful feature weight is lesioned. Both feature weights are necessary to reproduce the empirical pattern. Table S13 shows regression analyses based on empirical data.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_29"><head>Figure S7 :</head><label>S7</label><figDesc>Model comparison of spot-leaving models. Comparison of logistic regression models assessing the effects of different cues on spot-leaving decisions. Displayed are differences in widely applicable information criteria based on the pointwise expected log predictive densities (ΔELPD) relative to the best-fitting model. Values closer to 0 indicate better model performance relative to the best-fitting model. The importance of each set of cues can be assessed by comparing model performance to the most complex model not containing that set of cues. Error bars indicate ± 4× the standard error of the difference. Numerical results can be found inTable S15.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_30"><head>Figure S8 :</head><label>S8</label><figDesc>Stability of foraging strategies across competitions. Posterior estimates of leaveone-out correlations between individual-level model parameters across lakes. Each correlation coefficient is obtained by computing the full parameter estimate (trip-level + individual-level + lake-level estimate) for all individuals for one of the lakes and the average full parameter estimate for the same individuals on the remaining nine lakes. Correlations are computed for each posterior draw of the raw parameter estimates separately to obtain a posterior distribution of correlation coefficients. Correlations (95%CrI) for main model parameters of (A) the spot-selection model, and (B) the spot-leaving model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_31"><head>Figure S9 :</head><label>S9</label><figDesc>Adaptive consequences of foraging strategies. Posterior estimates (95%CrI) predicting foraging success (average catch in kg, z-standardized within each competition) as a function of estimated foraging strategies on the individual level for (A) spot-selection strategies and (B) spotleaving strategies. Posterior distributions for each parameter were obtained by computing the maximum likelihood solution for the respective regression equation across all posterior draws of the parameter. (C) Results of a Bayesian multilevel regression predicting foraging success (catch in kg) by lake-level and individual-level intercepts. The variance in catch success explained by the individual-level intercepts measures the intraclass correlation of foraging success across individuals (i.e., the repeatability of foraging success across individuals).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_32"><head>Figure S10 :S30Figure S11 :</head><label>S10S11</label><figDesc>Flexibility of giving-up times. Giving-up times at successful spots (time between last fish catch and patch-leaving) and unsuccessful spots (time between arrival and spot-leaving) as a function of (A) average catch (in kg) and (B) percentage of successful spot visits per lake. Dots (errors bars) show mean giving-up times (± 2× the standard error of the mean) per lake and solid line (shaded regions) display posterior estimates (95% CrI) of fixed effects of a Bayesian multilevel model predicting giving-up times by both lake-level characteristics, within individuals. See Tables S16 and S17 for the parameter estimates. Locations of competition sites. Displayed are the locations of all ten competition sites in Northern Karelia, Eastern Finland, the year in which the competition took place and the name of the lake site. For orientation, the city of Joensuu is located in the center of the image.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_33"><head>Figure S12 :Figure S13 :</head><label>S12S13</label><figDesc>Motives for Participation. The results of the Participation Motivation scale adapted from (74) on the item level (A) and the dimension level (B) by gender. Results are displayed as mean ± 2 times the standard error of the mean for each item and dimension, respectively. S32 Leisure Motivation Scale. The results of the Leisure Motivation scale adapted from (75) and (74) on the item level (A) and the dimension level (B) by gender. Results are displayed as mean ± 2 times the standard error of the mean for each item and dimension, respectively.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_34"><head>Figure S14 :Figure S15 :</head><label>S14S15</label><figDesc>Involvement Scale. The results of the Involvement scale adapted from (76) on the item level (A) and the dimension level (B) by gender. Results are displayed as mean ± 2 times the standard error of the mean for each item and dimension, respectively. S34 Relocation distance by individual and lake. Histograms show the distance travelled across individual for each of the 10 lakes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_35"><head>Figure S16 :</head><label>S16</label><figDesc>Number of visited angling spots per individual and lake.. Histograms show the number of visited angling spots across individuals for each of the 10 lakes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_36"><head>Figure S17 :</head><label>S17</label><figDesc>Patch Depletion. Results of model comparison, comparing different resource acquisition functions on all successful angling spot visits. Displayed widely applicable information criteria based on the pointwise expected log predictive densities (ELPD) relative to the best-fitting model. Table S12 shows numerical estimates. Error bars indicate ± 4 times the standard error of the difference.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_37"><head>Figure S18 :</head><label>S18</label><figDesc>Empirical and simulated giving-up times per angling spot. Displayed are simulated giving-up times (time between last fish catch or start of angling sequence and time of spot-leaving) for each visited angling spot as a function of empirical giving-up times. giving-up times are simulated based on the mean posterior estimates of the different versions of the angling spotleaving models. Displayed are mean estimates and 95% quantiles across N=50 simulation runs. Numbers indicate correlations (95% quantiles across all simulation runs) between simulated and empirical giving-up times.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_38"><head>Figure S19 :</head><label>S19</label><figDesc>Empirical and simulated giving-up times per foraging trip. Displayed are simulated giving-up times (time between last fish catch or start of angling sequence and time of spot-leaving) for each foraging trip as a function of empirical giving-up times. giving-up times are simulated based on the mean posterior estimates of the different versions of the angling spot-leaving models. Displayed are mean estimates across all angling spot of the respective foraging trip along with ± 2 times the standard error of the mean (x-axis) and 95% quantiles of the mean across N=50 simulation runs. Numbers indicate correlations (95% quantiles across all simulation runs) between simulated and empirical giving-up times.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_39"><head>Figure S20 :</head><label>S20</label><figDesc>Empirical and simulated giving-up times per individual. Displayed are simulated giving-up times (time between last fish catch or start of angling sequence and time of spot-leaving) for each individual as a function of empirical giving-up times. giving-up times are simulated based on the mean posterior estimates of the different versions of the angling spot-leaving models. Displayed are mean estimates across all angling spots of an individual along with ± 2 times the standard error of the mean (x-axis) and 95% quantiles of the mean across N=50 simulation runs. Numbers indicate correlations (95% quantiles across all simulation runs) between simulated and empirical giving-up times.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_40"><head>Figure S21 :Figure S22 :</head><label>S21S22</label><figDesc>Empirical and simulated giving-up times per lake. Displayed are simulated givingup times (time between last fish catch or start of angling sequence and time of spot-leaving) for each lake as a function of empirical giving-up times. giving-up times are simulated based on the mean posterior estimates of the different versions of the angling spot-leaving models. Displayed are mean estimates across all angling spot visited on the respective lake along with ± 2 times the standard error of the mean (x-axis) and 95% quantiles of the mean across N=50 simulation runs. Numbers indicate correlations (95% quantiles across all simulation runs) between simulated and empirical giving-up times. S41 Empirical and simulated giving-up times for successful and unsuccessful angling spots. Displayed are simulated giving-up times (time between last fish catch or start of angling sequence and time of spot-leaving) for each foraging trip as a function of empirical giving-up times. giving-up times are simulated based on the mean posterior estimates of the different versions of the angling spot-leaving models. Displayed are mean estimates across all angling spots split by successful and unsuccessful angling spots along with ± 2 times the standard error of the mean (xaxis) and 95% quantiles of the mean across N=50 simulation runs. Numbers indicate correlations (95% quantiles across all simulation runs) between simulated and empirical giving-up times within successful angling spots (lightblue) and unsuccessful angling spots (darkgreen).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_41"><head>Figure S24 :</head><label>S24</label><figDesc>Exemplary bathymetric maps. Maps of competition sites were made available to all participants two weeks prior to the start of the first competition. Participants were allowed to use GPS devices to locate themselves on the map. Displayed are three exemplary maps with varying lake-bed roughness. Distances are not to scale.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_42"><head>Figure S25 :</head><label>S25</label><figDesc>GPS error. Figure caption on next page.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_43"><head>Figure S25 :</head><label>S25</label><figDesc>GPS error. Displayed are the results of the GPS error analysis. (A) shows the distribution of pairwise distances of 4 GPS watches worn on the same arm during relocation for two hours on one of the competition sites by one study author. (B) shows distributions and boxplots of pairwise distances split by comparison. Values closer to 0 indicate lesser GPS error. (C) shows distribution of distances from the center of each known angling spot (as indicated by the video recordings). The center was computed as the average Longitude and Latitude during each angling sequence. (D) shows distributions and boxplots of the same metric across the ten competitions. (E) shows distribution of the average distances from the center of each known angling spot (as indicated by the video recordings). The center was computed as the average Longitude and Latitude during each angling sequence. (F) shows distributions and boxplots of the same metric across the ten competitions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_44"><head>Figure S26 :</head><label>S26</label><figDesc>Time allocation by individual and lake. Each column shows one participant, showing the proportion of time allocated to the three main behavioural states for each of the 10 competitions: angling, drilling and relocating. Within each competition, participants are ordered based on the proportion of time spent angling.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_45"><head>Figure S27 :</head><label>S27</label><figDesc>Video coding reliability between raters. Displayed are the results of video coding reliability analyses between the two coders. (A) shows the correlation between the number of annotated angling spots per video coded by both raters. (B) shows the number of annotated fish catches per angling spot for all angling spots annotated by both raters. (C) shows the correlation between annotated angling times per angling spot that was annotated by both raters. For (A-C) the black solid line indicates perfect agreement, dots closer to this line indicate higher agreement between raters. Black numbers indicate Pearson correlation coefficients along with 95% CI. (D)shows the distribution of absolute time difference between annotated fish catches for fish catches that were annotated by both raters.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_46"><head>Figure S28 :</head><label>S28</label><figDesc>Empirical distributions of turning angles and relocation distances. Density plots of empirical distributions and distances between angling spots used to inform the spot-selection model and trajectoy simulations. For visualization N = 158 datapoints exceeding 300m (max value = 1238m) are not displayed.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_47"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Angling Skill was measured using 6 Likert Scale items ranging from 1 to 5. SD = standard deviation; y = years; g = gram.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_48"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Note. post. mean = posterior mean; CrI = credible interval; refers to the posterior estimated standard deviation of parameter values across lakes (N = 10). Estimates are obtained from a multilevel model predicting success (more than 1 fish caught) at the spot-level from an intercept, and the four main model parameters (feature weights for Successful, Unsuccessful, Social and Roughness features described above), with random intercepts and slopes for each lake.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_49"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Note. CrI = Credible Interval; from a hierarchical beta regression model predicting mean normalized absolute turning angles (ranging from 0 to 1) and variance ( ) from high vs low social density (median split) with random slopes and intercepts for individual, foraging trip and lake. Estimates are based on N = 5,164 spots in low social density areas and N = 6,030 spots in high social density areas.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_50"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Note. CrI = Credible Interval; GUT Unsuccessful Spots = Giving up time (measured between start of angling and time of leaving); GUT Successful Spots = Giving up time (measured between time of last fish catch and time of leaving). Estimates are obtained from a multilevel model predicting GUT from an intercept, whether or not a spot was successful or not, and lake-level average catch (kg) with random intercepts and slopes for each participant. Estimates are based on N = 15,475 spots obtained after excluding the first spot of each foraging trip as for fitting of the spot-leaving model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_51"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Note. CrI = Credible Interval; GUT Unsuccessful Spots = Giving up time (measured between start of angling and time of leaving); GUT Successful Spots = Giving up time (measured between time of last fish catch and time of leaving). Estimates are obtained from a multilevel model predicting GUT from an intercept, whether or not a spot was successful or not, and lake-level ratio of successful spots (%) with random intercepts and slopes for each participant. Estimates are based on N = 15,475 spots obtained after excluding the first spot of each foraging trip as for fitting of the spot-leaving model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Alexander Schakowski * , Dominik Deffner, Raine Kortet, Petri T. Niemelä, Marwa M. Kavelaars, Christopher T. Monk, Maria Pykälä, &amp; Ralf H.J.M. Kurvers * Corresponding author. Email: schakowski@mpib-berlin.mpg.de</figDesc><table><row><cell>This PDF file includes:</cell></row><row><cell>Materials and Methods</cell></row><row><cell>Supplementary Text</cell></row><row><cell>Figures S1 to S28</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table S1 :</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Participant Characteristics by Competition</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2022</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2023</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>day</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>(N trips)</cell><cell>(46)</cell><cell cols="4">(50) (45) (50) (51)</cell><cell>(55)</cell><cell>(56)</cell><cell>(56)</cell><cell>(55)</cell><cell>(51)</cell></row><row><cell>Mean catch (g)</cell><cell>1,308</cell><cell>364</cell><cell>908</cell><cell>752</cell><cell>766</cell><cell>483</cell><cell>2,012</cell><cell>1,970</cell><cell>1,432</cell><cell>279</cell></row><row><cell>SD catch (g)</cell><cell cols="10">(1,433) (343) (805) (593) (768) (381) (1,186) (1,104) (1,187) (343)</cell></row><row><cell>Median catch (g)</cell><cell>862</cell><cell>226</cell><cell>734</cell><cell>629</cell><cell>604</cell><cell>395</cell><cell>1834</cell><cell>1762</cell><cell>962</cell><cell>129</cell></row><row><cell>Missing (N)</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Mean age (y)</cell><cell>59.2</cell><cell cols="5">59.7 60.0 60.4 59.9 61.8</cell><cell>61.2</cell><cell>61.2</cell><cell>61.3</cell><cell>61.1</cell></row><row><cell>SD age (y)</cell><cell>15.0</cell><cell cols="5">14.5 14.4 14.3 14.2 14.0</cell><cell>14.1</cell><cell>14.2</cell><cell>14.3</cell><cell>14.3</cell></row><row><cell>Median age (y)</cell><cell>64.0</cell><cell cols="5">64.0 64.0 64.0 64.0 65.0</cell><cell>65.0</cell><cell>65.0</cell><cell>65.0</cell><cell>64.0</cell></row><row><cell>Missing (N)</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>female (%)</cell><cell>17.4</cell><cell cols="5">20.0 20.0 20.0 19.6 27.3</cell><cell>26.8</cell><cell>26.8</cell><cell>23.6</cell><cell>27.5</cell></row><row><cell>Missing (N)</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Mean skill *</cell><cell>2.86</cell><cell cols="5">2.79 2.86 2.82 2.86 2.82</cell><cell>2.82</cell><cell>2.86</cell><cell>2.83</cell><cell>2.82</cell></row><row><cell>SD skill</cell><cell>0.50</cell><cell cols="5">0.53 0.47 0.47 0.52 0.48</cell><cell>0.50</cell><cell>0.50</cell><cell>0.50</cell><cell>0.47</cell></row><row><cell>Median skill</cell><cell>2.92</cell><cell cols="5">2.83 2.83 2.83 3.00 2.92</cell><cell>2.92</cell><cell>3.00</cell><cell>3.00</cell><cell>3.00</cell></row><row><cell>Missing (N)</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Mean experience (y)</cell><cell>44.8</cell><cell cols="5">44.3 45.2 45.9 45.9 45.4</cell><cell>44.3</cell><cell>45.4</cell><cell>45.3</cell><cell>45.2</cell></row><row><cell>SD experience (y)</cell><cell>14.3</cell><cell cols="5">14.7 14.6 13.9 13.8 13.8</cell><cell>14.5</cell><cell>13.5</cell><cell>13.6</cell><cell>13.9</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table S3 :</head><label>S3</label><figDesc>Posterior Estimates and Convergence Diagnostics Feature Validity</figDesc><table><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell>95%CrI</cell><cell>Lake0</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-1.74</cell><cell cols="2">[-2.33, -1.16] 0.92 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Successful</cell><cell>0.32</cell><cell>[0.13, 0.51]</cell><cell>0.28 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Unsuccessful</cell><cell>-0.27</cell><cell cols="2">[-0.41, -0.13] 0.19 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Social</cell><cell>0.23</cell><cell>[0.13, 0.33]</cell><cell>0.14 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Roughness</cell><cell>-0.05</cell><cell cols="2">[-0.17, 0.09] 0.18 1.00</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table S4 :</head><label>S4</label><figDesc>Posterior Estimates Relocation Distance Area-restricted search Credible Interval; Estimates are obtained from a hierarchical log-normal regression model predicting Relocation Distance from an intercept and the number of successive unsuccessful angling spot visits (n) with random intercepts and slopes for each participant, each foraging trip and each lake. Estimates are based on N = 11,194 spots obtained after excluding angling spots before the first successful angling spot.</figDesc><table><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell>95%CrIÎ</cell></row><row><cell>ntercept Relocation Distance</cell><cell>2.50</cell><cell>[2.37, 2.64] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Relocation Distance Successive unsuccessful spots</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>[0.04, 0.06] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Note. CrI =</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table S5 :</head><label>S5</label><figDesc>Posterior Estimates Turning Angles Area-restricted search Credible Interval; from a hierarchical beta regression model predicting mean normalized absolute turning angles (ranging from 0 to 1) and variance ( ) with random slopes and intercepts for individual, foraging trip and lake. Estimates are based on N = 11,194 spots obtained after excluding angling spots before the first successful angling spot.</figDesc><table><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell>95%CrIÎ</cell></row><row><cell>ntercept Turning Angle</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>[-0.08, 0.07] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell>[0.41, 0.52] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Turning angle∼Successive unsuccessful spots</cell><cell>-0.08</cell><cell>[-0.09, -0.07] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>∼Successive unsuccessful spots</cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell>[0.03, 0.05] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Note. CrI =</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table S6 :</head><label>S6</label><figDesc>Posterior Estimates Relocation Distance Social Area-restricted search Credible Interval; Estimates are obtained from a hierarchical log-normal regression model predicting Relocation Distance from an intercept and high vs low social density (median split) with random intercepts and slopes for each participant, each foraging trip and each lake. Estimates are based on N = 5,164 spots in low social density areas and N = 6,030 spots in high social density areas.</figDesc><table><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell>95%CrIÎ</cell></row><row><cell>ntercept Relocation Distance</cell><cell>2.94</cell><cell>[2.74, 3.14] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Relocation Distance∼Social Density (high vs low)</cell><cell>-0.41</cell><cell>[-0.58, -0.25] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Note. CrI =</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table S7 :</head><label>S7</label><figDesc>Posterior Estimates Relocation Distance Social Area-restricted search</figDesc><table><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell>95%CrIÎ</cell></row><row><cell>ntercept Turning Angle</cell><cell>-0.46</cell><cell>[-0.55, -0.37] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Intercept</cell><cell>0.60</cell><cell>[0.54, 0.65] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Turning angle∼Social Density (high vs low)</cell><cell>0.32</cell><cell>[0.23, 0.41] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>∼Social Density (high vs low)</cell><cell>-0.04</cell><cell>[-0.11, 0.02] 1.00</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table S9 :</head><label>S9</label><figDesc>Posterior Estimates Individual Variation</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Skill</cell><cell></cell><cell>Age</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Gender</cell></row><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell>95%CrI</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell>95%CrI</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell>95%CrI</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table S11 :</head><label>S11</label><figDesc>Missing Data Foraging Locations and Descriptive Statistics Mean Angling Time successful spots * (%) 784.2 502.3 412.4 689.6 581.7 687.0 705.5 852.9 1218.1 866.0 Median Angling Time successful spots (%) 636.7 433.3 375.0 442.3 394.6 500.0 594.8 745.7 625.0 683.3 Mean Angling Time unsuccessful spots * (%) 207.1 157.7 136.1 149.2 123.9 155.1 107.7 101.7 130.3 174.0 Median Angling Time unsuccessful spots (%) 179.0 137.6 121.4 126.2 113.5 151.2 94.8 97.8 123.1 170.5</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2022</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2023</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>day</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>Participants (N)</cell><cell>46</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>56</cell><cell>56</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>51</cell></row><row><cell>Missing watch/video recording (N)</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Missing watch/video recording (%)</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Locations (N)</cell><cell cols="10">1,249 1,809 1,966 1,690 2,081 2,363 1,737 2,033 2,055 1,903</cell></row><row><cell>Start/end missing (N)</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Video obstructed (N)</cell><cell>+19</cell><cell>+14</cell><cell>+5</cell><cell>+14</cell><cell>+7</cell><cell>+6</cell><cell>+15</cell><cell>+7</cell><cell>+8</cell><cell>+0</cell></row><row><cell>Noisy GPS (N)</cell><cell>+3</cell><cell>+2</cell><cell>+2</cell><cell>+1</cell><cell>+3</cell><cell>+2</cell><cell>+2</cell><cell>+1</cell><cell>+3</cell><cell>+4</cell></row><row><cell>Missing GPS (N)</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+1</cell><cell>+1</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+45</cell><cell>+49</cell><cell>+62</cell><cell>+95</cell><cell>+94</cell></row><row><cell>Missing Catch (N)</cell><cell>+16</cell><cell>+6</cell><cell>+5</cell><cell>+4</cell><cell>+7</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+2</cell><cell>+13</cell><cell>+2</cell><cell>+0</cell></row><row><cell>Subsequent Spots (N)</cell><cell cols="9">+204 +205 +201 +197 +228 +308 +334 +212 +187</cell><cell>+93</cell></row><row><cell>One spot left (N)</cell><cell>+1</cell><cell>+1</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+1</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+0</cell><cell>+0</cell></row><row><cell>Missing (N)</cell><cell>269</cell><cell>235</cell><cell>222</cell><cell>243</cell><cell>252</cell><cell>387</cell><cell>413</cell><cell>310</cell><cell>309</cell><cell>191</cell></row><row><cell>Missing (%)</cell><cell cols="8">21.5 12.9 11.3 15.8 12.1 16.4 23.8 15.2</cell><cell>15.0</cell><cell>11.2</cell></row><row><cell>Trips analysed(N)</cell><cell>39</cell><cell>46</cell><cell>43</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>52</cell><cell>46</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>49</cell></row><row><cell>Mean Locations per trip (N)</cell><cell cols="8">28.4 37.7 44.7 33.8 41.6 43.8 32.2 36.3</cell><cell>38.1</cell><cell>37.3</cell></row><row><cell>Median Locations per trip (N)</cell><cell cols="8">29.0 37.5 44.0 35.0 42.0 42.0 32.0 34.0</cell><cell>38.5</cell><cell>37.0</cell></row><row><cell>Mean Missing per trip (N)</cell><cell cols="8">6.09 4.88 5.05 4.84 5.04 7.17 7.65 5.54</cell><cell>5.72</cell><cell>3.75</cell></row><row><cell>Median Missing per trip (N)</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Trips with less than 5% missing (%)</cell><cell cols="8">72.7 81.3 79.5 78.0 80.0 81.5 72.2 75.0</cell><cell>77.8</cell><cell>90.2</cell></row><row><cell>Mean Successful locations per trip * (%)</cell><cell cols="5">28.8 16.7 16.8 20.1 15.5</cell><cell>8.4</cell><cell>32.2</cell><cell>22.9</cell><cell>13.3</cell><cell>4.0</cell></row><row><cell>Median Successful locations per trip(%)</cell><cell cols="5">24.1 15.4 16.1 17.0 14.0</cell><cell>7.7</cell><cell cols="2">30.7 23.7</cell><cell>9.8</cell><cell>3.0</cell></row><row><cell>Mean fish catches * (%)</cell><cell>3.7</cell><cell>2.9</cell><cell>3.0</cell><cell>4.4</cell><cell>5.7</cell><cell>2.6</cell><cell cols="2">14.0 15.5</cell><cell>12.4</cell><cell>2.2</cell></row><row><cell>Median fish catches (%)</cell><cell>2.8</cell><cell>2.7</cell><cell>2.6</cell><cell>3.5</cell><cell>3.3</cell><cell>1.5</cell><cell cols="2">11.5 10.4</cell><cell>5.8</cell><cell>1.3</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table S14 :</head><label>S14</label><figDesc>Results Model Comparison Spot-Selection Models model Δ ELPD SE Δ ELPD Note. Δ ELPD = difference in the widely applicable information criterion based on expected log predictive densities for each comparison, comparing each model to the best-fitting solution; SE Δ ELPD = standard error of the difference in ELPD comparing each model to the best-fitting model.</figDesc><table><row><cell>+Conditional Social</cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>0.000</cell></row><row><cell>+Social</cell><cell>-198.0</cell><cell>22.8</cell></row><row><cell>+Personal</cell><cell>-2,113.8</cell><cell>75.1</cell></row><row><cell>+Ecological</cell><cell cols="2">-5,047.0 108.9</cell></row><row><cell>+Locality</cell><cell cols="2">-5,238.8 110.1</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell cols="2">-6,213.8 113.2</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table S15 :</head><label>S15</label><figDesc>Results Model Comparison Spot-Leaving Models model Δ ELPD SE Δ ELPD Note. Δ ELPD = difference in the widely applicable information criterion based on expected log predictive densities for each comparison, comparing each model to the best-fitting solution; SE Δ ELPD = standard error of the difference in ELPD comparing each model to the best-fitting model.</figDesc><table><row><cell>+Spatial</cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>0.000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">+Global/Local Updating -430.4</cell><cell>30.2</cell></row><row><cell>+Patch Discovery</cell><cell>-638.1</cell><cell>38.6</cell></row><row><cell>+Time w/o catch</cell><cell>-3,157.2</cell><cell>82.3</cell></row><row><cell>Baseline</cell><cell cols="2">-7,429.3 116.3</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table S16 :</head><label>S16</label><figDesc>Posterior Estimates GUT and Average Catch</figDesc><table><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell cols="2">95%CrIÛ</cell></row><row><cell>nsuccessful Spots</cell><cell>163.9s</cell><cell cols="2">[146.4s, 182.2s] 1.01</cell></row><row><cell>Successful Spots</cell><cell>328.8s</cell><cell cols="2">[277.2s, 382.2s] 1.02</cell></row><row><cell>GUT Unsuccessful Spots∼Avg. Catch (kg)</cell><cell>-2.87</cell><cell>[-3.55, -2.19]</cell><cell>1.00</cell></row><row><cell>GUT Successful Spots∼Avg. Catch (kg)</cell><cell>-8.41</cell><cell cols="2">[-10.95, -5.53] 1.00</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head>Table S17 :</head><label>S17</label><figDesc>Posterior Estimates GUT and Percentage Successful Spots</figDesc><table><row><cell>parameter</cell><cell>post. mean</cell><cell cols="2">95%CrIÛ</cell></row><row><cell>nsuccessful Spots</cell><cell>155.7s</cell><cell cols="2">[140.2s, 172.0s] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>Successful Spots</cell><cell>335.4s</cell><cell cols="2">[283.9s, 384.6s] 1.00</cell></row><row><cell>GUT Unsuccessful Spots∼% Successful Spots</cell><cell>-.13</cell><cell>[-.19, -.70]</cell><cell>1.00</cell></row><row><cell>GUT Successful Spots∼% Successful Spots</cell><cell>-.60</cell><cell>[-.79, -.40]</cell><cell>1.00</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">lakes. Tables S9 and S10 show posterior estimates of regression analyses.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank Tomi Keinänen, Mika Issakainen, the North Karelian Sport Fishing Association (Pohjois-Karjalan Urheilukalastajat ry), Petra Siemers-Hering, and Katja Münz for invaluable help</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Note. CrI = Credible Interval; Estimates are obtained from a hierarchical log-normal regression model predicting the explored area (area of the convex hull around all visited angling spots for each foraging trip) from an intercept and the ratio of successful angling spot visits with random intercepts and slopes for each lake.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference of ecological and social drivers of human brainsize evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>González-Forero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41586-018-0127-x,10.1038/s41586-018-0127-x</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">557</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="554" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Life history, cognition and the evolution of complex foraging niches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Schuppli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Isler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Van Schaik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1016/j. jhevol.2015.11.007</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Human Evolution</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The origins of human cumulative culture: from the foraging niche to collective intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Migliano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Vinicius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2020.0317</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">377</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20200317</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1843" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Foraging Cognition: Reviving the Ecological Intelligence Hypothesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rosati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2017.05.011</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="702" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Socio-economic predictors of Inuit hunting choices and their implications for climate change adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hillemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Beheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ready</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2022.0395</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">378</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20220395</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1889" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tubers as fallback foods and their impact on Hadza huntergatherers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Marlowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Berbesque</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1002/ ajpa.21040</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Physical Anthropology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">140</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="751" to="758" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Berry Plants and Berry Picking in Inuit Nunangat: Traditions in a Changing Socio-Ecological Landscape</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Boulanger-Lapointe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1007/ s10745-018-0044-5</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Ecology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recreational Wild Berry Picking in Finland-Reflection of a Rural Lifestyle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pouta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sievänen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Neuvonen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1080/ 08941920500519156</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Society &amp; Natural Resources</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="304" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The transition to foraging for dense and predictable resources and its impact on the evolution of modern humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Marean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2015.0239</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">371</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20150239</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1698" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nahua mushroom gatherers use area-restricted search strategies that conform to marginal value theorem predictions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Pacheco-Cobos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1814476116</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10339" to="10347" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The life history of human foraging: Cross-cultural and individual variation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Koster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/sciadv.aax9070</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human social organization during the Late Pleistocene: Beyond the nomadic-egalitarian model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Glowacki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1016/ j.evolhumbehav.2022.07.003</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolution and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="418" to="431" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L.-A</forename><surname>Giraldeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Caraco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Social Foraging Theory, Monographs in Behavior and Ecology</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Behavioral Ecology</title>
		<editor>J. Koster, B. Scelza, M. K. Shenk</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for encounter-conditional, area-restricted search in a preliminary study of Colombian blowgun hunters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Winterhalder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1371/ journal.pone.0207633</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">207633</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Foraging complexity and the evolution of childhood</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Pretelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ringen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lew-Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/sciadv.abn9889</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9889</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Foraging as an evidence accumulation process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">El</forename><surname>Hady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007060</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1007060</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information and its use by animals in evolutionary ecology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Giraldeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Olsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcnamara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Stephens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tree.2005.01.010</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Ecology &amp; Evolution</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SiMRiv: an R package for mechanistic simulation of individual, spatially-explicit multistate movements in rivers, heterogeneous and homogeneous spaces incorporating landscape bias</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Quaglietta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Porto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1186/ s40462-019-0154-8</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Movement Ecology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalization, similarity, and Bayesian inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X01000061</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="640" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a Universal Law of Generalization for Psychological Science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shepard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.3629243</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">237</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4820</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1317" to="1323" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian Analysis Reporting Guidelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-021-01177-7</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1282" to="1291" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stan: A probabilistic programming language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of statistical software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gabry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Češnovar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">cmdstanr: R Interface to&apos;CmdStan&apos;. See mc-stan</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcelreath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1201/9780429029608</idno>
		<title level="m">Statistical rethinking: A Bayesian course with examples in R and Stan</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CRC press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating random correlation matrices based on vines and extended onion method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lewandowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kurowicka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Joe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of multivariate analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1989" to="2001" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference from iterative simulation using multiple sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1214/ss/1177011136</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistical Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="472" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1201/ b16018</idno>
		<title level="m">Bayesian Data Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical Bayesian model evaluation using leave-one-out cross-validation and WAIC</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gabry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10.1007/ s11222-016-9696-4</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistics and Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1413" to="1432" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Uncertainty in Bayesian leave-one-out cross-validation based model comparison</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sivula</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Magnusson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Matamoros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.48550/arXiv.2008.10296</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brms: An R package for Bayesian multilevel models using Stan</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-C</forename><surname>Bürkner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18637/jss.v080.i01</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The human as delta-rule learner</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dec0000112</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kolling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Akam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.conb.2017.08.008</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Reinforcement?) Learning to forage optimally</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="162" to="169" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A measure for assessment of beneficial and harmful fortitude: development and initial validation of the Sisu Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Henttonen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.heliyon.2022.e11483</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Heliyon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11483</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Leisure Motivation: A Meta-Analysis of the Recreation Experience Preference Scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Manfredo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Driver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tarrant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00222216.1996.11949770</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Leisure Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="188" to="213" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Human Dimensions of Recreational Anglers Targeting Freshwater Species in Coastal Ecosystems, with Implications for Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Koemle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Beardmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dorow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Arlinghaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/nafm.10672</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">North American Journal of Fisheries Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1572" to="1590" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Absher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hammitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Jodice</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/02614360600896668</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">A Modified Involvement Scale. Leisure Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="427" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisited: Why and How You Should (Still) Use DBSCAN</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kriegel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Revisited</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3068335</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Database Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Note. post. mean = posterior mean</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Estimates are obtained by computing the maximum likelihood solution of a multiple regression equation for each posterior draw of each parameter. The multiple regression equation contains the z-standardized parameter value as the criterion, and z-standardized skill, age, and gender as predictors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cri = Credible</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Interval</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Successful -0.84 [-0.93, -0.73] -0.53 [-0.68, -0.36</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Note. post. mean = posterior mean</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Estimates are obtained by computing the maximum likelihood solution of a linear regression equation for each posterior draw of each parameter. The linear regression equation contains the z-standardized parameter value as the criterion, and z-standardized avg. catch (kg) and percentage of successful spots as predictors. Caption for Movie S1. First person view. The video shows parts of a competition from the perspective of one participant. The participant first relocates to decide on a novel angling spot, then drills a hole and starts angling and catching fish. For illustration, parts of the angling sequence are removed from the video</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cri = Credible</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Interval</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://osf.io/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>The video can be accessed using the following link</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Aerial view. The video illustrates typical relocation patterns</title>
		<ptr target="https://osf.io/9hcsq/files/osfstorage/67b88baa0229851a83c34fb9" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Individuals move from one angling spot to the next. In some parts of the lake, participants appear to cluster more densely than in other parts. The video can be accessed using the following link</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Caption for Movie S3. 3D-animation. The video shows a 3D-animation of one of the 10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Red dots represent participants relocating on the ice cover of the lake, shadows represent angling locations on the lake surface. The lake-bed was inferred from the bathymetric data, assuming depth of the closest depth curve at the respective location</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>For visual purposes, the video is fast-forwarded to show the duration of the whole competition within one minute</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">In the beginning, all participants start from the same starting position and decide on an initial angling spot. The video can be accessed using the following link</title>
		<ptr target="https://osf.io/9hcsq/files/osfstorage/67b88c281f0f94076d3140c7" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
