<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Decision Making Under Extinction Risk</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
							<email>maximilianmaier0401@gmail.com.data</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">J L</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Syracuse University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henrik</forename><surname>Singmann</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Decision Making Under Extinction Risk</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:43+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>decision making</term>
					<term>risky choice</term>
					<term>extreme outcomes</term>
					<term>extinction</term>
					<term>mixture modelling</term>
					<term>computational modelling</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We thank Rani Moran for helpful feedback on a previous draft and suggesting the name Reset condition. We thank Dirk Wulff for helpful feedback on the initial task design and theoretical ideas. We thank Maarten Speekenbrink, Duarte Goncalves, and the members of the UCL Centre for Behavioural Data Science for helpful suggestions and ideas for improvement. We thank Vanessa Cheung for helpful comments and suggestions on a previous version of this manuscript.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decision Making Under Extinction Risk</head><p>Throughout their daily lives, people make decisions in light of risks that, if materialized, would change their lives as they know them: a potential jaywalker decides whether to cross the street in front of an incoming car, a driver decides whether they have enough space to make an overtaking manoeuvre, and a boxer decides whether to risk career-ending injury in a high stakes bout. At a collective level, people need to decide how much to invest in managing small probability high-stakes risks, such as extreme climate change or pandemics.</p><p>The common denominator across all these examples is the risk of irredeemable extreme outcomes. In the current paper, hopefully without sounding too ominous, we refer to such examples as decisions under extinction risk. Extant literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Elga et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b99">Wiener, 2016)</ref>, recent history, and everyday anecdotes ('that driver') suggest that people are bad at making decisions about these types of risks. However, in any real-world decision under extinction risk, a large set of psychological factors are at play simultaneously and it is difficult to disentangle the relative influence of different factors. For instance, inadequate social distancing during the Covid-19 pandemic could have been the result of self-interested decision making (especially with regards to younger people for whom COVID-19 was on average less severe), scope insensitivity (i.e., people do not take the large number of people affected from a pandemic outbreak into account), or underestimating the probability and cost of getting severely ill or even dying from the disease, to name just a few of many plausible factors.</p><p>Anyone tackling the challenges posed by extinction events will find little relief in the pages of mainstream decision making research. To see this, consider decision making research's 'fruit-fly', the binary-choice lottery paradigm (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Rieskamp, 2008)</ref>. In this paradigm, participants are presented with one lottery problem at a time, for example choosing between a sure win of £50 versus a 50% chance of winning £110. These lottery problems are independent in the fullest sense of the term: at no point do outcomes of these decisions affect the possibility of future choices or their outcomes. By contrast, the outcomes of decisions about extinction risks might reduce the options available in future decisions -or prevent any future decision making at all.</p><p>Of course, the binary lottery paradigm is only one among the many different options available to researchers. Paradigms such as the Balloon Analogue Risk Task <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Lejuez et al., 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Lejuez et al., , 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Pleskac, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Pleskac et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">Wallsten et al., 2005)</ref>, or the Bomb Risk Elicitation Task (BRET, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Crosetto and Filippin, 2013)</ref>, mitigate some of the limitations of the binary lottery paradigm. However, these tasks were not designed to study extinction risks as discussed in this article. They therefore come with several limitations that make them unsuitable to study decisions under extinction risk, such as dependencies between choice and event probabilities, impossibility of learning from experience, or the probability of the extinction event being much higher than realistic in real-world settings (for a detailed review of potentially relevant tasks and their limitations, see Appendix A).</p><p>Given that existing paradigms do not allow studying extinction risks, what predictions can be derived from the extant decision making literature? Prospect theory would suggest that low probability events are overweighted and people are loss-averse <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1992)</ref>. We might therefore expect people to be risk-averse for decisions involving low-probability, high impact options (and thus avoid jaywalking). However, this overweighting of low probabilities does not necessarily extend to contexts in which people learn about the probabilities from experience, a discrepancy known as the the description-experience gap <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Hertwig et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Kellen et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Lejarraga and Hertwig, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b101">Wulff et al., 2018)</ref>. For many extinction risks, people may not be aware of descriptive risk information but rather reason from their experience (or the experience of people they know). Further complicating this picture, other studies involving experienced options point to people overweighting extreme events (i.e., events with extremely good or bad utilities; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Lieder et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Lieder et al., , 2018</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Ludvig et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Madan et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">Sunstein and Zeckhauser, 2011)</ref>. Extinction events clearly have extreme utility; this literature would therefore predict their overweighting.</p><p>In addition to the probability of the extinction event, another factor that would likely influence people's decisions is the perceived badness of extinction. Several well-documented psychological effects imply an underestimation of the value lost by extinction. For instance, scope insensitivity (i.e., not valuing a good in proportion with its scope or size; <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Desvousges et al., 1993)</ref> and narrow bracketing (i.e., viewing one choice in isolation rather than as part of a wider set of choices; <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Read et al., 2000)</ref> may cause people to underestimate the cost of being precluded from a larger number of choices or experiences in the future. Likewise, opportunity cost neglect <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Frederick et al., 2009)</ref> may cause people to underestimate the opportunity cost of not being able to do what they could have done if they had avoided an extinction event.</p><p>The aforementioned factors would all affect decision making even if people had unbiased information about the probability of the extinction event. These factors are likely amplified by biases in the available samples, in particular survivorship or observer selection effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Ćirković et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b100">Wilson, 2023)</ref>: conditional on thinking about the probability of the extinction event, the decision maker has not been subjected to one themselves, and will therefore have experienced zero instances of it (e.g., someone who is reflecting on the risk of jaywalking will have zero personal experience with deadly accidents, as otherwise they would not be in a position to ponder this question). The impossibility of sampling extinction events from memory will likely lead to underestimation of the risk.</p><p>In summary, a number of considerations suggest that people will be risk-averse (overweighting of small probabilities from description &amp; overweighting of extreme events), whereas others suggest they will be risk-seeking (description-experience gap, underestimating the utility loss due to extinction, &amp; observer selection effects). Given the conflicting predictions that can be drawn from past research and the practical importance of the topic, it is surprising that there is a "notable scarcity of research on human behavior in the context of low-probability high-impact events" <ref type="bibr">(Sundh, 2024, p.7)</ref>. One of the main reasons for this absence may be the lack of a behavioural paradigm to study these types of risks, especially one that can be connected with normative benchmarks.</p><p>The present work contributes to the understanding of how people make choices under extinction risk. After providing the necessary clarification on what is meant by an extinction event, and offering two distinct definitions, we introduce an experimental paradigm suitable for its study -the Extinction Gambling Task (EGT). One of the benefits of the EGT is that it allows deriving optimal choice strategies for different variants of extinction events, which can be used as performance benchmarks.</p><p>After introducing the EGT, we report three experiments demonstrating its utility for studying and evaluating people's choices under extinction risk. Experiment 1 shows that participants are sensitive to differences between two different kinds of extinction events in a way that is qualitatively in line with the optimal strategies. Experiment 2 introduces a new type of catastrophic non-extinction event and shows that participants treat this type of event differently from the extinction events, again in line with predictions made from the optimal strategies. Finally, Experiments 3a and 3b demonstrate how the EGT can be used to study factors that might plausibly influence people's decision making under extinction risk. We leverage computational modeling to obtain a detailed account of the decision making strategies of individual participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Towards an Extinction Gambling Task (EGT)</head><p>It is typical for scientific investigations to call for regimentations of ordinary-language concepts through the development of technical definitions (e.g., from warmth to temperature). The case of human decision making is no different. What is perhaps distinct is the co-existence of multiple possible definitions. Take the case of 'risk', which can be defined as tracking the probability of the worst-possible outcome, or the variance among possible outcomes with known probabilities, to name just two possible definitions (see <ref type="bibr">Levy, 2015, Chap.</ref> 1; see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Konovalova and Pachur, 2021)</ref>. The same issue applies to 'extinction events', in part due to the wide range of domains to which the term could be applied (e.g., health, finance, climate).</p><p>In the present work, we consider cases of repeated choice. Participants are required to repeat the same decision (between an option containing the possibility of extinction and one without this possibility) a maximum of 100 times. Within these scenarios, there are two possible types of extinction events. The first we define as Keep, which establishes extinction as an end to the possibility of gains while keeping any gains made thus far. As a real-world example, consider a boxer who risks career-ending injuries every time they take on a high quality opponent for a high value payday. As devastating as career-ending injuries are, they do not undo the benefits gained from such bouts in the past. Our second definition, Lose, is much more drastic, referring to a complete wipeout of gains -past, present, and future. As an example, consider the case of a bank whose investment losses are greater than all of the profits generated in their entire history, which results in them going out of business (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b86">Taleb, 2007)</ref>. These definitions of extinction risk also apply to extinction risks involving life, depending on how one views death. While Alice and Bob might agree that death is an end, Alice might consider that this, nevertheless, does not erase all the good experiences accumulated throughout life (Keep). Bob, however, might consider that those experiences are also forgotten and therefore erased (Lose). Alice's view is reminiscent of philosophical positions that underscore the experiences we have collected as fundamental to the meaning of life <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Eagleton, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Mitsis, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Seneca et al., 2004)</ref>, whereas Bob's view would be reflected in positions such as existential nihilism, which emphasize the futility of human endeavors in light of death <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Kuhn, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">Sartre, 1972)</ref>. Both definitions of extinction can be implemented in the context of a repeated risky-choice task. Consider a lottery problem with a 'risky' and a 'safe' option:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Risky =     r 1 r 2 r E p 1 p p E     Safe =     s 1 s 2 q q    </formula><p>Each lottery is comprised of mutually exclusive outcomes (e.g., r 1 ) that occur with a given probability (e.g., p 1 ). Note that p + p 2 + p E = q 1 + q 2 = 1. The outcome r E corresponds to the extinction event. The consequences of this event will depend on the definition adopted.</p><p>To give a more concrete example:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Risky =     £10 £0 Extinct .475 .475 .05     Safe =     £1 £0 .50 .50    </formula><p>If a decision maker only encounters a single lottery problem once, then there is no difference between the potential £0 outcome from the Safe option and the Extinct outcome from the Risky option. For the two outcomes to become distinguishable, it is necessary for the decision maker to engage with multiple lottery problems and to accumulate gains. In the present implementation of the EGT, they will encounter the same lottery problem multiple times. Knowledge of how many times a lottery problem will be encountered allows the decision maker to better evaluate the exposure to risk vis-à-vis the opportunity for maximizing gains. This evaluation depends on the operating definition of extinction. In the next section, we outline the optimal strategies for both the Keep and Lose definitions of extinction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Optimal Solution for the Keep Definition</head><p>The Keep definition of extinction captures the idea of an end to the accumulation of gains, without any loss of past gains. In the EGT, where a lottery problem is encountered multiple times, this definition implies that the expected payoff of a strategy strongly depends on the position in the sequence of trials where the risky choices are played. Early in the experiment, extinction carries a higher (opportunity) cost than it does later in the experiment, as one misses out on more opportunities to earn money. By contrast, in the last trial, the opportunity cost is zero and the cost of drawing the extinction option is equal to the £0 outcome. Therefore, it would make sense to play the safe lottery in the first trials and the risky lottery towards the end. Specifically, we show that the expected value is maximised by following a strategy with a single switch point, before which participants should choose the safe option and after which they should choose the risky option. The expected value (E) for the Keep condition, assuming that a participant follows this optimal order of choices (that is, they first make N safe safe choices and afterwards N risky risky choices for a fixed total of N safe + N risky = N total choices), is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">E(N risky ) = s × N safe</formula><p>Expected value of safe-choice trials</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">+ p E × N risky −1 i=0 (1 − p E ) i × i × r</formula><p>Expected value of the risky-choice trials if one goes extinct at some point</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">+ (1 − p E ) N risky × N risky × r,</formula><p>Expected value of the risky-choice trials if one does not go extinct <ref type="bibr">(1)</ref> where s denotes the expected value of choosing the safe lottery, and r denotes the expected value of choosing the risky lottery -extinction excluded -and p E denotes the probability of going extinct when playing the risky lottery. If the safe choices are made first, then the expected value from the safe-choice trials is the number of safe-choice trials times the expected value per trial (first line of Equation 1). The second line denotes the probability of going extinct in the risky-choice trial multiplied by the payoff of this type of extinction (i.e., the expected value from the risky-choice trials over all extinction outcomes). Finally, the third line denotes the probability of surviving the entire experiment multiplied by the payoff of the risky-choices in this case. 1</p><p>The optimal number of risky choices can then be obtained by finding the maximum expected value across all possible N risky , argmax</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">N risky E(N risky ).<label>(2)</label></formula><p>But what if participants do not follow the optimal ordering? If the risky-choice trials are not played strictly after the initial block of N safe safe-choice trials, then the expected value for the latter (first term of Equation 1) changes. For example, consider the case where we replace two safe choices from this block with risky choices, namely the jth and kth trials, with j &lt; k &lt; N safe . Then</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">s × N safe replaced with − −−−−−− → s × (j − 1) first j − 1 safe choices + (s × (k − j) + r) × (1 − p E )</formula><p>risky choice at j and safe choices between j + 1 and k − 1</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">+ (s × (N safe − k − 1) + r) × (1 − p E ) 2</formula><p>risky choice at k and safe choices between k + 1 and N safe .</p><p>(3)</p><p>Comparing Equation 1 and Equation 3, we can see why the expected value is reduced whenever one deviates from the optimal order of playing all safe lotteries first and then all risky lotteries. The expected value for some of the safe choices is multiplied by the probability of survival (a number smaller than one, here (1 − p E ) and (1 − p E ) 2 ).</p><p>Finally, consider the case that the decision maker is given some initial endowment.</p><p>Then, the expected value for both choice options would simply change by a constant, namely the value of that endowment. This illustrates a more general fact: that the optimal strategy for the Keep definition does not depend on initial earnings, as the decision maker can keep them regardless of their choice in the next trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Optimal Solution for the Lose Definition</head><p>While it is clear that one should play risky on the final trial under the Keep definition, this is not so clear under the Lose definition, where one might lose all earnings gained on all previous trials. Indeed, under the Lose definition, the optimal solution is dynamic and has to account for participants' luck (i.e., their winnings from previous trials).</p><p>For example, if a participant chooses the risky option on the first three trials, they may receive the maximum payoff three times, or zero. In the first case, they have more to lose in subsequent risky choices than in the second case, and therefore they should play less risky in the following trials.</p><p>Deriving the dynamic optimal solution for this scenario requires the application of the Bellman equation, a standard method in economics (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dixit, 1990)</ref>. In particular, this method uses backward induction by using the relationship between the value function at one trial and the value function in the next trial.</p><p>Let Z denote current earnings. We can estimate the expected value of a risky choice with N remaining trials as</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">E risky (N, Z) = p 1 × E(N − 1, Z + r 1 ) + p 2 × E(N − 1, Z + r 2 ), (4) with E risky (0, Z) = Z.<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Analogously, we can estimate the analogous expected value of a safe choice:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">E safe (N, Z) = q 1 × E(N − 1, Z + s 1 ) + q 2 × E(N − 1, Z + s 2 ).<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The optimal choice in a given trial is then risky if E risky (N, Z) &gt; E safe (N, Z) and otherwise it is safe. Finally, the expected value of the gamble, given that the participant follows the optimal dynamic strategy, is determined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">E(N, ϵ) = max(E risky (N, ϵ), E safe (N, ϵ)).<label>(7)</label></formula><p>Unlike the Keep variant, the Lose variant does not imply a single optimal switch point. Instead, there are different possible strategies that would approximate the optimal solution well. Following the optimal policy closely would imply a gradual decrease of the number of risky choices; however, strategies that start safe or risky and then switch to risky or safe would lead to similar expected value, as long as the total number of risky choices is similar.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1: Empirical Choice Patterns for the Lose and Keep Conditions with 100 Trials</head><p>In the previous sections, we 1) argued that the extant literature makes conflicting predictions regarding whether participants would be risk-seeking or risk-averse when deciding whether to engage in actions that risk extinction and 2) derived optimal solutions for the EGT. We now report an implementation of the EGT that operationalises the Lose and Keep definitions of extinction and compare participants' choices against the optimal strategy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants &amp; Power</head><p>Participants were paid £1.50 for a 10-minute study. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design and Materials</head><p>Participants played a sequence of 20 practice trials, followed by 100 incentivised trials. Throughout the experiment, we displayed to participants how many trials they had left and how much money they had currently accumulated. On each trial, participants had to choose between two lotteries: a safe lottery with a 50% chance of not winning anything, and a 50% chance of winning 1p; and a risky lottery with a 47.5% chance of not winning anything, a 47.5% chance of winning 10p, and a 5% chance of extinction (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 1</ref> for an example trial). In Experiment 1, the risky lottery was always displayed on the left, and the safe lottery on the right. 3</p><p>Our two experimental conditions represented the two extinction definitions outlined in the Introduction. In the Keep condition, participants could keep what they had earned</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head><p>The Experimental Setup, as Shown to Participants on the Instruction Screen if they experienced the extinction event but could not earn additional endowment in the following trials. In the Lose condition, participants' entire earnings would be wiped out when experiencing the extinction event and they cannot earn any more endowment in future trials. After encountering an extinction event, participants still needed to play the remaining trials (to avoid any incentives for early extinction); however, the piggy bank in the top right corner turned into a mushroom cloud to indicate extinction and they could not accumulate any more earnings (we did not analyse choices made after the extinction event was experienced). At the end of the experiment, participants were paid their earnings as a bonus payment on top of their regular payment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants started the experiment on a welcome page with a high-level description of the experiment and the following two warnings: 'We advise against participation if you have or had problems with gambling (i.e., gambling addiction) at any point in your life,'</p><p>and 'At one point during the experiment, you may view a picture of a mushroom cloud. If you are not comfortable with this, please do not continue.' After agreeing to the consent forms, participants received detailed task instructions. These instructions included the probabilities and outcomes of all the gambles, what would happen if they drew the extinction event, and an annotated illustration of the lottery screen (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 1</ref>; the full experiment is shared on the OSF, https://osf.io/qhkw6/).</p><p>After reading all instructions, participants made decisions in 20 practice trials.</p><p>Notably, some participants drew an extinction event during these practice trials, while some did not. In this and the following experiments, we found no difference in the proportion of risky choices based on whether participants drew the extinction event during the practice trials 4 .</p><p>After the practice trials, participants answered two attention checks: 'What happens if you choose the risky lottery and you draw the extinction option?' (Correct answer for the Keep condition: 'I will keep all my past bonus money, but I cannot make more bonus money in the next trials,' Correct answer for the Lose condition: 'I will lose all my bonus money, and I cannot get any more bonus payments for future trials.'), 'What does the piggy bank on the top right indicate?' (Correct answer: 'Your current bonus'). Participants continued to the main part of the experiment independent of their answers to these questions; however, those who failed the attention checks were excluded from data analysis.</p><p>In the main task, participants chose between the lotteries displayed in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 1 100</ref> times. After all trials were completed, we asked participants two further attention checks before they could finish the experiment: 'How many trials were there in the main part of the experiment?' (Correct answer: '100'), 'What were the possible bonus payments per trial in this study?' (Correct answer: 'Extinction, 0, +1, +10'; the other incorrect choice options also included 'extinction' to avoid any uncertainties about whether 'extinction'</p><p>counts as a bonus payment or not).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Results of Experiment 1 are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>. The optimal solution is represented in the top row of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> as a dashed line. In the Keep condition (blue), the optimal strategy is to switch from choosing the safe lottery to choosing the risky lottery after trial 56. In the Lose condition (black), the aggregate optimal strategy was to start with more risky choices and then reduce the proportion of risky choices throughout. The top row of where 100 trials indicate that the participant survived until the end of the experiment), as well as the survival times expected for participants following the optimal strategy (red bars). This shows that more participants went extinct in the Keep compared to the Lose condition. Again, this indicates sensitivity to the core task characteristics, as extinction is more costly in the Lose condition. Further, in the Keep condition, some participants went extinct earlier than implied by the optimal strategy, whereas in the Lose condition, the survival times tracked the optimal expectations remarkably well (see also <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure G1</ref> for a visualization of the optimal choice for the Lose condition as a function of trial number and money, and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure E1</ref> for a by-participant summary of the data).</p><p>To statistically test people's sensitivity to the different extinction conditions, we applied a logistic mixed effects model which predicts choosing the risky option as a function Note. The optimal solution for the Lose condition is based on simulating 5000 participants who follow the dynamic solution (Equations 4-7). The decision is executed based on a softmax decision function, as otherwise tiny differences in expected value in the first choices would lead to deterministic switching between the safe and risky options. We use a very low temperature (0.02) so that the solution is very similar to a deterministic decision rule. The same qualitative pattern arises for a range of temperature values. See also <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure G1</ref> for a visualisation of the optimal choices in the Lose condition as a function of trial number and current endowment.</p><p>of trial number (standardised by subtracting the midpoint and dividing by the range), trial number squared (to account for a potential U-shape), and condition (Keep vs. Lose), as well as an interaction between trial number, trial number squared, and condition. The optimal strategy implies a higher proportion of risky choices overall in the Keep condition.</p><p>We perform this comparison across conditions using the estimated average riskiness (i.e., the predicted riskiness based on the model's fixed effects for each trial and condition which is then averaged per condition; this measure gives equal weight to each trial to address the selective dropout of more risky participants). <ref type="bibr">5</ref> We find a significant difference in the estimated average riskiness between conditions, z = 6.33, p &lt; .001, with the estimated proportion of risky choices being 53%; 95% CI [41%, 65%] in the Keep condition, as opposed to 9%; 95% CI [5%, 14%] in the Lose condition. For comparison, if all participants had followed the optimal strategy, these proportions would be 44% and 10%.</p><p>Further, the optimal strategy implies increasing risky choices during the task for the Keep condition and decreasing risky choices for the Lose condition. In line with this, we found a significant interaction between trial number and condition, Overall, these results suggest that participants were sensitive to the differences between conditions in a way that was (qualitatively) consistent with the optimal strategy. 6</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational Modelling of Individual Level Choices</head><p>The aggregate pattern of results in the previous section likely arose from a mixture of different strategies on the level of individual participants. For example, it is plausible that the steady increase in the probability of choosing risky in the Keep condition (top-row of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>) is actually the result of different participants switching from choosing safe to choosing risky at different time points. In particular, participants can: 1) play the risky option with a constant probability throughout; 2) gradually increase or decrease the probability of playing the safe or risky option; or 3) switch between playing safe and playing risky. These strategies could be played in either a deterministic or probabilistic Appendix D.</p><p>6 There was also a significant interaction between trial number squared and condition, χ 2 (1) = 6.17, p = 0.013, although both conditions had a positive slope (Keep: b = 7.16, 95% CI [6.02, 8.30]; Lose: b = 4.67, 95% CI [3.09, 6.25], indicating a U-shape pattern in the data in addition to the linear slope). The model with random slopes for trial number and trial number squared did not converge successfully (max|grad| = 0.025, tol = 0.002) and the models including only one of these random effects also did not converge. We, therefore, used a random intercept-only model. The results are qualitatively the same and quantitatively very similar for the (non-converged) random slopes model. way (e.g., switching from always safe to always risky vs. switching from playing safe 90% of the time to playing risky 90% of the time).</p><p>Modelling the individual-level strategies confers several benefits. First, some of these strategies are qualitatively closer to the optimal solution than others. For example, in the Keep condition, the optimal solution would imply a sudden switch from safe to risky (rather than a constant increase or a reduction), whereas switching from risky to safe, or playing only risky, would clearly result in a lower expected payoff. Therefore, modelling individual-level strategies helps us understand to what extent participants recognized the optimal strategy and were only impeded by their ability to estimate the correct parameters (e.g., some participants may have recognized that a single switch strategy was optimal, but did not know where the optimal switch point was), versus if they did not even qualitatively recognize the optimal strategy. Second, the optimal strategies differ between conditions in systematic ways. For example, in the Keep condition, it is best to switch from playing safe to playing risky, whereas this strategy is less strongly implied in the Lose condition.</p><p>Therefore, modelling individual level strategies allows us to better understand differences between conditions and sensitivity to the type of extinction event. Third, we can use parameters from computational models to get a better understanding of specific elements of participants' behaviour. For example, comparing the model estimated switch point to the optimal switch point gives some evidence of whether participants are risk-averse or risk-seeking. In the next sections, we first outline the model specification and then illustrate the three benefits discussed here through application of the model to the experimental data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Specification</head><p>To describe the above strategies, we implemented a hierarchical (dependent) mixture model with three components: a safe state, in which participants would play mostly the safe choice; a risky state, in which participants would play mostly the risky choice; and a gradual state, which describes a gradual increase or decrease of the probability of playing risky throughout the experiment (implemented with logistic regression). The model allows participants to switch between the safe and risky states during the experiment to accommodate the different types of strategies outlined above (e.g., switching from safe to risky, or switching from risky to safe). However, participants can not switch away from or into the gradual state. Further, we constrained the states so that the probability of playing risky when in the risky state is always &gt; 0.8, and the probability of playing risky when in the safe state is always &lt; 0.2 (for a detailed model specification, including information on prior distributions, see Appendix F).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational Modelling Results</head><p>The model showed good convergence (allR &lt; 1.01, <ref type="bibr" target="#b91">Vehtari et al., 2021)</ref>   Note. Each panel illustrates one participant who is representative of one of the six strategies. The y-axis denotes the probability of a given state shown in a coloured line (red, blue, and orange lines), the probability of choosing risky given the regression state (black line), and the actual choices as circles (1 denoting a risky choice and 0 denoting a safe choice). When one strategy has a posterior probability of almost 100%, the lines for the other two strategies will overlay at the bottom of the plot (i.e., only one is visible).</p><p>6. Many Switches: Participants who switched between playing mostly safe and playing mostly risky multiple times during the experiment. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref> shows that the proportion of strategies employed by different participants varied between conditions, χ 2 = 18.24, p = .002. 7 This again indicates sensitivity to the core task characteristics and qualitative understanding of the optimal strategies in several ways. First, participants in the Keep condition switched from safe to risky more often than in the Lose condition, as implied by the optimal strategy. Second, participants in the Lose condition played the safe strategy considerably more often than participants in the Keep condition. This is in line with the optimal strategy: extinction is more costly in the Lose condition than in the Keep condition; consequently, in the Lose condition, playing fewer risky choices is optimal. Third, we also saw slightly more switches from risky to safe in the Lose condition than in the Keep condition. This again is what we would expect, given that reducing the proportion of risky choices throughout is in line with the optimal strategy in the Lose condition. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Keep Lose</head><p>In both conditions, the majority of participants are assigned to the gradual strategy  Note. Beta coefficients are only plotted for those participants that were assigned to the gradual strategy and switch points are only shown for those participants who were assigned to the Safe → Risky strategy.</p><p>Finally, for the Keep condition, we can compare the switch point estimated by the model to the optimal switch point to see whether those participants who understood that the optimal strategy involved a single switch from safe to risky tended to switch too late or too early ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5</ref>, Panel B). This analysis indicates that most people switched later than the optimal switch point, t(19) = 6.74, p &lt; .001, consistent with risk-aversion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Experiment 1 compared participants' behaviour to the optimal strategies in the Keep and Lose conditions of the EGT. We found that participants' aggregate behaviour was qualitatively in line with the optimal strategies, approximating the optimal solution in the Lose condition particularly well. Computational modelling of individual differences revealed a variety of different strategies employed by individual participants. Even though only a small proportion of participants followed the optimal strategy exactly (i.e., single switch or gradual), most participants used a strategy that at least qualitatively resembled the optimal approach (e.g., constant increase of p(risky) in the Keep condition).  <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Frederick et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Persson &amp; Tinghög, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Spiller, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Comparing the choice patterns in the Keep and Lose conditions of the EGT allows us to draw some inferences about how well participants can reason about opportunity costs versus 'direct' costs. In the Keep condition, a participant's endowment is not at stake, but their opportunity to keep playing in later trials is at stake (i.e., extinction leads to opportunity cost). Conversely, in the Reset condition, a participant's endowment is at stake, but their opportunity to continue playing in later trials is not at stake (i.e., extinction leads to 'direct' costs). In particular, we can compare the choices at the beginning of the task in the Keep condition (where extinction would lead to high opportunity cost but low direct cost) versus the end of the task in the Reset condition (where extinction would lead to a high 'direct' cost but low opportunity cost). If participants display opportunity cost neglect, we would expect them to play too risky at the beginning of the task in the Keep condition, but we would not expect them to play too risky at the end of the task in the Reset condition. Consequently, we might expect more people in the Reset condition to follow the optimal single switch strategy than in the Keep condition (where some people would start too risky).d</p><p>Overall, Experiment 2 has one main hypothesis and one research question.</p><p>• Sensitivity to Extinction Condition: In the Keep condition, participants will increase the proportion of risky choices as they proceed through the experiment, whereas in the Reset condition, they will reduce the proportion of risky choices (preregistered). 8</p><p>• Opportunity Cost: Are participants in the Reset condition more in line with the optimal policy than participants in the Keep condition? (not preregistered) 9</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Optimal Strategy for the Reset Condition</head><p>Because participants stand to lose all extant earnings in the Reset condition, here the optimal strategy depends on how lucky participants have been and how many earnings they have won (as in the Lose condition). The optimal strategy for the Reset condition therefore also follows a dynamic solution: It is the same as in the Lose condition, with the addition that the optimal solution now also factors in the possibility of 'resets' (i.e., an event where one loses one's endowment but can continue playing). Specifically, the expected value of a risky choice with N remaining trials corresponds to</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">E risky (N, Z) = p 1 × E(N − 1, Z + r 1 ) + p 2 × E(N − 1, Z + r 2 ) + p 3 × E(N − 1, 0).<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Apart from this modification, the optimal solution follows the Lose condition:</p><p>Equation 6 determines the expected value of a safe choice, the value when zero trials are left equals the endowment (Equation 5), and the choice between safe and risky is determined by whichever of the two options has higher expected value (Equation 7).</p><p>Even though the Reset condition can conceptually be viewed as a mirror version of the Keep condition (as we argue in the introduction of this experiment), the optimal solution in the Reset condition implies a larger proportion of risky choices than in the Keep condition for the same maximum trial number, probabilities and outcomes (67.6% vs.</p><p>44%). The reason for this is that risky trials in the Reset condition can be played both before and after an extinction event is experienced. Consider a participant in the Reset condition who starts risky and is reset to zero after 40 trials. This participant should then continue playing risky for much longer than 4 more trials (44 trials is the optimum in the Keep condition), as it requires multiple trials of risky choices in the Reset condition before the endowment becomes so large that it has a higher expected value to play safe rather than risky. 10</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Participants were paid £1.20 for the 8-minute study. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and Procedure</head><p>The materials and procedure were the same as in Experiment 1, except that we replaced the Lose condition with the Reset condition. In addition, the position of the risky and safe choices on the screen was counterbalanced between participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>As in Experiment 1, the differences in participants' choices across conditions were qualitatively in line with the predictions of the optimal solutions (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). During the experiment, the proportion of risky choices increased in the Keep condition and decreased in the Reset condition.</p><p>We again use a mixed effects model with the same fixed effects specification as in Note. The optimal solution for the Reset condition is based on simulating 5000 participants, which follow the dynamic solution (Equations 5-8). The decision is executed based on a softmax decision function, as otherwise tiny differences in expected value in the first choices would lead to deterministic switching between 0 and 1. We use a very low temperature (0.02) so that the solution is very similar to a deterministic decision rule. The same qualitative pattern arises for a range of temperature values. In the Reset condition, participants cannot drop out; therefore, the 'Alive at Trial' and 'Alive until End' lines are identical in this condition. Also see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure G2</ref> for a visualisation of the optimal strategy in the Reset condition as a function of current endowment and trial number.</p><p>with the predictions of the optimal strategies, we find a significant interaction between condition and trial number, χ 2 (1) = 1427.62, p &lt; .001, with a positive slope for trial number in the Keep condition, b = 3.06, 95%CI [2.70, 3.42], and a negative slope in the Reset condition, b = −4.51, 95%CI <ref type="bibr">[-4.74, -4.27]</ref>. Consistent with opportunity cost neglect, but contrary to the optimal strategy, we find a significant difference between the conditions in estimated average riskiness, z = 2.23, p = .026, with the estimated proportion of risky choices being 34% 95%CI [26%, 43%] in the Reset condition and 50% 95%CI [39%, 62%] in the Keep condition. 12</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational Modelling Results</head><p>We applied the same computational model as in Experiment to investigate participants' decision strategies on an individual level. The model again showed good convergence (allR &lt; 1.03). In the Keep condition, the optimal strategy still involves switching to playing risky after trial 56. In the Reset condition, the optimal strategy involves switching in the other direction (Safe → Risky); however, because the solution is dynamic, this switch does not always occur at the same trial. Instead, the timing of the optimal switch point varies between participants. If participants do not take opportunity cost into account, we would expect those in the Keep condition to start more risky than implied by the optimal strategy, and consequently fewer participants in this condition would follow the optimal strategy.</p><p>Participants' strategies differed considerably between conditions (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 7</ref>; χ 2 = 57.17, p &lt; .001). In line with the optimal solutions, participants were more likely to switch from risky to safe in the Reset condition, and more likely to switch from safe to risky in the Keep condition. In line with our hypothesis that participants find it easier to reason about 'direct' costs than opportunity costs, more participants followed the optimal strategy (switching from risky to safe) in the Reset condition than in the Keep condition (switching from safe to risky), χ 2 (1) = 4.80, p = .028.</p><p>A comparison of participants' switch points to optimal switch points suggests risk aversion in both conditions, as in Experiment 1. As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>, those in the Reset condition switched from choosing risky to safe earlier than the optimal solution suggested, t(38.85) = 3.81, p &lt; .001, whereas those in the Keep condition descriptively switched from safe to risky later than suggested, though this effect is not statistically significant, t(13) = 1.32, p = .208 (this test is based on only 14 participants, three of whom switched very early). As in Experiment 1, the slopes of those participants assigned to the gradual strategy showed the expected direction (negative in the Reset condition and mostly positive in the Keep condition, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure I1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In Experiment 2, we introduced the Reset condition, in which participants lose everything if they draw the extinction event, but can continue to play and acquire future gains. As in Experiment 1, participants demonstrated sensitivity to the core task characteristics and alignment between individual-level strategies and the optimal solution.</p><p>Furthermore, we also found that more participants recognized the optimal single switch strategy in the Reset than in the Keep condition. This suggests that it is possibly easier for participants to reason about 'real' losses (i.e., their endowment, as represented by money in Note. Histogram of switch points for those participants that followed a single switch strategy.</p><p>Red denotes the distribution of optimal switch points (in Reset) and the single optimal switch point in Keep.</p><p>the piggy bank) than opportunity costs (i.e., not being able to continue playing and earning money).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3: Testing Factors That Influence Decision Making About Extinction Risk</head><p>In the first two experiments, we introduced three different definitions of extinction or catastrophic risks (Keep, Lose, &amp; Reset) and tested the influence of opportunity cost neglect via comparison between the Keep and Reset conditions. Experiment 3 aims to further demonstrate the EGT's potential by varying features of the task within extinction conditions to test the influence of a variety of psychological factors on decision making under extinction risk. In particular, we explore the influence of loss chasing <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Gainsbury et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Lister et al., 2016)</ref>, opportunity cost neglect (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Frederick et al., 2009)</ref>, and scope insensitivity (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Desvousges et al., 1993)</ref> on decision making under extinction risk.</p><p>Our aim is to demonstrate the utility of the EGT for studying the influence of such phenomena. Consequently, the following does not provide a definitive account of these phenomena, but rather a first demonstration of how they can be investigated using the EGT.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3a: Endowment and Losses</head><p>In Experiment 3, we extended the Lose condition by introducing small losses and a starting endowment (Lose + Endowment condition). This new condition is identical to the Lose condition from Experiment 1, with the addition that participants now start with a small endowment of 50p and decide between a safe lottery that has a 50% chance of winning 1p and a 50% chance of losing 1p; and a risky lottery that has a 47.5% chance of winning 10p, a 47.5% chance of losing 1p, and a 5% chance of extinction. In other words, the 0p outcome from before is now replaced with a −1p outcome.</p><p>The Lose + Endowment condition has both practical and theoretical motivations.</p><p>From a practical perspective, in the real world, people usually do not start from zero but with a small endowment which they can lose. In addition, there is usually a possibility of small losses even under the safe option. For instance, someone who decides not to jaywalk may risk being late for a meeting. This would likely result in more risky choices because people often play more risky to recover from previous losses (a phenomenon termed 'loss chasing' in the literature on casino gambling; <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Gainsbury et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Lister et al., 2016)</ref>, especially when these losses have not yet been realised (i.e., paper losses or losses that have not yet been 'cashed out' in the eyes of the participant; <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Imas, 2016)</ref>. Losing money in the piggy bank in our task would likely constitute an unrealised loss as this money has not yet been awarded to the player.</p><p>This condition additionally allows us to probe in more detail why participants'</p><p>proportion of risky choices declined during the task and, consequently, approximated the optimal solution in the Lose condition remarkably well in Experiment 1 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Figure 4)</ref>. One possible explanation for this decline is that participants play less riskily the higher their endowment (i.e., the more money is displayed in the piggy bank), similar to the idea of opportunity cost neglect studied in the previous experiment. If this was indeed the case, we would expect fewer risky choices at the start of the Lose + Endowment condition, where there is a higher starting endowment, than in the normal Lose condition (note that this difference would not be affected by loss chasing, as participants have not yet experienced any losses at this point). The proportion of risky choices should, however, decline more slowly in the Lose + Endowment condition, as participants' endowment will not increase as quickly as in the normal Lose condition due to the −1p outcome.</p><p>Therefore, this study has two main research questions: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and Procedure</head><p>The normal Lose condition was the same as in Experiment 1. For the Lose + Endowment condition, we updated the instructions and lottery screens to reflect the possibility of small losses, and the piggy bank on the first page of the experiment started with a value of 50. As in Experiment 2, we counterbalanced the position of the options on the screen.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The overall proportion of risky choices was higher in the Lose + Endowment modification than in the original Lose condition <ref type="figure">(Figure 9</ref>, top row). Furthermore, as in Experiment 1, the proportion of people who survived until the end was similar to the optimal solution in the normal Lose condition; however, it was lower than the optimal solution in the Lose + Endowment condition <ref type="figure">(Figure 9</ref>, bottom row), indicating greater risk-seeking in the Lose + Endowment condition.</p><p>As in the previous experiments, we use a logistic mixed effects model with effects of condition, trial number, and trial number squared as well as interactions between condition and trial number and condition and trial number squared. This indicated a significant difference in estimated average riskiness, z = 2.67, p = 0.008, with the estimated proportion of risky choices being 7%, 95% CI [4%, 12%] in the normal Lose condition and 19%, 95% CI [12%, 30%] in the Lose + Endowment condition (for comparison, the optimal would be 10% in both conditions). Further, we find no evidence for an interaction between trial number and condition, χ 2 (1) = 0.12, p = 0.734, with a negative slope in the normal Lose condition, b = −1.22, 95% CI [-1.64, -0.79], and the Lose + Endowment condition, Note. The optimal solution is based on simulating 5000 participants who follow the dynamic solution (Equations 4-7). The decision is executed based on a softmax decision function, as otherwise tiny differences in expected value in the first choices would lead to deterministic switching between 0 and 1. We use a very low temperature (0.02) so that the solution is very similar to a deterministic decision rule. The same qualitative pattern arises for a range of temperature values. b = −1.12, 95% CI [-1.49, -0.75]. 15 These results are consistent with RQ1 (more risky choices after the introduction of Losses) but not RQ2 (faster decrease in risky choices in the normal Lose condition compared to the Lose + Endowment condition). <ref type="bibr">15</ref> We also do not find a significant interaction between trial number squared and condition (χ 2 (1) = 0.08, p = .779) with a positive slope in both conditions (Lose: b = 3.10, 95% CI [0.66, 5.55], Lose + Endowment: b = 2.61, 95% <ref type="bibr">CI [0.30,</ref><ref type="bibr">4.92]</ref>). The maximal model that converged includes only random slopes for trial number squared but not for trial number; a model with random slopes also for trial number failed to converge max|grad| = 0.12 (tol = 0.002) and led to the same pattern of statistical significance and quantitatively very similar results).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational Modelling Results</head><p>The model again showed good convergence (allR &lt; 1.01). Since the optimal strategy for both conditions was virtually the same in this experiment, we did not expect any major differences in terms of participants' assignment to the different strategies. In line with this, we found no evidence for differences in strategies between conditions, χ 2 = 3.50, p = .643 (see Appendix J for a visualisation of the computational modelling results for this experiment).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Overall, Experiment 3a indicates evidence for risk-seeking after (paper) losses, as participants' responses were more risk-seeking in the condition including small (paper) losses (Lose + Endowment) than in the condition without such losses (Lose). Further, we did not find evidence that participants' risky choices are mainly determined by the amount of money in the endowment rather than the expected value of the total game. Instead, risky choices decreased during the experiment at a similar rate for both the Lose + Endowment and normal Lose conditions. This suggests that factors other than the endowment (e.g., exploration in the beginning of the task) cause the reduction in risky choices during the experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3b: Varying the Maximum Number of Trials</head><p>In Experiment 3b, we turn to another important feature of our task: unlike most other gambling tasks, the maximum number of trials has considerable impact on the optimal strategies in the EGT. Intuitively, as the maximum number of trials decreases, less can be lost by drawing the extinction outcome, and consequently participants should choose the risky lottery more often. A similar line of reasoning also applies for real-world decisions under extinction risk: when more is at stake in terms of investment or future time lost from going extinct, it becomes more important to avoid extinction risk. However, research on choice bracketing <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Read et al., 2000)</ref> and scope insensitivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Kahneman et al., 1999)</ref> suggests that people may not be sufficiently sensitive to the value that could be lost in case of extinction.</p><p>Choice bracketing refers to whether people, when faced with a sequence or set of choices, are more likely to integrate across them ('broad bracketing') or to consider each of the choices in isolation ('narrow bracketing'). People tend to view individual choices in isolation rather than integrating across the set; that is, they exhibit narrow bracketing <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bland, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Rabin &amp; Weizsäcker, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Read et al., 2000)</ref>. If narrow bracketing also pertains to the EGT, it would imply insensitivity to the total number of choices. Scope insensitivity describes a similar phenomenon whereby people do not value a good in proportion to its scope or size <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Kahneman et al., 1999)</ref>. It has been shown in a variety of domains, such as contingent valuation judgment <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Baron &amp; Greene, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Desvousges et al., 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Kahneman &amp; Knetsch, 1992)</ref>, charitable giving <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">(Maier et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b90">Västfjäll &amp; Slovic, 2020)</ref>, or in the reaction to mass suffering and genocides <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Cameron &amp; Payne, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Dickert et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">Slovic &amp; Västfjäll, 2010)</ref>. Like narrow bracketing, scope insensitivity would suggest that people are not sufficiently sensitive to the amount of time that is lost by extinction (or the number of future choices), and would therefore likely lead to deviations from optimal decision making under extinction risk.</p><p>In Experiment 3b, we investigated how people adjust their choices as the maximum trial number changes. We decided on the maximum trial number in the different conditions based on three considerations. First, we chose maximum trial numbers that imply a sufficient difference in optimal strategies to maximise the chance of finding an effect of maximum trial number if it is present. Second, we tried to avoid extreme cases where the optimal solution implies always or never choosing the risky option. Third, we wanted to retain a maximum trial number of 100 in one of the two conditions to allow a direct replication of Experiment 1.</p><p>Based on these considerations, we chose 60 and 100 as our maximum trial numbers for comparison. As the maximum remaining trials should mostly have an effect in the Lose and Keep conditions, where earnings from a large number of future trials can be foregone upon extinction, this experiment focuses on those two conditions. This resulted in the following four groups, with the optimal number of risky choices indicated in brackets:</p><p>1. 60 maximum trials -Lose condition (optimal strategy ≈14/60 risky choices)</p><p>2. 100 maximum trials -Lose condition (optimal strategy ≈10/100 risky choices)</p><p>3. 60 maximum trials -Keep condition (optimal strategy 44/60 risky choices)</p><p>4. 100 maximum trials -Keep condition (optimal strategy 44/100 risky choices)</p><p>Even though the difference between 60 and 100 trials might appear small, the implied difference in the proportion of risky choices is substantial. In the Lose condition, participants should choose the risky option more than twice as often for 60 compared to 100 maximum trials (23% vs. 10% of the time), and in the Keep condition, a bit less than twice as often (73% vs. 44% of the time).</p><p>In addition to testing the effect of maximum trial number, Experiment 3b also aimed to replicate the sensitivity to the core task characteristics found in the previous experiments (in particular, Experiment 1, which compared the same conditions but only for 100 maximum trials).</p><p>Overall, Experiment 3b tested one prediction and one research question:</p><p>• Sensitivity to Extinction Condition: The proportion of risky choices in the Keep condition will be higher than in the Lose condition, and participants in the Keep condition will increase the proportion of risky choices more than those in the Lose condition (preregistered). 16</p><p>• Sensitivity to Maximum Number of Trials: Are participants playing more risky when the maximum number of trials is lower? 17</p><p>16 The preregistration is availabe at https://osf.io/wesxa.</p><p>17 For this analysis, we deviate from the preregistration with an analysis that maps better onto our theoretical question. We report the preregistered analysis in a footnote in the Results section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Participants were paid £1.20 to participate in an 8-minute study. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Design, Materials and Procedure</head><p>The method was the same as in Experiment 1 aside from the addition of the maximum trial number manipulation (60 vs. 100), and the counterbalancing of the position of the two lotteries (as in Experiments 2 &amp; 3a). This resulted in a 2 × 2 (Extinction Condition × Maximum Trials) between-participants design.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>As in Experiment 1, participants' choices differed between the Keep and Lose conditions. In line with the optimal strategies, participants made more risky choices at the end of the experiment in the Keep condition, whereas they made more risky choices at the Note. In the Keep condition, the 60-trial condition is overlaid on the 100-trial condition in such a way that they both show the same end point. Therefore, the lines for the optimal solutions exactly overlay for 60 vs. 100 Maximum Trials. The optimal solution for the Lose condition is based on simulating 5000 participants, which follow the dynamic solution (Equations 4-7). The decision is executed based on a softmax decision function, as otherwise tiny differences in expected value in the first choices would lead to deterministic switching between 0 and 1. We use a very low temperature (0.02) so that the solution is very similar to a deterministic decision rule. The same qualitative pattern arises for a range of temperature values.</p><p>beginning of the experiment in the Lose condition ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 10</ref>). Regarding the influence of Maximum Trials, we find that in the Keep condition, participants increased their risky choices a similar number of trials from the end of the experiment, regardless of whether they would see a maximum of 60 or 100 trials ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 10</ref>, left panel, in which the 60-trial condition has been plotted according to the distance from the final trial). In the Lose condition, participants played a similar proportion of risky choices in the first 60 trials, again regardless of whether they would see a maximum of 60 or 100 trials ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 10</ref>, right panel).</p><p>We tested for the effect of Extinction Condition and Maximum Trials using a logistic mixed effects model with effects of trial number, trial number squared, Extinction</p><p>Condition, Maximum Trials, their two-way interactions, and their three way interaction.</p><p>We standardised the trial number by subtracting the midpoint and dividing by the range. 18 .</p><p>We first test participants' sensitivity to the Extinction Condition. As predicted, and as in Experiment 1, we find a significant difference in the average estimated riskiness, The visual pattern from <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 10</ref> suggests that in the Keep condition, participants play the same proportion of risky choices with the same distance from the end of the experiment, whereas in the Lose condition, participants play the same proportion of risky choices at the same distance from the beginning of the experiment. We therefore report an analysis which compares the estimated average riskiness of the condition with 60 maximum trials to the estimated average riskiness in the first 60 trials (Lose) and the last 60 trials Keep condition, z = 0.64, p = .522, or in the Lose condition, z = 1.22, p = .169. 20</p><p>18 Specifically, for the 60-trial condition: trialN r stan = (trialN r − 30.5)/60 and the 100-trial condition: trialN r stan = (trialN r − 50.5)/100 (Note that the mean of trials ranging from 1 to 100 is 50.5 not 50).</p><p>19 This is based on a random intercepts only model. The non-converged maximal model (max|grad| = 0.31, tol = 0.002) leads to the same conclusions. Further, in this experiment, we preregistered only a linear trial number predictor. Removing the trial number squared term leads to the same conclusions.</p><p>20 If we also include the quadratic trial number term as in the other studies, we find the same results in terms of the statistical significance pattern. If we had instead tested the impact of trial number on the proportion of risky choices standardising the trial number by subtracting the midpoint of the range and dividing by the range, we would find evidence for an effect of Maximum Trial Number in the Lose condition, z = 2.66, p = .008, but not in the Keep condition, z = 0.05, p = 0.96. The reason is that this analysis does not compare matching trials but rather compares the estimated average riskiness across 60 trials in the 60-trial condition to the estimated average riskiness across 100 trials in the 100-trial condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational Modelling Results</head><p>The models again showed good convergence (allR &lt; 1.01). As in Experiment 1, we found a significant difference in strategies employed between Extinction Conditions, χ = 33.31, p &lt; .001. More participants followed the risky strategy and the safe to risky switch strategy in the Keep than in the Lose condition. We found no evidence for an impact of the Maximum Trial Number on the employed strategy (Lose:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">χ 2 = 7</formula><p>.39, p = .191, Keep: χ 2 = 3.18, p = .682; see Appendix K for visualisations of the strategies as a function of Extinction Condition and Maximum Trial Number).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Experiment 3b replicated the findings of Experiment 1, where participants responded to the differences between the extinction conditions in ways that are qualitatively in line with the optimal strategies (i.e., they increased risky choices towards the end of the experiment in the Keep but not in the Lose condition). Regarding the impact of the maximum trial number, our results suggest that in the Lose condition, participants' choices depended on the number of trials already played (independent of the maximum trial number), while in the Keep condition, their choices depended on the number of trials remaining (again independent of the maximum trial number). These results are consistent with the hypothesis that choice bracketing and scope insensitivity may lead people to be insensitive to the maximum trial number.</p><p>However, in addition to this insensitivity, participants' behaviour also showed a surprisingly adaptive element in the Keep condition, which diminishes deviation from optimality: they switched at a constant distance from the last trial (rather than, for instance, after a constant proportion of trials). Therefore, insensitivity to trial number only leads to a deviation from optimality in the Lose condition, where the number of risky choices changes as the number of trials reduces. Participants in this condition played somewhat too safely when the maximum trial number is reduced (since the optimal strategy implies more risky choices for fewer trials, red dotted line in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 10</ref>). In the Keep condition, insensitivity to trial number leads to well-calibrated behaviour, because people switch on average with the same distance from the end, a behaviour that is aligned with the optimal strategy (black line in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 10</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>In this paper, we aimed to advance the understanding of decisions involving irredeemable losses (extinction risks). We proposed several definitions for decision making under extinction risk or catastrophic risks: (1) Lose, where all endowment is wiped out upon extinction and the participant cannot earn any payoffs for trials after the extinction event;</p><p>(2) Keep, where the endowment is retained upon extinction, but the participant cannot earn any payoffs for trials after the extinction event; and (3) Reset, where the endowment is wiped out, but the participant can continue playing. We derived optimal strategies for these three definitions, and operationalised them in a new experimental paradigm, the Extinction Gambling Task (EGT).</p><p>Leveraging the EGT and computational modelling, we were able to obtain a nuanced understanding of people's choices in the task, which highlights both strengths and weaknesses in human decision making under extinction risk. On the positive side, the strategies employed by participants indicated a general qualitative understanding of the differences between extinction conditions and they were closer to the optimal solution than we had anticipated. However, our studies also indicate several deficits: consistent with opportunity cost neglect <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Frederick et al., 2009)</ref>, we found that people are more in line with the optimal strategy and less risk seeking when their endowment is at stake than when the opportunity to keep playing is at stake (Experiment 2); in line with research on loss chasing <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Gainsbury et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Lister et al., 2016)</ref>, we found that introducing losses leads to excessive risk taking (Experiment 3a); in line with research on scope insensitivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Desvousges et al., 1993)</ref> and choice bracketing <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">(Read et al., 2000)</ref>, we found that participants in the Lose condition are not appropriately sensitive to the maximum trial number (Experiment 3b).</p><p>A pertinent question concerns how the results from the 'small world' <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">(Savage, 1972,</ref> pp.82-91) of our task relate to decision making about extinction risk in the real world.</p><p>There are several real-world examples suggesting that people might be dealing with extinction risks rather poorly (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b99">Wiener, 2016)</ref>. For instance, despite the recent pandemic and the possibility of another more deadly pandemic during our lifetimes <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Marani et al., 2021)</ref>, governments' investment in pandemic preparedness is relatively small compared to other areas of spending <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Michael &amp; Mark, 2024)</ref>. Some of our findings are consistent with poor decision making about extinction risks. Specifically, people's choices in our task are affected by irrelevant factors (e.g., the introduction of losses and endowment in Experiment 3a), and sometimes participants are not sufficiently sensitive to other factors that should affect decision making (e.g., the total number of trials in the Lose condition of Experiment 3b). Some of the phenomena that we document have also been found in more realistic (albeit less controlled) settings (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Coleman et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Slovic &amp; Weber, 2013)</ref>. These observations suggest that the task may indeed be appropriate to isolate psychological factors that affect real-world decision making.</p><p>However, we do not only find limitations in human decision making. Participants were relatively good in terms of the qualitative strategies that they employed and they were sensitive to the differences between extinction conditions. To the extent that people make reasonably good decisions in our task but bad decisions in a corresponding real-world scenario, this would suggest shortcomings in real-world decisions other than an inability to be able to understand the nature of the risk. In the next paragraphs, we outline several modifications of our task that can be used to study additional processes, which have not yet been addressed in the current paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Extending the Extinction Gambling Task</head><p>The current version of the EGT constitutes a simple starting point with fixed risks and fixed payoff probabilities. There are various possible modifications to the structure of the task that can be straightforwardly extended from the current paradigm. For instance, it would be interesting to explore multiplicative rather than additive payoffs (e.g., one's wealth grows by a constant percentage every trial if one does not go extinct), variable risk over trials, or situations where an extinction event is possible for both lotteries. This may allow researchers to relate decision making about extinction risk to research in fields adjacent to psychology, particularly optimal foraging theory and economic theory. Optimal foraging theory discusses the trade-offs that animals or humans face when searching for food, including, for example, the risk of being attacked by predators <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(Stephens &amp; Krebs, 1986)</ref>. While this work has important differences from extinction risks as currently operationalised in our task, 21 it would be possible to modify the payoff functions to align our task more closely with the problems faced in optimal foraging. Another application area would be pension savings, where insurers suggests similar optimal strategies as in our</p><p>Reset condition (invest your assets risky when young and safe when older, AXA Pensions, 2024; Vanguard, 2021). Here, again, our task could be modified to more closely match the economic problem of saving for retirement by switching from an additive to a multiplicative reward structure.</p><p>Further, the EGT could be modified to test to what extent people follow through on their planned behaviour and how this affects decision making about extinction risks. In the experiments reported here, participants engaged with the EGT dynamically (i.e., they experienced the outcomes of their choices in each trial before making the decision for the next trial). We argue that this dynamic implementation mimics the way people make most decisions under extinction risk in the real world. Consequently, the EGT should be prone to the same biases that operate in real-world decision making under extinction risk, in particular, survivorship or observer selection effects (e.g., by being alive, one has never experienced a fatal event). Previous work has investigated decision making about extreme risks in static setups (i.e., all choices are specified in advance; <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Perfors &amp; Van Dam, 2018)</ref> or a combination of the two <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Crosetto &amp; Filippin, 2013)</ref>. Moving forward, it would be interesting to leverage the dynamic aspect of the EGT to study discrepancies between planned and on-the-spot actions, also known as dynamic inconsistencies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barkan &amp; Busemeyer, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Cubitt et al., 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Hotaling &amp; Kellen, 2022)</ref>.</p><p>Future work could also explore using the EGT as an individual difference measure.</p><p>The EGT as implemented in this paper was not designed for this purpose and we caution against directly using the task as individual difference measure, as the current one-shot setup with a single block and one extinction event likely has low reliability. Reliability could, however, be increased by chaining the current task multiple times in a row. The current duration of the main part of the task is around 6 minutes, so chaining the task would be feasible in terms of duration and participant engagement. However, creating a multi-block version would distort the nature of the extinction event, as it would not wipe out all earnings, but only the earnings for this block. It would also allow participants to learn from their experiences of extinction events. Both of these properties are in conflict with the definition of extinction events we outlined in the introduction. Future research investigating the potential differences between repeated and one-shot designs is therefore necessary before versions of the task that are suitable for measuring individual differences can be employed.</p><p>Many of the extinction risks that people are exposed to are collective rather than individual risks. For instance, when taking measures to mitigate climate change, if one country does not reduce its emissions but other countries do, this country could "free ride"</p><p>and enjoy the benefits of mitigated climate change without the cost of reducing its own emissions. Public goods tasks that study cooperation in the context of preserving resources for the next generation <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Hauser et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Jacquet et al., 2013)</ref> find that, absent any interventions to improve cooperation, defection is usually too high to preserve the public good. In order to test the collective decision making elements of extinction risks, we are currently working on adapting the task into a public goods game, where players play in groups of five. In this type of task, choosing the risky option constitutes a form of deflection as the player who plays risky accumulates all the payoffs from the risky decision themselves, but if they draw the extinction option, the whole group will go extinct. By comparing risk-taking in the individual level task to risk-taking in the collective task we can quantify to what extent non-optimal decision making about extinction risk is driven by cooperation problems. Additionally, a collective task will allow us to test interventions to improve collective decision making, such as median voting <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Hauser et al., 2014)</ref> or increased communication between participants. We see this potential to study both individual and collective decision making within the same paradigm as another strength of the EGT.</p><p>Another way in which the EGT could be modified to account for social interactions is by incorporating competition between different players, which would be similar to some existing dice games, and has been shown to affect risky choices in previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">(Schulze et al., 2015)</ref>. 22 A competitive setup would introduce additional game-theoretic elements as the optimal strategy in this type of game also depends on what the other players would choose. For example, if the other players are very risky and likely to go extinct, one can win easily by being safe; on the other hand, if the other players follow a safer strategy, it becomes optimal to play more risky to increase variance and have a chance of achieving a score that is higher than each of the other players. These competitive dynamics may play out in real-world decisions, such as when multiple companies compete to develop a potentially dangerous technology. The competitive setup would allow us to test to which extent risk-taking is increased compared to the individual level game and allow testing</p><p>22 For instance, in "Pass the Pigs", two players need to roll a set of two-pigs and are scored depending on which side the pig falls on. For a mathematical treatment, see https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ULhRLGzoXQ0.</p><p>interventions to reduce risk taking (e.g., communication and contracts between the players).</p><p>Finally, future work may benefit from adding realistic cover stories pertaining to specific risks to the EGT, or from combined experiments investigating the convergence between the EGT and vignette-or survey-based approaches to study decision making related to extreme risks <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Caviola et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Coleman et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">Schubert et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>While the EGT ensures a high degree of internal validity (as all optimal strategies and payoffs are known), these vignette-based approaches, while being less controlled, map more directly onto specific situations that the decision maker may face.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Closing Remarks</head><p>Until now, little psychological research had investigated decisions under extinction risk. This paper introduced the Extinction Gambling Task (EGT) as the first paradigm designed to study these decisions. While our findings offer valuable psychological insights, the primary aim of this work was to lay a robust foundation for future research in this area. Given the applied relevance of decisions under extinction risk, it is important to consider the usefulness of a laboratory task like the EGT. Some researchers have argued that much of decision-making research has had very limited real-world impact, due to a focus on designing tasks for testing formal models in artificial situations instead of studying "consequential decisions" <ref type="bibr" target="#b97">(Weiss &amp; Shanteau, 2021)</ref>. While it is important to study consequential decisions, we contend that meaningful laboratory tasks are a useful methodological tool to this end if they reflect relevant features of real-world decisions (for relevant discussions, see Fiedler, 2018; Garcia-Marques &amp; Ferreira, 2018). The EGT has been developed primarily with this goal in mind. The computational modelling conducted here was designed to understand the nuances in the observed choice data, rather than for testing different formal models. This enables researchers to observe individual choice strategies in scenarios with meaningful features that isolate key properties of decisions under extinction risk, such as repeated choice opportunities, wealth accumulation, and the possibility of irredeemable outcomes. Given how these features map onto real-world scenarios, we are optimistic about the EGT's potential for facilitating scientific insight. We hope that our work and the development of the EGT will help to bring much-needed research attention to a significant domain that has been largely ignored until now.</p><p>boxes selected and the probability of finding the bomb, similar to the BART. Second, in the BRET, participants either choose the number of boxes they wish to collect in advance, or observe boxes being collected sequentially (without making an active decision on each instance) until they decide to hit the stop button. Both of these versions are quite different from real-life decisions about extinction risks, such as jaywalking, which involve repeated choices between different options..</p><p>Because of the growing interest in human action in the face of extreme risks (for theoretical papers see e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Slovic &amp; Weber, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">Sundh, 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b95">Weber, 2006)</ref>, it is unsurprising that the need for experimental research has been recognised: <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Perfors and Van Dam (2018)</ref> proposed a new choice paradigm in which people make repeated choices under the risk of extreme black swan events that completely wipe out their accumulated earnings. Specifically, participants first executed a single choice and then (without feedback from their first choice) specified a policy according to which they would choose 2000 times in a row. The riskier lottery included a small-probability event that wiped out all previous earnings. However, these black swan events cannot be considered to be extinction events as defined in this paper (where losses are unrecoverable), given that participants were still able to accumulate future gains. Also, the initial commitment to a specific number of risky choices prevents any influence of experience and the investigation of how people frame and adjust their choices across trials (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bland, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Rabin &amp; Weizsäcker, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Read et al., 2000)</ref>. Further, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Elga et al. (2024)</ref> discuss resource allocation in the face of extinction risks;</p><p>however, their results mostly apply to scenarios where the risk is very high, and the number of repeated choices is low, which is different from the setup proposed in our paper and extinction risks in the real-world.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Details on Analytic Approach, False Positive Rate, and Power</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Accounting for Selection Effects</head><p>A key problem in our design are selection effects due to the extinction event. In other words, some participants drop out earlier than others, and this dropping out is related to the risk-seeking behaviour of participants and, consequently, the assigned extinction condition (as the condition affects risk-taking). To account for the attrition between conditions, we analysed the differences based on estimated marginal means, giving equal weight to each trial number. See below for the corresponding R code in Experiment 1.</p><p>Step 1: Fit Model res &lt;-afex::mixed(response01 ∼ (trialNr+trialNr2)*condition + (1|id), family = "binomial", method = "LRT", data = d_mixed, per_parameter = "trialNr")</p><p>Step 2: Create Contrasts</p><p>The code below first creates a grid with all possible combinations of condition, trialNr and trialNr squared. It then assigns orthogonal sum to one contrasts to all values were trial number is equal to trial number squared.</p><p>ems1 &lt;-emmeans::emmeans( res, c("condition", "trialNr", "trialNr2"), type = "link", at = list(trialNr = unique(d_mixed$trialNr), trialNr2 = unique(d_mixed$trialNr2)))) ems_ref &lt;-as.data.frame(ems1) contr &lt;-ifelse( (ems_ref$trialNrˆ2 == ems_ref$trialNr2) &amp; (ems_ref$condition == 0), -0.01, ifelse( (ems_ref$trialNrˆ2 == ems_ref$trialNr2) &amp; (ems_ref$condition == 1), 0.01, 0 ) )</p><p>Step 3: Test Condition Difference emmeans::contrast(ems1, list(m = contr), type = "response", infer = TRUE)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Estimating False Positive Rate and Power</head><p>To estimate the statistical power of our design and to verify that our analysis would indeed accurately capture the data generating fixed effects between conditions in the presence of selection effects, we conducted a simulation-based power analysis for mixed effects models. While the R script shared on the OSF page can easily be adapted for a variety of settings, this appendix focuses on the setting of an interaction between trial number and extinction condition as well as a main effect of extinction condition (similar to Experiment 1). We simulated from a trial number slope, which starts from a probability of selecting the risky option of .5 in the first trial, declining to .05 during the experiment in Condition A, while it increases from 0.05 to 0.5 in Condition B. Further, we added a main effect of condition, whereby condition B is shifted by 1 on the logit scale (in comparison, the condition effect found in Experiment 1 was 1.12). We simulated from models without this main effect to asses the false positive rate and from models with this main effect to asses the statistical power. The random intercepts and slopes of trial number were 1 on the logit scale. We assume a sample size of 80 per condition. We also compared the mixed effects model approach to simply t-testing the difference in the proportion of risky choices between conditions. We repeated each condition 1000 times. <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table C1</ref> summarises the results. The first two columns show the performance of both models when there is no selection. This indicates an almost nominal error rate, calibrated estimates and good power to detect an effect. The second two columns show what happens if we introduce selection effects (i.e., a chance of dropping out when choosing the risky option). The performance of the mixed effects models is similar, with slightly lower power due to the reduced number of trials. However, merely t-testing the difference in proportion between conditions dramatically increases the error rate as the selective dropout distorts the simple proportion estimates (unlike the mixed model, which can account for this through modelling the trial number effect) and actually has a higher chance of claiming an effect when there is none than when one is present (due to the different starting points form the fixed slope and the condition effects cancelling each other out under selection).</p><p>1263  Note. Av. Res. Scale = averaging on the response scale. In other words, the model predictions are obtained by extracting predictions on individual participant level on the response scale and then averaging them. Av. Logit Scale = averaging on the logit scale. In other words, the model predictions are obtained by extracting predictions on individual participant level on the logit scale, averaging them, and only then transforming them back to the response scale.</p><p>The tests and estimated proportion based on the emmeans package outlined in the main part of the manuscript would correspond to averaging responses on the logit scale and then transforming back to the response scale. To test the robustness of our results to the Jensen's inequality, we therefore also conducted a bootstrapped test based on the responses on the linear scale. To do so, we extrapolated the response scale predictions for each participant to 100 trials (to account for differential attrition) and then used a boostrapped test on those predictions to assess the condition differences. This procedure 1282 always lead to the same results as are presented in the main part of the manuscript.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix F Full Model Specification and Implementation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Full Model Specification</head><p>Our model had the three following response models that describe the probability of choosing risky (p(r)) either in terms of a constant probability or as a function of the current trial number (t):</p><p>P (r|safe st.) = logit(α s,i ) −1 (Safe State) × 0.2 (9) P (r|reg. st. = logit(α reg,i + β reg × N trial ) −1 (Logistic Regression State)</p><p>P (r|risky st.) = logit(α r,i ) −1 (Risky State) × 0.2 + 0.8</p><p>N trial denotes the trial number. We used a hierarchical implementation for α s , α reg , α r and β reg with random intercepts and random slopes. We did not directly model the covariation between intercepts and slopes, as this would increase the number of parameters that need to be estimated, considerably, impeding model convergence.</p><p>We then introduced a hidden Markov model component that allowed transitions between the safe and the risky states to model the switch points. However, as described above, we did not allow switches to and away from the regression state. The transition matrix below shows the structure of the model with the rows and columns being ordered as</p><p>(1) safe, (2) regression, (3) risky and ω denoting the probability of staying in the safe or risky state once in it:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">Γ i,j =         ω 0 (1 − ω) 0 1 0 (1 − ω) 0 ω        <label>(12)</label></formula><p>Finally, the starting probability for each state is denoted by the uniform three-dimensional simplex ρ with a separate ρ estimated for each participant (i.e., no hierarchical structure for ρ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Prior Distributions</head><p>For the grand mean and standard deviation on all α and β we always use a normal and half-normal distribution:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">µ ∼ normal(0,1)<label>(13)</label></formula><p>σ ∼ normal(0,1) +</p><p>For the transition probabilities simplex [ω, − ω] we use</p><p>[ω, 1 − ω] ∼ Dirichlet(30,1),</p><p>which is equivalent to ω ∼ beta(30,1),</p><p>and reflects the assumption that participants who are in a certain state (i.e., play mostly risky or mostly safe) are more likely to play risky or safe again on the next trial than to change the state. Finally, the initial state probability has the uniform prior ρ ∼ Dirichlet(1, 1, 1)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implementation</head><p>We implemented the model in cmdstan (version, 2.34.1 cite) and fitted it using cmdstanr (Version 0.6.1, cite). We ran each modelith 1000-3000 warmup iterations and Note. Histograms show the distribution of risky choices within ten trials. For example, panel "1" shows the distribution of average probabilities to make a risky choice across participants for trials 1 to 10. The top row indicates the data and the rows 2 and 3 below each show one random draw from the posterior predictive distribution.  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>also shows participants' choices as a function of trial number.Figure 2indicates that participants' choices differed between the two extinction conditions in a manner qualitatively consistent with the difference in the optimal solutions. Specifically, risky choices increased across trials in the Keep condition, but decreased across trials in the Lose condition. The top row ofFigure 2also suggests that choices were quantitatively closer to the optimal solution in the Lose condition than in the Keep condition.The bottom row ofFigure 2shows the survival times of participants (white bars,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2 Risky Choices and Survival Times in Experiment 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>χ 2 (1) = 580.99, p &lt; .001, with a positive marginal linear slope in the Keep condition b = 3.79, 95% CI [3.44, 4.14], and a negative marginal linear slope in the Lose condition b = −2.52, 95% CI [−2.99, −2.06].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and recovered the patterns in the data well (see Figures H1 and K3 for posterior predictives). The computational modelling allowed us to identify six types of individual strategies, as visualised in Figure 3: 1. Gradual: Participants who continuously increased or decreased their probability of playing risky during the experiment. 2. Constant Risky: Participants who mostly played the risky option, and their probability of choosing risky did not change during the experiment. 3. Constant Safe: Participants who mostly played the safe option, and their probability of choosing safe did not change during the experiment. 4. Risky → Safe: Participants who switched from playing mostly risky to playing mostly safe at a certain trial number. 5. Safe → Risky: Participants who switched from playing safe to playing mostly risky at a certain trial number.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Six Different Strategies Identified by the (Dependent) Mixture Model</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Proportion of Participants Allocated to Each of the Six Strategies in Experiment 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 4 ,</head><label>4</label><figDesc>which was implemented with logistic regression. Based on the optimal strategies, we would expect the regression to have a positive slope in the Keep condition and a negative slope in the Lose condition. Panel A ofFigure 5visualises the regression slopes of those participants who were assigned to the gradual strategy for the two conditions; all regression slopes are indeed negative in the Lose condition, and positive in the Keep condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5 (A</head><label>5</label><figDesc>A) Beta Coefficients for Both Conditions and (B) Switch Points for the Keep Condition in Experiment 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Experiment 1 (</head><label>1</label><figDesc>effects of condition, trial number, and trial number squared as well as the interactions of condition with trial number and with trial number squared).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Proportion of Participants Allocated to Each of the Six Strategies in Experiment 2 More Participants Switch from Safe to Risky in the Reset Condition than from Risky to Safe in the Keep Condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 8 Participants' Switch Points and Optimal Switch Points for Experiment 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 9 Risky Choices and Survival Times for Experiment 3a</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 10 Risky Choices for Each Maximum Trial Number and Extinction Condition for Experiment 3b</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>Keep) of the condition with 100 maximum trials. Consistent with the visual impression from Figure 10, this indicates no evidence for an effect of Maximum Trial Number in the</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure D1 Comparison of Model Predictions and Data for Experiment 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure G2 Heatmap Visualizing the Optimal Choice As a Function of Trial Number and Money for Experiment 2 -Reset Condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure H2 Model Predictions vs. Data in the Keep Condition (Exp. 1)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure K3 Switch Points in Comparison to the Optimal Switch Point in the Keep Condition</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Reset. In this condition, participants lose all their earnings when the extinction event occurs, but they can continue playing and accumulate new gains. In practical terms, Reset is a mirror version of the Keep condition implemented in Experiment 1 (in which participants can keep all the money they have earned, but cannot make new gains after extinction).The motivation for this new condition is twofold. First, it can be mapped onto real-world risk scenarios, where one loses everything but can recover (e.g., if one's house gets destroyed in a natural disaster). Second, it allows us to test the influence of opportunity cost neglect. Opportunity costs are foregone benefits that one would have incurred if one had chosen an alternative option. A key feature of extinction events is that they have high opportunity cost: all the benefits one could have incurred after the extinction event are now lost. Research shows that people tend to exhibit opportunity cost neglect; that is, they insufficiently take into account opportunity costs as compared to</figDesc><table><row><cell>Experiment 2: Introducing a Reset condition</cell></row><row><cell>In Experiment 2, we introduce a new experimental condition -</cell></row></table><note>'direct' costs</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>On top of that base payment, participants in the Reset condition earned an average bonus of £1.22 IQR [£0.79, £1.57] and in the Keep condition £1.03 IQR [£0.40, £1.35]. The study was approved by the ethics chair for UCL's Department of Experimental Psychology (EP/2021/005). Initially,197 participants completed the study. One participant indicated the wrong number of trials, six participants did not indicate correctly that the piggy bank in the top right corner of the screen indicates their current bonus earnings, six participants did not remember the possible payoffs in the experiment correctly, and 20 participants indicated that they did not understand the nature of the extinction event (some participants failed multiple of these checks). After these exclusions, we obtained a final sample of 173 participants. The mean age of participants was 40.60 years (sd = 12.15). Eighty-eight participants were</figDesc><table /><note>female and 85 male. The Reset condition had 77 participants and the Keep condition had 96 participants.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>On top of that base payment, participants in the normal Lose condition earned an average bonus of £0.44 IQR [£0.00, £0.60] and in the Lose + Endowment condition £0.41 IQR [£0.00, £0.63]. Initially, 210 participants signed up for the study. 14 Three participants failed the attention check asking them about the total number of trials, nine failed the check asking about the possible outcomes of the lotteries, 25 did not know what the extinction event indicated, and six did not know what the piggy bank indicated. Afterexcluding participants who failed these attention checks, we were left with a final sample of 147. The average age was 41.21 (sd = 14.73), participants were female and 75 were male. Seventy-six participants were in the normal Lose condition and 71 in the Lose +</figDesc><table><row><cell>Participants The study was approved by the ethics chair of UCL's Department of Experimental Psychology (EP/2021/005). Participants were paid £1.20 to participate in an 8-minute study. Endowment condition.</cell></row></table><note>1. Is overall risk-seeking increased in the Lose + Endowment condition compared to the normal Lose condition? (not preregistered) 2. Does the proportion of risky choices decline faster in the normal Lose condition than in the Lose + Endowment condition? (preregistered) 13</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>On top of that base payment, participants in the Lose condition earned an average bonus of £0.52 IQR [£0.00, £082] and in the Keep condition £0.77 IQR [£0.22, £1.19]. The study was approved by the ethics chair of UCL's Department of Experimental Psychology (EP/2021/005). Initially, 393 participants completed the study. We excluded participants based on four different comprehension/attention checks. Four participants indicated the wrong number of trials, 14 participants did not indicate correctly that the piggy bank in the top right corner indicates their current bonus earnings, 18 participants did not remember the possible payoffs in the experiment correctly, and 65 participants indicated that they did not understand the nature of the extinction event. Some participants failed multiple of these checks. After these exclusions, we obtained a final sample of 305 participants. The mean age of participants was 40.35 years (sd = 13.03). 158 participants were female and 147 male. 142 participants were in the Lose condition (85 in the 60-trial condition and 57 in the 100-trial condition) and 163 participants in the Keep condition (96 in the 60-trial condition and 67 in the 100-trial condition).</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table C1</head><label>C1</label><figDesc>Power analysis for mixed Model and t-testing proportions Estimates indicated with * are on linear probability scale rather than logodds scale.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Selection</cell><cell>No</cell><cell></cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>True condition difference (logit)</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Power mixed model</cell><cell cols="3">4.9% &gt;99.9% 5.2%</cell><cell>&gt;99.9%</cell></row><row><cell>Power difference between proportions</cell><cell cols="4">4.0% &gt;99.9% &gt;99.9% 72%</cell></row><row><cell>Estimate mixed model (logit)</cell><cell cols="2">0.00 0.98</cell><cell>0.00</cell><cell>1.01</cell></row><row><cell>Estimate mixed model (probability)</cell><cell cols="2">0.00* 0.20*</cell><cell>0.00*</cell><cell>0.20*</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Estimate difference between proportions 0.00* 0.16*</cell><cell>-0.22*</cell><cell>-0.10*</cell></row><row><cell>Note.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">We derive all of our optimal solutions on the basis of expected value in the main text. The qualitative patterns of the optimal solutions are very similar if one instead uses expected utility, although with somewhat fewer risky choices (see Appendix B).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">For comparison, this difference was 44% in Experiment 1. See Appendix C for details of this power analysis, which also demonstrates the robustness of our analytical approach to the selection effects introduced by the extinction event.3 Experiment 3b replicated the findings of Experiment 1 where lottery position was counterbalanced between participants.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Experiment 1: χ 2 (1) = 0.31, p = .575; Experiment 2: χ 2 (1) = 0.78, p = .376; Experiment 3a: χ 2 (1) = 0.96, p = .328; Experiment 3b: χ 2 (1) = 0.84, p = .361</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">For more details on our approach, including a simulation study to verify its accuracy, see Appendix C. For a visual comparison of model predictions and data and a robustness check for Jensen's inequality, see</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">We use a simulation-based chi-square test as the chi-square approximation may be incorrect given the number of observations per cell. Therefore, no degrees of freedom are provided.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8">The preregistration is available at https://osf.io/8uas6. In the preregistration, we use a previous terminology and refer to the Keep condition as the Keep-stop condition and the Reset condition as the Lose-continue condition.9  We initially preregistered that the main test for the role of opportunity cost neglect is whether there is a significant difference in the number of risky choices between both conditions. However, as this test was based on a static optimal policy for the Reset condition, this is no longer the most informative test (see section 'Optimal Strategy for the Reset Condition'). Following the preregistration with a test comparing the average riskiness between conditions, would come to the same conclusions.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">This difference in optimal strategy is also why the effect of opportunity cost neglect cannot be directly tested by comparing the proportion of risky choices, but instead requires computational modelling of the individual level strategies.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">The model also had by-participant random intercepts and initially by-participant random slopes for both trial number and trial number squared. As the maximal model did not converge (max|grad| = 0.33, tol = 0.002) and candidate models with random slopes for only trial number or trial number squared also did not converge, we report results from a reduced model with only by-participant random intercepts. The maximal model shows the same pattern of statistical significant effects as the reduced model.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="12">For the quadratic term, we also find a significant interaction effect, χ 2 (1) = 214.61, p &lt; .001, with a strong quadratic effect in the Keep condition (i.e., U-shaped effect, b = 9.87,95%CI [8.65, 11.09]) and a weak negative quadratic effect in the Reset condition (i.e., inverse U-shaped effect, b = -0.72, 95%CI [-1.51, 0.07]).</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="13">The preregistration is available at https://osf.io/8dntk. If this test was significant, we would follow up by testing the difference at the first trial, to delineate this from the influence of loss chasing.14 We excluded three participants that seemed to have signed up twice, due to a problem with the experimental software.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="21">In particular, in our task, a participant could play it completely safe and consequently not be exposed to any extinction risk, whereas a forager usually needs to expose themselves to some risk of predation as they would otherwise face an even larger risk of starvation.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A Existing Paradigms and Their Limitations</head><p>Among the most popular paradigms (for a recent overview, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Pedroni et al., 2017)</ref>, the Balloon Analogue Risk Task (BART) stands out as including something resembling an extinction event <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Lejuez et al., 2002</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Lejuez et al., , 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Pleskac, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Pleskac et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b94">Wallsten et al., 2005)</ref>. In the BART, participants' earnings increase each time they pump a balloon.</p><p>Each additional pump, however, risks bursting the balloon and earning nothing. While the bursting of the balloon might be viewed as an extinction event, the BART does not capture how people reason about the types of extinction risks described above. This is because the losses are limited to that specific balloon trial, leaving the earnings from pastand future -balloons unaffected. Also, the BART imposes a strong relationship between choice and event probabilities: the more you pump, the greater the chances that the balloon will pop at each subsequent pump. However, in many real-life examples, the frequency of committing a risky act does not necessarily increase the risk of extinction with each subsequent action. That is, ceteris paribus, your 20th jaywalk is not more risky than your 1st.</p><p>The Bomb Risk Elicitation Task (BRET, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Crosetto and Filippin, 2013)</ref> is another paradigm worth highlighting. In this task, participants decide how many boxes to collect out of 100. One of these boxes contains a bomb. Participants receive more earnings with each box they collect, but if they happen to collect the box containing the bomb, their earnings are reduced to zero. The BRET can be administered in a static and a dynamic version. In the static version, people specify the number of boxes to collect in advance. In the dynamic version, one box is collected every second until the participant presses the stop button. While the BRET has been shown to be a useful tool to study risky choices in general, it was not designed to apply to extinction risks and differs from decisions involving extinction risks in at least two respects. First, exactly one extinction outcome is among the set of options with certainty. This, again, results in a dependency between the number of Note. Payoffs, probabilities and trial number are the same as in Experiments 1 and 2. We used an exponential function to model the diminishing returns with an exponent of 0.66 based on <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Kellen et al. (2016)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix C Appendix D Mixed Model Predictions vs. Data for Experiment 1 and Jensen's Inequality</head><p>When estimating the proportion of choices in each group using a mixed-effects model, one concern is that averaging the individual responses on the logit scale and then transforming back to the probability scale leads to more extreme (i.e., further from .5) predictions than first transforming the individual responses to the response scale and then averaging them.</p><p>This is a special case of a property called Jensen's Inequality (see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jensen%27s_inequality). <ref type="figure">Figure D1</ref> illustrates this issue using the data from Experiment 1. We can see that the blue dots (representing predictions obtained by transforming back to the response scale before averaging) are consistently closer to .5 than the crosses (representing predictions obtained by averaging first and then transforming back to the response scale). Using the data visualisation here, the linear averaging is more similar to the data, as the plotted data is the proportion of risky choices in each trial, which also corresponds to averaging on the linear scale. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Probs C: Softmax Recursion</head><p>Note. Panel A shows a striking and surprising pattern, where there is no clear boundary between playing safe and risky choices. Panels B and C help us understand the reason for this by using a softmax transformation to derive choice probabilities based on the expected value of the two options with a very low temperature of 0.02. Panel B applies a softmax transformation to the determnistic recursive function, while Panel C uses a recursive softmax function directly. Comparing both of these panels to Panel A suggests that in a large area of the parameter space, there is almost no difference between playing safe and playing risky in terms of the dynamic solution. So the pattern of Panel A is the result of only tiny differences in EV between the safe and risky option that can flip based on how sequences of choices starting from a certain tile make it easier to reach the safe vs. risky state.  </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Axa Pensions</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>2024-11-04</idno>
		<title level="m">Lifecycle strategies</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Changing plans: Dynamic inconsistency and the effect of experience on the reference point</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Barkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/BF03212962</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03212962" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="547" to="554" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determinants of insensitivity to quantity in valuation of public goods: Contribution, warm glow, budget constraints, availability, and prominence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/1076-898X.2.2.107</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/1076-898X.2.2.107" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">107</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How many games are we playing? an experimental analysis of choice bracketing in games</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.socec.2019.03.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.03.011" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Escaping affect: How motivated emotion regulation creates insensitivity to mass suffering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cameron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1007850605129</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1007850605129" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Crying wolf: Warning about societal risks can be reputationally risky</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Caviola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Coleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Winter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/gtr53</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/gtr53" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anthropic shadow: Observation selection effects and human extinction risks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ćirković</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sandberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bostrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Risk Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1495" to="1506" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1539-6924.2010.01460.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1539-6924.2010.01460.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transforming or tinkering: The world remains unprepared for the next pandemic threat</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cárdenas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dybul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kazatchkine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Miliband</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nordström</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sudan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zedillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Obaid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Lancet</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How important is the end of humanity? lay people prioritize extinction prevention but not above all other societal issues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Coleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Caviola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Goodwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/qn7k5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/qn7k5" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The &quot;bomb&quot; risk elicitation task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Crosetto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Filippin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11166-013-9170-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11166-013-9170-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic choice and the common ratio effect: An experimental investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cubitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Starmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sugden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">450</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1362" to="1380" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1468-0297.00346</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1468-0297.00346" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring natural resource damages with contingent valuation: Tests of validity and reliability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Desvousges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Dunford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Boyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Contributions to Economic Analysis</title>
		<editor>B. H. Baltagi &amp; F. Moscore</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">220</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-0-444-81469-2.50009-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-444-81469-2.50009-2" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scope insensitivity: The limits of intuitive valuation of human lives in public policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dickert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jarmac.2014.09.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jarmac.2014.09.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Research in Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Optimization in Economic Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dixit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The meaning of life: A very short introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Eagleton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>OUP</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">People make suboptimal decisions about existential risks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Elga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-Q</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/384230783_People_" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to make psychology a genuine science of behavior: Comment on Dolinski&apos;s thoughtful paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Make_Suboptimal_Decisions_About_Existential_Risks Fiedler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">https://doi/10.5964/spb.v13i2.26079</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi/10.5964/spb.v13i2.26079" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opportunity cost neglect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Frederick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Novemsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nowlis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1086/599764</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1086/599764" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chasing losses in online poker and casino games: Characteristics and game play of internet gamblers at risk of disordered gambling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gainsbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Suhonen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Saastamoinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">217</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="220" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.psychres.2014.03.033</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2014.03.033" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is observing behaviour the best way to understand behaviour?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Garcia-Marques</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Ferreira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5964/spb.v13i2.26076</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5964/spb.v13i2.26076" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cooperating with the future</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Peysakhovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nowak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nature13530</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nature13530" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">511</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="220" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decisions from experience and the effect of rare events in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Barron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="534" to="539" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.0956-7976.2004.00715.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0956-7976.2004.00715.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic decision making: Empirical and theoretical directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hotaling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Psychology of learning and motivation</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="238" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The realization effect: Risk-taking after realized versus paper losses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Imas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2086" to="2109" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.20140386</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.20140386" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intra-and intergenerational discounting in the climate game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jacquet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hauert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Marotzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Röhl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nclimate2024</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nclimate2024" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Climate Change</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1025" to="1028" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valuing public goods: The purchase of moral satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Knetsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Environmental Economics and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0095-0696(92)90019-S</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0095-0696(92" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">90019</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic preferences or attitude expressions?: An analysis of dollar responses to public issues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ritov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schkade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Varian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="242" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1007835629236</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1007835629236" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory: An analysis of decisions under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">278</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How (in) variant are subjective representations of described and experienced risk and rewards? Cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pachur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2016.08.020</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2016.08.020" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="138" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The intuitive conceptualization and perception of variance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Konovalova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pachur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2021.104906</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2021.104906" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">217</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kuhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Nietzsches philosophie des europäischen nihilismus</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Nietsche&apos;s philosophy of european nihilism</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">De</forename><surname>Gruyter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How experimental methods shaped views on human competence and rationality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lejarraga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/bul0000324</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/bul0000324" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of the Balloon Analogue Risk Task (bart) as a predictor of adolescent real-world risk-taking behaviours</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lejuez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Aklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zvolensky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pedulla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Adolescence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="479" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/s0140-1971(03)00036-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-1971" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="44" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of a behavioral measure of risk taking: The Balloon Analogue Risk Task (BART)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lejuez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kahler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Richards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Ramsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stuart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Strong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037//1076-898x.8.2.75</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//1076-898x.8.2.75" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stochastic dominance: Investment decision making under uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Utility-weighted sampling in decisions from experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 2nd Multidisciplinary Conference on Reinforcement Learning and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overrepresentation of extreme events in decision making reflects rational use of cognitive resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000074</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000074" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gambling goals predict chasing behavior during slot machine play</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Nower</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wohl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Addictive behaviors</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="134" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.addbeh.2016.06.018</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addbeh.2016.06.018" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extreme outcomes sway risky decisions from experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="156" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.1792</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.1792" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Remembering the best and worst of times: Memories for extreme outcomes bias risky decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Madan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ludvig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-013-0542-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-013-0542-9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="636" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating (sequential) unit asking: An unsuccessful quest for scope sensitivity in willingness to donate judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Caviola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.2335</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bdm.2335" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introducing the extinction gambling task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Singmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://escholarship.org/uc/item/4qk2v6s2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intensity and frequency of extreme novel epidemics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Katul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Parolari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2105482118</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2105482118" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">35</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The world is not ready for the next pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Foreign Affairs</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Oxford handbook of epicurus and epicureanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mitsis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The risk elicitation puzzle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pedroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bruhin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dutilh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="803" to="809" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-017-0219-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-017-0219-x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human decision making in black swan situations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Perfors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Van Dam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://escholarship.org/uc/item/3p76280v" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opportunity cost neglect in public policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Persson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tinghög</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">170</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jebo.2019.12.012</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jebo.2019.12.012" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision making and learning while taking sequential risks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pleskac</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">167</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of an automatic response mode to improve the clinical utility of sequential risk-taking tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pleskac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Wallsten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lejuez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0014245</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0014245" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Narrow bracketing and dominated choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Weizsäcker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1257/aer.99.4.1508</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1257/aer.99.4.1508" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1508" to="1543" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Choice bracketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Keren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Laibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Elicitation of preferences</title>
		<editor>B. Fischhoff &amp; C. F. Manski</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="202" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Springer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-94-017-1406-8_7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-017-1406-8_7" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The probabilistic nature of preferential choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0013646</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0013646" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1446</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Being and nothingness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-P</forename><surname>Sartre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<publisher>Pocket Books</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The foundations of statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<publisher>Courier Corporation</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of existential Risk: Moral Judgments about Human extinction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Caviola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Faber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-019-50145-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-50145-9" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Of matchers and maximizers: How competition shapes choice under risk and uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Schulze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Van Ravenzwaaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogpsych.2015.03.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogpsych.2015.03.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="78" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the shortness of life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Seneca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<pubPlace>Penguin UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affect, moral intuition, and risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/1047840X.2010.521119</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/1047840X.2010.521119" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="398" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Perception of risk posed by extreme events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2293086" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opportunity cost neglect and consideration in the domain of time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Spiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="98" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.copsyc.2018.10.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.copsyc.2018.10.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Foraging theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Stephens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Krebs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<publisher>Princeton university press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human behavior in the context of low-probability high-impact events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sundh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Humanities and Social Sciences Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1057/s41599-024-03403-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-024-03403-9" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overreaction to fearsome risks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sunstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Zeckhauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10640-010-9449-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10640-010-9449-3" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Environmental and Resource Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="449" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The black swan: The impact of the highly improbable</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Taleb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Random house</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advances in prospect theory: Cumulative representation of uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF00122574</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00122574" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Vanguard&apos;s life-cycle investing model (vlcm): A general portfolio framework</title>
		<idno>2024-11-04</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A psychological perspective on charitable giving and monetary donations: The role of affect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Västfjäll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-45500-2_14</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-45500-2_14" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Psychological perspectives on financial decision making</title>
		<editor>T. Zaleskiewicz &amp; J. Traczyk</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="331" to="345" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P.-C</forename><surname>Bürkner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rank-normalization, folding, and localization: An improved R for assessing convergence of mcmc</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bayesian analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1214/20-BA1221</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1214/20-BA1221" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling behavior in a clinically diagnostic sequential risk-taking task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Wallsten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pleskac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lejuez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0033-295X.112.4.862</idno>
		<ptr target="https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0033-295X.112.4.862" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experience-based and description-based perceptions of long-term risk: Why global warming does not scare us (yet)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Climatic Change</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="120" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10584-006-9060-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10584-006-9060-3" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The futility of decision making research. Studies in History and Philosophy of Science Part A</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shanteau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.shpsa.2021.08.018</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.shpsa.2021.08.018" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The tragedy of the uncommons: On the politics of apocalypse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Wiener</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Global Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="80" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b100">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The anthropic principle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Cosmology</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="505" to="514" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b101">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A meta-analytic review of two modes of learning and the description-experience gap</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Wulff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mergenthaler-Canseco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>6000 sampling iterations. 23 . All Rhats were smaller 1.03. 24</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b102">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">For Experiments 1 and 3 we ran 3000 iterations, of which 1000 were warmup iterations using adapt delta = 0.95. For Experiment 2 we run 9000 iterations with 3000 warmup iterations using adapt delta = 0.98. For Experiment 4, we run 9000 iterations, 3000 warmup with adapt delta .95 in the Lose condition and adapt delta</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>98 in the Keep condition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b103">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">For Experiment 1 all Rhats were smaller 1.01, for Experiment 2 all Rhats were smaller 1.03, for Experiment 3a all Rhats were smaller 1.01, for Experiment 3b all Rhats were smaller than 1</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
