<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Breaking reality&apos;s constraints on motivated cognition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nina</forename><surname>Strohminger</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Melnikoff</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Legal Studies and Business Ethics The Wharton School</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology Northeastern University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Breaking reality&apos;s constraints on motivated cognition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:43+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>It is thought that wishful thinking is constrained by reality; people cannot believe the utterly implausible simply because they want to. Here, we call into question this basic principle of motivated cognition. We show that certain goals systematically bias judgments in spite of powerful countervailing evidence. This is more than a harmless delusion. Goals can lead to greater endorsement of patently absurd theories (Studies 5 &amp; 6), and impede performance in negotiations (Study 7). These effects only emerge for strong, highly motivated goals: when people have a relatively weak goal for an outcome, reality constrains bias. Not only does this require a revision to the theoretical record, it serves as a cautionary warning to managers and other decision-makers, who are susceptible to the biasing forces of motivation.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>To be a good trial lawyer you have to be a good hater.</p><p>-Janet Malcolm, The Journalist and the Murderer Forming accurate beliefs is both intrinsically desirable and important for effective decision-making, whether one is trying to optimize policy decisions, business strategy, or a negotiation outcome. It has long been known that goals can distort beliefs, but current theories assert that motivated bias disappears when certainty about the correct conclusion is high ("reality constraints"). This assumption applies to decision-makers across a variety of contexts. It suggests that when a manager advocates for a new business strategy, or when a lawyer advocates for their client, they can ignore the threat of motivated bias as long as ambiguity about the correct conclusion is low. In this paper we investigate whether this is true.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reality constraints on motivated cognition</head><p>When we want badly for something to be true, we often wind up believing it. But some ideas are so ridiculous that no amount of motivation can make us believe them. As much as I might want to fly by flapping my arms, this notion collapses beneath the weight of evidence to the contrary. Motivated cognition is constrained by reality.</p><p>This idea permeates the literature on motivated cognition. According to Kunda's foundational account, goals exert an influence on reasoning, but "this influence is limited by people's perceptions of reality and plausibility <ref type="bibr">" (1990, p. 491)</ref>. Motivated reasoning is after all a type of reasoning-this is what distinguishes it from pure fantasy or hallucination: "people are still responsive to reality and don't simply believe whatever they want to believe" <ref type="bibr">(Epley &amp; Gilovich, 2016, p. 127)</ref>. Motivated reasoning reliably loosens its grip on the psyche when people are confronted with strong arguments that undo the persuasive power of their preferred conclusion <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Petty &amp; Cacioppo, 1986)</ref>.</p><p>Festinger also observed that reality places a natural limitation on the flexibility of belief: "If a person is standing in the rain and rapidly getting soaked, he will almost certainly continue to have the cognition that it is raining no matter how strong the psychological pressures are to eliminate that cognition" <ref type="bibr">(1957, p. 21)</ref>. Motivational forces can only exert their power when evidence for an undesirable conclusion is shaky.</p><p>The balancing act between reality and biasing motives shows up repeatedly in models of motivated cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Pyszczynski &amp; Greenberg, 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Trope &amp; Liberman, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Kruglanski, 1996)</ref> including computational models <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Monroe &amp; Read, 2008)</ref>. Though these models vary in the exact mechanism for motivated cognition they propose, they are in agreement that motivated beliefs must maintain some contact with reality.</p><p>It is common to invoke reality constraints (or lack thereof) to explain motivated bias. In one such bias, experts underestimate the magnitude their own forecasting errors <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">(Tetlock &amp; Belkin, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Tetlock, 1998)</ref>. Tetlock chalks this up to "loose reality constraints that made it easy to wriggle out of disconfirmation" <ref type="bibr">(2003, p. 248)</ref>. In legal reasoning, the desire for coherence leads to the belief that complex or contradictory pieces of trial evidence are consistent with one another, particularly after a verdict has been reached <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Holyoak &amp; Simon, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Simon, 2004)</ref>. Simon argues that these coherence-based shifts are made possible by ambiguity: "Ambiguous variables are more amenable to change; unambiguous variables, such as indisputable facts and paramount principles are less likely to shift" <ref type="bibr">(2004, p. 548)</ref>. In formal models of this phenomenon, an ambiguous input is required in order for cognitive processes to be flexible towards coherence <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Holyoak &amp; Thagard, 1989)</ref>.</p><p>In another well-documented phenomenon, people romanticize the traits of their intimate partners <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Gagné &amp; Lydon, 2004)</ref>. This is an illusion, but not one that is "patently false": "individuals base their perceptions on a kernel of truth but construe this reality in the most positive light possible" <ref type="bibr">(Murray, 1999, p. 24)</ref>. In order to arrive at a desired conclusion, there cannot be a complete uncoupling with reality.</p><p>Self-serving biases are constrained by plausible deniability <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Dunning, 1999)</ref>. People lie, steal, and cheat more when it is easy to rationalize away that they are lying, stealing, or cheating <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Schweitzer &amp; Hsee, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Mazar, Amir, &amp; Ariely, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Gino, Norton, &amp; Weber, 2016)</ref>. People overestimate how much they possess desirable traits, but only when those traits leave ample room for interpretation. When the traits are tightly-defined, this bias is undone <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dunning, Meyerowitz, &amp; Holzberg, 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bélanger, Kruglanski, Chen, &amp; Orehek, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>The need for a plausible version of reality is reflected in the strategies people undertake when under the influence of motivated cognition. For instance, people choose to reduce cognitive dissonance by altering their interpretation of ambiguous information rather than clear-cut facts <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Festinger, 1957)</ref>. People apply a different standard to evidence that leads to conclusions they long for ("Can I believe this?") than those they dread ("Must I believe this?"; <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Gilovich, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ditto &amp; Lopez, 1992)</ref>. This asymmetrical skepticism only works, of course, if the evidence is ambiguous enough that doubt can be introduced. With sufficient evidence, the answer to "Must I believe this?" becomes Yes, and one must relinquish the preferred belief.</p><p>According to Tetlock, a reckoning with reality is what forces reasoners to resort to rationalization to begin with: looking away, reframing, searching for pretexts, invoking byzantine explanatory forces, and other cognitive gymnastics <ref type="bibr">(1998,</ref><ref type="bibr">2002)</ref>. If there is no way to construct a justification for the desired conclusion, the bias will fall apart. It is precisely because facing reality would alter the belief that people avoid it.</p><p>Little surprise, then, that when ambiguity is experimentally manipulated, motivated bias often disappears. Judgment is distorted by preferred but irrelevant information, but only when there is flexibility in whether that information could be considered relevant ("elastic justification"; <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Hsee, 1995</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Hsee, , 1996</ref>. This same pattern plays out in the confirmation bias and the polarization bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">(Tesser &amp; Cowan, 1977;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Trope &amp; Bassok, 1982)</ref>.</p><p>In short, reality constraints are ubiquitous within the study of motivated cognition. 1 As Kunda put it, "People believe what they want to believe only to the extent that reason permits" <ref type="bibr">(1990, p. 483</ref>).</p><p>Yet there is a puzzle here. If motivated cognition is tethered to reality, why do people hold so many beliefs that are not? The moon landing was faked. Ghosts haunt us from the dead. Horoscopes are real. Vaccines cause autism. Tupac is alive and well. If reality constrains wishful thinking, beliefs like these could only emerge from non-motivational factors, such as false information, mistakes of reasoning, and cognitive laziness <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Evans, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Stanovich, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Morewedge &amp; Kahneman, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Non-motivational factors no doubt account for many outlandish beliefs, and may even account for all of them. Another possibility, however, is that motivated cognition is less constrained by reality than has previously been supposed.</p><p>Speculation to this effect already dots the literature. The force field analysis theory of motivated cognition proposes that, while ambiguity does generally constrain the degree of bias, this may be a semi-permeable constraint <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Kruglanski et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Kruglanski, Jasko, &amp; Friston, 2020)</ref>. How else to explain cases where the bereaved deny the death of those they have lost, or partisan voters adopt ludicrous conspiracy theories about political candidates <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Kruglanski, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Helzer &amp; Dunning, 2012)</ref>? While these certainly seem like beliefs driven by motivated processes, they have yet to be established as such.</p><p>It is natural, also, to wonder: what exactly counts as a reality constraint? Prior work has provided minimal guidance. Reality constraints have been variously characterized as "indisputable facts and paramount principles" or "a kernel of truth" <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Murray, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr">Simon, 2004, loc. cit.)</ref>. 2 At times, the literature appeals to little more than intuitive examples: Festinger's man who has been soaked by the rain, or Tetlock's expert confronted with godlike access to counterfactuals. This gives some sense of what would count as a reality constraint, but is less helpful in delineating what degree of evidence these theories consider sufficient to thwart a goal.</p><p>This poses something of a problem for the researcher who wishes to test whether goals are necessarily reined in by reality constraints. Because we cannot rely on precise definitions to guide us, the best strategy will be to look at how reality constraints have been operationalized in previous studies, and use this as our benchmark in experimental design.</p><p>In one study on motivated prejudice, people high in anti-Black prejudice were less likely to recommend college admission to Black applicants-but only when the scholastic <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We note here, in passing, that reality constraints are not only a feature of biases that emerge due to motivational factors, but are critical to cognitive bias more generally. Convergent evidence across disparate research programs suggests that in order for cognitive bias to thrive, it needs the freedom afforded by uncertainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1974;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Kahneman, Slovic, &amp; Tversky, 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Darley &amp; Gross, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Camerer &amp; Weber, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Jacowitz &amp; Kahneman, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Hodson, Dovidio, &amp; Gaertner, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Oreskes &amp; Conway, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Lee &amp; Morewedge, 2022</ref>).</p><p>2 Reality constraints are easier to define when the independent variables are numeric. In the elastic justification literature, reality constraints are described as "specific, certain values (e.g. $500)" as opposed to numerical estimates that are "imprecise and open to multiple interpretations (e.g. ranges or sets of values)" <ref type="bibr">(Schweitzer &amp; Hsee, 2002, p. 185)</ref>. Most accounts of motivated reasoning, of course, seek to explain performance on topics that are not so easily quantified. information about applicants was ambiguous <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Hodson et al., 2002)</ref>. When this information was unambiguous, the biased admission decisions disappeared. In the low reality constraint (ambiguous) condition, the student had an excellent grade point average and a mediocre SAT score (or vice-versa). In the high reality constraint (unambiguous) condition, the student had an excellent grade point average and an excellent SAT score <ref type="bibr">(or neither)</ref>. Note that what counts as a reality constraint in this experiment is not exhaustive evidence that delivers perfect certainty about the applicant's academic qualifications. After all, maybe the applicant cheated, or forged their records, or made some extraordinarily lucky guesses on tested material. Instead, a reality constraint-one that is enough to eliminate motivated prejudice against Black college applicants-is one where the evidence is (i) consistent and (ii) considered to be highly diagnostic (in this case, of scholastic merit).</p><p>An example from legal psychology is also illustrative <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ask, Rebelius, &amp; Granhag, 2008)</ref>. Police trainees who were motivated to believe that the suspect was guilty believed that exonerating evidence was only valid when it was so strong it forced the undesirable conclusion (i.e. that the suspect was innocent). When the evidence was incriminating, all evidence-regardless of reliability-was considered valid for drawing the desired conclusion. In the low reality constraint condition, an eyewitness had chosen the suspect in a lineup (or chose someone other than the suspect). In the high reality constraint condition, blood on the suspect's jacket was tested, and showed either that the DNA matched the victim or did not match the victim. Police trainees are aware that eyewitness testimony can be unreliable, so they were able to rationalize away a lineup selection of someone other than the suspect. However, police trainees believe that DNA evidence is highly reliable, so it was difficult for them to discount it. As with <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Hodson et al. (2002)</ref>, the reality constraint does not absolutely prevent doubt. Not only is such evidence not encountered in real life, it is not possible even in principle-no evidence can eliminate every last filament of doubt. Rather, a reality constraint occurs when the evidence is highly diagnostic-so much so that the motivated bias disappears. To borrow a term from the legal world, we might say a reality constraint is one that eliminates reasonable doubt.</p><p>The question before us, then, is this: Are there types of motivational forces that can break reality constraints, as traditionally conceived? In what follows, we propose that certain types of goals-goals that are especially strong-are capable of circumventing reality constraints. We provide empirical support for this hypothesis across eight experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Can Strong Goals Break Reality Constraints?</head><p>When someone assumes the role of advocate, their personal beliefs tend to shift away from their original view and towards the side they are arguing for <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Janis &amp; King, 1954;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Festinger &amp; Carlsmith, 1959;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bem, 1967;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Higgins &amp; Rholes, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Thompson &amp; Loewenstein, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Loewenstein, Issacharoff, Camerer, &amp; Babcock, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Babcock, Loewenstein, Issacharoff, &amp; Camerer, 1995)</ref>. A feature of this "advocacy bias" is that the person need not act as advocate-merely having the goal to advocate for a given side is enough to elicit the bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Melnikoff &amp; Strohminger, 2020)</ref>. In this respect, the advocacy bias is a form of motivated cognition: the goal (in this case, of advocacy) shapes the belief.</p><p>Like other types of motivated cognition, the advocacy bias has not been described as impervious to reality constraints (and several authors have argued precisely the opposite; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Festinger &amp; Carlsmith, 1959;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bem, 1967;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Elliot &amp; Devine, 1994)</ref>. But emerging research suggests that advocacy goals are unusually strong-strong enough perhaps to break reality constraints.</p><p>In what sense are advocacy goals "strong"? A distinctive feature of advocacy is how easily it elicits goal-congruent belief change. As noted above, merely assigning someone to the role of advocate is enough to trigger a cascade of goal-consistent cognitive changes. What's more, advocacy goals are strong enough that they alter judgments that other goals do not <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Melnikoff &amp; Strohminger, 2020)</ref>, such as the otherwise universal and inflexible belief that, deep down, people are morally good <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">(Strohminger, Newman, &amp; Knobe, 2017)</ref>. In addition to ease of elicitation, advocacy goals display an unusual tenacity. Once the goal to advocate is in place, people have remarkably little control at overriding its biasing effects. Advocacy goals distort judgments even when participants are offered financial incentives to be unbiased; even when they are warned that their goal could bias them; even when they are allowed to recuse themselves if they feel they cannot be objective <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Engel &amp; Glöckner, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Melnikoff &amp; Strohminger, 2020)</ref>. The advocacy bias is observed even among professional lawyers, who face dire consequences for overestimating the strength of their cases <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Gross &amp; Syverud, 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Rachlinski, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Kiser, Asher, &amp; McShane, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Eigen &amp; Listokin, 2012</ref>), suggesting that this bias cannot be unlearned or trained away <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">(Stark &amp; Milyavsky, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Spamann, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Melnikoff &amp; Strohminger, 2020)</ref>.</p><p>In sum, advocacy goals appear to be unusually strong. They are unconstrained by several factors generally capable of preventing goals from changing beliefs-factors like the desire to avoid bias, the stability of existing beliefs, and professional training. Perhaps reality is another constraint that advocacy goals can break.</p><p>Prior research has recognized, at least informally, that goal strength could be a relevant dimension affecting whether a belief will be adopted <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Festinger, Riecken, &amp; Schacher, 1956;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Atkinson, 1957;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kunda, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Kruglanski et al., 2012)</ref>. What we are suggesting is that with a sufficiently strong goal, reality constraints will be abandoned.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview of Studies</head><p>All advocates-whether managers advocating for stakeholders, lawyers advocating for clients, or activists advocating policy change-form the goal to defend the interests of their chosen person, group, or cause. For our studies, we developed an "advocacy game" to capture this essential ingredient of advocacy goals. The game was also designed to be flexible in the sense that it can be used to induce the goal to advocate for virtually any position without requiring fundamental changes to the task structure.</p><p>In the advocacy game (Studies 1-4 and a pilot study) participants are assigned to the role of prosecuting attorney or defense attorney in the trial of a man who stands accused of a crime. At the beginning of the game, participants read a case file containing unambiguous evidence of the defendant's factual guilt. After giving participants a goal to advocate-either to defend or prosecute the defendant-we asked participants point blank: did he commit the crime? Prior work on motivated cognition makes a clear prediction: all participants, regardless of desired verdict, should agree that the defendant is guilty. We left very little room for doubt, so motivated cognition should have no ledge to perch on. Alternately, the strength of advocacy goals could make it unusually tenacious, even in the face of overwhelming evidence. If so, defense attorneys may arrive at the untenable belief that the defendant is innocent. Studies 1-4 test between these possibilities, and consistently show that advocacy goals (but not non-advocacy goals) flout reality constraints. Studies 5 and 6 generalize these findings to a different measure of bias, and Study 7 explores the consequences of advocacy goals for performance in negotiations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>All of our studies were powered to achieve at least an 80% chance of finding a significant effect (p &lt; 0.05 two-tailed) of small-to medium-size (odds ratio 1.25) based on a priori power analyses performed in G*Power <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Faul, Erdfelder, Buchner, &amp; Lang, 2009)</ref>. We also sought to maximize power by excluding inattentive participants (which reduces error variance) and by using a within-subject manipulation of question type. This within-subject manipulation allowed us to estimate random subject-level intercepts in our statistical models, which increases statistical power by factoring out subject-level variance.</p><p>In all studies, we recruited participants from the crowdsourcing platform Prolific, with the restriction that they must use a desktop computer to complete the survey, be located in the United States, and not have taken any previous study from our lab related to the advocacy bias (e.g. from <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Melnikoff &amp; Strohminger, 2020)</ref>. Each study included multiple attention checks that served as pre-registered bases for exclusion (for a complete list, see Online Appendix). For each study, our initial sample, and final sample after planned exclusions, are as follows: Study 1 included 534 participants before exclusions, and 480 after (Mdn age = 29, 46% female, 99.0% native English-speakers); Study 2 included 525 participants prior to exclusions, and 473 after (Mdn age = 30, 51% female, 99.6% native Englishspeakers); Study 3 included 529 participants before exclusions, and 464 after (Mdn age = 32, 41% female, 99.4% native English-speakers); Study 4 included 719 participants before exclusions, and 662 after (Mdn age = 30, 49% female, 99.8% native English-speakers); Study 5 included 598 participants before exclusions, and 556 after (Mdn age = 31, 46% female, 99.6% native English-speakers); Study 6 included 880 participants before exclusions, and 852 after (Mdn age = 32, 48% female, 99.4% native English-speakers); Study 7 included 820 participants before exclusions, and 734 after (Mdn age = 30, 53% female, 99.3% native Englishspeakers).</p><p>All studies were approved by the Institutional Review Board of the University of Pennsylvania, and all participants gave informed consent. Data, study materials, and preregistration information are available on the OSF repository at: https://osf.io/dz2b9/ ?view_only=b8f6a47b4f684ea792d63ba0116fb9e7 (blinded link for review).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pilot Study</head><p>Studies 1-7 were informed by a pilot study, the methods and results of which are provided in the Online Appendix. Briefly, our pilot study considered the possibility that when people have a goal to advocate, they abide by reality constraints, but have a harder time doing so. Perhaps under normal circumstances, ideas that are desirable but implausible are easy to reject, but when the goal to advocate is in place, such ideas become more alluring-just not alluring enough to be accepted as true. To test this idea, we gave participants a goal to defend or prosecute someone whose guilt was unambiguous. Then we asked "Is the defendant guilty?" and recorded mouse cursor trajectories as participants clicked a button labeled 'yes' or 'no'. We expected all participants to click 'yes,' but  <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Probability of responding correctly as a function of question ("Is Harrison guilty?" vs. control) and desired verdict. When a strong (advocacy) goal is induced (Pilot, Study 1, Study 2) there is bias: a greater probability of denying Harrison's guilt among participants who desired a not guilty verdict. Conversely, when a weak (non-advocacy) goal is induced (Study 3) there is no bias. *** indicates p &lt; 0.001, ns indicates p &gt; 0.05 (not significant). for trajectories to veer closer to 'no' among participants with a goal to defend, indicating greater difficulty in providing the correct response <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Stillman, Krajbich, &amp; Ferguson, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Melnikoff, Mann, Stillman, Shen, &amp; Ferguson, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>We observed the predicted pattern of mouse cursor trajectories. To our surprise, we also observed an effect on choices: participants with a goal to defend were likelier to deny the defendant's guilt outright ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). We were, frankly, not expecting to find an effect on choices. If the goal to defend led participants to believe that a clearly guilty man was innocent, this would challenge the long-held view that wishful thinking is reined in by strong countervailing evidence (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kunda, 1990)</ref>.</p><p>This pilot study, while intriguing, does not necessarily show that advocacy goals affect sincere beliefs. The responses could reflect experimenter demand, performative roleplaying (how a defense attorney 'ought' to respond), or error (accidentally pressing the tempting response). Ruling out these alternative explanations becomes the focus of the subsequent studies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Studies 1 and 2</head><p>Suppose a man has been accused of burgling a cache of jewels. Video footage surfaces of him in the act, providing conclusive evidence of his guilt. Under such circumstances, even a defense attorney (privately, at least) should be unable to deny what happened. Studies 1 and 2 were designed to test whether the advocacy bias is brought to heel by such incontrovertible evidence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Participants were instructed to evaluate, as accurately as possible, the case of a man who has been accused of a crime. They were given the evidence against the defendant, Harrison, who was caught on camera stealing from a jewelry store. In the pilot study, we found that this video evidence is considered highly dispositive of factual guilt: when asked the probability (scale 0-100%) that the man in the security footage was Harrison, the most common response was 100% (M = 97%). Because there was near-universal agreement that there was no doubt as to the defendant's guilt before goal activation, we conclude that this evidence meets the standard criterion for a 'reality constraint'. (For detailed study materials, see Online Appendix.)</p><p>After reading the case file, participants were asked to indicate whether Harrison stole the jewelry, yes or no (binary forced choice). Per our pre-registration, anyone who responded that Harrison did not steal the jewelry was excluded from further analysis.</p><p>Participants then received an advocacy goal: prosecute or defend Harrison at trial. To provide the strongest possible test of our hypothesis, our studies introduce all information about the defendant before inducing the goal to advocate. Beliefs formed prior to the activation of an advocacy goal should be less susceptible to bias than beliefs formed after the goal is in place <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Babcock et al., 1995)</ref>. This strategy also narrows the scope of how to interpret any effects we might observe. Our studies are designed to test how advocacy goals influence beliefs after belief-relevant information has already been encoded.</p><p>To ramp up goal activation, we informed participants that they would be able to finish the 20-minute study 10 minutes early if the jury votes in their favor. Participants were also walked through instructions for how the trial would proceed.</p><p>This was followed by a measure of bias. Participants answered a series of nine yesor-no questions including the target question: "Is Harrison guilty of theft?" For the eight control questions, five had a correct answer of "yes" (e.g., "Are emeralds green?") and three had a correct answer of "no" (e.g., "Is the Earth bigger than the sun?"). If the goal to advocate breaks reality's constraints on motivated cognition, defense attorneys should incorrectly respond to the target question (but not control questions) more frequently than prosecuting attorneys. To permit comparisons to our pilot study, we recorded mouse cursor trajectories, though they are no longer the focal point of the investigation.</p><p>In Study 1, we incentivized accuracy on the measure of bias to prevent participants from reporting anything other than their genuine beliefs. Before completing the measure, participants were told that in order to accomplish their advocacy goal, they must answer every question correctly-just one incorrect answer would result in their being removed from the role of advocate and losing the opportunity to end the survey 10 minutes early. Note that by telling participants that incorrect responses would result in their removal from the role of advocate, we eliminated conflict between the goal to advocate and the goal to answer correctly. For defense attorneys, indicating that Harrison is guilty furthered, rather than hindered, the goal to advocate on Harrison's behalf. Accordingly, defense attorneys have no reason whatsoever to deny Harrison's guilt.</p><p>We bolstered the accuracy incentive in Study 2 by clarifying in the most explicit terms possible that participants must answer accurately regardless of whether the answer is flattering or unflattering to the defendant. In both studies, participants indicated whether it was the case that answering even one question incorrectly would prevent them from ending the survey early. Any participant who failed this attention check was excluded from analysis.</p><p>We obtained additional insight into participants' beliefs by presenting a series of probes after the measure of bias. Participants indicated the extent to which they agreed or disagreed with the following statements: "I'm 100% certain that Harrison is guilty of theft" and "Given the evidence, I should be 100% certain that Harrison is guilty of theft." Responses were on a Likert scale from −3 ("Strongly disagree") to 3 ("Strongly agree"). Participants explained their answers on a free response item.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1 Results</head><p>. Consistent with the pilot study, we found an advocacy bias on participants' choices. There was a significant desired verdict (guilty vs. not guilty) × question type (critical vs. control) interaction (β = 1.92, SE = 0.56, z = 3.44, p &lt; 0.001) such that defense attorneys were likelier to answer 'no' than prosecuting attorneys on the critical trial (β = −2.32, SE = 0.32, z = −7.30, p &lt; 0.001) but not on control trials (β = −0.40, SE = 0.46, z = −0.85, p = 0.39; <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). On control trials, participants in both conditions answered correctly 99% of the time, but on the critical trial, 93% of prosecutors said that the defendant was guilty, compared to just 55% of defense attorneys. Advocacy goals distort explicit choices even when participants are fully incentivized for accuracy.</p><p>How do participants explain their responses? While prosecuting attorneys are close to ceiling in their certainty of the defendant's guilt (M = 2.69, SD = 0.93), defense attorneys are less certain (M = 0.46, SD = 2.56; β = −2.23, SE = 0.18, t = −12.6, p &lt; 0.001). Prosecuting attorneys also agree more strongly that they ought to believe the defendant's guilt given the evidence (M = 2.77, SD = 0.76) compared with defense attorneys (M = 0.78, SD = 2.57; β = −2.00, SE = 0.17, t = −11.5, p &lt; 0.001).</p><p>Poring through the free responses proves illuminating. For prosecuting attorneys, responses look overwhelmingly like this participant's: "Harrison was caught on video stealing the jewelry and it was verified that it was him." Defense attorneys responded quite differently. Here are some typical responses. "Harrison could have an identical twin brother, or it could've been a man that looked like him." (Twins were spontaneously mentioned five times in the sample.) "Videos can be doctored. We are in an age of Photoshop. While the evidence is compelling, it is not 100% guaranteed to be true." Another person explains: "There is a high chance that he has been mistakenly framed."</p><p>Not all participants offer a positive theory; many simply gesture towards slivers of doubt, and hang their hopes on that: "Until I find out more information about the case and more evidence against Harrison, I cannot personally believe he is guilty." Another: "I haven't seen the footage or know of any other evidence." Yet another: "While evidence can be incriminating, one video of him is not enough for me to be convinced that he was the culprit." Such responses made us wonder if we had simply not made the evidence irrefutable enough. We take up this matter in Study 7.</p><p>In short, defense attorneys indicate greater uncertainty about the defendant's guilt, and in many cases downright certainty in his innocence. The content of these doubts can be vague; but it can also be strikingly precise, springing to life with all the color and audacity of the best crackpot theories. Study 5 builds upon these insights to focus more directly on how advocacy goals influence uptake of dubious theories.</p><p>Study 2 Results. Despite the further inducements for accuracy in Study 2, participants once against displayed an advocacy bias in beliefs about guilt. There was a significant desired verdict × question type interaction (β = 1.30, SE = 0.63, z = 2.05, p = 0.04) such that defense attorneys were likelier to answer 'no' than prosecuting attorneys on the critical trial (β = 1.46, SE = 0.37, z = 3.99, p &lt; 0.001) but not on control trials (β = 0.16, SE = 0.53, z = 0.31, p = 0.76; <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). On control trials, participants in both conditions answered correctly 99% of the time, but on the critical trial, 94% of prosecutors said that Harrison was guilty, compared to just 79% of defense attorneys. Participants' explanations of their own beliefs shows the same pattern as in Study 1 and can be found in the data posted on the OSF repository at: https://osf.io/dz2b9/ ?view_only=b8f6a47b4f684ea792d63ba0116fb9e7.</p><p>It does appear that removing sources of experimenter demand reduced the degree of bias. The percent of defense attorneys who affirmed the defendant's guilt shifted from 43% (pilot study) to 55% (Study 1) to 79% in the present study. However, even with these strenuous efforts, the bias remains. We conclude that advocacy goals can induce false beliefs even when evidence against those beliefs is, by the standards otherwise employed by those same people, unassailable. After all our efforts, more than one in five defense attorneys still believe that a man caught on camera stealing jewelry did not commit the theft.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>One way we have established that our stimuli meet the criteria for 'reality constraints' is by showing that they induce near-complete certainty that the defendant is guilty when there is no goal in place. Another, complementary, way of demonstrating this would be to show that when our stimuli are evaluated under the influence of goals known to be subject to reality constraints (goals of the sort found in classic motivated cognition research), no bias emerges. Study 3 was designed to provide this assurance. It has nearly the same design as Study 2, but instead of inducing an advocacy goal, we induced a nonadvocacy goal-a goal to achieve a particular outcome, but not by advocating for that outcome.</p><p>Prior experimental demonstration of reality constraints uses non-advocacy goals, which may be weaker than advocacy goals. For instance, the non-advocacy goal to see oneself in the best light possible leads to biased self-assessments of one's traits as betterthan-average, but only when the trait can be interpreted in many ways ('intelligent') and not when the trait is unambiguous ('mathematical') <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dunning et al., 1989)</ref>. Introducing a financial incentive to interpret images in a certain way biases perceptions in a goalconsistent manner, but only when the images are visually ambiguous <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Leong, Hughes, Wang, &amp; Zaki, 2019</ref>). Thus we predict that, in our paradigm, if the evidence is truly unambiguous about guilt, a non-advocacy goal regarding the defendant's guilt should fail to bias beliefs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>To induce non-advocacy goals, we told participants that they would observe someone else defend or prosecute in the trial of Harrison. If their side won, they would finish the 20-minute survey 10 minutes early. By tying each verdict (guilty or not guilty) to the same incentive used in Studies 1 and 2 (earning twice as much money per hour), this procedure induces a goal-to end the survey early-the achievement of which required a particular verdict, but not advocating for a particular verdict <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Melnikoff &amp; Strohminger, 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Study 3 did not ask participants to explain their response regarding the defendant's guilt, as we predicted high agreement across conditions that he was guilty. Aside from these changes, the design of this study was identical to that of Study 2.</p><p>Results. For control trials, participants who wanted a guilty verdict gave the correct response 98% of the time, and those who desired a not guilty verdict gave the correct response 99% of the time. This high level of agreement is maintained on the critical trial. The same percentage of participants in both conditions (93%) reported that the defendant is guilty. A binomial linear mixed-effects regression reveals a nonsignificant interaction between desired verdict and trial type (β = 0.91, SE = 0.63, z = 1.44, p = 0.15) such that those who desired a favorable outcome for the defense side were just as likely to answer 'yes' as those who desired a favorable outcome for the prosecuting side on critical trials (β = −0.05, SE = 0.48, z = −0.10, p = 0.92) as well as on control trials (β = 0.86, SE = 0.47, z = 1.83, p = 0.07; <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). In short, when the experimental paradigm is adjusted to elicit a weaker non-advocacy goal rather than a stronger advocacy goal, the bias on judgment of guilt disappears. This provides further evidence that our stimuli eliminate reasonable doubt, which reins in motivated cognition when the goal is weak. (Refer to Studies 5-7 for a complementary demonstration, that this weak goal manipulation elicits motivated cognition when judgment parameters are ambiguous.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 4</head><p>One concern with the studies presented thus far is the critical dependent measure-"Is Harrison guilty?"-could be interpreted as a question about legal guilt, rather than factual guilt. Perhaps those who gave a "No" response intended to convey that Harrison has not been (or should not be) found guilty in a court of law, rather than he did not steal the jewelry. If that is what participants had in mind, then maybe reality constraints curb motivated cognition after all. To some extent, this concern is mitigated by participants' explanations from Studies 1 and 2-many of these responses expressly denied that Harrison was factually guilty. While these data are suggestive, they do not give the peace of mind we would prefer. Study 4 was designed to test whether advocacy goals bias beliefs that are explicitly about factual guilt.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Study 4 followed the same procedure as Study 2, with two key changes.</p><p>The advocacy goal was altered so that instead of ambiguously probing legal guilt, it clearly probed factual guilt. For instance, in the instructions for the "Attorney at Law" game, participants were told that "To disprove a piece of [exonerating / incriminating] evidence, you must type the phrase ['Stole the jewelry!' / 'Didn't steal the jewelry!'] as soon as you see Harrison." In Study 2, the directive for the game instructions had been to type the word 'GUILTY' (or 'INNOCENT').</p><p>The other change was to the critical dependent measure. This was changed from "Is Harrison guilty?" to "Did Harrison steal the jewelry?" Whereas the former could be interpreted as a question about whether Harrison was or should be found guilty, the latter question pertains only to factual guilt.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>In analyzing these data, we had to adopt a new statistical approach to test whether advocacy goals induced bias. This is because 100% of prosecuting attorneys correctly answered the critical question. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The complete absence of variance among prosecuting attorneys creates unreliable parameter estimates when goal is included as a predictor in a logistic regression model. To sidestep this problem, we first tested the effect of question type only among defense attorneys, and then tested whether, among defense attorneys, the rate of correct responding to the critical question was significantly less that 100% (i.e. the rate observed among prosecuting attorneys). Both analyses revealed that advocacy goals induced bias. Among defense attorneys, there was a significant effect of question type (β = 2.69, SE = 0.32, z = 8.51, p &lt;0.001) such that defense attorneys responded 'no' to the critical question 19% of the time compared to 2% for the control questions. Moreover, a binomial test revealed that the rate of correct responding to the critical question among defense attorneys was significantly less than 100% (95% CI = [75.2%, 85.7%], p &lt;0.001). Advocacy goals bias responses even on a question that clearly singles out factual guilt: "Did Harrison steal the jewelry?"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 5</head><p>In Study 5, we generalize the results of Studies 1-4 to a new measure of bias. Instead of asking people to affirm or deny an incontrovertible truth, we asked participants to rate the plausibility of patently absurd theories of the crime.</p><p>To confirm that the patently absurd theories were, in fact, patently absurd, we manipulated whether participants had a strong (advocacy) goal or a weak (non-advocacy) goal. We predicted that non-advocacy goals would fail to alter endorsement of these beliefs, whereas advocacy goals would break free of these reality constraints.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Similar to prior studies, participants received a description of Harrison, and the evidence that he robbed a jewelry store: He was caught on camera committing the crime.</p><p>Next, we implemented two between-subjects manipulations: desired verdict (guilty vs. not guilty) and goal strength (strong vs. weak). In the strong goal condition, we induced an advocacy goal, manipulating desired verdict as in Study 2. In the weak goal condition, we induced a non-advocacy goal, manipulating desired verdict as in Study 3.</p><p>After the manipulations, we presented (in randomized order) three highly improbable theories of the crime. To develop these materials, we drew from actual theories advanced by participants in Studies 1 and 2: that it was Harrison's identical twin in the video; that the video is a deepfake developed by a criminal organization who are framing him; that Harrison stole the jewelry but did so while sleepwalking and therefore is not responsible for the crime. Participants rated the probability that each theory was true, from 0% to 100%. We predicted that these absurd theories would be considered more plausible among participants who desired a not guilty verdict versus participants who desired a guilty verdict, but only in the advocacy goal condition.</p><p>If non-advocacy goals fail to alter beliefs about absurd theories, a question would arise: Are non-advocacy goals constrained by reality, or did our induction of non-advocacy goals fail? To address this, we included a manipulation check in the form of global evaluations of the defendant: how good of a person he is; how bad of a person he is; how warm of a person he is; how cold of a person he is. Participants responded to each question on a 7-point scale. Global evaluations are relatively unconstrained by the evidence at hand, so both types of goal should produce bias on this measure (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Melnikoff &amp; Strohminger, 2020)</ref>. The Online Appendix provides a detailed description of the procedure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Global evaluations of the defendant were computed by taking the mean of the two positive ratings (warmth, goodness) and subtracting the mean of the two negative ratings (coldness, badness). A linear regression model revealed a significant main effect of desired verdict (β = 0.56, SE = 0.20, t = 2.37, p = 0.02; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>), such that global evaluations were more positive among participant who wanted a not guilty verdict versus those who wanted a guilty verdict. Critically, this effect was not qualified by an interaction with goal strength (β = 0.22, SE = 0.40, t = 0.55, p = 0.58), confirming that both goals were equally capable of inducing motivated bias in the absence of reality constraints. Thus, if either goal fails to alter beliefs about absurd theories, this should be interpreted as related to how the goal handles reality constraints, rather than a failure of goal induction.</p><p>For endorsement of absurd theories, reality constraints reined in the effects of nonadvocacy goals, but failed to halt the effects of advocacy goals. There was a significant desired verdict × goal strength interaction (β = 6.52, SE = 2.77, t = 2.36, p = 0.019) such that those who desired a verdict of not guilty considered the absurd theories more plausible than those who desired a guilty verdict, but only when they had the strong goal of advocacy (β = 6.51, SE = 1.94, t = 3.35, p &lt; 0.001). When under the influence of the weaker non-advocacy goal, desired verdict had no effect (β = 0.01, SE = 1.97, t = 0.003, p &gt; 0.999; see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>).</p><p>Strong advocacy goals, but not weaker non-advocacy goals, increase the appeal of patently absurd theories. This dissociation was specific to evaluations of the implausible: global evaluations were equally biased by both kinds of goals. These findings demonstrate, with a novel dependent measure, that strong goals are capable of breaking reality constraints.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 6</head><p>We undertook Study 6 as a kind of dare. 4 So far, we have shown that advocacy goals-unlike other kinds of goals-can override reality constraints on motivated cognition. This manifests through denying an incontrovertible truth (i.e. denying the guilt of an obviously guilty man) and through heightened endorsement of absurd theories. This reinforces our characterization of advocacy as a strong goal, but are there limits on its strength? Is there a degree of unreality after which even the advocacy goal will be defeated? Study 6 represents our attempt to discover where that line is.</p><p>We do this by turning our absurd-o-meter up to 11. Rather than limit ourselves to natural explanations of a crime (e.g. the defendant has an identical twin brother) in this study we expand to the supernatural (e.g. the real culprit is a shapeshifting monster). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Study 6 was identical to Study 5 with three modifications. First, in Study 6, we included a within-subject manipulation of how absurd the exculpatory theories were. All participants rated the plausibility of two "moderately absurd" theories, which also appeared in Study 5, along with two newly-developed "extremely absurd" theories. The moderately absurd theories were (i) Harrison's identical twin stole the jewels and (ii) the incriminating video footage was faked by a criminal organization. The extremely absurd theories were (i) Harrison was abducted and cloned by aliens, and it was the clone who stole the jewelry, and (ii) a shapeshifting creature stole the jewelry after assuming Harrison's form (see Online Appendix for complete study materials). By testing for belief bias across degree of implausibility, we can better estimate just how much power strong advocacy goals have to evade reality constraints.</p><p>The second modification was to the response scale that measured the subjective plausibility of each theory. Our aim was to improve our ability to infer, in absolute terms, how probable participants considered each theory. Such inferences are difficult to draw from the slider scale used in Study 5, since slider scales make it easy to impose one's own, abstract meaning on the underlying number line, ignoring the units specified by the experimenter. For instance, participants could have used the physical distance of the slider from each endpoint to express, in non-probabilistic terms, how much they endorsed each theory. Though this does not impair our ability to infer the effect of goals on the subjective plausibility of absurd theories, it does makes it difficult to infer exactly how much credence participants gave to each theory in absolute terms. We addressed this in Study 6 by replacing the slider scale with a dropdown list of probabilities. Participants could indicate the probability of each theory being true by selecting one of 24 options: 0% (coded in the data as "1"), Greater than 0% but no greater than 1%, Greater than 1% but no greater than 5%, Greater than 5% but no greater than 10%, Greater than 10% but no greater than 15%, ..., Greater than 95% but less than 100%, 100% (coded in the data as "24"). We took responses on this scale to reflect, in absolute terms, the subjective probability of each theory.</p><p>The final change to Study 6 aimed to verify that participant responses to the exculpatory theories reflect actual beliefs rather than the insincere or mistaken endorsement of goal-consistent conclusions. Our strategy was to include a fifth exculpatory theory that was not just absurd, but mathematically impossible. After completing the responses regarding the first four (nomological) theories, participants received additional information about the case. We told participants that security footage of the heist shows that the thiefwhoever he is-has nine fingers. Upon examination, it is discovered that Harrison has two hands, one with four fingers and one with five fingers. We asked participants: "Given that Harrison has only two hands-one with only five fingers and one with only four fingerswhat is the probability that Harrison has 10 fingers?" Harrison having ten fingers would be exculpatory since the thief only has nine fingers, but it is not a conclusion that can be drawn given the premises. To deny that 4 + 5 = 9 requires overcoming not just evidence, but deductive logic itself. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> To accept the premise that Harrison has only two hands, one with four fingers and one with five fingers, is to accept that Harrison does not have ten fingers; any participant who reports that Harrison has a non-zero probability of possessing ten fingers must have misunderstood the question, rejected the premises, or responded insincerely. Thus, if participants are reporting their sincere beliefs and properly interpreting the questions in this experiment, their responses to the exculpatory but impossible theory should be unresponsive to our manipulations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Our pre-registered analysis plan for testing the effect of advocacy on the endorsement of absurd theories was to fit linear regression models. However, we had to abandon this plan after observing that the residuals of these models strongly violated the assumption of normality. This was a symptom of extreme skewness in the outcome measure: the median response on our 24-point scale ranged from 1 to 3, and fewer than 20% of ratings were greater than 4.</p><p>We addressed this issue in two steps. We collapsed all ratings of 5 and above on the endorsement measure (that is, corresponding to an estimate of at least a 10% chance <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> Frequencies of subjective probability ratings for exculpatory (but absurd) theories of a crime, divided across condition in Study 6. The rightmost column (in bold) shows the total amount of nonzero credence given to each theory broken down by condition, along with whether the two compared conditions are statistically distinct. Across conditions, only strong goals altered the subjective plausibility of absurd theories. that the theory was true; this represents 17.7% of all responses) into a single category. This transformed our 24-point measure of subjective plausibility into a 5-point measure, where a rating of 1 = 0%, 2 = (0%, 1%], 3 = (1%, 5%], 4 = (5%, 10%], and 5 = (10%, 100%]. The decision to bin our measure into five categories was intended to reduce skewness while maximizing the measure's sensitivity; the boundaries and number of categories were determined before running further analyses. We used this transformed measure of subjective plausibility as the outcome variable in ordinal regressions, which, unlike linear regressions, make no assumptions about normality. Our first ordinal model regressed the subjective plausibility of the four absurd theories on goal strength (high vs. low), desired verdict (guilty vs. not guilty), absurdity (moderate vs. extreme), and their interaction terms. The model also included random intercepts for participant and individual theory.</p><p>The results confirmed that our manipulation of absurdity was successful. Extremely absurd theories were considered less plausible than moderately absurd theories (β = 5.86, SE = 0.17, z = 33.64, p &lt; 0.001). This is not a subtle effect. The extremely absurd theories were assigned a 0% chance of being true 78% of the time, whereas the moderately absurd theories were assigned a 0% chance of being true just 7% of the time. Conversely, extremely absurd theories were assigned an at least 10% chance of being true 3% of the time, whereas moderately absurd theories were assigned an at least 10% chance of being true 32% of the time (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> for a full breakdown of plausibility ratings).</p><p>Our model revealed that strong goals modulated the subjective plausibility of exculpatory theories regardless of how absurd they were. We found a significant interaction between goal strength and desired verdict (β = 0.82, SE = 0.36, z = 2.29, p = 0.022). In the strong goal condition, participants who desired a not guilty verdict considered the exculpatory theories significantly more plausible than participants who desired a guilty verdict (β = 0.51, SE = 0.26, z = 1.99, p = 0.046). Conversely, in the weak goal condition, desired verdict had no effect on subjective plausibility (β = −0.32, SE = 0.25, z = 1.25, p = 0.212). The goal strength × desired verdict interaction was not moderated by absurdity (β = 0.28, SE = 0.37, z = 0.74, p = 0.46). It was significant both for moderately absurd theories (β = 0.75, SE = 0.38, z = 1.97, p = 0.049) and extremely absurd theories (β = 1.02, SE = 0.44, z = 2.32, p = 0.021). In other words, people who had the strong goal to advocate for the defendant were more likely to give credence to absurd theories-and this was just as true for theories that implicated monsters as those that implicated the mob.</p><p>As a sanity check (which felt more than usually warranted after such results), we analyzed responses to the mathematically impossible theory. Perhaps responses to the nomological theories were insincere or otherwise not indicative of belief. If so, strong goals should lead to goal-consistent responding to all questions, even if that means endorsing a mathematically impossible theory. We tested this possibility by regressing the transformed ratings of the plausibility of the nonsensical theory on goal strength, desired outcome, and their interaction term. The interaction was not significant (β = 0.42, SE = 0.44, z = 0.94, p = 0.348). Desired outcome had no effect on plausibility ratings regardless of whether the goal was strong (β = 0.14, SE = 0.31, z = 0.47, p = 0.639) or weak (β = 0.56, SE = 0.31, z = 1.79, p = 0.078). Across conditions, nearly all participants reported that the mathematically impossible theory had a 0% chance of being true. Because strong goals did not generate endorsement for mathematically impossible theories, we can conclude that the increased endorsement of absurd (but nomological) theories reflects actual belief.</p><p>Strong goals break all manner of reality constraints, pushing even into the supernatural realm. 6 This study also replicates the findings in Study 5 with a novel measurement scale, thereby reinforcing our conclusion that strong goals can increase endorsement for the most far-fetched of beliefs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 7</head><p>We are left with the question of whether the ability of strong goals to circumvent reality constraints has practical consequences for those who advocate. We take up this question in our final study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Participants first read a case about a person-either a man or woman-accused of armed robbery. The evidence was either incriminating or exonerating. The incriminating evidence was damning to the point of redundancy: not just video footage of the accused in the act (as in previous studies), but the defendant's DNA at the scene of the crime, no alibi, and a clear motive. The 'exonerating' evidence was not, in this study design, intended to be exonerating. It was meant to be ambiguous, but the results of a manipulation check showed that participants found it unambiguously exonerating (see Online Appendix for analyses). Accordingly, both types of evidence should eliminate the biasing effect of weak (non-advocacy) goals, whereas neither type of evidence should eliminate the biasing effect of strong (advocacy) goals.</p><p>We manipulated desired outcome (pro-defendant vs. anti-defendant) and goal strength (strong vs. weak) as in Study 5, with one exception: Instead of incentivizing participants with the possibility of finishing early, we incentivized them with the possibility of winning a $0.60 bonus conditional on the jury reaching the desired verdict. Then came a dependent measure: participants guessed the probability of the jury finding the defendant guilty.</p><p>Next, participants reported their reservation point in a plea negotiation-our other primary dependent measure. We explained that the defendant would be sentenced to 15 years in prison if found guilty at trial, but could receive a more lenient sentence in exchange for pleading guilty. We asked participants to suppose the defendant was interested in a plea deal. In the advocacy condition, participants reported the worst offer they would accept (in the anti-defendant condition) or the worst offer they would advise the defendant to accept (in the pro-defendant condition). In the non-advocacy condition, participants reported the worst offer the prosecution should accept (in the anti-defendant condition), or the worst offer the defense attorney should advise the defendant to accept (in the prodefendant condition). The response scale ranged from one to fourteen years. Answers constituted participants' reservation points--the least attractive offers they found acceptable. A deal can be made if, and only if, reservation points overlap. According to standard models of motivated cognition, unambiguous evidence should make it easy to strike a deal by leaving little room for bias to creep into the negotiation. However, if advocacy goals circumvent reality constraints, they should thwart negotiations even when the evidence is unambiguous.</p><p>Afterwards, participants read a second case about another defendant accused of armed robbery. This person was the opposite gender of the first defendant; whether the first defendant was a man or a woman was randomized between subjects. The second case had incriminating evidence if the first case had exonerating evidence, and vice versa. Thus, all participants saw both types of evidence. The other conditions-desired outcome and goal strength-were held constant within subjects. Participants answered all the same questions about both cases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Contrary to our expectations, the subjective probability of a guilty verdict was biased by desired outcome regardless of goal strength. Participants who desired a guilty verdict deemed a guilty verdict more probable than participants who desired a not guilty verdict in both the advocacy condition (β = 1.25, SE = 0.25, t = 4.94, p &lt; 0.001) and non-advocacy condition (β = 0.49, SE = 0.25, t = 1.98, p = 0.048)-though the effect was significantly stronger in the advocacy condition (β = 0.75, SE = 0.35, t = 2.12, p = 0.03).</p><p>This finding confirms that our induction of non-advocacy goals was successful. Still, it seems to run contrary to our claim that advocacy goals are especially prone to circumventing reality constraints. There is, however, an alternative account: It is possible that regardless of how clear the evidence is, there always exists a range of plausible beliefs regarding the subjective probability of a guilty verdict. After all, juries are notoriously *** ns </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Guilty</head><p>Not Guilty <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. The worst acceptable offer (reservation point) for a defendant's plea bargain, depending on goal strength and desired verdict in Study 7. Bias emerges only among those with an advocacy goal. Bars indicate 95% confidence intervals derived from the reported linear regression models. *** indicates p &lt; 0.001, ns = not significant.</p><p>unpredictable. On this account, a dependent measure with less "wiggle room" should reveal the predicted dissociation between advocacy goals and non-advocacy goals. This is precisely what we find in our analyses of plea negotiations. We found a significant desired verdict × goal strength interaction on reservation points (β = 1.53, SE = 0.37, t = 4.14, p &lt; 0.001). This interaction was not qualified by type of evidence (exonerating vs. incriminating; β = 0.11, SE = 0.19, t = 0.57, p = 0.57). As expected, there was no bias in the non-advocacy (weak goal) condition. That is, desired verdict had no effect on reservation point (β = −.36, SE = 0.26, t = 1.39, p = 0.16), indicating that participants agreed on what a fair deal would be regardless of whether they were proor anti-defendant. By contrast, there was bias in the strong goal condition: the reservation point was significantly higher when the desired verdict was guilty versus not guilty (β = −1.16, SE = 0.26, t = −4.44, p &lt; 0.001; <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>). This means that, on average, participants in the strong goal condition disagreed on what constituted a fair deal.</p><p>Our data also allow us to determine whether plea negotiations are more likely to fail when someone has an advocacy goal. To run this analysis, we began by creating negotiation dyads. Each dyad consisted of two reservation points: one from a participant *** 40% 60% 80%</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Strong</head><p>Weak</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Goal Strength Probability of Reaching a Plea Deal</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Evidence Type</head><p>Damning Exonerating <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. Probability of a negotiation dyad striking a plea deal as a function goal strength (strong vs. weak) and evidence type (exonerating vs. incriminating) in Study 7. Densities were derived from 10,000 bootstrapped samples in which negotiation dyads were randomly selected with replacement.</p><p>who desired a guilty verdict, and one from a participant who desired a not guilty verdict. We created all possible negotiation dyads that met the following criteria: (1) both reservation points came from participants who desired the same type of goal (advocacy or non-advocacy), and (2) both reservation points were based on the same type of evidence (damning or exonerating). For each dyad, we assumed a deal would have been struck if the reservation points overlapped. Then, we randomly sampled, with replacement, from the entire set of negotiation dyads, and recorded the percentage of the sampled dyads that would have reached a deal within each condition. We repeated this process 10,000 times to create a bootstrap distribution.</p><p>On average, a deal would have been struck 60% of the time in the weak goal condition, and just 45% of the time in the strong goal condition. The 99% confidence interval (CI) of the mean difference (mean ∆ = 14.89) did not contain zero (99% CI = [.04, .26]), indicating a significant effect at p &lt; 0.01. We also found a significant effect of evidence type, such that deals would have been struck more often when the evidence was damning (M = 57%) versus exonerating (M = 48%) (mean ∆ = 9.1; 99% CI = [.02, .17]). The goal strength × evidence type interaction was not significant (99% CI = <ref type="bibr">[-.11, .19]</ref>).</p><p>These results suggest that strong advocacy goals-but not weaker non-advocacy goals-can systematically thwart negotiations, even when the evidence leaves little space for disagreement on what constitutes a fair deal.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>It is practically a truism that motivated cognition is constrained by reality. In this paper, we have discovered that this foundational hypothesis has an important exception. Advocacy goals break reality's constraints on motivated cognition, leading to beliefs that defy overwhelming evidence. Contrary to what prior work suggests, decision-makers cannot rest easy just because the evidence before them is unambiguous. Motivated cognition can continue to elicit bias in even the face of formidable reality constraints. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Some previous theoretical work had suggested that this finding was possible <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Kruglanski et al., 2012)</ref>. But these theoretical claims of permeable reality constraints had never been verified empirically. Our paper provides the first direct evidence to this effect. We also identify that a specific type of goal-the goal to advocate-is capable of breaking reality constraints.</p><p>Our work sheds light on what would otherwise be a perplexing set of phenomena: denials of the patently obvious, boosterism of the patently absurd. Prior work has shown that highly dubious beliefs can emerge from a sufficiently potent brew of false information, errors of reasoning, and cognitive laziness <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Evans, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Stanovich, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Morewedge &amp; Kahneman, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Pennycook &amp; Rand, 2019)</ref>. The studies presented here reveal a new ingredient capable of inducing belief in the unbelievable: the goal to advocate for a particular cause.</p><p>Dominant theories, and decades of empirical work, suggest that a modicum of ambiguity is required for motivated cognition to operate. As prevalent as this idea is, the boundaries of this claim have always been vague and impressionistic. We dealt with this problem by reviewing canonical depictions of reality constraints and designing our studies to match a comparable standard found in earlier operationalizations. Naturally it would have been more convenient had the field provided a clear definition of a reality constraint, because we could have relied on it from the outset. But too much focus on what does or does not counts as a "reality constraint" risks obscuring the real theoretical issue. The proper way to understand this mechanism is not as a categorical matter-the precise dose of reality that constrains motivated bias-but as one of degree. What kinds (and strengths) of goals, compared with what degree of evidence, can counteract motivated cognition?</p><p>We identify a particular type of goal-advocacy-which has the power to defeat reality constraints, as traditionally conceived. Our findings are consistent with and build on previous research by showing that advocacy goals, in addition to circumventing factors like top-down control, professional training, and belief stability, also circumvent the constraints of reality itself <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Melnikoff &amp; Strohminger, 2020)</ref>. We have used these findings to characterize the goal to advocate as a strong goal. Whether other goals can also break reality constraints remains an open question.</p><p>Our findings speak to some clearly undesirable ways that advocacy goals impact the performance of decision-makers. In Studies 5 and 6, defense attorneys are more likely to endorse absurd theories about the case before them. The advocacy bias also impedes negotiation performance. The results of Study 7 suggest that pretrial negotiations are likelier to fail among negotiators with advocacy goals because these goals lead negotiators to choose overly conservative reservation points. This may explain why civil litigation so often goes to trial when it would be mutually beneficial to strike a deal <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Gross &amp; Syverud, 1991</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Rachlinski, 1996)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> These findings underwrite an irony: advocacy makes decision-makers worse, at least in the handling of objective information. Advocacy is, in some sense, a process that undermines itself. This insight has important implications for managers, policy-makers, lawyers, and other decision-makers who are, in many situations, bound by professional duty to advocate, be it for a client in a criminal trial, the stakeholders of a private company, or the citizens of a community. Further research will be needed to outline where else this bias hinders the advocate, where it has no effect, and where (if ever) it serves the interests of the advocate.</p><p>These results add to our understanding of how highly implausible theories emerge, and why people sometimes give credence to them. But they also present a novel puzzle. The standard account of how goals alter beliefs appeals to the role of motivated reasoning (to be contrasted with the more general umbrella term of motivated cognition; <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Kunda, 1990)</ref>. Goals lead people to access, construct, and evaluate beliefs in a biased-but nonetheless systematic-manner to arrive at a desired conclusion. It is hard to see how this motivated reasoning process could produce the completely unreasonable beliefs endorsed by our participants. The very definition of motivated reasoning seems to require that the process be constrained by reality. By demonstrating that reality constraints can be broken by advocacy goals, our findings raise the intriguing possibility that advocacy goals bias beliefs through a novel form of motivated cognition, a process separate and distinct from motivated reasoning. Alternatively, it may turn out that motivated reasoning is less constrained by reality than prior theoretical and empirical work suggests, in which case models of motivated reasoning would need to be revised. Either way, identifying the mechanisms by which advocacy goals bias beliefs will be crucial to the development of accurate theories of motivated cognition, making this a significant direction for future research.</p><p>Further research will be required to address limitations of the present work. Although we find that advocacy goals can lead some people to endorse absurd beliefs, the majority of our participants remained level-headed in their responses. It is possible that these seemingly level-headed participants actually harbored biased beliefs, and simply chose not to express them. It is also possible that individuals vary in their susceptibility to advocacy goals, such that advocacy goals lead some people, but not others, to take leave of their senses. Identifying the source of this variation is a critical direction for future research, as it speaks to the boundaries of motivated cognition and how bias plays out in real-world settings.</p><p>One of the lessons of this paper is that evidence, even the strongest evidence, is never so beefy that doubt cannot slip past. This is one of doubt's more charming proper-ties. Doubt can shrink to occupy any space, even the coziest zero-dimensional space. Its elasticity is infinite. Throughout our studies, we present participants with evidence that, in a neutral mindset, comfortably edges out reasonable doubt. It is true that evidence sometimes leaves no room for reasonable doubt. But there is always space for her slim cousin, unreasonable doubt.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The influence of desired verdict and goal strength on global evaluations (e.g. warmth) of the defendant in Study 5. Strong (advocacy) and weak (non-advocacy) goals both biased these judgments to the same degree, showing that the manipulation elicits bias when the correct answer is ambiguous. Bars indicate 95% confidence intervals derived from the reported linear regression models. Asterisk indicates p &lt; 0.05.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>The subjective likelihood of absurd theories as a function of desired verdict and goal strength in Study 5. The strong goal of advocacy leads to increased perceived likelihood of absurd theories, but the weak goal does not. Bars indicate 95% confidence intervals derived from the reported linear regression models. *** indicates p &lt; 0.001, ns indicates p &gt; 0.05 (not significant).</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">The eagle-eyed reader will have noticed that in previous experiments, the proportion of participants in this condition who answered the target question correctly hovers around 93%. This discrepancy suggests that, for some respondents, the question "Is Harrison guilty?" was indeed interpreted as relating to or inclusive of legal guilt!</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">And on the recommendation of a delightfully ambitious editor.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">It is not clear what it would mean for a mind to believe that 2 + 2 = 5; this advanced level of mental decay is generally considered so haunting it is reserved for dystopian novels (viz.<ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Orwell, 1949)</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">The extremely absurd theories used in this study were the result of a rather free-spirited brainstorming session wherein the authors generated the most absurd exculpatory accounts of the evidence they could muster. Endorsement of these theories requires not only believing that aliens and shapeshifting monsters exist, but that they have a penchant for fine jewelry.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">Most cognitive biases are rather like deciduous plants, which need an occasional watering with reality in order to flourish. The advocacy bias is a cactus in the information desert.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8"><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Gross and Syverud (1991)</ref> put it succinctly: "A trial is a failure."</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The &apos;elasticity&apos; of criminal evidence: A moderator of investigator bias</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ask</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rebelius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Granhag</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1245" to="1259" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivational determinants of risk-taking behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="359" to="372" />
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biased judgments of fairness in bargaining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Babcock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Issacharoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1337" to="1343" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bending perception to desire: Effects of task demands, motivation, and cognitive resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bélanger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kruglanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Orehek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Motivation and Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="802" to="814" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-perception: An alternative interpretation of cognitive dissonance phenomena</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recent developments in modeling preferences: Uncertainty and ambiguity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="370" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hypothesis-confirming bias in labeling effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Darley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivated skepticism: Use of differential decision criteria for preferred and nonpreferred conclusions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ditto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Lopez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="568" to="584" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A newer look: Motivated social cognition and the schematic representation of social concepts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dunning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ambiguity and self-evaluation: The role of idiosyncratic trait definitions in self-serving assessments of ability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dunning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Meyerowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Holzberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1082" to="1090" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do lawyers really believe their own hype, and should they? A natural experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Eigen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Listokin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Legal Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="267" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the motivational nature of cognitive dissonance: Dissonance as psychological discomfort</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Elliot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Devine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="382" to="394" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Role-induced bias in court: An experimental analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Glöckner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="272" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The mechanics of motivated reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Epley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In two minds: Dual-process accounts of reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S B</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="454" to="459" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical power analyses using G*Power 3.1: Tests for correlation and regression analyses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Faul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Erdfelder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Buchner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-G</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1149" to="1160" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A theory of cognitive dissonance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Festinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
			<publisher>Stanford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Palo Alto, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive consequences of forced compliance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Festinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Carlsmith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="210" />
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">When prophecy fails</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Festinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Riecken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
			<publisher>University of Minnesota Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Minneapolis</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bias and accuracy in close relationships: An integrative review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gagné</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Lydon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="322" to="338" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How we know what isn&apos;t so: The fallibility of human reason in everyday life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Free Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivated bayesians: Feeling moral while acting egoistically</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Gino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="212" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Getting to no: A study of settlement negotiations and the selection of cases for trial</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Syverud</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Michigan Law Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="393" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Don&apos;t try: Civil jury verdicts in a system geared to settlement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Syverud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="64" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California Law Review</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On motivated reasoning and self-belief</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Helzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dunning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>S. Vazire &amp; T. Wilson</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="396" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Handbook of self-knowledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Saying is believing&quot;: Effects of message modification on memory and liking for the person described</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Rholes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="378" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Processes in racial discrimination: Differential weighting of conflicting information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hodson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Dovidio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Gaertner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="460" to="471" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bidirectional reasoning in decision making by constraint satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holyoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analogical mapping by constraint satisfaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holyoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Thagard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Elastic justification: How tempting but task-irrelevant factors influence decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1006/obhd.1995.1054</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1006/obhd.1995.1054" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="330" to="337" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Elastic justification: How unjustifiable factors influence judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measures of anchoring in estimation tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Jacowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1161" to="1166" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of role playing on opinion change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Janis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Judgment under uncertainty: Heuristics and biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Let&apos;s not make a deal: An empirical study of decision making in unsuccessful settlement negotiations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Kiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Asher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mcshane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Empirical Legal Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="591" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivated social cognition: Principles of the interface</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kruglanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Social psychology: Handbook of basic principles</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="493" to="520" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>E. Higgins</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivation, cognition, and reality: Three memos for the next generation of research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kruglanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The energetics of motivated cognition: A force-field analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kruglanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bélanger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Köpetz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pierro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mannetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">All thinking is &apos;wishful&apos; thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kruglanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jasko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Friston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="413" to="424" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The case for motivated reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Kunda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="480" to="498" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noise increases anchoring effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Morewedge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neurocomputational mechanisms underlying motivated seeing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Leong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="962" to="973" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-serving assessments of fairness and pretrial bargaining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Issacharoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Babcock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Legal Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dishonesty of honest people: A theory of self-concept maintenance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Amir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="633" to="644" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tracking prejudice: A mouse-tracking measure of evaluative conflict predicts discriminatory behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Melnikoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychological and Personality Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="266" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The automatic influence of advocacy on lawyers and novices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Melnikoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Strohminger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A general connectionist model of attitude structure and change: The ACS (Attitudes as Constraint Satisfaction) model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Monroe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="733" to="759" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Associative processes in intuitive judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Morewedge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="440" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The quest for conviction: Motivated cognition in romantic relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Merchants of doubt: How a handful of scientists obscured the truth on issues from tobacco smoke to global warming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Oreskes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Conway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Bloomsbury Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nineteen eighty-four</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Orwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1949" />
			<publisher>Secker &amp; Warburg</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lazy, not biased: Susceptibility to partisan fake news is better explained by lack of reasoning than by motivated reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">188</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The elaboration likelihood model of persuasion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Petty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Cacioppo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in experimental social psychology</title>
		<editor>L. Berkowitz</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="203" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward an integration of cognitive and motivational perspectives on social inference: A biased hypothesis-testing model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pyszczynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="340" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gains, losses, and the psychology of litigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Rachlinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Southern California Law Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stretching the truth: Elastic justification and motivated communication of uncertain information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schweitzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hsee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="201" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A third view of the black box: Cognitive coherence in legal decision making. The University of Chicago Law Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="586" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extension: Lawyers&apos; role-induced bias arises fast and persists despite intervention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Spamann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Legal Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="485" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The robot&apos;s rebellion: Finding meaning in the age of darwin</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stanovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>Chicago University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chicago, IL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Towards a better understanding of lawyers&apos; judgmental biases in client representation: The role of need for cognitive closure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Stark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milyavsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="216" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Washington University Journal of Law &amp; Policy</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using dynamic monitoring of choices to predict and understand risk preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31738" to="31747" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The true self: A psychological concept distinct from the self</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Strohminger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Knobe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="560" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some attitudinal and cognitive consequences of thought</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tesser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="226" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Close-call counterfactuals and belief-system defenses: I was not almost wrong but i was almost right</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="639" to="652" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social functionalist frameworks for judgment and choice: Intuitive politicians, theologians, and prosecutors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="471" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Correspondence and coherence: Indicators of good judgment in world politics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Thinking: Psychological perspectives on reasoning, judgment and decision making</title>
		<editor>D. Hardman &amp; L. Macchi</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Chichester, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="250" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Counterfactual thought experiments in world politics: Logical, methodological, and psychological perspectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Belkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Princeton, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Egocentric interpretations of fairness and interpersonal conflict</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="197" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confirmatory and diagnosing strategies in social information gathering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Trope</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bassok</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social hypothesis testing: Cognitive and motivational mechanisms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Trope</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Liberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Social psychology: Handbook of basic principles</title>
		<editor>E. Higgins &amp; A. Kruglanski</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="270" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgment under uncertainty: Heuristics and biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">185</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1124" to="1131" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
