<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Free ranking vs. rank-choosing: New insights on the conjunction fallacy</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2021-04-27">April 27, 2021</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Torr</forename><surname>Polakow</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrei</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerome</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Industrial Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Curiosity Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tel-Aviv University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology, Institute for Information Processing and Decision Making (IIPDM)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Haifa</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>3498838</postCode>
									<settlement>Haifa</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Psychological and Brain Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Industrial Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Gordon Curiosity Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indiana University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>47405</postCode>
									<settlement>Bloomington, Goren</settlement>
									<region>Indiana</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Tel-Aviv University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Free ranking vs. rank-choosing: New insights on the conjunction fallacy</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2021-04-27">April 27, 2021</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:46+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Decision making</term>
					<term>Fallacy</term>
					<term>Ranking</term>
					<term>Presentation Mode</term>
					<term>Social agents</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>It has been consistently shown that when asked to rank options, people often make fallacious judgements. Furthermore, such fallacies can be sensitive to presentation mode. In the first study, we explored a novel type of ranking presentation, namely, choosing between two rank orders of options. To enable a direct comparison of fallacy rates between free ranking and the new presentation mode, we calculated the frequencies of the two presented rank orders in a free ranking condition. Our analysis shows that people choose the non-fallacious rank order significantly more when asked to choose between two rank orders as compared to freely ranking the possible options. In a second study, we explored whether an agent presenting the rankings to choose from has an effect. To alleviate social biases we used videos of social robots as the presenting agents. We show that rank orders presented by social agents significantly reduce the fallacy rates, compared to rank orders presented without an agent. We discuss the results in view of social decision making theories, wherein a ranking presentation by a social agent is comparable to a consultation with another person regarding free ranking. Our results suggest that fallacious decision making can be mitigated by a social agent presenting rankings to choose from.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Decision makers are often required to select from different alternatives. The most prevalent mechanisms are discrete choices between alternatives and ranking. Discrete choices among alternatives result in better differentiation, when compared to rating scales <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[Wijnen et al.(2015)</ref>] , yet are problematic when the number of alternatives is large <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[Ock, Yi, Ahn, &amp; Jo, (2016)</ref>]. Ranking is often based on multiple criteria <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[Roy(1985)</ref>], but is susceptible to various problems, such as weighting issues <ref type="bibr">[Zanakis, Solomon, Wishart, &amp; Dublish, (1998)</ref>] , misinterpretation of personal preferences and internal inconsistencies in the ranking methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[Leoneti and Leoneti(2016)</ref>].</p><p>In this contribution we address a novel mechanism for decision makers, namely, discrete choice between predetermined rankings. In other words, the decision maker selects between two rank orders of alternatives. This mechanism becomes more useful as different ranking methods appear <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[Leoneti and Leoneti(2016)</ref>], multiple recommendation systems are available <ref type="bibr">[Portugal, Alencar, &amp; Cowan, (2018)</ref>] and advisors abound. Thus, decision makers can select not from different alternatives, but from different rankings of alternatives. We focus on an important aspect of ranking, namely, judgemental fallacies, i.e., judgments that violate classical probability theory. One common fallacy is the conjunction fallacy, which was introduced by Tversky and Kahneman <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[Tversky and Kahneman(1983)</ref>]. They presented to the subjects a hypothetical personality sketch of a fictitious individual, and asked them to rank order the alternatives according to their probabilities:</p><p>Linda is 31 years old, single, outspoken, and very bright. She majored in philosophy. As a student, she was deeply concerned with issues of discrimination and social justice, and also participated in anti-nuclear demonstrations.</p><p>Linda is an elementary school teacher.</p><p>Linda is active in the feminist movement. <ref type="bibr">(F)</ref> Linda is a social worker.</p><p>Linda is a member of the League of Women Voters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Linda is a bank teller. (T)</head><p>Linda is an insurance salesperson.</p><p>Linda is a bank teller and is active in the feminist movement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(T &amp;F )</head><p>A conjunction fallacy occurs when people rank option (T&amp;F) higher than (T) or higher than (F) (single conjunction fallacy) or higher than both (double conjunction fallacy). This is a judgemental fallacy since in classical probability theory, the probability of the conjunction (T&amp;F) can never be higher than its constituents (T, F). Thus, the actual (real-world) frequency of the conjunction can never be higher than its constituents, yet people do rank the conjunction as more probable. In the original version of the experiment, 85 percent of the respondents ranked option (T&amp;F) as more probable than option (F). Tversky and Kahneman confirmed and replicated these results for different fictional scenarios.</p><p>These results have been replicated numerous times with various scenarios, showing that people who freely rank options have high probability of making a judgmental fallacy. However, several studies have shown that the mode of presentation of the scenario and the options can drastically change the fallacy rates. Results by Morier and Borgida <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[Morier and Borgida(1984)</ref>] highlight the importance of the question's framing and its effect on the fallacy rates.</p><p>Hertwig and Gigerenzer <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[Hertwig and Gigerenzer(1999)</ref>] replicated the results of Tversky and Kahneman when the subjects were asked to rank or give probabilities to the different options. However, they asked the subject frequency questions such as: "200 women have the same description as Linda above. How many out of the 200 women are bank tellers, bank tellers and feminist etc." In this condition, fallacy rates dropped below 20 percent.</p><p>Wedell and Moro <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[Wedell and Moro(2008)</ref>] found that frequency judgments as well as probability judgments produce lower rates of conjunction fallacies than rank orders, and so the effect of using frequency may not be as important as requesting a judgment rather than a rank order.</p><p>An interesting study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Charness [Charness(2009)</ref>] looked into conjunction fallacy under conditions which allowed a group of individuals to consult with each other. In a treatment with incentives, participants were informed that there was a correct answer and that anyone who chose this correct answer would receive 4$. In the treatment without incentives, participants were told that they would receive 2$ for filling out the questionnaire. These experiments were conducted with individuals, pairs, and trios of participants. When no incentive was given, the fallacy rates were 58%, 48% and 26% for single, pairs and trios, respectively. For the incentive condition, the fallacy rates were 33%, 13% and 10% for single, pairs and trios, respectively. These results are particularly interesting showing that incentive and/or cooperation with other participants, reduce the fallacy rates. Thus, the presentation of different rank orders, which is analogous to hearing other participants rank orders, should have a similar effect.</p><p>In real world scenarios, another presentation mode is common, namely, discrete choice between two rank orders of options, each having the same alternatives, ranked in different order. This is in contrast to free ranking, probability judgments or direct comparison between two specific alternatives.</p><p>We thus set out to compare people's conjunction fallacy rates of free ranking vs. discrete choice between ranking, where in the latter we mean that the participant has to choose between presentation of two specific rank orders. Thus, the goal of the current studies is to better understand the influence choosing between rankings has on fallacy rates, i.e., whether this prevalent presentation mode can mitigate conjunction fallacies, and what attributes of the options' presentation are important for this effect. There are several leading models of conjunction fallacies, such as the averaging model <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[Juslin, Nilsson, &amp; Winman, (2009)</ref>] , Costello's probability plus noise model <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[Costello, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Costello, Watts, &amp; Fisher, (2018)</ref>] and quantum cognition models <ref type="bibr">[Busemeyer, Wang, &amp; Shiffrin, (2015)</ref>]. However, none have specifically addressed the presentation mode of rank choosing. A-priori, these models generate the hypothesis that rank choosing should follow the same fallacy rate as free ranking: participants assign higher probability to rank orders, based on free ranking probabilities, and thus should choose rank order with fallacy more than without. Thus, the main null hypothesis states that there will not be a significant difference in fallacy rates between free ranking and rank-choosing (H1). Moreover, the presenter of the choices has not been considered before, except from Charness <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[Charness(2009)</ref>], which showed that consulting with people significantly reduces the fallacy rates. Thus, a second null hypothesis states that a social presenter of the rank-choosing will significantly reduce fallacy rates (H2). We conducted two studies to test these hypotheses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Questionnaire</head><p>We used the following personality sketches of two fictitious individuals, Emma and Liz, followed by a set of occupations and avocations associated with each. For Emma, the two characteristics that we asked about were "manager" (M)</p><p>and "likes to exercise" (E) and for Liz they were "programmer"(Pr) and "likes to paint" (Pa). The two questions are given below:</p><p>Q1: Emma lives in an apartment with her two cats in the center of the city and is an outgoing person. She takes yoga classes at the gym three times a week, enjoys reading science-fiction books and volunteers at least once a week in an animal shelter.</p><p>Emma is a manager (M).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Emma likes to exercise (E).</head><p>Emma is a manager and likes to exercise (M&amp;E).</p><p>Q2: Liz lives in a Victorian home in Oakland. She is an analytical thinker and works at a start-up company. She tries to attend a few classes at the gym every week. She is very ambitious at her job and also enjoys cooking very much and is quite good at it.</p><p>Liz is a programmer (Pr).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Liz likes to paint (Pa).</head><p>Liz is a programmer and likes to paint (Pr&amp;Pa).</p><p>In the original Linda story, one of the options was consistently assigned by participants a higher probability than the other (T &gt; F ) and was thus also ranked higher <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[Bhatia(2017)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hofmann et al.(2018)</ref>]. The conjunction fallacy that ensued was predominantly a "single-conjunction", i.e., the prevalent conjunction fallacy ranking was T &gt; T &amp;F &gt; F .</p><p>In the current study, we deliberately designed the questionnaire to explore two scenarios: Q2 represents a Linda-like scenario in which P r &gt; P a, whereas Q1 represents a more equi-probable scenario in which M ≃ E.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Participants</head><p>In our study, the participants were Amazon Mechanical Turk (AMT) users. We asked for Amazon Mechanical Turk users that were native English speakers from North America that had completed at least 100 tasks with an approval rate &gt; 95%. First the participants were asked to give their consent, age, gender and education. Then, each participant was presented with the questionnaire on Qualtrics (Qualtrics, Provo, UT). While completing the questionnaire, the participants had to pass a screening check, namely, a trap question, in which we asked "What does Liz enjoy doing?", instead of ranking or choosing a ranking.</p><p>The study was approved by our Institutional Review Board.</p><p>3 Study 1: Free ranking vs. Rank-choosing</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Conditions</head><p>The study was designed to have two conditions: RANK and CHOOSE. In the RANK condition, the participants were asked to rank the statements according to their perceived probability. In the CHOOSE condition, participants were presented with two rankings; one that represented a ranking with no fallacies, e.g., the conjunction statement was ranked lowest and; one that represented a conjunction fallacy, e.g., the conjunction statement was ranked higher than one of the other statements. Participants in the CHOOSE condition were asked to choose which ranking they agreed with. The side on which the fallacious ranking was presented alternated randomly between participants and across questions within subjects.</p><p>We administered each condition twice, once for Q1 followed by Q2 and once in the other order. Due to the screening of AMT, the following number of qualified participants was achieved: RANK Q1Q2 (n = 122, female=59, age=32 (s = 0.9)), RANK Q2Q1 (n = 90, female=54, age=36 (s = 1.1)), CHOOSE Q1Q2 (n = 146, female=77, age=37 (s = 0.9)), CHOOSE Q2Q1 (n = 85, female=50, age=35 (s = 1.1)).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Results</head><p>The analysis showed that while the RANK condition conformed to previous studies, with 61% fallacy rate, the CHOOSE condition had a significantly lower fallacy rate, 32%. However, due to different ex-ante probabilities of each condition, a direct statistical significance test of the two conditions was not possible. Hence, we performed the following procedure to analyze their difference. We first tested whether participants' choices were significantly different than random selections. We then calculated the rank order in both conditions, i.e., binary relations between each ranking-pairs, and then directly tested for differences between these rank orders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">RANK condition</head><p>We first analyzed the ex-ante probabilities of rankings and then tested for difference from random ranking. In the current setup, there were six possible rankings, from which four were fallacious. Therefore, the ex-ante random ranking probabilities resulted in 2/3 chance of ranking fallaciously (1/6 for each fallacious option).</p><p>A Fisher-exact test was performed on the fallacious vs. non-fallacious options and random ranking. The analysis shows that there was no significant difference between participant's ranking and random ranking (Q1: p = 0.838, Q2: p = 0.057, Fisher's exact test). However, a deeper analysis of the relative frequency of each ranking showed that the rankings were not equi-probable (χ 2 = 20.17, p = 0.001).</p><p>Hence, while the fallacy rate was not significantly different than random ranking, the ranking themselves were not random.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">CHOOSE condition</head><p>In this condition, participants had a binary choice to make, two possible rankings to choose from, one fallacious and one not. Therefore, the ex-ante probabilities of random selections were 1/2. A binomial test was preformed on these binary choices to check if they differed from random and revealed that participants chose the non-fallacious ranking significantly more than random selection (p &lt; 0.0001). These results, namely, that the RANK condition was not significantly different than random ranking and the CHOOSE condition was significantly different than random choice, do not support hypothesis H1, that the two conditions will not be significantly different.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3">Ranking order</head><p>To enable a direct comparison between the two conditions, we analyzed the ranking orders, by investigating the binary relations between every two rankings <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[Ock et al.(2016)</ref>]. In the RANK condition, we compared the ranking frequency, whereas in the CHOOSE condition we analyzed the relative proportion of each rank-pair selection. For example, in Q1, the options were M (manager), E (exercise) and M &amp; E (manager and exercise). We thus compared between ranking pairs, e.g., M &gt; E &gt; M &amp;E and M &gt; M &amp;E &gt; E. For each ranking pair in the CHOOSE condition, all of which included both a fallacious and a non-fallacious ranking, we compared the frequency with which those specific rankings were chosen in the RANK condition. We thus treated each ranking pair as a binary decision, even in the RANK condition, and could perform a direct χ 2 test between the two conditions. Our analysis showed that the two conditions were significantly different for the ranking pairs presented (χ 2 = 12.18, p &lt; 0.001).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.4">Questions and order effects</head><p>Comparing the two questions, Q1 and Q2, we found that both show approximately the same trend of RANK having a significantly higher fallacy rates than CHOOSE (Q1 RANK 65% and CHOOSE 29%, Q2 RANK 57% and CHOOSE 36%). A deeper analysis showed that while the question itself (Q1,Q2) was not a significant predictor of fallacy rate, there was a significant interaction between condition and question, such that Q1 had higher fallacy rates than Q2 in the RANK condition, whereas the opposite occurred in the CHOOSE condition (χ 2 = 79, p &lt; 0.001, with β(CON D) = 0.87, p &lt; 0.001, β(Q) = −3.1, p = 0.112, β(CON D × Q) = 0.65, p = 0.02, logistic regression). Analyzing the specific free ranking the participants performed, we found that for Q1 rankings with M &gt; E (49.5%) were very similar to E &gt; M (50.5%). On the other hand, for Q2 we found a different picture, with P r &gt; P a (68%) being much more frequent than P a &gt; P r (32%). These results substantiate our initial design of the different questions.</p><p>We analyzed the effect of order on the conjunction fallacy, i.e., whether the first encountered question (regardless of type Q1 or Q2) had a different fallacy rate than the second question, and found no significant effect (χ 2 = 0.2, p = 0.64)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Discussion</head><p>The results of the comparison were highly significant, and did not support the null hypothesis H1. They showed that asking participants to choose from two rankings drastically reduced the conjunction fallacy rate. Current mathematical models, such as the averaging model <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[Juslin et al.(2009)</ref>], the probability theory plus noise <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[Costello(2009)</ref>] and quantum cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[Busemeyer et al.(2006)</ref>], have not addressed this particular presentation mode. However, the a-priori hypothesis, that people would select ranking according to their "simulated" freeranking probabilities, had been shown to not be supported.</p><p>While frequency judgments also lower the fallacy rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[Wedell and Moro(2008)</ref>], the currently observed rates are still much higher than the frequency judgments, and do not directly relate to the selection presentation mode. Semantic <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[Bhatia(2017)</ref>] and co-occurrence <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[Hofmann et al.(2018)</ref>] analyses, may explain the difference between the two questions, Q1 and Q2, for example "analytical thinker/ambitious" is semantically more associated with "programmer" than "likes to paint". Furthermore, representativeness of the options presented has been shown to affect meta-cognitive processes related to conjunction fallacy rates <ref type="bibr">[Dujmović, Valerjev, &amp; Bajšanski, (2020)</ref>]. However, these approaches do not directly relate to the presentation mode.</p><p>It has been recently shown that group reasoning can lessen the fallacy rates, as well as using paradigmatic reasoning, as compared to narrative reasoning <ref type="bibr">[Donati, Guazzini, Gronchi, &amp; Smorti, (2019)</ref>]. This social effect, also reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Charness [Charness(2009)</ref>], does have similar reduction in conjunction fallacy rate, when considering no incentives and a "trio" formation. In other words, one can think of the two rankings as the opinions of two fellow participants, which, together with the actual participant, constitute a "trio" formation", thus reducing the fallacy rate.</p><p>In order to check this hypothesis we conducted a second study in which we used artificial agents, namely, social robots, to present the rankings participants can choose from. Hence, one robot always answered according to the conjunction fallacy, whereas the other robot answered with no fallacy. To maintain consistency and embodiment, for both questions, the robots maintained their side, e.g., for both Q1 and Q2 the robot with fallacies always stayed on the left side. To control for this consistency-related condition, we ran the CHOOSE condition again, but now without alternating the sides of ranking presentations.</p><p>4 Study 2</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Conditions</head><p>The study was designed to better understand the attributes that make rank choosing mitigate fallacy rates. In real-life scenarios, the system or agent that presents the ranking to choose from is usually consistent, i.e., one system or agent usually either makes fallacies or not; it does not alternate randomly between fallacious rankings and non-fallacious ones. For this purpose we introduced the CONSISTENT condition, which differed from the CHOOSE condition from study 1 only in the consistency of the ranking presentation. In other words, the CONSISTENT condition's presentation of the fallacious rank ordering was the same for both presented questions, i.e., it did not alternate randomly as in the CHOOSE condition. Effectively, the only change between the CHOOSE and CONSISTENT conditions was in the second presented question, in which the fallacious ranking was presented in the same position (left/right) as in the first question for the CONSISTENT condition and random position in the CHOOSE condition.</p><p>Another important aspect is the presenter of the ranking, i.e., whether it is a "system" or a "social agent" <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[Logg, Minson, &amp; Moore, (2019);</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kunkel, Donkers, Michael, Barbu, &amp; Ziegler, (2019)</ref>]. To study the influence of the presenter, we introduced the SOCIAL condition, in which a video of a social robot presenting the rank ordering came before the participants' choosing. In each video, the presenter asked the robots a question. Then each robot gave its rank verbally according to its fallacy. For example, a robot with a single conjunction fallacy in question Q1 ranked the options: M highest, then M&amp;E and lastly E, <ref type="figure">Fig. 1(right)</ref>. Subtitles were displayed for everything that was said, by the presenter or robots.</p><p>In summary, the CONSISTENT condition was contrasted to the CHOOSE condition, to study whether a consistent presentation of ranking influences the fallacy rates, and to the SOCIAL condition to study whether the presenter of the rankings influenced the fallacy rates.</p><p>In the SOCIAL condition, in each video two NAO robots (1 blue and 1 red)</p><p>were presented, one on the left and one on the right with a presenter in the middle, <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref>. We counterbalanced the color and fallacious side of the robots across participants.</p><p>Since we have shown that there is no order effect, we administered each condition once for Q1 followed by Q2. We had in total 240 and 274 participants for the SOCIAL and CONSISTENT conditions, respectively. However, due to the screening of AMT, the following number of qualified participants was achieved: SOCIAL (n = 227, female=118, age=37 (s = 0.9)), CONSISTENT (n = 160, female=89, age=38 (s = 0.9)). <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Screenshot from one of the videos that was presented to the participants. In this image, the left robot behaved according to a non-fallacious ranking, and the right robot behaved according to single conjunction fallacy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results</head><p>The analysis showed that the CONSISTENT condition had similar fallacy rates to the CHOOSE condition, with 31% fallacy rate (χ 2 = .13, p = 0.71). However, the SOCIAL condition had a significantly lower fallacy rate, 24%, compared to the CONSISTENT condition (χ 2 = 6.79, p = 0.009).</p><p>Questions: Comparing the two questions, we found that both showed approximately the same trend (Q1 CONSISTENT 32% and SOCIAL 28%, Q2 CONSISTENT 30% and SOCIAL 20%), with no significant interaction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Discussion</head><p>The analysis showed that if a social agent, in this case a social robot, presents the rankings, fallacy rates drop even more than mere rank choosing, thus supporting hypothesis H2. The fallacy rates are now on-par with those reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Charness [Charness(2009)</ref>] for "trio". Our CONSISTENT control condition, which resulted in almost identical fallacy rates as CHOOSE, rules out an effect due to consistency of presentation.</p><p>Since the only difference between the conditions was the actual appearance of a social agent, we can conclude that not only the presentation mode influences fallacy rates, but also the presenter itself, <ref type="figure">Fig. 2</ref>.</p><p>One can consider the robots as agents giving advice. It has been shown that people adhere more to advice when they think it comes from an algorithm than from a person, even when the algorithm's process is unknown <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[Logg et al.(2019)</ref>]. Hence, one can consider the two robots as artificial agents giving advice, with an underlying algorithm. This may influence how participants viewed the social robots, compared to human presenters <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[Charness(2009)</ref>].</p><p>Moreover, we did not comment directly why each robot selected its options, which has been shown to increase trust in similar systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[Kunkel et al.(2019)</ref>].</p><p>The robot also did not explain its own behaviour, which has been shown to improve collaboration between people and robots <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[Tabrez and Hayes(2019)</ref>]. This lack of explanation may have influenced how people perceived the robots' advice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">General discussion</head><p>Previously, the two main mechanisms for decision makers, i.e., ranking and discrete choice between alternatives, have been compared. Ock et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[Ock et al.(2016)]</ref> presented a similar conversion from ranking to discrete choice was made, but it compared choices between alternatives and not ranking. It was shown that ranking and paired-comparison are consistent.</p><p>Conversely, we have shown that presenting two rankings to choose from results in a drastic reduction in conjunction fallacy rates. We also showed that having a social agent presenting the rankings strengthen the mitigation effect of the fallacy.</p><p>Hence, there are two cumulative effects when social agents present their options: the first, and vastly more effective, is the fact that there is a choice to make and not ranking. The second effect, which is significant but has a smaller  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Fallacy rates as a function of conditions, including those reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Charness, 2009)</ref> for trio with no incentive. * * * p &lt; 0.001, * * p = 0.004 (CHOOSE-SOCIAL), p = 0.0094 (CONSISTENT-SOCIAL).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RANK</head><p>effect size, is the appearance of a social agent.</p><p>The results reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Charness [Charness(2009)</ref>] can be viewed as presentation of options by social agents. Several important conjectures come from our presented results.</p><p>First, that voicing one's reasons for its opinions is unnecessary for an effective mitigation of the conjunction fallacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[Kunkel et al.(2019)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Tabrez and Hayes(2019)</ref>].</p><p>In Study 2, the robots did not explain their rankings, only expressed them. Furthermore, even without a social agent, the mere presentation of ranking options reduced the fallacy rate.</p><p>Second, humans are not the only social agents that can influence one's opinions. The remarkably similar fallacy rates reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Charness [Charness(2009)]</ref> and in our SOCIAL condition shows that having any social agent is enough. While one option for why social agency is important may be its consistency, our</p><p>CONSISTENT condition results show that it is not the case. Alternatively, the embodiment of the social agent may be the major factor.</p><p>Third, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Charness [Charness(2009)</ref>] has raised the truth-wins standard as a possible explanation for the phenomenon . his explanation claims that simply encountering a more "truthfull', i.e., non-fallacious, option results in decrease in one's own fallacious decisions. Our results partly support this explanation, as we have shown that the mere presentation of the rankings, without a social agent nor reasoning, suffices to reduce fallacy rates.</p><p>A complementary explanation maybe due to dual-process or "slow-and fastbrains" [Kahneman(2011), Andersson et al. <ref type="formula">2020</ref>]. It has been recently shown that in order to avoid the conjunction fallacy, additional neurocognitive resources, mainly in the fronto-parietal network, are required <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[Andersson et al.(2020)</ref>]. One option is that when asked to freely rank, participants engage fast intuitive processes, wherein the fast and less rational brain takes over. On the other hand, when asked to choose between rankings, participants engage in a more deliberative mode, comparing the two alternatives, possibly also to one they have already formulated. Thus, during this deliberation, their slow and rational brain takes over and results in much smaller fallacy rates. The fronto-parietal network has also been implicated in social interaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[Lahnakoski et al.(2012)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Arioli and Canessa(2019)</ref>]. Thus, social interaction may increase the effects of the slow and rational brain even more.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>We have reported on a new type of presentation, wherein participants have to choose between two rankings. Our analysis shows that this mode of presentation drastically reduces conjunction fallacy rates. Furthermore, presentation by an (artificial) social agent reduces the fallacy rates to those reported by conferring with two other human companions. While we have shown that mere presentation of the rankings is enough to induce reduction in fallacy rates, supporting the truth-wins standard, a cumulative effect of social agents is harder to explain. Future studies will endeavor to unveil the mechanisms behind these effects. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Amazon</head><label></label><figDesc>Mechanical Turk is a common method to collect large amounts of data [You &amp; Robert Jr., (2018); Canning, Donahue, &amp; Scheutz, (2014)]. While there has been some debate about the validation of MTurk users in the scientific community, recent studies validated that MTurk users are an appropriate sample for research, when cautionary actions are taken [Hauser &amp; Schwartz, (2016); Berinsky, Huber, &amp; Lenz, (2012)].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>of pharmacoeconomics &amp; outcomes research 15, 721-728. ISBN: 1744-8379 Publisher: Taylor &amp; Francis.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conflict of Interest Statement</head><p>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contribution</head><p>G. G. and J. R. B. developed the study concept. T. P. and A. T. contributed to the study design. Data collection was performed by T. P and data analysis was performed by T. P. and G. G. T. P. drafted the manuscript, and A. T., J. R. B. and G. G. provided critical revisions. All authors approved the final version of the manuscript for submission.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Funding</head><p>This study was supported by Israel-US Binational Science Foundation grant No. 2016262.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Open Practices Statement</head><p>The data and materials for all experiments are available at https://osf.io/5ta2w/ and none of the experiments was preregistered.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neurocognitive processes underlying heuristic and normative probability judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andersson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2019.104153</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">196</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural processing of social interaction: Coordinate-based meta-analytic evidence from human neuroimaging studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Canessa ;</forename><surname>Arioli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Arioli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Canessa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/hbm.24627</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Brain Mapping</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3712" to="3737" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Associative judgment and vector space semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000047</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>American Psychological Association</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A quantum information processing explanation of disjunction effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 28th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society &amp; the 5th International Conference of the Cognitive Science</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Mahwah, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Erlbaum</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="135" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the Conjunction Fallacy in Probability Judgment: New Experimental Evidence Regarding Linda. Economics Working Paper Archive</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Charness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>The Johns Hopkins University,Department of Economics</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How probability theory explains the conjunction fallacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Costello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bdm.618</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="234" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The &apos;conjunction fallacy&apos; revisited: how intelligent inferences look like reasoning errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gigerenzer ;</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple Co-Occurrence Statistics Reproducibly Predict Association Ratings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hofmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/cogs.12662</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Let Me Explain: Impact of Personal and Impersonal Explanations on Trust in Recommender Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Juslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300717</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Association for Computing Machinery</title>
		<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Association for Computing Machinery<address><addrLine>Glasgow, Scotland Uk</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Probability theory, not the very guide of life</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Naturalistic fMRI Mapping Reveals Superior Temporal Sulcus as the Hub for the Distributed Brain Network for Social Perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Lahnakoski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnhum.2012.00233</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Considerations regarding the choice of ranking multiple criteria decision making methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leoneti ;</forename><surname>Leoneti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Leoneti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Leoneti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1590/0101-7438.2016.036.02.0259</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pesquisa Operacional</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="277" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Algorithm appreciation: People prefer algorithmic to human judgment. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes 151</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Logg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.obhdp.2018.12.005</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="103" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The conjunction fallacy: A task specific phenomenon?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Morier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Borgida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167284102010</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<publisher>Morier and Borgida</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How many alternatives can be ranked? A comparison of the paired comparison and ranking methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Ock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>655-660. ISBN: 1098-3015 Publisher: Else- vier</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Value in Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Methodologie multicritere d&apos;aide a la decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Roy(1985)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving Human-Robot Interaction Through Explainable Reinforcement Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hayes</forename><forename type="middle">;</forename><surname>Tabrez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tabrez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/HRI.2019.8673198</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">14th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2167" to="2148" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extensional versus intuitive reasoning: The conjunction fallacy in probability judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kahneman ;</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing boundary conditions for the conjunction fallacy: Effects of response mode, conceptual focus, and problem type</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moro ;</forename><surname>Wedell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wedell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2007.08.003</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discrete-choice experiments versus rating scale exercises to evaluate the importance of attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Wijnen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Expert review</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
