<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The rise and fall of memories: Temporal dynamics of visual working memory</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2024-04-30">April 30, 2024</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andre</forename><surname>Sahakian</surname></persName>
							<email>a.sahakian@uu.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Helmholtz Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Utrecht University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Heidelberglaan 1</addrLine>
									<postCode>3584 CS</postCode>
									<settlement>Utrecht</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Surya</forename><surname>Gayet</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Helmholtz Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Utrecht University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Heidelberglaan 1</addrLine>
									<postCode>3584 CS</postCode>
									<settlement>Utrecht</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><forename type="middle">L E</forename><surname>Paffen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Helmholtz Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Utrecht University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Heidelberglaan 1</addrLine>
									<postCode>3584 CS</postCode>
									<settlement>Utrecht</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Van Der Stigchel</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Experimental Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Helmholtz Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Utrecht University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Heidelberglaan 1</addrLine>
									<postCode>3584 CS</postCode>
									<settlement>Utrecht</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The rise and fall of memories: Temporal dynamics of visual working memory</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2024-04-30">April 30, 2024</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:54+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Visual working memory (VWM) is a cognitive system, which temporarily stores task-relevant visual information to enable interactions with the environment. In everyday VWM use, we typically decide how long we look to encode information, and how long we wait before acting on the memory. In contrast, VWM is typically studied in unnaturally rigid paradigms that keep presentation times and delays fixed. Here, we ask how visual memories build up over self-paced viewing times, and how they 1 decay over self-paced delays, in a task that naturally engages VWM. We employed a copying task, in which participants were tasked to recreate an &quot;example&quot; arrangement of items in an adjacent empty &quot;workspace&quot;. We tracked their unconstrained viewing and copying behavior at the level of individual items&apos; viewing times and the time to successful placements (i.e., delay). Our results show that performance monotonically increased for viewing times up to one second (per item), and plateaued afterwards. Interestingly, while views exceeding one second did not strongly improve performance for short (two second) delays, views beyond one second did improve performance for longer delays. In contrast, this pattern was not observed in Experiments 2A and 2B, where viewing and delay times were experimentally manipulated (i.e., in more typical, rigid paradigms). These findings showcase the importance of considering aspects of naturalistic behavior, like decision making, when studying VWM. We suggest that in everyday situations, short glances are sufficient for immediate use from VWM, but long views are required for effective delayed use.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Visual working memory (VWM) is an essential cognitive function in our everyday behavior (A. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Baddeley, 1992</ref>; A. D. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Baddeley &amp; Hitch, 1974;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">A. D. Baddeley &amp; Della Sala, 1996)</ref>. It allows us to maintain visual information for a short time period in order to smoothly and efficiently interact with our surroundings <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Heuer et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Nobre &amp; Stokes, 2019)</ref>. Keeping visual information available is important, because relevant objects are often removed from sight temporarily, for instance due to shifts in gaze direction (i.e., looking at something else), or due to occlusion by other objects. VWM can store relevant visual information, so 2 humans can plan actions and successfully execute them in a dynamic visual environment.</p><p>For example, to safely cross a multi-lane intersection, we rely heavily on our visual working memory. When we have looked in one direction, we need to remember what was there while we look in the other direction. Or when a car moves out of sight behind a parked bus, we need to keep the car in memory to safely cross the street. Even though we know a great deal about VWM from decades of research (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Brady et al., 2024</ref> for a recent review), a relatively small portion of the literature has focused on the time course of visual memories: how they are built up over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Bays et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Bundesen, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">de Jong et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Donkin et al., 2015)</ref>, and how they decay over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Donkin et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Oberauer &amp; Lewandowsky, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Souza &amp; Oberauer, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Souza et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zhang &amp; Luck, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>Thinking of the traffic example again, while we look at a vehicle, a memory representation presumably gradually builds up (i.e., comprising its size, location, velocity, etc.). When the vehicle disappears from sight, the quality of this memory representation decays over time, and new incoming information might interfere with the representation of the vehicle. Our current goal is to uncover how the duration of encoding and the time until utilization jointly determine how well information can be utilized in a naturalistic context. In doing so we can learn what the most time-efficient course of action is: How long do we need to look at relevant visual information to enable successful actions? How long can we wait before the stored information has decayed so much that it cannot be utilized successfully anymore?</p><p>Our main goal naturally divides into three questions: (1) How are visual memory representations built up during visual inspection? (2) How do they decay while being retained in VWM? And (3) Does the time spend to build up representations influences the decay of these representations? Importantly, we want to investigate the three posed questions during naturalistic memory use. That is, in a task in which participants have unrestricted access to view task relevant information, and are allowed to report the information at any time and in any desired order, akin to real-world memory-guided behavior.</p><p>Typically in visual working memory studies, answering the main question requires an experiment with a rigid task structure. Therefore, in the vast majority of VWM studies, both the presentation time of memoranda and the time until a report is prompted are fixed. To illustrate, when investigating whether memory performance is better for familiar items (an image of a car) than abstract items (a scrambled image of car), both types of items should be presented for the same duration, and should be probed after the same delay period <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Asp et al., 2021)</ref>. The upside of this approach is that any variability in the outcome measure cannot be explained by (strategic) changes in encoding or retention time, so that any variation in performance can be explained by the experimental manipulation of interest. The downside of this approach, however, is that it does not reflect working memory use during real-world, self-paced behavior. Natural contexts allow for different encoding and retention strategies, which can be tuned to the task context or stimulus type. Thus these temporally rigid paradigms offer little insight in the interplay of variable encoding times and retention times, which play a large role in everyday behavior. Still, there are some studies which have parametrically manipulated for how long information was presented <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Bays et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Brady et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">de Jong et al., 2023)</ref>. These studies have revealed a typical pattern of memory performance: performance initially increases with longer presentation times, and then plateaus for even longer presentation times. Another downside of a fixed temporal structure is that we cannot be certain that observers actively encode the information during the entire presentation time. Observers might disengage before stimulus presentation ends (i.e, encoding time might be shorter than presentation time), which could explain the plateauing of performance. In a self-paced task design though, much like in natural behavior, the viewing time will likely reflect the actual encoding time more closely, as we assume that when observers are free to look at other relevant information they will do so when they are done encoding. There are also studies regarding retention times (or memory decay), which have shown that longer retention times (perhaps unsurprisingly) result in worse memory performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Donkin et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Oberauer &amp; Lewandowsky, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Rademaker et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Schurgin et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Souza &amp; Oberauer, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Souza et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zhang &amp; Luck, 2009</ref>). Yet, to the best of our knowledge, no working memory study has directly investigated interactions between encoding times and delays. For example, one possible interaction might be that longer encoding times produce more robust representations (i.e. representations which decay slower). In the related research field of long-term memory though, the equivalent interaction has been studied. There are studies reporting a slower rate of forgetting, with a higher degree of initial learning (A. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Baddeley et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Stamate et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Yang et al., 2016</ref>). Yet, there are also studies reporting the opposite: equal forgetting rates regardless of initial degree of learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Allen et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Rivera-Lares et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Slamecka &amp; McElree, 1983)</ref>.</p><p>Apparently the findings in the long-term memory field are diverging, and do not strongly steer our expectations for current questions regarding working memory. Furthermore, most long term memory studies also typically apply temporally rigid paradigms -albeit with much longer durations. To fill the gap of knowledge about the temporal development of working memories in everyday contexts, we employed a self-paced paradigm which allows for, and encourages a more natural use of VWM.</p><p>There have been a handful of studies, which investigated VWM use in a self-paced task design <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Ballard et al., 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Böing et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Draschkow et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Fu &amp; Gray, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Hayhoe et al., 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Hoogerbrugge et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Koevoet et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Melnik et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Morgan et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Sahakian et al., 2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Sahakian et al., , 2024</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Somai et al., 2020)</ref>. Most of these studies employed some variation of a "copying task". The goal for a participant in such a task is typically to recreate an arrangement of items from an example (which is somewhat reminiscent of assembling a jigsaw puzzle by looking at the cover). Participants pick up items from a separate item pool and position them within an initially empty workspace to copy the example arrangement. Importantly, participants are allowed to look at the example as often and as long as they want. Akin to typical VWM experiments, participants in this paradigm need to encode information in VWM, retain this information for some time and utilize it. The way in which this task engages VWM, however, is much more similar to daily VWM use: the visual environment is stable and accessible for inspection at any time. Therefore, participants do not need to memorize all information that will become relevant for imminent action, but can choose to memorize only part of it, and encode the rest later (contrast this to the typical VWM paradigm in which all information must be memorized within a predetermined short time frame, after which the information will not be available anymore) (Van der Stigchel, 2020). Of particular importance to the present study, in the copying task participants are also free to choose how long they encode information into VWM, and how long they wait before they apply this memorized information. Due to the self-paced nature of the task and the various strategies that are used, a natural spread in delays emerges. Everything considered, this task paradigm is ideally suited to answer the three questions we posed before. First: "How does the representation strength of information develop (increase) over time as it is in view?", second: "How does the representation strength develop (degrade) over time as information is retained?", and third: "How does the viewing time affect the degradation of representations over time?" Despite the fact that multiple studies employing the copying task paradigm have been conducted, these questions are yet to be addressed. Regarding previous copying task studies of ours in particular <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Sahakian et al., 2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Sahakian et al., , 2024</ref>, the experimental set-up did not allow to monitor viewing times for individual items. Therefore, questions about encoding time and decay times of individual items could not be addressed. We designed the current experiment to overcome these previous limitations: here we precisely tracked which individual items were viewed, for how long they were viewed, and whether successful utilization of the items ensued.</p><p>In our study we had participants perform a computer task in which they recreated arrangements consisting of 8 items in a 4 by 4 grid. In order to track where (more specifically: at which item) participants were looking, we limited their view of the to-be-copied example grid: they could only see a small (item-sized) area around the mouse cursor. Previous work showed that using such a cursor-directed aperture in copying task paradigms <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Sahakian et al., 2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Sahakian et al., , 2024</ref>, produced very similar viewing behavior to other studies which employed eye-tracking <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Ballard et al., 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Draschkow et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Somai et al., 2020)</ref>. By tracking, for each to-be-copied item, how long it was viewed, and whether or not that item was subsequently copied or not, we derived how the duration of viewing individual items predicted the ability to successfully apply the encoded information. Furthermore, by tracking the time between the end of a view and the (un)successful application of the viewed item, we derived how the delay predicted the ability to successfully apply the encoded information.</p><p>To briefly summarize our main results: First, we found that memory performance increased with longer viewing times, but only up to a certain duration (about 750 ms) after which further prolongation of the viewing times did not lead to better performance. Second, we found that memory performance monotonically decreased with longer delays. Lastly, and most interestingly, we found that even though longer views did not lead to better performance on the short term (i.e, when it would be applied immediately), longer views did create more robust memories, which were successfully applied after long delays. An open question at this point was whether this pattern of results would generalize to typical VWM paradigms. Results from two additional experiments employing typical VWM paradigms (i.e., with a forced report after fixed viewing times and delays), suggested that it does not; longer views did not create more robust memories in typical VWM experiments with forced choice responses and fixed viewing times. In the General Discussion, we suggest that the influence of viewing time on decay (as observed in the copying task alone) is specific to open-ended tasks, where participants can choose to withhold their response when certainty about a memory item drops below a critical threshold. This study provides the first steps to a comprehensive understanding of visual working memory use in natural interactions with the environment. Particularly, we argue that considering the self-paced nature of our interactions is essential to capture the temporal dynamics of naturalistic working memory use.</p><p>2 Experiment 1: A naturalistic VWM task</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Methods</head><p>The methods are very similar, and in some aspects identical to previously published studies from our lab <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Sahakian et al., 2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Sahakian et al., , 2024</ref>. We report the full methods here, but note that parts in this section may be paraphrased or copied from the methods sections of those articles.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1">Participants</head><p>Data of 49 participants were collected. We included the data of 46 participants (35 females and 10 males) in the formal analyses. The mean age of the included participants was </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2">Apparatus and stimuli</head><p>The experiment was scripted using the JavaScript libraries jsPsych version 7.3.0 (de Leeuw, 2015) and Fabric.js version 5.2.4 (fabricjs.com). We used Gorilla to build and run the experiment (Anwyl-Irvine et al., 2020). Despite using tools primarily meant for online experiments, we ran this experiment in the lab. Data was collected in two identical rooms.</p><p>Both rooms had a Windows PC connected to a Dell monitor (model: P2419H; screen size: the Google Chrome (version 108) or Microsoft Edge (version 109) browser. Participants used a computer mouse to complete the task.</p><p>The twenty shapes of the items were adapted from stimuli used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Arnoult (1956)</ref>.</p><p>The twenty colors were selected from the HSLuv color space (www.hsluv.org). Specifically, we selected 20 perceptually equidistant hues (starting at a hue value of 3.59 degrees, and adding 17.95 degrees to get the next hue value) on the color wheel, with the saturation set to 89.1% and luminance to 64.35% (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1)</ref>.</p><p>In order to track what part of the experimental display participants were looking at in this online study, we implemented a cursor-directed aperture in our task <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Anwyl-Irvine et al., 2021)</ref>. Effectively, this meant that a black overlay covered the view of the display, and only a circular area surrounding the location of the cursor was made transparent (see <ref type="figure">Figure 2B</ref> and <ref type="figure">Figure 2C</ref>; or see https://osf.io/5pj8b for a demonstration video). The aperture was small (the size of an item) in the Model area, and was large (the size of a 4x4 grid) in the Workspace and Resource area. Specifically, the radius of aperture was set to respectively 3% or 15% of the width of the light gray experiment rectangle. The edge of the circular aperture was blurred by applying a Gaussian filter with a standard deviation equal to 10% of the radius of the aperture. The experience of the participant was similar to looking around in a darkened environment using a focal flashlight. The location of the aperture was recorded 60 times per second. To provide a cue as to where the Model grid was, a green outline of the Model was always visible. Without the outline it was unnecessarily hard for participants to determine in which cell an item was, as they had no overview of the entire Model grid. The twenty shapes and twenty colors that were combined to create the stimuli in the experiment. Given 20 shapes and 20 colors, we could create 400 unique stimuli. For each trial, a random selection (without replacement) of four shapes and four colors was used to create 16 unique stimuli (with the restriction that any two colors were at least 3 hues apart). From this pool of 16 stimuli, 8 were randomly selected (with replacement), and randomly positioned in the Model grid for each trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.3">Procedure</head><p>After giving informed consent, reading the instructions and completing two practice trials (one with a complete view of the task, and one with a black overlay and a cursor-directed aperture), participants started the main task. The goal in every trial was to recreate an arrangement of eight items in a four-by-four grid, called the Model grid. Participants did this by dragging and dropping items from the Resource grid onto the Workspace grid (see <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>). When an item was placed in its correct location it would be locked in place.</p><p>When an items was placed incorrectly, however, the item would fly back to its original place in the Resource grid. Once the eight items were correctly placed in the Workspace the trial was completed and the participant could move on to the next trial. There were <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Overview of a trial in Experiment 1. Panel A shows an overview of the task display. There were three relevant four-by-four grids. From left to right they were the Model-, Workspace-and Resource grid. The Model needed to be recreated in the Workspace using the items from the Resource. The items were picked up and dragged to the correct location in the Model grid using the computer mouse. Panel B shows the task view during experimental trials. A black overlay covered the entire task display. Only a circular area, always centered on the mouse cursor, was made visible. While the aperture was in the Model area (i.e., left of the dark gray bar) the aperture was just large enough to see one item. Panel C again shows the task view during experimental trials, but when the cursor was in the Workspace and Resource area (i.e., right of the dark gray bar). Here the aperture was much larger: it provided complete view of the Workspace grid. See https://osf.io/5pj8b for a demonstration video. random sample of four different colors (with the restriction that the distance between any two colors was at least 3) was used to generate 16 unique items (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>). These 16 items comprised the Resource grid. On each trial a new Model grid was created by selecting eight items (with replacement) from the Resource grid, and placing them in six different locations. Selecting items with replacement entailed that the same item might have occurred more than once in a Model grid.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.4">Measures</head><p>The two main measures were the viewing time and delay of individual items. To facilitate interpretation, we split the task execution into two alternating phases: 1) Viewing sessions, the phase in which the aperture was in the Model area and items were inspected; and 2) Building sessions, the phase in which the aperture was in the Workspace and Resources areas and items were dragged to the Workspace. To finish a trial, a participant would typically cycle through multiple repetitions of such sessions. We defined the viewing time of an item to be the time the cursor (i.e., the center point of the circular aperture) was inside the cell that contained the item. This would be the time that an item was visible to the participant. 1 As the same item may have been inspected multiple times (within an viewing session and across multiple viewing sessions) our final outcome measure for viewing time was the sum of all viewing times of the item (i.e., the cumulative viewing time). We 1 By this procedure instances where the aperture moved across an item's cell were also labeled as (very short) views. To remove such cases we implemented an additional rule that only views which were longer than 120 ms were labeled as views. The threshold of 120 ms was chosen as the most reasonable value based on the distribution of all viewing times. We realize that this is an arbitrary choice, and therefore we performed our main analyses with other thresholds that were within a reasonable range (specifically: 60, 80, 100, 140, 160, 180 ms). We found that all options produced equivalent results. We report these results in Supplementary material A.</p><p>ignored the views of an item after it was placed correctly in the Workspace.</p><p>We defined the delay of an viewed item (our second measure), to be the time from the end of the view of the item until that item was correctly placed. At the end of a Building session, some items that were inspected were not placed. For these items, the delay was the time from the end of the most recent view until the end of the building session. Note that we disregard errors: we are only interested in whether or not viewed items ended up being placed or not.</p><p>At the end of each building session, we listed the items that were (at some point) inspected</p><p>and not yet placed at the start of this building session. Some of these inspected items would be correctly placed at the end of this building session, and some would not be placed. For each inspected item (correctly placed or not) we would then determine its view time and delay as described above. Note that this procedure will result in some items appearing multiple times in the list.</p><p>To illustrate the procedure, we provide an example with (arbitrarily chosen) data (see ended; then item C is placed after 5.3 seconds after the end of item C's view ended; then this building session ends at t=24.0 as the aperture enters the Model area again, without item A and D being placed. The list will be extended by these items with the associated viewing and delay times (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Table of raw data points. This is an illustration of the structure of the data from a trial in a copying task. Each row represents the information (viewing time and delay) and fate (whether it is placed or not) of an item that is inspected during an viewing session. Note that these values match with the schematic overview of the measures shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>. Note that the delay of an item always starts immediately when the viewing of that item ends. The delay either ends when that item is placed, or at the end of the building session.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.5">Analysis</head><p>To predict whether an item was placed or not, based on the viewing time and delay, we conducted a generalized linear mixed model (GLMM) analysis using the Wilkinson nota-tion: Placed ∼ Viewing time * Delay + n-th Trial + n-th Viewing session + (1 + Viewing time * Delay | Participant ). We also added the trial number and the viewing session as predictors. We used a logit function to fit the data, as we are dealing with a binomial outcome measure: an item was successfully placed or it was not. Using a GLMM is preferable as it allows us to consider each data point (i.e., a row from the table as illustrated in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). The alternative would be to pool data into arbitrarily sized bins, which might inadvertently introduce biases. We used the lme4 package in R to run the GLMM analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Bates et al., 2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Results</head><p>Our primary interest was how viewing time and delay affect VWM performance. But to get a general sense of how participant approached the task we first report the summary statistics of participants' behavior in the task. Participants took on average 44 (SD = 7.6) seconds to complete a single trial (i.e. copying one arrangement of 8 items). On average, participants needed 6.3 (SD = 1.4) viewing sessions per trial, and took 12 (SD = 3.9) seconds per trial to view items. Finally, participants made on average 0.85 (SD = 0.57) errors per trial. These basic behavioral measures were comparable to previous (online) studies employing a similar task from our lab <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Sahakian et al., 2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Sahakian et al., , 2024</ref>.</p><p>The results regarding the temporal dynamics show that the probability to successfully place an item significantly increased as the viewing times were longer (β = 0.65; SE = 0.12; z-value = 5.42; p &lt; 0.001). In a GLMM the estimates (or the β) represents log odds, which are not straightforward to interpret. Raising e to the power of a log odds value gives an odds ratio (e log odds = odds ratio), which is easier to interpret. The interpretation is as follows:  the chance to successfully place an item was e 0.65 = 1.92 times as large for every additional second the item was viewed (or the chance increases by 92% per second of viewing time).</p><p>Furthermore, the results show that the probability to successfully place an item significantly decreased when delays were longer (β = -0.34; SE = 0.028; z-value = -12.11; p &lt; 0.001).</p><p>This should be interpreted as the chance to successfully place an item was e −0.34 = 0.71 times as large for every additional second of delay (or the chance decreases by 29% per second of delay). Finally the results show that there is a significant interaction between the viewing time and delay (β = 0.075; SE = 0.018; z-value = 4.30; p &lt; 0.001). An interaction means that the rate of change in VWM performance due to one variable is dependent on the other variable. Putting numbers to it, we interpret this interaction as follows: For every second of viewing time the β of delay increases by 0.075. Thus, with longer viewing times the decay during delay becomes slower.</p><p>Although binning data depends on arbitrary choices, it does make it easier to visualize general patterns (see <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> and <ref type="figure">Figure 7)</ref>. So to visualize the VWM representation strength across viewing time and delay, we binned all listed items (across all participants and all trials) into nine bins based on the items' viewing times (short, medium and long) and their delays (short, medium and long). In each of the nine bins we computed the proportion of correctly placed items, by dividing the number of correctly placed items in the bin by the total number of items in the bin (i.e., the sum of correctly placed items and the not placed items).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Interim Discussion</head><p>In Experiment 1, we investigated how the time spent viewing visual information, and the time this information was retained before being used, jointly impacted memory performance.</p><p>Importantly, we did so in a task that naturally engages VWM, and does not enforce any specific viewing or memorization strategies. Relating the independent measures of viewing time and delay to the memory performance showcases three distinct findings. First, in line with studies manipulating presentation times of memory arrays, the memory performance initially increases with longer viewing times but performance plateaus quickly, which means that from a certain encoding duration onward there is no direct benefit of viewing any longer. Second, in line with studies manipulating delay periods, memory performance decays quickly after presentation ends, which means that it is advantageous to utilize memorized information as quickly as possible. Third, and arguably most interesting, we show there is an interaction between viewing time and delay on memory performance: after short viewing times performance decays faster than after longer viewing times, which means that if you need to retain information for a long time it pays to look for longer.</p><p>Intrigued by this finding, we sought to further investigate the interaction between viewing time and delay, asking whether this interaction is fundamental to the buildup and decay of VWM representations, or specific to strategical VWM use as allowed for by self-paced <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: VWM performance in Experiment 1 across both viewing times and delay. The y axes represent the memory performance in the copying task. More specifically, it shows the percentage of cases in which an item was viewed, and a successful action followed (i.e., placing the item in the correct grid cell). Each point represents all values within a range of viewing times and a range of delays. Viewing times were duration an individual items was viewed. The delay was the time from the point an item was no longer viewed until the item was placed, or until a new viewing session began. The error bars represent the 95% confidence intervals of the participant means.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>task.</head><p>To address this question we employed a typical (i.e., temporally rigid) VWM task.</p><p>We chose to base our paradigm on a continuous color report task used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Schurgin et al., 2020</ref>, as they demonstrated a presentation time and delay effect on memory strength using this paradigm. Crucially, though, Schurgin et al., 2020 manipulated presentation times separately from delay periods, making it impossible to investigate the aforementioned interaction. We therefore implement this paradigm, but manipulated both presentation times and delay periods simultaneously, in a within-participants design.</p><p>4 Experiment 2A: A typical rigid VWM task</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">Participants</head><p>We recruited participants via Prolific (www.prolific.co), a platform for recruiting participants for online studies. Using Prolific's screening tool, we made our study available to participants who (1) reported to have no issue seeing colors, (2) were fluent in English, (3) were aged 18-35, (4) were located in the UK, and (5) had an approval rate higher of at least 95%. We incrementally included participants to the online study to reach the predetermined number of 60 participants. In total we collected data of 66 participants and excluded 6 of them from formal analysis because of incomplete data (either due to early quitting, or a technical failure to correctly save all online data).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Apparatus and stimuli</head><p>The task was generally based on the "Continuous colour report" task described in Schurgin et al., 2020. We coded the task and hosted it in Gorilla (Anwyl-Irvine et al., 2020), using the jsPsych (version 7.3) (de Leeuw, 2015) and the custom plugin "jspsych-psychophysics" <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Kuroki, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>We selected 360 colors from the HSLuv color space (www.hsluv.org). The hue values ranged from 0 up to 359 in steps of 1, the saturation value was fixed at 90, and the luminance value was fixed at 70. We ensured that any two colors presented in the same trial were more than 15 hue values separated from each other.</p><p>The memory items were colored circles with a radius of 32 pixels <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6</ref>. They could appear at one of six fixed placeholder locations at an eccentricity of 140 pixels from a central fixation cross.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.3">Procedure and design</head><p>After being presented the instructions and completing four practice trials, participants completed the experimental trials. In each trial, a participant was presented with either 1 or 3 items, then after a delay, one of the items' locations was emboldened, prompting the participant to report the color of the indicated item (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6</ref>). Participants could report the color on a continuous color wheel (specifically, 360 options), using their mouse.</p><p>A ball moved around the color wheel as the cursor moved around the central fixation cross.</p><p>The ball had the color of that part of the color wheel it was on, indicating the current selected color. Participants moved their mouse to select a color and confirmed their report by clicking.</p><p>We manipulated our two factors of primary interest, presentation time and delay, within participants; but we manipulated set size between participants. The memory items were presented for either 0.1, 1.1 or 2.1 seconds; and were then removed for a delay period of 2, 4, or 6 seconds. Half of the participants were presented with 1 item in each trial, and the other half with 3 items. For each of the 9 combinations of a presentation time and delay, there were 33 trials, resulting in 297 trials per participant. The order of the trials was randomized.</p><p>Due to a randomization error, for each participant only a set of 9 unique trials (comprising all combinations of the 3 presentation times and 3 delay conditions) was generated and presented. This entailed that in all cases where the presentation time was 1.1 s and the delay 6 s, the same set of colors in the same locations was presented and the same items was probed. This held for each of the 9 unique combinations of presentation times and delays. All participants, therefore, repeated each of their 9 trials 33 times in an intermixed fashion. 2 The colored circles were presented for 0.1, 1.1, or 2.1 seconds. After a delay of either 2, 4, or 6 seconds during which the colors were not visible, a color wheel appeared and the probed location was made bold. Participants had to report the color of the probed item, by clicking on a specific hue on the color wheel. In Experiment 2B (right) participants had to memorize the color of a single square. The square could appear on the perimeter of a virtual circle around the fixation cross. The colored square was presented for 0.1, 0.5, or 2 seconds. After a delay of either 0.1, 0.5, 1, 4, or 10 seconds during which the square was not visible, a color wheel appeared. Participants had to report the color of the square by clicking on a hue on the color wheel. Please note that the specific stimulus features in this figure panel (sizes, colors, locations, etc.) do not exactly match those of the actual experiment. For the precise methods we refer to the methods section of <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Donkin et al., 2015.</ref> We performed a Bayesian Linear Regression in JASP (JASP Team, 2023). The dependent variable was the precision of the reports on the color wheel. Precision was computed as the reciprocal of the circular standard deviation, minus the expected value if all responses would be purely random <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Bays et al., 2011)</ref>. As such a precision of 0 corresponds to random guesses, and higher values correspond to qualitatively better reports. Furthermore, we used the Model Terms: presentation time, delay, set size, and an interaction term of presentation time and delay. We use the BF inclusion across matched models of the Posterior summaries as evidence for or against an effect. We used the default settings for the analysis in the JASP software, and we set the seed value to 1 for reproducibility. We conform to the labels suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Kass and Raftery, 1995</ref> for the interpretation of Bayes factors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results</head><p>We found decisive evidence for a main effect of presentation time (β = 1.29; 95% Cred. <ref type="bibr">Int. = [0.73,</ref><ref type="bibr">2.29]</ref>; BF incl = 2.49 × 10 7 ). This means that for every additional second an item was presented the precision increased by 1.29 (see <ref type="figure">Figure Figure 7</ref>). We found no conclusive evidence for a main effect of delay (β = -0.03; 95% Cred. <ref type="bibr">0.22]</ref>;</p><p>BF incl = 1.17). This entails that we cannot draw conclusions about the effect of delay on the precision of the responses. We found decisive evidence for a main effect of set size (β = -1.00; 95% Cred. ; BF incl = 4.06 × 10 8 ). This means that for every additional item that was presented the precision decreased by 1.00. Finally, we found no conclusive evidence for an interaction effect of presentation time and delay (β = <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>: Precision of responses in Experiment 2A and Experiment 2B.</p><p>Note that the data of Experiment 2A (left) is the pooled data of the set size one and set size three conditions. Also note that in Experiment 2B (right) there were 5 delays, but for the sake of clarity of the visualization we pooled the data of the 0.1, 0.5 and 1 second delay conditions (which had very similar precision). The precision of the responses was computed as the reciprocal of the circular standard deviation (1 / cSD) of the errors, minus the expected value if all reports would be random. The error bars represent the 95% confidence intervals of the participant means.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Interim Discussion</head><p>In a typical, temporally rigid VWM task, we parametrically manipulated the presentation times of memory items and of the delays until a forced memory report. Under these task circumstances we found no evidence for an interaction between presentation time and delay on VWM performance. Even though the main effect of presentation time was evidently present, the main effect for delay was much less so. The lack of an effect for delay might therefore hide the potentially present interaction effect between presentation time and delay.</p><p>Possibly our experiment contained too few trials per delay condition (99 versus 300 in the experiment by <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Schurgin et al., 2020)</ref> to produce a reliable effect of delay. Our choice of the number of trials per condition was limited by the maximum duration of the online experiment. Fortunately, a published study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Donkin et al., 2015</ref>, employed a paradigm quite similar to Experiment 2A of this study. Although their experiment aimed to answer very different question, it was also suited to answer our question: whether, in a temporally rigid VWM task, presentation times determined the rate of decay of VWM representations.</p><p>6 Experiment 2B: Reanalysis of Donkin et al., 2015</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Methods</head><p>For the full methods we refer to the original article <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Donkin et al., 2015)</ref>. For our current purposes we describe only the relevant sections. Generally this paradigm is very similar to the set size 1 condition of Experiment 2A. On standard trials 3 participants were presented with one colored square for a variable presentation time, and after a variable delay period reported the specific hue of the square on a continuous color wheel. There were 3 presentation times: 0.1, 0.5 and 2 seconds; and there were 5 delays: 0.1, 0.5, 1, 4, 10 seconds. Each combination of presentation time and delay occurred 90 times for each participant in a randomly intermixed order. Eight participants completed this study in a lab.</p><p>The analysis was almost identical to that of Experiment 2A. The only difference was that we could not consider a set size effect, as the set size was always one in this study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Results</head><p>We found decisive evidence for a main effect of presentation time (β = 1.11; 95% Cred. <ref type="bibr">Int. = [0.66,</ref><ref type="bibr">1.54]</ref>; BF incl = 3.68 × 10 5 ). This means that every additional second an item was presented the precision increased by 1.11 (see <ref type="figure">Figure Figure 7</ref>). We found </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Interim Discussion</head><p>Using a previously published dataset we aimed to find whether longer presentation times for visual information results in a slower decay of VWM representations, akin to the findings of Experiment 1. Importantly, we were now specifically interested in whether this was the case in rigid VWM tasks. In the reanalysis of Donkin et al., 2015 we found very strong evidence for both an effect of presentation time, and of delay. In contrast to Experiment 1, however, we did not find conclusive evidence in favor of an interaction suggesting that the quality or strength of the VWM representations degraded at a similar rate, regardless of the time they had been presented.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">General Discussion</head><p>In this study we investigated how self-paced viewing times and delays jointly determine how memories are formed and how they fade. Although the time courses of memory buildup and memory decay have been studied before, they have mainly been studied separately. What is more, they have exclusively been studied in temporally rigid experimental designs. These rigid paradigms have been unable to capture an essential aspect of naturalistic working memory use: in almost all our daily memory-guided behavior, our interactions are selfpaced, rather than enforced on us. This self-paced nature of our interactions might elicit a very different behavior than researchers have measured thus far in the lab. To fill this gap we employed a copying task, in which participants recreated an (always accessible) example arrangement of items in an empty space. In this task, participants were not restricted in the choice or number of items to memorize or report, nor in the amount of time spent encoding or retaining these items in memory before placing them on the workspace grid.</p><p>By using such an open-ended visual working memory (VWM) task, we evoked a widerange of self-paced viewing times and delays, much like one would encounter in everyday human behavior. With the current paradigm, we replicated two main findings from previous literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Bays et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Brady et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">de Jong et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Donkin et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Oberauer &amp; Lewandowsky, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Souza &amp; Oberauer, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Souza et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zhang &amp; Luck, 2009)</ref>: (1) an initial increase in memory performance, which eventually plateaued as, viewing times increased beyond a second, and (2) a monotonic decrease in memory performance as delays increased . Importantly, we found an interaction between viewing time and delay on memory performance that has not been reported before in the shortterm memory literature: as viewing times increased, the rate of decay became slower. This interaction is reminiscent of the age-old adage of teachers: "If you shortly study for an exam the night before, you might pass the next day but you will have forgotten everything the next week. But when you study for longer, you will pass the exam and you will likely remember what you learned for the years to come." We therefore subsequently hypothesized that the interaction might be a fundamental attribute of working memory representations -this claim has been made after all for long-term memory representations <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Yang et al., 2016)</ref>. To our surprise, however, one experiment (Experiment 2A) and one reanalysis of a previously published study (Experiment 2B) -both using typically rigid paradigmsshowed converging evidence that the precision of visual working memory representations do not follow the same pattern: The precision of representations degraded at the same rate regardless of the time visual information was presented. This leads us to conclude that the interaction we find using a naturalistic paradigm does not reflect a fundamental attribute of VWM representations. In the light of our previously proposed model describing naturalistic VWM use <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Sahakian et al., 2023)</ref>, we discuss two distinct mechanisms that could potentially reconcile the emergence of an interaction in naturalistic VWM task and an absence hereof in rigid force-choice experiments. We first briefly explain our model, and then discuss the two explanatory mechanisms.</p><p>In previous studies we have introduced and expanded on the Mountains of Memory (MoM) model of VWM use in day-to-day behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Sahakian et al., 2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Sahakian et al., , 2024</ref>. In short, this model describes whether or not an observer will choose to utilize memory content, or to re-examine the external world instead. This decision is determined by the certainty (or knowledge about the quality) of the VWM content, and a context-dependent action threshold. The certainty of the memory content can be thought of as a mountainous landscape, where different stimulus features (i.e., color, shape, etc.) exist in different locations of the landscape, and the height of the peaks at each location describes the amount of certainty for the memory representation of that feature; the higher the peak, the more likely an observer is to (correctly) report the corresponding feature. In this analogy, the action threshold, thought of as the height of a sea inundating the landscape, determines what memory content is deemed good enough to act on in a given situation (i.e., parts of the landscape above sea level). In our work so far, we have used this model to describe differences in VWM use between conditions (e.g., a condition in which actions are penalized more severely than another, thus increasing the threshold for action). Importantly, in this earlier work, we considered the certainty of the representations only at a single point in time:</p><p>the (virtual) moment at which a decision is made. In the current study which considers the whole time range, the findings highlight the sometimes counter-intuitive influence of an action threshold on VWM use, when memory representations decay over time. Specifically, we postulate that the simple concept of an action threshold (which determines whether or not observers will act upon VWM content) can explain the observed interaction of memory performance between viewing time and delay in VWM use, even if VWM representations themselves would buildup and decay in a non-interactive manner.</p><p>The first mechanism which might explain the emergence of an interaction in naturalistic VWM task, is that actions are never forced in the naturalistic VWM task, while in the rigid task actions are always forced (we provide a visual explanation in <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>). In the copying task, participants repeatedly choose whether to act on a memory (i.e., pick up an item and place it somewhere). In some cases (when confident of their memory) they might try to place an item, in other cases (when unsure of their memory) they might choose not to place an item but have a look at the example again. In our MoM model, the Action threshold indicates the minimal required certainty to act on memory content. Indeed, previous work has shown that when participants look at the example again, memory is not fully depleted, as participants have some residual (albeit unsure) memories of items <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Sahakian et al., 2023</ref>). In the copying task, not acting on a memory that is there (because the certainty does not exceed the Action threshold) leads to a worse performance measure: we register that no successful action followed an item view. Compare this to not filling in an answer in a multiple-choice test on questions you are unsure of your answer: Not filling in an answer, likewise, leads to a worse performance measure on the test (compared to always filling in your best guess). In contrast, in typical VWM tasks, actions (or responses) are forced (akin to an action threshold that is infinitely low): Participants provide their best guess every time the memory is probed. For forced report designs, this means that with decreasing representation strength (e.g., due to increasing delays), the outcome measure gradually decreases. In free report designs, however, with decreasing representation strength (or certainty), the outcome measure also gradually decreases until the certainty falls below the Action threshold. From that point onward, the outcome measure drops sharply to zero, as no actions are undertaken. This non-linear relation between memory decay and the outcome measure in free report paradigms (such as the copying task) give rise to an interaction, because the action threshold is reached later when the initial memory certainty was high, and is reached earlier when the initial memory certainty was low (see <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>).</p><p>The second possible reason, is the amount of interference during the delay period <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Oberauer &amp; Lin, 2023)</ref>. While in the continuous recall tasks there is only a blank screen to look at, in the copying task, participants see and do much more in the delay period (i.e, memorize other items, search for and place items). Perhaps, knowing that there will be visual interference and other mentally demanding actions, prompts participants to encode the task relevant information much better, in anticipation of various distractions. Therefore, specifically in the naturalistic task, participants might use longer viewing times to generate more robust representations which remain strong enough to use after prolonged periods. In typical paradigms, there is less interference and the interference is predictable and uniform across conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Bays et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Schurgin et al., 2020)</ref>. A predictable and uniform interference in all conditions (common in typical VWM tasks) likely encourages a uniform encoding strategy in all conditions.</p><p>Regarding the paradigm of the main task (i.e. the copying task in Experiment 1), it is worth noting why the self-paced behavior is so relevant in making this task more naturalistic.</p><p>Almost all prior studies devoted to temporal dynamics of VWM enforce a preset temporal structure (e.g., several presentations times, or a few forced delay durations) <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Bays et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Donkin et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Oberauer &amp; Lewandowsky, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Rademaker et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Schurgin et al., 2020)</ref>. Although this approach might give good estimates of the VWM performance at the time points being probed, there is a draw back as well: Especially for longer presentation times, it might be unclear whether participants are attentively encoding the visual stimulus for the entire period it is presented. Perhaps, participants might feel after a short while that they encoded the stimulus well enough, and for the rest of the <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>: The emergence of an interaction due to the nature of a task. This schematic shows how an interaction can emerge between the effect of viewing times and the effect of delays on performance in free report paradigms (like the copying task in Experiment 1), while there is no interaction in equivalent forced report paradigms (like the typical VWM tasks in Experiment 2A and 2B). Panel A illustrates how two traces of certainty decline gradually over a delay period. The green line shows the certainty of an item which was viewed for longer and thus had a higher certainty to begin with. The orange line shows the certainty of an item which was viewed for shorter. The blue line and shaded area mark the "Action threshold": when the certainty of a memory drops below the line, it will not be acted upon. Panel B shows the decline of performance in a free report paradigm. Performance in such tasks are generally measured by whether a successful action took place. At the two time points where the respective certainties drop below the action threshold, no actions take place and as such the performance measure for "successful actions" drops to zero. Panel C shows the decline of performance in a forced report paradigm. Performance in such tasks are generally measured by the quality of the reports (e.g. precision, accuracy, etc.). As the responses are forced the Action threshold becomes irrelevant (or more accurately, in forced choice tasks the Action threshold is lowered to zero), and performance tracks certainty of the memories. Note that the light blue shaded areas in the bottom two plots are only there to help marking the moments at which the certainties would drop below the action threshold, and should not be interpreted as the action threshold (as the action threshold is measured in certainty, not in performance).</p><p>The two smaller plots on the right, show the performance of the two types of tasks (free vs. forced report) at two delays (t1 and t2). The y-axis labels mimic the performance measures of Experiment 1 and Experiment 2. In the upper right plot (representing a copying task), there is an interaction between viewing time and delay, while in the lower right plot (representing a typical VWM task) there is no interaction.</p><p>period they stop encoding. After all, in natural viewing conditions humans make about 3 eye movements per second, meaning they keep their gaze at one point generally for only a few hundred milliseconds <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Henderson, 2003)</ref>. VWM is therefore not attuned to work in the context of being forced to look at objects for a predetermined period of time. In the current copying task, participants determine themselves how long they fixate a stimulus, which is far more in line with everyday use of VWM. Moreover, the viewing time probably reflects the true encoding duration better, under the assumption that participants stop looking when they are done encoding.</p><p>Despite the obvious advantages of the self-paced nature of our main task, this design choice also obscured some interesting aspects about the buildup and decay of VWM content.</p><p>In our analyses we did not consider the events that happened during the delay period. A few examples of what could happen during the delay are: (1) other items might be viewed, thus loading up VWM even more, (2) other items might be placed, thus activating and acting on other VWM content, or (3) time might be spent on deciding what to do, thus increasing the delay duration. Of course, all these processes are not mutually exclusive. As such, the contribution of these individual processes to the decay of VWM representations is hard to disentangle. Future research into the role of viewing time and delay on VWM-based actions will shed more light onto the temporal aspects of the buildup and decay of memories.</p><p>From a broader perspective, the time course of the buildup and decay of visual memories is likely related to the way information is gathered: how long objects are inspected, and if (and when) are they reinspected? It has been argued before that the amount of information humans internalize (i.e., encode in working memory) and how much they leave in the external world to be internalized later, depends on a trade-off between the costs associated to internalizing and the costs associated to leaving information in the external world <ref type="bibr">(O'regan, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Somai et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Van der Stigchel, 2020)</ref>. In this framework, how long information is looked at can be regarded as a cost associated with internalizing information. In the context of such a trade-off, the time invested in viewing information is an important factor: looking for longer presumably strengthens the memory, but depending on the context the amount of time available might be limited. Furthermore, as viewing time increases the added benefit of viewing for longer diminishes. Having an understanding of how the viewing duration determines how well information is stored can reveal what the optimal course of action is in the trade-off between internalizing information or leaving it externally. In the same vein, how quickly information fades away from VWM might affect this trade-off as well: if one needs to retain information for a prolonged time, it is worth to invest more time in looking. Studying temporal dynamics in naturalistic contexts can thus open new avenues for instructing people with memory deficits to better deal with their impairment. Beyond clinical relevance, these findings can also be relevant for professionals doing VWM-demanding work under time pressure (e.g. air traffic controllers, radiologists).</p><p>In sum, we investigated how the time spent looking at visual information and the time that this information was kept in VWM jointly determine how memories are put to use. By employing a self-paced, naturalistic VWM task, we replicated two key findings of typical VWM studies, and revealed a third and novel finding: (1) with increasing viewing time, performance gets better until it plateaus; (2): performance deteriorates with increasing delays, and (3) we uniquely show that in a naturalistic tasks, performance deteriorates slower following longer viewing times. We also showed that a slower deterioration of performance after longer viewing times does not stem from the way pure VWM representations develop</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>21.3 (SD = 1.59). The experiment was approved by the Ethics Committee of the Faculty of Social and Behavioural Sciences of Utrecht University. The approval is filed under numbers 23-1027 and 23-0605. All participants gave informed consent before beginning the task. They either received course-credits or participated voluntarily without monetary compensation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The twenty shapes and twenty colors that were combined to create the stimuli in the experiment. Given 20 shapes and 20 colors, we could create 400 unique stimuli. For each trial, a random selection (without replacement) of four shapes and four colors was used to create 16 unique stimuli (with the restriction that any two colors were at least 3 hues apart). From this pool of 16 stimuli, 8 were randomly selected (with replacement), and randomly positioned in the Model grid for each trial.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 )</head><label>3</label><figDesc>. Let us say a trials starts at time point t=0.0 s. Some time into the trial, a viewing session starts at time point t=15.0 s, first item A is inspected for 0.3 seconds (t=15.2 s -t=15.5 s), then item B for 0.5 seconds (t=15.8 s -t=16.3 s), C for 1.2 s (t=16.6 s -t=17.8 s), and finally item D is inspected for 0.6 seconds (t=18.1 s -t=18.7 s). In the building session that follows, item B is placed 4.5 seconds after the end of item B's view</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Schematic overview of the temporal measures in Experiment 1. This overview shows the events during a trial in a copying task on a time line, and matches the timings of events shown inTable 1. The yellow outlined bar represents a "viewing session": the time during which the aperture hovered over the Model area. During a viewing session, individual items are viewed. The filled yellow bars represent the time an individual item is viewed. The yellow arrows above the bars again represent the duration each item was viewed for. The blue outlined bar represents a "building session": the time the time during which the aperture hovered over the Workspace and Resource area. The vertical blue lines in the building session indicate that an item was (correctly) placed. The blue arrows above indicate the duration of the delay.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>VWM performance in Experiment 1. The y-axes represent the memory performance in the copying task. More specifically, it shows the percentage of cases in which an item that was viewed was subsequently placed in the correct grid cell. On the left, the performance is shown over increasing viewing times. Each point represents a bin, as viewing times had a continuous spread. On the right, the performance is shown over increasing delays. A delay is the time an item is no longer viewed until the item is placed, or until a new viewing session begins. Again, each point represents a bin, as the delays also had a continuous spread. Each colored line in the background represents a participant's mean values. The error bars and shaded areas represent the 95% confidence intervals of the participant means.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Upon successful completion of the experiment participants received 5 GBP. The experiment was designed and conducted in compliance with the Declaration of Helsinki, and it was approved by the Ethics Committee of the Faculty of Social and Behavioural Sciences of Utrecht University. The approval is filed under number 21-0297. All participants gave informed consent to use their data for scientific purposes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Trial overviews of Experiment 2A and Experiment 2B. In Experiment 2A (left) participants had to memorize either three (as displayed here) or one colored circles distributed over six possible locations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>- 0 .</head><label>0</label><figDesc>04; 95% Cred. 0.05]; BF incl = 0.40). This entails that we cannot draw conclusions about an interaction effect of presentation time and delay on the precision of the responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 7).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>decisive evidence for a main effect of delay (β = -0.17; 95% Cred.; BF incl = 3.4 × 10 4 ). This entails that for every additional second of delay on the precision of the responses decreases by 0.17. Finally, we found no conclusive evidence for an interaction effect of presentation time and delay (β = -0.03; 95% Cred.   0.02]; BF incl = 0.41). This entails that we cannot draw conclusions about an interaction effect of presentation time and delay on the precision of the responses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fixed effects of the fitted GLMM of Experiment 1.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">In principle, participants could learn which item in a a memory array would be probed, but an additional analysis (see supplementary material B) showed that performance did not substantially increase over the 33 repetitions of a trial. This indicates that participants likely did not notice nor benefit from this unintended randomization procedure.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">There were also so-called "labeling" trials interspersed with the standards trials, but these are irrelevant for our purposes, so we ignore them in our discussion of the study.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>over time. Rather, we argue, it is the naturalistic context of the task, which gives rise to this pattern of more robust memories with longer viewing times. With this research we bridge the gap between the way memories themselves develop over time, and how they relate to memory-based actions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Data availability</head><p>All data, data processing scripts, and statistical analyses are uploaded on the OSF platform, and are accessible via the link: https://osf.io/dg73u/. This study was not preregistered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10">Acknowledgments</head><p>This project has received funding from the European Research Council (ERC) under the European Union's Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme (grant agreement n°8 63732).</p><p>We thank, among several others, Dion van Harten, Julia Riemersma, Marthe Frank, Nikki Vierboom, Noémi Sterk and Tabitha van Heerde for their help in data collection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11">Declaration of Competing Interest</head><p>There are no competing interests to declare.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kemp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Morson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Grindheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Does telephone testing of long-term memory retention and forgetting influence performance in young and older adults? an examination using the crimes test. The Neuropsychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MouseView.js: Reliable and valid attention tracking in web-based experiments using a cursor-directed aperture</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Anwyl-Irvine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Armstrong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Dalmaijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/S13428-021-01703-5/TABLES/7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/S13428-021-01703-5/TABLES/7" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gorilla in our midst: An online behavioral experiment builder. Behavior research methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Anwyl-Irvine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Massonnié</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Flitton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kirkham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Evershed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-019-01237-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01237-x" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="407" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Familiarity and recognition of nonsense shapes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Arnoult</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/H0047772</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/H0047772" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="276" />
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Greater visual working memory capacity for visually matched stimuli when they are perceived as meaningful</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Asp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Störmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/jocn_a_01693</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn_a_01693" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of cognitive neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="902" to="918" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1736359</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1736359" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">255</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5044</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="556" to="559" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The problem of detecting long-term forgetting: Evidence from the crimes test and the four doors test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kemp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cortex.2018.01.017</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2018.01.017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="79" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0079-7421(08)60452-1</idno>
		<idno>1016/S0079-7421(08)60452-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology of Learning and Motivation -Advances in Research and Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working memory and executive control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Della Sala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.1996.0123</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.1996.0123" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">351</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1397" to="1404" />
			<date type="published" when="1346" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory representations in natural tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ballard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hayhoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Pelz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/JOCN.1995.7.1.66</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/JOCN.1995.7.1.66" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of cognitive neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="80" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mächler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bolker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18637/jss.v067.i01</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v067.i01" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal dynamics of encoding, storage, and reallocation of visual working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bays</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Gorgoraptis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Wee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Husain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1167/11.10.6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1167/11.10.6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="6" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye movements as proxy for visual working memory usage: Increased reliance on the external world in korsakoff syndrome</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Böing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Brink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hoogerbrugge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Oudman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Postma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nijboer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Der</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stigchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3390/jcm12113630</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm12113630" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Clinical Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noisy and hierarchical visual memory across timescales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s44159-024-00276-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1038/s44159-024-00276-2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working memory is not fixedcapacity: More active storage capacity for real-world objects than for simple stimuli</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Störmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Alvarez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7459" to="7464" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1520027113</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1520027113" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of visual attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bundesen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0033-295X.97.4.523</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/0033-295X.97.4.523" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive encoding speed in working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>De Jong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Van Rijn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Akyürek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/09567976231173902</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1177/09567976231173902" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">09567976231173902</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">jsPsych: A JavaScript library for creating behavioral experiments in a Web browser</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>De Leeuw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-014-0458-y</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-014-0458-y" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Verbal labeling, gradual decay, and sudden death in visual short-term memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Donkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Nosofsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shiffrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-014-0675-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-014-0675-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="170" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When Natural Behavior Engages Working Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Draschkow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kallmayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nobre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.CUB.2020.11.013/ATTACHMENT/D934118E-1F3C-46D9-9E1F-E66CB6B720DC/MMC1.PDF</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.40" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="869" to="874" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">/</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.CUB.2020.11.013/ATTACHMENT/D934118E-1F3C-46D9-9E1F-E66CB6B720DC/MMC1.PDF</idno>
		<idno>CUB . 2020 . 11 . 013 / ATTACHMENT / D934118E -1F3C -46D9 -9E1F</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory versus perceptual-motor tradeoffs in a blocks world task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W.-T</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://escholarship.org/uc/item/5mn4s2zt" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page">22</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task constraints in visual working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hayhoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Bensinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ballard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0042-6989(97)00116-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/S0042-6989(97" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Vision research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human gaze control during real-world scene perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2003.09.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2003.09.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="498" to="504" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory for action: A functional view of selection in visual working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heuer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ohl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rolfs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/13506285.2020.1764156</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/13506285.2020.1764156" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Visual Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5-8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="400" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Don&apos;t hide the instruction manual: A dynamic trade-off between using internal and external templates during visual search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hoogerbrugge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Strauch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nijboer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Der</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stigchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1167/jov.23.7.14</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1167/jov.23.7.14" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">JASP (Version 0</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jasp Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Computer software</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/01621459.1995.10476572</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/01621459.1995.10476572" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="795" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Koevoet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Naber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Strauch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Somai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Der</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stigchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differential aspects of attention predict the depth of visual working memory encoding: Evidence from pupillometry</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1167/jov.23.6.9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1167/jov.23.6.9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new jspsych plugin for psychophysics, providing accurate display duration and stimulus onset asynchrony</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kuroki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-020-01445-w</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-020-01445-w" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="310" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The world as an external memory: The price of saccades in a sensorimotor task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Melnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Schüler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rothkopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>König</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fnbeh.2018.00253</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.3389/fnbeh.2018.00253" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in behavioral neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">253</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving memory after interruption: Exploiting soft constraints and manipulating information access cost</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Patrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Waldron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Patrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0018008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1037/a0018008" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of experimental psychology: Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Premembering experience: A hierarchy of timescales for proactive attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nobre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Stokes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2019.08.030</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2019.08.030" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Forgetting in immediate serial recall: Decay, temporal distinctiveness, or interference? Psychological review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">544</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An interference model for visual and verbal working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H.-Y</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0084327</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1037/h0084327" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">461</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Canadian Journal of Psychology/Revue canadienne de psychologie</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence of gradual loss of precision for simple features and complex objects in visual working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rademaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Sack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xhp0000491</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1037/xhp0000491" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rate of forgetting is independent of initial degree of learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Rivera-Lares</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Logie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Della Sala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13421-021-01271-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-021-01271-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1706" to="1718" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mountains of memory in a sea of uncertainty: Sampling the external world despite useful information in visual working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sahakian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gayet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Paffen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Der</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stigchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2023.105381</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2023.105381" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">234</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105381</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Action consequences guide the use of visual working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sahakian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gayet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Paffen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Der</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stigchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xlm0001326</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0001326" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychophysical scaling reveals a unified theory of visual memory strength</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Schurgin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-020-00938-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-00938-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1156" to="1172" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Normal forgetting of verbal lists as a function of their degree of learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Slamecka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mcelree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0278-7393.9.3.384</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-7393.9.3.384" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for the world as an external memory: A trade-off between internal and external visual memory storage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Somai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Der</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Stigchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.CORTEX.2018.12.017</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/J.CORTEX.2018.12.017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time-based forgetting in visual working memory reflects temporal distinctiveness, not decay</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Souza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13423-014-0652-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-014-0652-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Getting more from visual working memory: Retro-cues enhance retrieval and protect from visual interference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Souza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Rerko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/xhp0000192</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1037/xhp0000192" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Forgetting in alzheimer&apos;s disease: Is it fast? is it affected by repeated retrieval? Neuropsychologia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Stamate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Logie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Della Sala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2020.107351</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2020.107351" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">107351</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An embodied account of visual working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Van Der Stigchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/13506285.2020.1742827</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/13506285.2020.1742827" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Visual Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="414" to="419" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of learning experience on forgetting rates of item and associative memories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Ning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Moscovitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/lm.041210.115</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1101/lm.041210.115" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Learning &amp; memory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="378" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
